And the answer is that homeworks
and the final exam
count toward your final
grade in the class.
Quizzes and class participation
do not.
Now, class participation, there
really is no way to
participate directly during
the video lectures.
But we do have an online forum
that you can see in the
courseware.
And it is a very useful
way to get help with a
question you have.
Usually the student's answer
the questions much more
quickly than I do.
You'll often get an answer
within 15 or 20 minutes from
somebody out there.
And we also have some teaching
assistants that we've hired
for this term that could help
you out in the forums as well.