And the answer is
that MongoDB is
document-oriented, as we've shown.
It does not support joins,
because joins are not
horizontally scalable.
It is schemaless.
And technically, is it
really schemaless?
Each document can have
its own schema.
There are indexes that you
can associate with each
collection, which is
a form of schema.
But we call it schemaless.
The schema is, I would say,
flexible, and the schema is
not documented for a particular
collection.
And then finally, MongoDB
supports SQL.
MongoDB does not support SQL,
and that is specifically
missing in the product.
It would be difficult to support
SQL with all of the
sub-documents and sub-arrays
that are offered within the
document-oriented model.
All right, so that's
the answer.