OK, so where does MongoDB
fit in the world?
If you think about databases and
data storage in general,
you could think about these two
axes, one of them being
the scalability and performance
that is offered by
the database--
more being better-- and the
other being the depth of
functionality that the
database offers.
So up here in this left-hand
corner, very scalable but not
having very much functionality,
are programs
like Memcached and other general
key value stores.
And these programs are really
scalable and high-performance,
but they just offer almost
no functionality.
So then on the other end of the
scale, you've got really
rich functionality
from relational
database management systems.
And these are your Oracles, your
DB2s, your SQL servers.
Now the question is can we get
somewhere close to this level
of functionality but without
giving up all the scalability
and performance we
had over here?
Because relational database
management systems are not
known for being particularly
scalable.
They scale up pretty well.
You can add more and more
hardware to them to get higher
performance from
a single node.
But if you want to scale out
and use commodity hardware,
it's not particularly
good at that.
So MongoDB tries to
live over here.
And the idea is to retain
most, if not all, of the
scalability and performance
while giving you a lot of
functionality to work with,
but not quite as much
as you'd get here.
So what's missing here,
between here and here?
Well, there's a few different
things that are missing.
One is that MongoDB does
not support joins.
Now I talked about MongoDB
storing documents, and those
documents, each document is
stored in a collection.
But if you wanted to do a join
between two collections, you
can't do it within MongoDB.
And the reason is joins is one
of the items that scales
particularly poorly when
you try to scale
out to multiple nodes.
Another piece of functionality
missing in MongoDB is
transactions.
Now that sounds pretty bad,
but the truth is that you
often don't need transactions
in MongoDB in applications
where you would need them
in a relational system.
And the reason is that in
MongoDB, the documents are
hierarchical, as I showed
in the earlier segment.
And you can access those
documents atomically.
So something that might require
multiple updates
within a relational system can
be handled within a single
atomic transaction within
a single document.
So what MongoDB does not support
is transactions across
multiple documents.
And the reality is that most
of the world, you're not on
the same system, so you often
need ways to deal with systems
that are not in the same
transactional space.
OK, it's time for a quiz Let's
talk about MongoDB relative to
relational databases.
Which features did MongoDB
omit in order to retain
horizontal scalability?
Joins, indexes, secondary
indexes, and transactions
across multiple collections.
So which of these did
MongoDB omit?