All right so this is the
terminal window inside Mac OS
X. And Mongo's already
been installed here.
So what we're going to
do is we're going to
start the Mongo shell.
And the first thing we're going
to do is, we're going to
go into a particular database
where we're going to put our
collections.
In this case, we're going
to call it the test
database, use test.
And the way Mongo works is that
if the database has not
previously been used, it
automatically creates it.
And you could put collections
in it.
JavaScript Object Notation
is the way we
express data inside Mongo.
And the shell uses JavaScript
itself.
So let's imagine that there is
a collection called things.
And in this collection, we
want to save something.
So I'm going to say a very
small document in things.
So I'm going to put the document
with a key a with the
value 1, key b, with the
value 2, and a key c,
with the value 3.
What you see here is, I've
specified db, which is a
standard keyword inside
the shell.
Things as our collection, save
as our command, open
parenthesis, and then, right
here, we have the JavaScript
Object Notation.
This is a JSON document.
So it's got three keys,
a, b, and c, with
values 1, 2, and 3.
I hit Return, and then that
is now saved inside that
collection.
If I want to find it, I can
do a db.things.find,
and there it is.
I could add another document,
db.things.save.
And in this case, I'm going
to put in a, b, c.
And them I'm going to put
in another field, d.
And the reason I'm going to do
that is just to sort of make
the point that Mongo is
schemaless, and that these
documents can co-exist in
the same collection.
That's very different than the
world of relational, where you
can't have two different
structures and two different
rows in the same table.
So we'll do that.
So what happened there?
Do you see the syntax error?
Syntax error is right here.
That's got to be a colon.
Let's redo that.
And there we go.
Now we've got two documents
in the same collection.
Now you see that they've been
assigned these object IDs.
And we're going to talk more
about those object IDs later.
But they are unique identifiers
that the database
uses to keep track
of each document.
And there's always an index on
these object identifiers, so
if you search for a document
by the object identifier,
it'll find it efficiently.
Now, we see that we have these
two different documents, and
they have two different
structures.
If we want to find one of those
documents, we can do that.
And we can specify a prototype
document right here.
We're going to say find a:1.
Find the documents
where a is 1.
And if we do that, you can see
it only finds this first
document and leaves out
the second document.
OK, let's just do a short quiz
based on what we just learned.
And then I'll show you some
more complex documents.
For our next quiz, which of the
following expressions are
valid JSON documents?
Check all that apply.