In this segment we're
going to install MongoDB
3.0 on Microsoft Windows.
And I'm going to take
you through all the steps
to do that.
Now I've got a Microsoft
Windows 8 computer here,
and it is running the
traditional desktop.
And I'll show you how to
find and download MongoDB.
So go to Google and
type download MongoDB,
and that will take you
to this first link.
The first organic link
is mongodb.org/download.
Let's click on that.
And then at the top
you can see there's
an option to use the
MongoDB Management
Service to run MongoDB.
We're not going to do that.
We're going to actually run
it ourselves on our computer.
And right now, at the
time of this recording,
we had the 3.0.0 release
that's available.
And when you see it, it may
be a slightly newer version.
It may be 3.0.1 or
3.0.2 or beyond.
We're going to take the
64-bit release because this
is a 64-bit operating system.
We recommend the 64-bit release.
We definitely do not recommend
using a 32-bit release
for production because it
limits the total addressable
size of the data using the
default storage engine.
I'm going to download
the MSI file.
OK.
Now the MSI file is downloaded.
And now I'm going
to run it, which
is going to install
MongoDB on the computer.
So we're going to
click through Next.
We're going to accept
the license agreement.
Next again.
I'm going to take a Complete
install, and install it.
It's going to ask me if I'm
serious about installing it,
and yes I am.
And then it's going
to click Finish.
Now where did it put it?
Well, I'll show you
where it put it.
It put it in C drive, Program
Files, MongoDB, right here--
Server 3.0, bin.
OK?
So that's where it is.
Now let's see what's
in this directory.
So in this directory are
a bunch of executables.
And the ones we care about
the most are Mongo and MongoD.
Mongo is the shell, and
MongoD is the server.
Now we want to run this
from the command line.
Before we do that let's
do a couple of things.
First of all, let's
change our path
so that we have access to
this directory from the shell.
So I'm going to
go here to System.
I'm going to click on
Advanced System Settings.
And then I'm going to click
on Environment Variables.
And then I'm going to go to the
Path Variable right down here.
Let's scroll down and
find a Path Variable.
Path, of course, is where
Windows looks for executables
from the command prompt.
And then I'm going to
add something to it.
So what I want to add is I want
to add this directory right
here.
Perfect.
So I'm going to select that.
I left clicked on it, and
then it actually selected it.
This is exactly what
I wanted, because that
will let me do a copy
of it without having
to completely retype it.
And now, I go back to
my Environment Variables
and go to the end, and then
I'm going to hit Paste.
And I say, OK.
And then I'm going to say, OK.
And I'm going to say, OK.
Now that I've done that,
I should be able to,
in a new shell, get
to these executables.
So let me get a new shell.
Right click on the Start
menu, Command Prompt.
And now if I type MongoD,
it should start up.
Now there's one other thing we
need to do before we do this.
We need a slash data
slash db directory,
which is where MongoD is
going to put the data.
So let's do that md slash
data, md slash data slash db.
And now let's type
mongod and hit Return.
And when we do that,
you can see that.
We're seeing a log from MongoD.
And it's still running, so it's
still printing out the log.
The program hasn't exited.
It's just the log is running
right to the Command Prompt.
And if you read
the log messages,
you can see that it
tells you that it's
listening on port
27017, and that it's
putting its data in data
slash db, which is a default.
Now let's get another
shell right here.
And now let's run the
Mongo Shell program.
Before we were running MongoD.
Now we're just
going to run Mongo.
And we're going to hit Return.
And that's going to make a
connection to local host 27017.
And when we did that, we can
put something into the database.
So I'm going to put db.names.
So db-- I'm in a test database,
names of the collection-- dot
insert.
I'm going to put a
document with one key name,
and with the value
being my name.
And it says that we
wrote one document.
And now if we query
the collection,
we see there's a document with
an underscore ID, name Andrew
Erlichson.
So we've successfully
gotten MongoDB installed
on our Windows machine.
Now, if you Control
C out of this,
then MongoD will no
longer be running,
and you will no longer be able
to store data or read data
from the database.
Now you can obviously run it
as a service if you'd like,
and there's supposed to be
instructions for doing that
on the web and our manual.
But for this course, we often
run it from the command line.
And it's more convenient.
And it kind of gives
us a better feel
for what's going on
with the database.
All right.
So that's how you get
MongoDB running on Windows.