We are well on our way to
building our first web-based
application backed by MongoDB.
Let's go over how this
is going to work.
We've already installed
MongoDB.
And it is running as a MongoD
process on our computer.
And we want to write a
Python application.
And this application, which is
written in Python, is going to
use the Bottle framework which
is going to allow it to take
HTTP requests from the
outside world, homes
all across the world.
And your Python program, in
order to speak to MongoDB,
needs some sort of driver.
And that driver is
called PyMongo.
And from there, it would allow
your application to speak via
BSON to the MongoD process.
Now I'm going to go over how to
install PyMongo on a Mac.
And then we'll go and show
you how to do it on a PC.
But it's pretty similar.
And then after that, in a later
lesson, we'll show you
how to integrate the
Bottle piece.
So let's get started.
You need to download
the driver.
A good place to start for any
of the MongoDB drivers is at
api.mongodb.org.
And that's where I started.
Let me show you what it looks
like when you get there.
And then you can see
it has all these
different languages listed.
And I'm going to click
on Python.
And the current version
as of the time of this
recording is 2.5.
And I'm going to click on
installing an upgrade.
And it makes a suggestion that
if you're using a Windows
machine, use the pre-packaged
installer.
But on a Mac or other Unix
machines, you can use pip to
install it using pip
install pymongo.
And that's what we're
going to do.
Now when I first did
this, I didn't
actually have pip installed.
And I used easy install.
I think the command was easy
install, install pip, to get
pip installed.
But once pip was installed, you
can just give the command
pip install pymongo, which
you'll need to do as root.
Let's go through this.
So who am I?
I am not root.
So I'm going to become root.
And now I have root
in the computer.
And now I'm going to do
pip install pymongo.
And what that's going to do is
going to reach out on the web
and download and compile
anything it says needed.
And then it did that.
And now it's installed.
Now to test it, I've written
a small program.
Notice I exited from
being root.
I no longer need to be root.
I wrote a small Python
program,
pymongo_getting_started.py.
And we're going to go over
that line by line to
understand how it works.
So the first thing it does
is it imports PyMongo.
And from PyMongo, it
imports the Mongo
client connection class.
Then it makes a connection using
Mongo client to local
host at port 27017, which
is the default
port for the database.
Then it connects to the test
database and to the names
collection.
Now you may recall in an earlier
lesson that I inserted
my name into the names
collection.
And actually, I edited
that out to be
Richard's name off camera.
And we'll be able to pull
a name out of that.
So let's see how that works.
We didn't need to do a find
in the collection.
So we do a find_one, which
finds one document in the
names collection, puts it
into this item variable.
It'll the wind up being
a Python dictionary.
And then we just
print that out.
And that's the entire program.
So let's just go
through there.
And let's run it by
calling Python,
pymongo_getting_started.
Let's see what we get.
And we get Richard.
And just to review again, what
we've done here is we've
installed the PyMongo
piece of the puzzle.
And we have Bottle installed.
But we haven't shown you how
to integrate Bottle and
PyMongo yet.
And we'll get to that soon.
But after this step, you should
have PyMongo installed
on your computer, if
you're a Unix user.
For Windows users, we have
a separate lesson
on installing PyMongo.