In this class, we're
going to build a
blog backed by MongoDB.
And that's going to be a web
application, and we're going
to do it using Python.
We need a web framework to do
this in, and one of the
simplest web frameworks out
there, which I like because it
is pretty simple and
straightforward, is called Bottle.
And Bottle is basically one
Python file that can run a web
server and let you take requests
at certain URLs and
do basic form processing, get
some templates for returning
information to the user.
So let's go through and
take a look at that.
You can go to
bottle.py.org/doc/dev and you
can see that it talks about
Bottle and how it works and
what its features are.
And we're not going to get too
much into that in this course.
We're going to give you a lot
of the code and we're not
going to heavily test
you on that.
But you can see, they have a
listed Hello World program,
and they also have a suggestion
that you use easy
install to install Bottle.
So I am going to try that,
and we're going to
see how that goes.
So here I am in my window, and
I'm going to run easy_install.
Actually, I'm already in root,
which I know you need to be to
make this work, and I'm going
to run easy_install.
And let's see, it seems
to have worked.
So if that's true, then I should
be able to run their
Hello World program.
Let's see if that works.
So you can use any text
editor you want.
I'm most comfortable
with Emacs.
What I've done here is, I've
copied the Hello World program
into my text window.
And it's pretty straightforward.
We'll see what it does.
Basically, it looks like it
creates a route, which is a
URL that's going to watch at
/hello/name, where it will
find that name from the URL,
and it will print out a web
page with hello your name.
And it runs it at port 8080.
So that's the entire program.
So let's see if that works.
So we'll go into the terminal
window, and we'll go into our
program and we'll
run Hello World.
It says it's listening
on port 8080.
So we're going to go into our
web browser and we're going to
go to URL /hello/name and
see if that works.
So here we go; hello Andrew.
And here we go; hello
Bob, hello
Richard, and hello Dwight.
So that works.
And you're welcome to
try to get this
running on your own computer.
You're going to have to that
for your first homework
assignment.
But again, this is a basic
Python program that imports
certain methods from
the module Bottle.
It imports the route method,
the run method,
the temporal method.
It creates a route, which means
it's a URL path that
it's going to listen on and
answer requests for.
In this case, it's dynamic
ones, so it teaches us
something about dynamic URLs,
that it can take requests for
/hello/ any string name and then
it will return an HTML
document with your name in it.
So that's the way Bottle works.