All right.
Let's talk about PyMongo.
PyMongo acts as the
glue that connects
your program to the database.
So you have some
application code, which
I'll represent by this
box right here, your app,
and in order to talk to
the database, MongoDB,
represented by this M, you
need something in the middle.
And that thing in the
middle is PyMongo.
So we need to install
PyMongo on your computer
so that you can talk to the
database from your application
program from Python.
Now to do that,
we're going to start
by going to api.mongodb.org.
Let's do that now.
So we start at
api.mongodb.org, and that's not
a particularly pretty page.
It's a pretty basic page.
It's an old page from the
early days of our ecosystem,
but it very cleanly
lists all the languages
that we support and gives you a
quick link to the documentation
and the install instructions
for the language.
In this class, we're
going to use Python,
so we're going to click
right here on Python.
And then, we're going to see
all the different versions
of the driver, the PyMongo
driver, that are offered.
Now we're going to use a beta
version of the PyMongo driver
in this class.
We're going to use the 3.0 beta.
Now this is not the
production version,
but it's the version
that will be released
in the next couple of weeks.
And by the time you watch
this, it may have already
been released, so
you may not see a B
after this when you go here.
But right now, if
you come to the page
at the time of this
recording, it's still in beta.
So we're going to install it.
We're going to go to
the documentation.
And once we do that, we're
going to look down this page.
There's a lot of information
here, by the way.
There's a quick start
guide that's fantastic.
There's all the
API documentation,
and I'm going to
show you that later.
But right now, let's focus on
the installing and upgrading
instructions.
I'll click right there.
And it says that to
install I can use pip, pip
install pymongo.
Pip is an installer.
Now pip looks at PyPI
as a place to get
all of the distributions.
And unfortunately, since
the PyMongo driver is still
in beta right now, the 3.0
driver is still in beta,
if we typed pip install
pymongo at the command line,
we wouldn't get this version.
We would actually get
the released version.
So if we scroll down the
page, at the very bottom,
is some information for
installing the beta version.
So I'm going to make this
smaller so I can grab it.
All right.
Now I'm just going to
select this with my mouse.
I'm going to copy
that, and now I'm
going to bring that
to a command line.
So we go to the command
line, and we become root.
Now I'm root.
And now I'm going
to paste that down.
All right.
Let's paste that.
And now it's
running the install.
And now it's installed.
All right.
So now that it's
installed, we might
want to actually try
to write a small Python
program that uses the database.
So let's look at that.
So I have one of those
programs right here.
Let's look at it in editor.
So this is a very short program
that's going to use PyMongo
and it's going to read
something in the database.
And I'm going to
explain it line by line.
And then we're going
to test it out.
And we'll see if
it really worked.
So the first thing
we're going to do
is we're going to
import PyMongo.
This is a Python program.
And from PyMongo, we're
going to import MongoClient.
And that just makes
it a little bit easier
to use that symbol
so we don't have
to say pymongo.MongoClient.
Then we're going to
create a connection
using MongoClient to localhost
27017-- that's a default port.
We could omit that in this
case, and it would still work.
We're going to connect to
the database, test database.
Then we're going to connect
to the names collection,
names equals db.names.
And then we're going
to call find one
on the names collection.
And we're going to
print the value that
is kept for the name key.
So we have a document.
And we're going to
look up the name key,
and print that what's in
there, and get the value out.
So let's try that out
and see what happens.
So to run this program, I invoke
Python from the command line.
And then python
pymongo_getting-started.py.
And I hit Return.
And it prints out
Andrew Erlichson,
which is exactly what we put
in earlier if you remember.
We can see this in Mongo, too,
that if we do db.names.find,
that we have one document
with name Andrew Erlichson.
And by the way, the reason
this worked-- and this
is an easy thing to
get tripped up on--
is that MongoD, the
database server,
is still running in this window.
So if MongoD is not running
in this window, it won't work,
and you'll get an error.
So let's say I killed it.
Now if I try to run my program,
now it's going to get an error.
And I'll show you
that in case you
see this error when you try.
All right.
Now I'm trying to
run the program here.
But now the database
is not running.
And so now, we're hanging
on the connect call
and waiting for the time out.
And you can see, after a period
of time, we get this timeout.
And we edited out
the wait, but you can
see it says Connection refused.
And if we just start the
database server up and running
and then run it,
then it works fine.
It prints out the one document
it found, which is my name.
All right.
So that's how you get
PyMongo installed.
This on a Mac.
However, installing it on a
PC is pretty much the same.
If you install Python on the
PC, you'll get setup tools.
And by changing your path
to include those scripts,
you can use pip, which
can install PyMongo.
Now as a reminder, we're using
the 3.0 version of PyMongo
driver in this class.
It's in beta right
now, so you may
need to use that special
pip install line.
But in a few weeks, it's
not going to be in beta,
and simply saying pip
install pymongo will work.
I won't enter it
here, but that is
all you need to install
it when it's out of beta.