All right.
So we've written a small program
that pulls data out of
the database and prints
it to the screen.
Let's review that
program again.
The Pymongo Getting
Started Program.
And you can see here that we
import the MongoClient class
from the Pymongo package.
And then we connect to
the database server.
Connect to the test database.
The names collection.
And do a find_one.
And if we print that out,
it prints Andrew.
Well, let's say we wanted to
change data in the collection
and see it get updated.
How do we do that?
Well, let's open up Mongo.
We're already connected
to the test database.
Let's look at db.names.find.
There's the one object
in the collection.
Let's assign that to a
JavaScript variable.
And we're going to do a find
one so that we get one
document out of it.
We can look at that document.
Here it is.
We can modify it right in
the JavaScript shell.
And we can save it back
out like this
using the Save command.
And if we do that, then we'll
see now it's Dwight.
Or I could just do the
find one without
assigning it to a variable.
Let's do that.
Here we go.
There's a find or find one.
If we do a find one we
see the same thing.
See, the name is Dwight.
And if we exit and run the
program again, we can see that
it now prints Dwight.
So you might wonder how that
Save command works.
And we're going to go
over that later.
But I'll give you a short
introduction to that.
db.names.save, if you call it
without parentheses, then you
will see the actual JavaScript
code that makes the function
inside the Mongo shell.
And you can see that the Save
command does something sort of
interesting.
It checks whether or not there's
actually an object ID
already associated.
And if there isn't an object
ID, it assigns
one and does an insert.
And if there is an object ID,
then it does an update.
And if you recall, when we did
that find one like this and
then we looked at j, we had
the object ID in here.
So when we called db.names.save
with j like
that, we did that and it went
through the Save command.
It said, there is
an object ID.
So this must be an update of the
object, not an insert of a
new object.
And that's how the Save command
works in the shell.
All right.
So the next part is we get to
bring it all together and show
you how to do all of this using
Bottle so there is a web
application behind this rather
than a command line
application.