I want to circle back now and
show you the blog that we're
going to be building
in this class.
So I've built most of it here,
and I'm going to take you
through it quickly.
I think most people know
what a blog is.
It's a long form format for
writing articles with titles.
You can see here I've
copied some articles
from the 10gen blog.
And here, I'll click on one,
this "Free Online MongoDB
Classes."
And you can see that there's a
slug that is in the URL along
with a byline with my
name and a date.
And then at the bottom, you can
see the tags it was filed
underneath.
And then there are some comments
by some readers, and
we can add another comment
right here.
After we add that comment, we
can submit it, and it'll be
part of the blog entry.
And then if we go here to the
Home on the blog, we'll see
all the articles again.
We can also add a new
entry into the blog.
I'm not going to add a new entry
right now, but this is
one of the pages that we'll be
implementing along with a
Sign-up page and
a Logout page.
So you'll be building this
yourself as well as extending
it, and we'll be showing you how
to build a schema for this
and helping you along with
writing the code.
So this is the way it'll look
when it's all finished, but I
wanted to give you this
high-level view of it to sort
of concretely explain what we're
going to be using as a
vehicle for teaching
in the class.