All right.
So, turns out, that there's only
one of these four where
you have to use a separate
collection.
The first one is that the data
would be duplicated across
multiple objects within
the collection.
Now, this is not a reason why
you have to put the data in a
separate collection.
You might want you because you
don't want to go to the
trouble of changing it
everywhere in the source
documents, if a piece of data
changes in the sub-documents,
but it certainly isn't
a requirement.
You need an index on
the data element.
So know we support indexing
sub-documents, as well as
array elements, so there's no
problem with embedding data in
a document.
You can still index it.
And then finally, the data
is not isomorphic.
Well, I'm not sure exactly
what that means
here in this context--
I sort of made it up.
But no, it's not a reason.
Isomorphic means all the same
type, and you could, in fact,
put data in each document that
was a slightly different
type-- one was an array, and
one was an array plus a
sub-document, that
would be fine.
And there's no reason why you'd
have to put that to a
separate collection.
But this third one here is a
reason why you might have to
use a separate collection, which
is that if the embedded
data would exceed the 16
megabyte document limit,
within MongoDB, you have no
choice but to put that data in
its own collection and reference
it within the
primary collection using some
sort of identifier.