Let's talk about Python lists.
Python lists are incredibly
useful, very easy to use.
To create a new list in Python,
you start with a
square bracket and you
add your items.
In this case, I add an orange,
apple, or banana, all in
single quotes, and you close
with a square bracket.
You might notice that looks
just like JSON, very
convenient.
And if I wanted to assign it
to a variable a, I could do
that by doing a equals.
If I wanted an empty list, I
would create it like this.
And if I wanted to create
a list of lists, I
could do that too.
I could say, give me, the first
item's going to be an
orange, and I can use single
quotes or double quotes for
these strings.
It doesn't matter.
Second is going to be a pair,
and the third, for whatever
reason, is going to be
a list of numbers.
And in Python, if I don't put
anything after the decimal
point, these will be integers.
All right, let's give all that
a try in the shell so we can
see what that looks like.
So a equals apple,
pear, banana.
And if I just give a and hit
return in the shell, it will
give me the contents
of that variable.
I can also just print
it like that.
If I want to create another
list, with just integers in
it, I can do that,
1, 2, and 3.
And I can create a list that's
got lists of lists in it.
So for instance, I can create--
the first item's
going to be a 1, second
item is going to be a
list of fruit again--
apple, orange, and pear.
And then we're going
to have a three.
Let's see what's in it.
We can see there's three
items in it.
The first one is one.
The second one is a list.
And the third one
is number three.
You can dereference a list by
giving the ordinal value of
the location.
So I print c of 0 is 1, c of
1 is going to be that list,
apple, orange, and pear.
And c of 2 is going to
be the number 3.
Very easy to manipulate lists
and create lists.
Very useful because,
of course, lists
are directly in JSON.
OK, time for a quiz.
Python lists, write the code
to initialize the list with
the items hammer,
nail, and wall.
And assign the list to the
variable named things.
And do it right here.