There are lots of operations
that you can do on a list.
Let's go back to our example,
before, we looked at this
small list, which has apple,
pear, and banana in it.
And we've assigned it to a.
So if we wanted to add another
item to that list, we could
use the append function.
And we could append
a kiwi onto it.
And if we look at a now,
we'll see it's apple,
pear, banana, and kiwi.
If we wanted to change,
directly, one of the items in
the list, we could do that.
We could say a of 1 equals
grape, and they're
ordered from zero.
And now if we look at a,
we can see that it's
been changed to grape.
We can also remove an
item from the list
using the delete command.
We'll do a of 2, which
will be banana.
Now, if we look at a, we see
that banana is now missing.
It's apple, grape, and kiwi.
Now if you want to see all the
things are possible to do with
the list, you use a dir
command inside Python.
And it will look at the object
and tell you all the different
things that are possible.
I'm not going to go through
a lot of these.
They are internal commands
that we don't need to
understand.
But you can see there's
a pop, and there's a
remove, there's an extend.
You can look up the
documentation, but this dir
command is very useful,
especially inside the shell,
if you're trying to understand
what a method
can do inside Python.
I'll just quickly, briefly show
you the page here from
the Python docs, which shows
all the basic commands that
you can do, all the basic
functions and methods you can
call on the list--
append, extend, insert, remove,
pop, sort, reverse it.
And these are pretty
straightforward.
You probably won't use very
many of them when you're
working in this course.
But it's good to know
that they're
available if you need them.
Here's the quiz.
Manipulating a Python list.
Write the code to append
hammer onto
a list named things.