Next up, we're going to talk
about while loops.
While loops in Python are
pretty simple to use.
Let's show you some
code to do it.
We're going to iterate through
this list of fruit that we
created earlier, and we're
going to use a while loop
rather than a for loop.
You remember how natural it was
to do it in a for loop.
You just said for item
and fruit, and
you were done, basically.
But a while loop will be
slightly more complicated.
First, I'm going to have to use
a variable, i, to count
through the loop.
And now I'm going to
set it equal to 0.
And then I'm going to have the
conditional be while i less
than the len of fruit.
Now, len, as an operator, I
haven't told you about before,
but it'll tell you the
length of the list.
And so the length, in this case,
will be 3, and so it'll
iterate to the values
0, 1, and 2,
which is what we expect.
And then for each one, it'll
print fruit of i.
And you'll notice that
then I had i = i + 1.
This is within the loop body
because it's indented.
I did not do i++, which is what
I would most naturally
do, being a C guy, because i++
is not legal inside Python.
Because this is more readable,
so this is the structure and
the idiom that is used inside
Python, i = i + 1.
All right.
Let's go through and
see if that worked.
Let's run python while_loop.py,
and what do I get?
I get apple, orange,
and grape.
And if you recall from the
program, that was exactly the
order they were put in, apple,
orange, and grape.
So that's how while loops work.