OK, we've seen how to
iterate through a
list with a for loop.
But how would you get iterate
through a dictionary, which
looks like JSON document?
So here I've created a small
JSON document as a dictionary
inside Python, with my name
being Andrew Erlichson, my
favorite color being blue,
my hair being brown.
And then I'm going to write this
for loop to go through
this dictionary.
So I declare my own variables
dynamically here.
For key in person, I named it
key because I thought that
would be intuitive.
But you could name it
anything you want.
And now that's going to tell
Python to iterate through the
person dictionary and assign
name, and then favorite color,
and then hair to key.
And then it's going to print
out the key value, and then
the value from the actual
dictionary person key.
Now a couple things to note.
First is that we're using the
concatenation operator that we
learned earlier, with strings.
Second that you certainly don't
need to put this key in
quotes because it's
a variable.
And so it's not a literal string
that you're trying to
reference into person.
All right, so let's see what
happens when we run that.
Python, for loops.
So when we run that, we find out
that my hair is brown, my
favorite color is blue.
And my name is Andrew
Erlichson.
And so once again, it's
important to point out that
the order that came out of this
dictionary is not the
order that it went into
this dictionary.
So it went in name, favorite
color, hair.
And it came out hair, favorite
color, name.
All right, it's time for a quiz
on Python for loops and
dictionaries together.
Let's say you have the following
code-- people is a
dictionary with these
values shown here.
We integrate through people,
and then check when item is
equal to favorite color, and
then print people of item.
What does this program print?