Sometimes life does not
go exactly as planned.
And when you're writing
programs in Python,
the same thing can happen.
There can be errors.
Sometimes they're unexpected.
And we can handle those errors
because those errors will
raise exceptions in Python.
And we can catch
those exceptions.
So let me show you
what I'm talking about.
All right, here's a very small
program written in Python
called exception_uncaught.py
which does nothing but print 5
divided by 0.
And then after that it
prints "but life goes on."
So let's see what happens
when I run that program.
So I'm going to run the
program by invoking the Python
interpreter on
exception_uncaught.py,
and what happens is that rather
than print 5 divided by 0,
which of course it can't do,
I get a zero division error
and the program exits and it
does not print but life goes
on.
What if I wanted a print
"but life goes on?"
How could I do that?
I have another version
of this program that
will catch the exception
that's raised by this division
by zero error that I've
introduced into the program.
So the program looks
pretty much the same
in terms of what it
actually does, but you
can see that the print
to 5 divided by 0
is now in this new
type of control block,
and this is a try except block.
The way this works is
you have to import sys,
and then you use try
colon, you indent,
and then you have the code
that you want to run and catch
exceptions for.
And then there's
an exception block
which catches a certain
type of exception.
Now, this form right here,
except Exception as e,
is going to catch
everything of type exception
which is nearly all
exceptions that you might want
to catch inside Python
except for, I think,
hitting Control-C and
some other keyboard
errors that you probably
don't want to catch.
If you catch one of
these exceptions,
you're then going
to print it out.
So to do that you're going to,
in this case, print exception,
colon, and then we print the
type of the exception and then
the exception itself and we
assume that the exception has
a way to print itself.
And then after that, we
print "but life goes on."
Now, if we do that, we should
see "but life goes on,"
plus we've caught the
exception and so it
won't exit the program.
Let's run it.
All right.
So now the program runs.
We still don't find out
what 5 divided by 0,
is because, of course, that
has no value, it's undefined.
But in this case, we actually
get this print statement
which prints that we have a type
exceptions.ZeroDivisionError.
That's the type
of the exception.
And then it prints
out the exception
itself, which is integer
division or modulo by zero.
And after that we get
"but life goes on."
So we've caught the exception
raised by the program
and we've continued.
Now, this is going
to be important
later on because you're
going to want to also do
this inside your programs
that talk to the database,
because exceptions can occur
when trying to write data
to the database, and you
want to know about them
and handle them in
a systematic way.
You may want to
retry the inserts
to the database or an
update to the database,
or you may want to raise the
arrow all the way to the user.
It's up to you.
But you certainly
want to know when
an error occurs when you're
trying to read or write data
to the database.
So this is how exceptions
work within Python,
and you'll be using this
throughout the course.