In this optional section, I'm
going to go over how the
Bottle framework works and a
little bit of background on
web servers in general, in case
you don't have a lot of
experience programming
on the web.
This is completely optional,
and you also can learn it
yourself if you want
to go on the web
and Google for Bottle.py.
All right, so let's talk about
the web for a second.
So on the web, you use a web
browser, such as Chrome.
And that web browser
displays web pages.
Those web pages are in HyperText
Markup Language.
And your web browser displays
those pages by making requests
over TCP over IP, usually
on port 80
using the HTTP protocol.
And so the way that stacks up
is that at the bottom is IP,
and TCP is built on top of that,
and HTTP is built on top
of that, to some sort
of web server.
And this web server, in our
case, is going to be running
Python with the Bottle
framework.
If you've seen URLs, that they
have a host name and then
usually some path,
like mypage.
Now by default, if there's no
path, then you're asking for
the index of the website-- the
main page, the slash page.
A request to get a page is
called the get request.
All right, so let's go over how
we would create a simple
Bottle-based program to answer
web requests on a port.
One small note-- we can't use
port 80, typically, when we're
not root on a machine.
So in the previous examples,
I've been using port 8082, and
now I'm just going to use port
8080, which is a non-reserved
port and can be used by a user
that doesn't have elevated
privileges on it, certainly
on a Unix machine.
OK, so let's go over it.
Here's a very small program that
prints out Hello World.
And let's go over the basic
parts of this program because
they're going to be the same
in all Bottle programs.
So let's start out by importing
the framework right
here, import Bottle.
That way, you'll have
access to the
methods inside the framework.
And then, if you want to specify
a handler that will
display web pages when users ask
for your website, without
any path, the slash, like
www.google.com, or just local
host, then you do it with this
bottle.route decorator, set to
slash, and then you have a
function here, and this name
here at home_page
is arbitrary.
You can have it be called
anything you want.
And in this case, we're just
going to return Hello World.
That's all we're going to do.
Now, if we want to create a
handler for the test page URL,
we can do that as well.
We declared @Bottle.route
and then /testpage.
And again, after this the
function name is arbitrary,
and this returns a test page.
These final two statements,
you're going to probably want
to have them in all your
bottle programs.
The first one turns
on debugging,
which is very useful.
For one thing, you won't have
to restart the web server
every single time you want
to make a change.
It'll reload the pages.
It'll watch the pages.
And the second is
the run command.
And that does two things.
It specifies what port you're
going to listen on, which in
this case is port 8080.
And the second is that it gives
the host name that we're
going to accept requests for.
Under the HTTP 1.1 protocol all
web requests have a host
name in them so that multiple
web services can
run on the same port.
So let's see what happens
if we call that.
First, let's start
the web server.
And it's already started, but
I'm going to restart it so I'm
starting the web server now by
calling Python, hello.py.
It starts up.
Prints out messages
to standard out.
So this is a good place to look
if there are any errors.
And then I can go to
my web browser.
And I can make a request
for local host.
And I'm going to make that
request to :8080, 8080 that's
the web port we gave.
And if we do that, we can see
here a couple things happened.
First is, it printed out Hello
World on the screen.
And the second is that the web
server acknowledged taking
your request.
You can see it said the get
right here from 1.0.0.127
which is my loop back
IP for my machine.
So all right, that works fine.
If you want to see exactly what
came over the wire, you
can use Curl to do it,
and I'll do that now.
Curl, if you don't have it
installed, is a great little
program for making requests
to web servers
from the command line.
So I'm going to do curl minus i,
which gives me the headers
back as well to local
host 8080.
And when I do that, you can see
that I get back a 200 OK,
the date, and actually the web
server identifies itself as a
Python server, WSGI server,
and then it says that the
content it text/HTML.
And this is actually not
a valid HTML page.
It's missing the HTML in the
body and everything else.
But that's OK.
I'll show you how to add
that in a second.
And then if we want to make a
change here and request slash
testpage, because we're also
going to list slash testpage,
then we can do that,
slash testpage.
And then we get, this is
a test right here.
And that's the same thing
we'd get if we
went to the web browser.
This is a test page.
Now, if I wanted to return to
more proper page, I could.
I have to know a little
bit of HTML.
But the basic page
looks like this--
HTML, title, close title, body,
and then close the body,
and then close the HTML.
And that's a more complete
web page.
And then if we go back to our
web browser and just make a
request for the root page of the
web server, it prints out
Hello World.
But now, if we view
the source--
oh, might need to restart
the server here.
And I'll do that.
There we go.
I think, with debugging turned
on, I think your
views will be re-read.
And we haven't gone over
what views are yet.
But not source code itself.
So we see what happened there.
Now it looks pretty much the
same, and that's because the
web browser is going to hide the
fact that the page was not
valid before.
Web browsers are pretty
forgiving these days.
But if we view the source, we
can see that now it has HTML,
title, no title, and then the
body, and then a closing body
tag, and a closing HTML tag.
And if we go in using Curl, you
should see the same thing.
So I'll do that.
And then you can see it says
HTML, title, and then body.
OK, so that's how you
create routes
inside your Bottle scripts.