OK, let's go over functions
in Python and
how to define a function.
So here's a small snippet of
code that defines a function.
You can see that every function
in Python starts with
the word def.
And then you have the function
name followed by parentheses
and any arguments you want
passed to the function.
And then there's a colon.
So in this case, I've actually
created a function that
analyzes a little list.
I have a list here that's got
some fruit in it, apple,
orange, grape, kiwi,
orange, apple.
You can see there are
some repeated items.
And I want to analyze how
many times each item
appears in this list.
So to do that, I'm going to
initialize a dictionary inside
this function as an
empty dictionary.
And then have a look at
each item in my list.
And then I'm going to increment
a counter inside the
dictionary for the key using the
item in the list as a key
into the dictionary, into
the hash table.
I'm just to increment it by one
and then at the end I'm
going to return the dictionary
and then we can print it out.
So here's the main
body of the code.
It calls analyze list with the
argument being this list of
fruit and then prints out the
resulting dictionary.
Let's see what happens
when we run this.
All right, so when we run
this, we get an error.
So why is that?
It says here that key
apple is undefined.
So let's look back at our code
and try to figure out where we
get that error.
So it turns out that the issue
is, you can't access an item
from a dictionary prior
to setting it.
And the first time we find an
item in the list like apple,
and then we try to set count
of apple equal to count of
apple plus 1, we are
dereferencing something that
is undefined.
So how do we fix this?
Pretty straightforward.
We check to see if it's
in there or not.
So if item in counts, then
we can increment by one.
Else, we're going to set
it equal to one.
And that should fix it.
Let's see if it does.
I've saved it.
Go to that window.
And run it once again.
And this time it completes and
it prints out the resulting
dictionary.
It says that orange appears
twice, kiwi once, grape once,
and apple twice.
And if we look back at our code,
you can see that orange
does appear twice, and apple
appears twice, and grape
appears once, and kiwi
appears once.
So it looks correct to me.
And that's how you define a
function inside Python.