All right.
We've talked a little bit
about how Python works
and how exceptions
in Python work.
And now I want to show you how
exceptions work in PyMongo.
Now, I've written
a small program
that I'm going to
go through that's
going to attempt to
insert a document twice
into the same collection.
And we're going to get an
exception on the second insert.
So let's see what
this program does.
You can see right here,
we create a document.
The document has first name,
Andrew, last name Erlichson,
that's me.
And then we insert it, using
insert_one into the collection.
And we catch any exception that
occurs and we print it out.
After we insert it,
you can see, what we do
is we print the
document out and then we
try to insert it again
right here using insert_one.
Add at the second_insert fails,
then we print out an error.
Let's see what happens
when we run it.
So I'm going to
run this program.
And you can see,
here's the result
of the first print statement.
It prints a document out that
has last name, Erlichson,
first name, Andrew.
This is actually a
Python dictionary.
And then it inserts it.
And after the insert, when
we print it out again,
we see it has a new item, which
it has an underscore ID in it,
which is an object ID.
This was added by the
Python driver itself.
And when we try to insert
it again we get a failure.
We get a duplicate key error.
Now, why did we get a
duplicate key error?
We get a duplicate key error
because underscore ID must be
unique within the collection.
You can't have two documents
with the same underscore ID.
And when we try to insert
that document again,
once the driver had added an
underscore ID, we get a failure
and we can't insert it.
So we'll look into
the collection
real fast to confirm
that it's not there.
Let's run Mongo and
do db.users.find.
And we can see there's
only a single one there.
I'll print it out pretty.
And there it is.
Now, what if we do want to
insert this document twice?
How can we fix this
program to do it?
Let's see how we would do that.
So this program creates
a document right here,
inserts it using insert_one
and then prints it again.
Well, what if we reassign
the variable doc,
create a new dictionary
that's missing underscore ID,
and then did the insert?
Let's try that.
So to do that, we'll
save the program.
I'm going to drop
the collection.
Make sure that we start
out with a clean slate.
And then I'm going to
run the program again.
So I'm running it again.
Python mongo_exception.py,
that's my program.
And when we do that, now
we are able to insert it
and we have two
different underscore IDs,
which is what we need.
And if we go inside Mongo
and do db.users.find,
we can see that I'm in
this collection twice.
All right.
So that's how
exception processing
works within PyMongo.
And this program is
available online,
so if you want to download it
and see it yourself so that you
can use the same template
when you catch exceptions
when you write your programs
and try to insert things
or read things for
MongoDB, you can do that.