In this first homework, we're
going to have you install
MongoDB just like we showed
you in the lesson.
You're going to install either
for PC or Mac depending on
what you're using at home.
And we're going to have to use
the mongorestore command to
load up the database with some
files that have been exported
before using mongodump.
And then we're going to also
have you connect with the
shell to the Mongo database and
use the findOne command to
look up a document in
the collection.
So let's talk a little
bit about this
mongorestore command.
So most databases have a way to
get data in and out of the
database, and MongoDB
is no different.
And there's a mongodump and a
mongorestore command that you
can use to bring data in
and out of database.
We've created some collections
and used mongodump to dump
them out, and you're going
to use mongorestore to
bring them back in.
Connecting with the mongo shell
is going to require you
to have Mongo installed and
running, of course.
You're going to use the M101
collection, which is going to
be restored by the mongorestore
command.
And then finally, the findOne
command is on the mongo shell
db.homework.findone to find the
data element you need to
answer the quiz.
All right so let's see
what that looks like.
I'm going to do it right here,
so you can see what it looks
like on a Mac.
I'm going to tar -xvf
homework1.tar.
I've done that.
You see it's created a dump
directory with M101 and some
of the data here from these
different collections.
And then there's two other files
you're going to need for
the other two homeworks.
So let's look at how we
get this data in.
So we run mongorestore right
here, and I just hit return.
And it connects to
the local MongoDB
server, which is running.
And you can see right here, it
creates some collections.
So it creates the M101 database,
and it creates a
funnynumbers collection and the
Homework One collection.
And if I then start Mongo and
use M101 and show the
collections, you can see that
there's a funnynumbers
collection an the Homework One
collection and some indexes.
So I'm not going to show you
what's in those collections,
because that's the assignments
for the homework--
to prove you're able to do it.
But if you have any questions,
just put your
questions in the forums.
I'm sure somebody else is
running into the same problems
as you are.
All right.