OK, we've come a long way.
And now it's time to talk
about saving data using
PyMongo to MongoDB.
I've written a program to
show you how to do it.
So let me show you that.
This is a very small program.
And some of these parts are
familiar to you already.
You can see we start by
importing PyMongo.
And then we connect to
the database with the
Mongo client class.
We connect to the m101 database
and then to the
people collection.
And then over here, we're
going to create a Python
dictionary that has an embedded
Python array.
So let's look at
how this works.
So we have a Python dictionary
with the key name and the
value Barack Obama.
We have another key here, role
and the value being president,
and another key here, address,
with the value being another
dictionary, which has several
parts within it.
And then the final key is this
interests key, and its value
is a list, a Python list, with
government, basketball, and
the Middle East.
And then we call people, which
is the name of the collection,
it's the pointer to the
collection, and dot insert,
and the person that we
created right here.
And that's the whole program.
And at the bottom you
can see we call
Maine, which calls this.
So let's run that program
and see what happens.
All right, so let's use m101.
All right.
So now we're going to
run the program.
And we're going to
see what we get.
So let's get to the right
directory here.
So now let's run this program
and see what happens.
So we wrote the program
saving_data.
I'm going to run it.
It runs pretty quickly.
There you go.
And now let's run
the Mongo shell.
And we're going to use the
m101 database and look at
db.people.find and
see what's in it.
There's the document
we just created.
And let's pretty print that out
to make it a little bit
easier to read.
All right, so let's look at the
document that we put into
the database.
You can see here that there's
an object ID now.
And this was not something
that we specified in the
program, if you recall.
And what's happened there is
that the driver has created an
underscore ID by using
a BSON object ID.
We're going to talk more
about those IDs
later on in the course.
But every single document has
an underscore ID value.
And it does have to be unique.
And the driver did insert
one for us.
And then we see that we have
the interests array with
government, basketball, and the
Middle East, and his role
being president, and his name
being Barack Obama, and the
address, which has a
sub-document within it.
So you can see this is
the data that we
saved from the program.
But you might also notice that
the order of these items is
not the same as we specified
in the Python program.
And that's because
in Python 2.7,
dictionaries are not ordered.
And so as a result, the order it
went into the database was
not the same order as we
specified in the program.
So that's how you add data to
MongoDB, using PyMongo.