All right.
In this problem, you had to
restore the collection and
then run this program.
And the program is
Homework 1-2.py.
Let's run it together--
hw1-2.py.
It prints out that the
answer is 1815.
Let's look at what that
program does.
We can see it makes a connection
using the Mongo
client class, connecting
to local hosts.
It then connects to the m101
database and the funny numbers
collection.
It then iterates through
that collection.
In each document, there
is a key called value.
And the value is retrieved.
And then we divide it by 3, by
calling mod 3, and find out
when the remainder is 0.
And then, for that item, we
can keep a running sum.
And at the end, it prints
out the answer.
And that's it.