All right.
And the answer is
db.zips.aggregate $project,
suppress the _id, and then
give me the city.
And the city is a lowercase
version of the current city,
the $city from documents.
Population is just included,
so we just do that
with a colon one.
And that's similar to the way
we do it when we do a find.
State is included, and zip is
equal to the $_id value from
the document.
Maybe it's a little bit tricky,
but totally legal, and
that's the answer.
It's a little bit interesting
the way this gets parsed,
because if there's a one here,
then Mongo takes to mean just
included, but if it's something
more complex like a
JSON document or a dollar sign,
then it winds up having
to do something more complex.
So it seems like there's a
pretty big switch on whether
or not there's a simple integer
here or something more
complex when it's parsing what
to do with each of these keys.