Ok, the next stage of the aggregation
pipeline I want to tell you about
is the match phase.
Now match performs a filtering
which is an n:1 operation.
Match will go through each document
and see if the document
matches your criteria.
And if it does, then it will push it
through to the next stage
of the aggregation pipeline.
Now there are two reasons
why you might want to match.
The first is that, you might want
to filter the documents
and only perform aggregation
on a subset on them.
And the second reason that you might want
to perform a match is you might want
to filter the result itself
which is to perform an aggregation
and then after that, to filter the results.
Alright, lets look at the zip code
collection and see how this might work.
So, here's what the zip code
collection looks like.
It's got one document for each zip code
which is in the _id with a city
and a location
and a population and a state.
Now lets say we wanted to filter
this data set and only aggregate
on documents in a particular state,
lets say the state of California.
This is a document
for the state of Alabama
California has an abbreviation of CA
so we're going to filter on that.
Here's how we would do this
using aggregation
Now this is a small script and emax here.
First we use agg, then we call
db.zips.aggregate and our aggregation
pipeline only contains a single phase
which is a match phase
and you can see here
that this is in square brackets
so the aggregation pipeline stages
are part of an array
and there's only one in this case.
And the match is specified right here
and its very similar to the way
you would specify a criteria
for a fine command.
We're saying that the state
needs to be California.
There you go, move the cursor
so you can see the quotes.
Lets run that and see what happens.
Ok, so I ran that and you can see
that the results now, that every document
that we see that's produced
by aggregation, is California.
Now that we've reduced our data set
down to just California
we can perform a grouping
and get the population for each city
by grouping on the city, and I'll show
you how to do that.
Alright, here's how you would first
filter for California with the match
and then we have a comma here.
This is the second element in the array
in the pipeline and now we're going
to perform a group operation
in this stage of the pipeline.
We're going to group on the city
and we see that its $city to pull the city
field out of the document as it passes by.
And we're going to aggregate
on the population: $pop.
If you remember the documents,
pop was where the population
of each zip code was held.
And then, just for fun we're going to also
keep track of all the zip codes
that are included in a city and we do this
by defining a new field called zip codes.
And then, using the aggregation operator,
add to set and aggregating on the _ids.
And the _ids themselves are going
to be zip codes as the document passes us by.
So again, we're grouping on the city
and as we look at each document,
if the document is in a particular city
bucket, we're going to add its population
to the population field and then
we're also going to add the zip code
to a zip codes array.
And if we do that, lets see what we get.
Ok, so now we see the documents
have been aggregated on city
so for instance we have TERMO
and STANDISH and RAVENDALE
and its population and then you can see
that there's a list of zip codes
that are included in that city.
And for these particular cities,
it looks like they're all single zip codes
in very small cities.
But I think if we go towards the top
there might be one
that has multiple zip codes.
Yes! TRUCKEE has a population of 9743,
still a small town but it includes
two zip codes as you can see with both
these array of zip codes.
But this document isn't very pretty
because rather than saying, city, here
instead it says _id and that's just
the nature of aggregation,
that you have to define an _id
that you're going to group by.
So if we want to have this be a little
bit prettier, we can reshape this document
to essentially rename the _id field
to city, and we can do this
through projection.
And let me show you how that works.
Ok, so right here is the same aggregation
query but this time we have one more stage.
So we have our matching stage
to filter only our documents
in California, right here.
And we have our grouping stage,
to group by the city
so that we can get the population.
And that's how we wound up
with the _id and the result.
And now, finally we're going to reshape
these documents, which is a 1:1 operation.
And at this projections stage
of the pipeline
we're going to suppress
the printing of _id
we have _id: 0, and we're going to define
a new field called city.
And that new field uses the $_id value,
so that's basically
a reshaping of the document
and a renaming of the document.
And we're going to include the population
which we did by saying, population: 1
and then we're going to include the zip
codes by saying zip_codes: 1.
And that says, include these things
in the final result.
And that's going to reshape our result
to look a little prettier,
and let's see how that looks.
Ok, so now we've reshaped the document
and you can see that, the population
is here, the zip codes are here
and the city is here.
You'll also notice that MongoDB did not
retain the original ordering of the fields.
So on our previous result, the _id came
first and now the population came first,
and then the zip codes and then the city.
And this is different
than what we actually specified.
We had city, population, zip codes
and we got population, zip codes, city.
So, the projection step will specify
which fields you want to bring
through to the final result,
to the next stage of the pipeline,
I should say, because you could aggregate
further from here but it does not
retain the order necessarily.
Ok, now its time for a quiz.
So thinking again about the zip code
collection which we've been playing with,
write an aggregation query with a single
match phase that filters for zip codes
with greater than a 100,000 people.
And you may need to look up
the use of the $gt operator, if you've
forgotten how to do that.
I put a link to it here in the docs.
The way I found this by the way
is by typing: $gt space
MongoDB into google.
So, google is your friend when it comes
to looking up the MongoDB documentation
so write that query right here.