Let's start out with a simple
example of aggregation in
MongoDB to motivate how
this stuff works.
Now I'm going to start
out with an example
from the SQL world--
SQL world of relational.
Let's say we had a
products table.
And that products table had a
name, category, manufacturer,
and price for each item.
So this is a table of
electronics items.
It might be iPad, which is a
tablet from Apple, with a
price of 499.
If I wanted to get a report of
how many products there were
from each manufacturer--
the way I would do that in SQL,
is select manufacturer
comma count star from products,
where I group by
manufacturer.
And this would give me a report
that would provide me
the number of products from
each manufacturer.
Again, that's select
manufacturer, count star from
products, group by
manufacturer.
There is a comma right here.
Now if you don't understand
SQL, this is
not critically important.
But, if you do, it
might help you.
The report that we'd get would
look something like this.
We would have a manufacturer
and then the count
star for each one.
So we would have a little
report that said, OK.
Apple has two products and
Samsung has three products.
So it's this group by clause
that is very interesting,
along with this aggregation
function, which in SQL, was
count star.
Now how do we do that
in MongoDB?
Let's go and look at a
collection that is very
similar to that table from
the relational world.
Here we have a table of items
that are exactly the same as
ones that were in the other
relational table, where each
one has a name.
And it's--
Kindle paper white,
in the category--
tablets, in the manufacture--
Amazon.
And there's like six or seven
things in this collection.
It's pretty small.
I just created it now.
How would we aggregate so that
we could find out the number
of products from each
manufacturer?
The way we do that
is as follows.
I put this collection in a
database called aggregation.
So that doesn't matter.
That's where I put
the collection.
We would call the aggregate
function.
And this is how you would do
it in the Mongo shell.
And, in this unit, we're going
to focus mostly on the Mongo
shell because it maps very
cleanly to the drivers.
And I don't think it adds a lot
to explain how it works in
the drivers.
But let's say we do
db.products.aggregate, and,
again, products of
the collection.
I want to do a group by, and
then I would have a dollar
group operator.
And then I want to group
by manufacturer.
And I want to get the count.
And the way I do that--
we'll explain how this
works a bit later--
is we create a new key, called
num_products, and we sum for
each one, 1.
And we're not going to explain
exactly how this works right
now because I want to
go through it in
the following lessons.
I just wanted to give you a
high level overview of the
aggregation framework
right now.
But I want you to just
notice a few
things about this command.
The first is that the dollar
group operator
is in its own document.
So dollar group right here.
The second is, this
is an array.
And there can be other
operators.
And we're going to go through
how that works.
But, for right now, we
just have the one.
So I had open parenthesis and
I had an open array here.
And then I have a document
with dollar group.
The value for the dollar group
operator has a couple
different parts.
The first part is _id.
And you can kind of think of
this as creating a new
collection, where we're going
to group by manufacturer.
Manufacturer was a key in
my collection, but now
it's data to this--
it's a field.
And, as a result, we have to
prepend this dollar sign, and
the whole thing needs
to be quoted.
And then it's going to create
a new field called
num_products that is going to
call the dollar sum operator
and add one for each one.
We'll go through exactly
how this works.
But let's just see it work,
and see what we get.
So I just call that aggregation
function.
And what I get is a result.
And the MongoDB aggregation
framework returns its results
as a document inside MongoDB.
So that's one limitation of the
aggregation framework, is
that the document can't be
larger than 16 megabytes, just
like a normal document.
But you can see there's an array
of documents, actually,
in the result.
And each one is a row of that
table we would have seen from
the SQL world.
So Google num_products one,
Amazon num_products two, Sony
num_products one.
All right.
So that's the overview of the
way you would do a simple
group by and get the number of
items by manufacturer in the
small collection.
Now it's your turn to write one
of these, so you can get a
feeling for how it goes.
Here's the quiz.
Let's say you had a collection
of products, just like the one
I just showed you.
And you wanted to count the
number of products, not by
manufacturer, as I just
did, but by category.
So you just need to go back and
look how that query works.
Have the resulting
key be called
num_products, just as I did.
You just need to change the
column name here, from
manufacturer to category.
Or I should say, the key name.
That's all that's required
to get this to work.
And we'll explain how it works
in subsequent lessons.
But I'd like you to
type that below.
And, just so it makes it easier
for us to grade it, if
you could double quote
all of the key names,
that would be helpful.
That's not, strictly speaking,
necessary, and I didn't double
quote everything.
But just double quote it all.
That will make it better.