I realized as I was doing the
last lesson that we had never
really shown that the _id key of
a document can itself be a
complex document.
And it can be.
It just needs to be unique.
So I just wanted to quickly
make that clear.
So here I have a little
collection called foo.
And I'm just inserting something
with an _id being a
document of name andrew, class
m101, and hometown New York.
If I do that and I look at the
collection, you can see that I
have an _id of a
document here.
And so this is not something
that's unique to aggregation.
This is something that's
generally true about mongodb,
which is that your _id field
can be a document.
It doesn't need to be
a scalar value.
I think we've always shown it as
a scalar value, and that's
certainly most typical.
But in aggregation, it actually
isn't typical.
And I don't want you to think
that that's unusual or that's
a special case for mongodb
because it's not.
And the only real requirement
for _id is that it be unique
because it is a unique primary
key for the collection.
So if I try to assert that
document again with the exact
same document as its _id field
as its value, I'll find that
it won't go in.
And you can see that I get
a duplicate key error.