We've already showed you how to
use sum to count the number
of products from each
manufacturer.
What if we just want to sum
up the prices that each
manufacturer charges?
That's a little bit of a strange
thing to ask, but it's
not too hard to figure
out, using
the aggregation framework.
Here's the original program that
aggregated these number
of products by manufacturer.
And, in that case, we were using
$sum, and we were using
the integer one here.
But if we want to sum
the prices, we
just change it slightly.
And what we do is, we create a
new key, called sum_prices.
And use the $sum operator.
And then, here, give $price,
which is the column name from
the documents that are coming
into the pipeline.
And, of course, we have
quotes around it.
And we have to use $price so
that MongoDB knows that it's
the price document key
we're looking for.
Let's run that and
see what we get.
All right.
This is the result right here.
I'll just bring it up and show
you that I ran it here.
All right.
So Mongo, using_sum.js--
that was the file that
I just showed you.
You can see that it just gives
you a document in the result
set for each manufacturer and
sums their prices up--
pretty straightforward.
All right.
Let's do a quiz.
For this quiz, we're going to
have you write an aggregation
query using sum.
If you'd like, you can download
the data set that I'm
going to use for this.
You don't need because I've
given you enough information
to do it right here, but it
might be useful to you to have
a data set on your local machine
so you can play with
these queries.
This is a data set of zip code
and population information in
the United States.
You can get it from
media.mongodb.org/zips/json,
and you can import it using
Mongo import into a zips
collection, inside any database
of your choosing.
Now, just to give you folks
from outside the US some
background on the way
this data looks,
this is a city name.
This is the state.
There's 50 states in the United
States, and each one of
them has a two letter
abbreviation.
So LA is Alabama.
NY would be New York.
The states are non-overlapping.
These are postal codes,
right here.
We call this a zip code, but
it's also just a postal code.
The postal codes are
non-overlapping; although, a
city may span multiple
zip codes--
multiple postal codes.
This is some geolocation
information about
where the city is.
We're not going to use
that right now.
This is the population
of this postal code--
that is the zip code.
So that's the way this
data set looks.
And what I'd like you to do, is
write an aggregation query
to sum up the population
by state.
So you need to group by state
and sum up the population.
Now, so that our quiz checker
can check it-- our quiz
checker isn't that
sophisticated--
make sure that you call the key
that's going to hold the
population and the resulting
documents--
call it population.
And it'd be helpful if you could
put quotes around the
different key names and the
different operators.
That'll probably work
better for you.
The collection is assumed
to be called zips.
So it's going to be something
along the lines of
db.zips.aggregate, and then
open parenthesis, and your
long expression, and
close parentheses.
So we want an aggregation query
that'll tell us the
population--
sum of the population--
by each of the 50 states
of the United States.