The next aggregation expression
we're going to go
over is addToSet.
Now addToSet is interesting
because there is no direct
parallel from the world
of SQL to do what
you can do with addToSet.
And let me give you an example
of how it works.
Let's go back to our
little data set
of electronics products.
And imagine that what we want
to do is figure out, what
products does each manufacturer
sell?
So to do that, we basically want
to group by manufacturer.
And then, for each of the
manufacturers, we want to
create a new array of categories
they sell in.
And it looks just like this.
Here we are using the
aggregation database again,
which is where I put
my little data set.
We have db products
that aggregate.
We're grouping again.
That's a stage we're invoking
from the aggregation pipeline.
And we're going to group on
_id maker manufacturer.
Maker is my name.
Manufacturer is the key piece
of information here--
$manufacturer--
to pull the manufacturer value
out from the manufacturer key.
And then, we're creating a new
key in the resulting document
set, called categories.
And we're using addToSet
$category.
And if you recall,
each of these
documents had a category.
And what this will do is, it's
building a new set of
documents, grouped
by manufacturer.
And if the category is not in
this category's array, it's
going to add it.
AddToSet adds it, only if
it's not already there.
And the answer get
looks like this.
So this will give us documents
for each manufacturer, which I
called maker, like Google makes
tablets, Amazon makes
tablets, Sony makes laptops.
They make other things, too,
but not in my data set.
Samsung makes tablets
and cell phones.
And Apple makes laptops
and tablets.
They also make cell phones,
but I didn't put
it in the data set.
So you can see how that works,
so that you can build up an
array, while grouping by
another key, like, for
instance, manufacturer.
Time for a quiz.
Now you're going to write
a query using addToSet.
This uses the zip
code database--
the population by zip code--
that we've been using in
the last few problems.
You can see it in using sum
quiz, if you're not
familiar with it.
And I showed you some data
out of that data set.
Again, you can download to your
computer if you want.
In this case, I just found in
California, the city, Palo
Alto, and I got all of the
different documents out that
correspond to that city
and that state.
And now you can see there's
three different zip codes,
94301, 94303, and 94306, that
all correspond to Palo Alto.
That is correct.
So what I'd like you do, is
write aggregation query that
will return the postal codes--
that is zip codes--
that cover each city in
the United States.
And the result should look
something like this, where
grouping by the--
you can see we have
the city here.
And then we have a list of the
postal codes that corresponds
to that city.
And, for the purpose of this
problem, we'll ignore the fact
that cities do appear
in multiple states.
And that most people consider
them to be different cities,
especially when they're
thousands of miles apart.
For instance, Springfield,
Missouri, and Springfield,
Massachusetts are not
close together.
And they're not the same place,
but for our purposes,
they'll be the same place.
So write a query
that does that.
You can deduce what you need to
do, in terms of the names
of the keys in the result
document, based on
what you see here.
Again, it's called zips.
And write your query below.