And the answer is in this case
that the result was the same.
And the reason the result is the
same, if you think about
it, is that we're going through
these documents one by
one and we're adding the postal
codes that map to a
particular city and we're going
to inspect each source
document once.
And we know that the postal
codes, which are in the _id
fields, which is what we're
pushing, are unique in the
collection because, of course,
_id is unique in the
collection.
So we know that it doesn't
really matter whether we push
it or add it to set, we should
get the same answer.
Now, I ran this on the
actual data set.
And it turns out that you
don't get the exact same
answer because the order that
the postal codes show up is
slightly different.
And I'm not actually sure
why that would be the
case, but it is.
I guess it doesn't guarantee
the order.
So what I did is I sorted
them first--
and we're gonna learn about
sort very soon--
and when I sorted all of the
documents by postal code and
then ran it, the result
was exactly the same.
And when I say the same, I
meant the same from a set
theory standpoint, which is that
the same items appeared
in the result.
I wasn't really thinking about
the ordering of the items
within the result set.
But if you thought they were
different because they might
come up in a different order,
the postal codes might be in a
different order under each
city, well then you can
consider yourself
correct as well.
But for the purposes of this, I
decided they were the same.