OK.
And the answer is that 52
and 22 will be returned.
52 and 22.
So what is this doing?
Well, first it's grouping by
a,b, and it's finding the max
value of c in that grouping.
And then it's grouping just by
a and finding the minimum
value of those.
So I'll show you what it looks
like after the first stage.
So this is what it looks like
after the first stage where
it's grouping by a and b and
finding the max value of c.
And you can see that you have
97, 22, 52, and 54.
And in that final stage, it
was grouping just by a and
finding the min value.
Well, if you group by a here,
you could see there were two
ones where a is one, the first
and second entry right here.
And so it's finding the
min value of that.
So it's finding 22 between
those two documents.
And then over these two
documents, it's finding the
min value of c, and so
it's finding 52.
So 22 and 52, and that
was the answer.
22 and 52.
So that's how you can
reason your way
through what it's doing.