The next stage of the
aggregation pipeline that I
want to show you is
the project phase.
Now, the project phase lets you
reshape the documents as
they come through
the pipeline.
It's a one to one stage
of the pipeline.
So, for every document that
comes into the project phase,
one document will leave
the project phase.
You can do things like
remove a key.
You can add a new key.
You can reshape the keys.
And by that I mean that you
could take a key and decide to
put it into a sub document
with another key.
There's also some simple
functions that you
can use on the keys.
Things like toUpper
and toLower.
This will make a value uppercase
and this will make a
value all lowercase.
This can be useful if you want
to standardize the values.
You can then do some grouping on
them if there's some mixed
case going on in the values
prior to grouping.
You can add something
to the value.
If it's an integer, you can add
10, or 20, or one, or two.
You can multiply by a number.
So let me show you an example.
We have this little product
collection that I've been
showing you and doing a lot of
little transformations on, and
I want just reshape
these documents.
So to do that, I have this
aggregation query,
db.products.aggregate.
And rather than call $group,
I'm calling $project.
Now, remember.
This is an array of stages.
So I could have projections
and groupings, and I could
have multiple projections
and multiple groupings.
Right now I'm just going to
have a single projection.
And the first I've done is
specify that I don't want to
include the _id field.
Then I've also specified that
I want to create a new key
called maker and have it
contain the value of
$manufacturer.
And you'll notice that
$manufacturer is protected by
quotes here.
Don't forget to do that if
you're calling upon its value.
And I'm running it through the
toLower function because I
want to get a lowercase
version of that.
Then I'm creating a new key
called details, which is a
document that has
two keys in it.
One is a category, which is
the old category from the
document, and the other is the
price, which is using the
multiply function and
is multiplying.
And you'll notice this is
an array right here.
It's multiplying the
price times 10.
And finally, I've got another
key called item which contains
the old value of the
key called name.
So, let's see what happens
when I run that.
All right.
If I run that, I'm going
to get a result that
looks just like this.
I've already run it.
So you can see here, it says
maker, Amazon, details,
category, Tablets,
price, 1990.
It's been multiplied by 10.
And finally, item,
Kindle Fire.
So the main reason you typically
project is because
you want to clean up the
documents, but you can also do
it at the beginning if you want
to eliminate and cherry
pick certain keys out
of the document.
That could save a lot of memory
when you're running
through a large number
of documents.
It's essentially a form of
filtering step that you would
get rid of a bunch of data
before you send it to the
grouping phase.
OK, it is time for a quiz.
Now, thinking about that zip
code collection that we've
been looking at before, the
documents look like this if
you recall.
And I'd like you to write a
aggregation query that has a
single projection stage that
will transform a document to
look like this.
And you'll notice that this
is lowercase and that the
location is gone, and that the
state is still here, and that
the _id seems to be gone but
there's a new zip code key and
it's got the old
value from _id.
And for the purpose of this
query, just so that the quiz
checker can get it right, make
sure that if there's anything
you're going to do with the
_id field that you specify
that first in the aggregation
query.
And everything else should
appear in the exact order it
appears in these two documents,
since that's the
order it'll create
the results in.
So you need to do that just
to get the answer right.
OK.