Next phase of the aggregation
pipeline is $match phase.
Now, $match performs a filter on
the documents as they pass
through the pipe, and it
has a reducing effect.
So, there might be n documents
in for every one document out.
It may pass all the documents,
but it may pass some subset of
the documents.
And the reason you might want to
match is because you'd like
to filter the results and only
aggregate a portion of the
documents, or search for
particular parts of the
results set after you
do the grouping.
Now let's look at the zip code
collection again, and let's
say that I wanted to match only
on documents that are in
New York State.
So, the state of New
York, which is NY.
We could do that with this
expression right here.
So db.zips.aggregate, and then
we open our square brackets,
because again, this is a
pipeline but we're only going
to have one item in the pipe
right now, one stage, and
that's the match stage.
And then here you can see the
syntax is very similar
to that of a find.
Basically, I specify that
I would like the
state to be New York.
And this is a simple selection
of the items where the state
is New York.
And if I do that, this
is what I get.
And you can see that what it's
done is find only the zip
codes that are located within
New York state.
And once I do that, I might
want to do a grouping and
figure out what the population
of each city is.
If you recall, a city can have
multiple zip codes within it,
multiple postal codes.
So we have to aggregate across
the cities of a group by the
city to get the population
of the city.
So, we'll look at that.
Now, in this, we see a more
traditional aggregation
pipeline because it has
multiple phases.
First we're going to match and
find everything that is state
New York, and then we're going
to group and create a new set
of result documents.
We're going to group by $city,
by specifying the _id is
$city, and then we're going to
create a population key, which
is the $sum of $pop from
those documents.
We're going to add up the
population and then, just for
fun, we're going to also keep
track of all the zip codes
that appear in that city by
you doing an add to set.
And if we do that, we will
get this result here.
So we can see that New York City
has a lot of zip codes in
it and a pretty big
population.
According to this, it says
it's 1.4 million.
So, this data set considers
Manhattan to be New York and
the other four boroughs,
Brooklyn, Queens, the Bronx,
and Staten Island, to be
separate cities, because the
overall population of New York
City is about 8 million, but
this New York means Manhattan,
for those who know their
American geography and are
aware of the population.
And this data set's also
a few years old.
And you can see here all the
different populations of the
different cities in New York.
Now, let's say we wanted to
reshape this document to be a
little bit prettier.
In particular, we don't like
that our city appears as an
_id, but instead we want it
to say the word city.
So, now that we understand the
project operator, we can
certainly do that.
So let's see how that works.
Now there are three phases
to our pipeline.
First we're going to match on
the state being New York, then
we're going to group by city
and get the population, and
finally, we're going to
project a little bit.
We're going to suppress the _id,
we're going to create a
new key called city and use the
_id field, and then we're
going to just pass through
the population.
And here we could have just been
population colon 1, it
would've been the same result,
and zip codes colon 1.
So if we do that,
what do we get?
You can see this is a little
bit prettier result.
So now I have population,
zip code, and city.
Interestingly, although I
specified them in a different
order, it didn't change the
order in the document.
So that's an interesting
thing to note.
I specified city, population,
zip, but I got out something
that looks like population, zip,
city, which means that, I
guess, MongoDB, when it's
doing that projection it
doesn't necessarily impose order
that you provide in the
projection.
Just to confirm that it wouldn't
have mattered whether
I wrote $population or
$population 1, let's just
change that to be just
a 1 and see if that
works the same way.
I think it should.
And yeah, it does.
It works exactly the same way.
All right.
Here we go.
And that's how that works.
all right, so now let's do a
quiz and you are going to
write a $match.
So, thinking again about the
zip code collection which
we've been playing with, write
an aggregation query with a
single match phase that filters
for zip codes with
greater than 100,000 people.
And you may need to look up the
use of the $ greater than
operator if you forgot
how to do that.
I put a link to it
here in the Docs.
The way I found this, by the
way, is by typing $gt space
MongoDB into Google.
So, Google is your friend when
it comes to looking up the
MongoDB documentation.
So, write that query
right here.