Skip and limit inside the
aggregation pipeline work
pretty much the same way skip
and limit work when you do a
simple find.
So it doesn't make any sense to
skip and limit unless you
first sort, otherwise, the
result is undefined.
And what you want to do is first
skip and then you limit.
Doesn't usually make a lot of
sense to limit and then skip.
And skip forward just skips
forward to the document set.
So if you have a set of ordered
documents, and it's
coming at you, let's say, in
this direction, and you want
to skip forward--
So if you skip five, you skip
one two, three, four, five.
And then you start here.
And then if you limit it to
three, you get one, two,
three, the next three
documents.
If you recall when we did a
find, the order in which you
gave skip and limit didn't even
matter because the server
would automatically, or the
drivers, would reorder it so
that it first sorted,
and then it
skipped, and then a limited.
But in the case of the
aggregation framework where
you are given an ordered list of
stages, the order in which
you specify skip and
limit do matter.
Let's look at an example of
using skip and limit.
We're going to go back to our
query that we've been working
with in the last few lessons
where we were going through
that zip code data and searching
for all of the zip
codes in New York, and finding
the population for each city,
projecting the information,
sorting it by population, and
then skipping forward 10, and
then limiting it to the next
five items.
So if we do that, then we get
these items right here, which
are still some big population
places.
But the first 10 are missing
from the list, and then we get
the next five from the list,
which is Astoria, which in
Queens, Jackson Heights, Far
Rockaway, also Queens,
Ridgewood, and Binghamton.
These are not in Queens,
and Jackson Heights
I think is in Queens.
So all right.
That is how you skip
and limit.
Now, it is time for quiz.
Here's the quiz.
Suppose that you change the
order of skip and limit in the
query shown in the lesson
to look like this.
So rather than skipping first
and then limiting, you limit
and then you skip.
How many documents do
you think will be
in the result set?