Now that we've gone over how a
sort works in the aggregation
pipeline, we can talk about
first and last.
First and last are group
operators, and they're going
to allow us to get the first or
last value in each group as
the aggregation pipeline
processes the documents.
So, I think a little example
will make it more clear how
this works.
So, let's say we have
a set of documents.
And these are the
documents here.
And they've been
sorted by a, b.
So they've been sorted by a, b,
for instance we have this
document with value a, 0, b,
23, then 0 b, 45, 0, b, 97.
And again, here we
have 0, b, 17--
excuse me, I wanted
to make this a 1.
1, b, 17, 1, 68, and 1, 73.
So you can see how they're
sorted a, b.
Now let's say I want
to group by a.
If I group by a then I'm going
to process the documents
logically on this set and
logically on this set.
And then if I ask for the first
of b as I'm grouping by
a, I'm going to get this value,
and I'm going to get
this value.
So, in the grouping by a where
a is 0, I'm going to get the
first of b is 23, and a where
a is 1 the first of b is 17.
On the other hand, if I ask for
last, then I'm going to
get this value and this value.
So, after a sort phase, these
first and last operators can
find the first or last document
in sorted order in
each group.
So, let's see how we would use
this in a practical situation.
All right.
Let's say we wanted to
find the largest
city in every state.
So, how would we do this?
Well, we would have to find the
population of the city in
every state, and I do this here
in this first grouping
where I'm looking at a group
by state and city.
And then I get the population
as the sum of the pop in a
group by state and city.
And I actually have just this
part of the query and I'll
show you the results.
You can visualize what it does
before we can move on.
I call that phase one.
Let's look at that.
I'm going to pipe it some more,
just to make it a little
cleaner on the eyes.
So you can see that what we get
is basically every city in
every state we get
the population.
So, Smoot, I guess, Wyoming.
And we do that.
Now we have the population
of every city.
So what do we do next?
Well, the next thing we need to
do is we need to sort it by
state comma population.
And remember that these
documents have and _id of
state and city, so my sort has
to be on _id.state and
population.
So we do that.
And you can see that we sort
by _id.state and by
population.
And we don't need dollar signs
here because this is a sort
operation and the key names
are on the left side here.
So I call this phase two.
Let's see what we get out
of the system for that.
All right.
So, in phase two, in every
state, I have a descending
list of cities by population.
So I can already see that in
Alaska, Anchorage is the
biggest city.
And then it's going to go
through all the other Alaska
cities, and eventually it'll
go on to another state.
We have a lot of cities
in Alaska.
So let's go to phase three.
So, in phase three, now I want
to pick out just the first one
when I group by state.
So, just to review those
documents again to remember
how they look.
Those documents have _id, which
is the document of state
and city, and a population
here.
So, this next grouping is
going to group by state.
For each state, we want the
city which is the first
document in that grouping.
So the first city.
$_id.city.
First one.
And population, first
population.
And that's going to be what we
need to get the information
we're looking for.
So that's called phase three.
Let's take a look at that.
All right.
In phase three, I now have
filtered it down to the
biggest cities in every single
state by using my first
operator on what was previously
a descending sort
by state comma population.
But they're not in any
particular order, which is
interesting, because they were
sorted by state before and
after the group by phase,
they seem to
be arbitrarily ordered.
So to fix that up, what we're
going to do is finally we're
going to sort it
by state again.
And the final part of this is
that we're going to sort it by
state and that's going to give
us the final result.
Let's take a look at that.
Now we can see that in Alaska
it's Anchorage, in Alabama
it's Birmingham, and so forth
all the way down.
Now we have the largest
city in every
state ordered by state.
If we wanted to clean it up a
little bit more, we could do a
project, and we could rename
this _id operator to be state,
but I didn't do that.
All right.
So, let's do a quiz.
Given the following
collection--
and this is a collection we used
on an earlier problem, a
little collection--
what would be the value of
c in the result from this
aggregation query?
And you can see what we're doing
here is, well, you can
read it, but we're matching on a
being 0 and we're sorting by
c descending, and then we're
doing a group where we look at
the first value of c.
And to figure that out,
what's the value of c.
I'll just tell you, there's
only one value of c.
There's only one document
in the result set.