Let's talk about the unwind
pipeline stage.
In MongoDB, documents
can have arrays.
And it's not easy to group on
something within an array
unless we move it out of
the array form and
make it more flat.
So if you remember, this is sort
of pre-joined data when
you have a document
with an array.
And what we're going to do is
we're going to use unwind to
unjoin the data and then
basically rejoin it in a way
that lets us do grouping
calculations on it.
So let's look at an example.
Let's say I unwind on c.
What it's going to do is for
each document, it's going to
create a document with the
remainder of the document plus
each value from this array.
So this is what you'd get
for this document.
You'd get a 1, B 2, c being
apple, a 1, b 2, c being pear,
and a 1, b 2, c being orange.
So I got three documents as this
document passed through
the pipeline if I'm unwinding on
the dollar c, which is this
key right here.
And once I do this unwind, what
I can do is I could group
by what I just unwound and count
something else or sum
something else.
That's typically the
way you'll use it.
And if there are five documents,
for example, and
each one has three elements in
the array, then you would get
15 documents out of
the unwind stage.
So there's sort of a data
explosion from unwind.
But we need that, because we
need the data in a way that
looks, honestly, a little bit
more tabular, a little bit
more relational, so that we
can then group it on the
elements in the array.
So time for quick quiz,
see if you understand
the way unwind works.
Let's say that we have the
following collection.
We have two elements
in the collection.
And the first one is Barack
Obama, and he likes social
justice, health care,
and taxes.
And the second one is Mitt
Romney, and he likes a
balanced budget, corporations,
and binders full of women.
So let's say you want
to unwind the likes
array of each document.
How many documents will you
wind up with when you pass
these two documents through
the collection?