Sometimes you have more than
one array in a document.
And in that case, you may
want to double unwind.
And therefore create a Cartesian
product of the two
arrays, as well as the
rest of the document.
Let me give you an
example of that.
I've created a little e-commerce
inventory, where
I've got these items, like, for
instance, a t-shirt that
come in a list of sizes as
well as a list of colors.
So here's some chino pants
in sizes and colors.
Now what if we want to figure
out the number of items that
are available at any given size
and color, regardless of
what the name of
the product is?
How would we do that using the
aggregation framework?
I'll show that to you.
So ignore the top
of this file.
This JavaScript program first
creates the collection.
And here is where the
interesting stuff starts.
We call db.inventory.aggregate.
We're going to unwind
by sizes.
And then right after we unwind
by sizes, we're just going to
create a new set of documents
where each size is with the
rest of the document.
And each size will have
a colors array.
And then we're going to
unwind by colors.
And at this point, we
have a list of names
and sizes and colors.
So it might be polo shirt,
small, navy, and polo shirt,
small, white.
That's what we're going to get
at the end of the second
unwind phase.
If we want to group it,
we do it like this.
We do a grouping, where the
"_id" is set to the size,
$sizes, and color, $colors.
Don't be fooled by the
fact this is plural.
After the unwind happens, this
is now, in a sense, singular
because there's going to
be one item in each
document for these.
And then I can just count it
using $sum, adding one.
And if I do that,
what do I get?
I get pretty much what
you'd expect.
In the "_id" field of each of
these result documents, I see
there's a size and a color.
And I'm going to count the
number of times they appear.
So size small, color red,
there's two items.
And size 32 by 32, and these
are inches for pants in the
United States.
Color white, there's one item.
All right.
So that's how you double unwind
if there's more than
one array, and you want to
expand both arrays out and do
aggregation on the items.
Let's do a quiz.
Can you reverse the effects of
a double unwind, two unwinds
in a row like I showed you?
Can you reverse the effects of
double unwind in our inventory
collection, shown
in the lesson,
with the $push operator?
We talked about the $push
operator being able to reverse
the effects of an unwind.
Can you reverse two unwinds
using the $push operator?
So think about that.