And the answer is yes, with
two pushes in a row.
So what does that look like?
I'm just going to show it to you
because it's wild enough
that it's kind of fun.
So here we go.
First, I'm unwinding by
size and colors again.
And then I am grouping again
by size and color.
So at this point, I have the
result I had during the
lesson, which is that I've
grouped by size and color.
And now I want to get the
original documents
for the most part.
So how would I do that?
Create the size array first.
I group on name and colors,
and then I push
the size onto sizes.
So these are scalars at
this point, and now
I'm building an array.
And then, after I do that, I
have a second phase where I
create the colors array.
Right here I push the colors,
and I look at name and sizes.
And then I build the
size array by
grouping on name and colors.
Now at this point, colors
is no longer--
their $colors is no
longer a scalar.
It's actually an array,
because I
built an array of colors.
So I'm grouping on the name of
the product and an array of
colors, and I'm pushing sizes
onto a new sizes key.
And that will produce
the same result.
And then, just to clean
it up, I'm going to
reshape it using project.
I'm going to drop the id, I'm
going to create the name from
_id.name, I'm going to include
the sizes, and I'm going to
include the colors
from _id.colors.
So if I run that,
reverse_double_unwind.js, you
can see I get back in the result
field pretty much the
original documents.
The ordering is a little bit
different, but I can see that
here is name "T-Shirt" and here
are my sizes, and here
are my colors.
And here's my "Chino Pants",
and here are my sizes, and
here are my colors using
that push operator.
So that's pretty neat, and
it works pretty well.
And you could do it with
two push operators.
You can also do it with a single
stage if you're willing
to use the set operator and
you know that they were
originally unique.
So let me show you what
that looks like.
So here we're going to do
the exact same thing.
We're going to unwind by size
and colors, and then we're
going to do a single grouping
stage, and we're going to use
addToSet, versus push.
And we can essentially
build them
simultaneously using addToSet.
I tested it.
It seems to work, because in
this particular case the items
were unique in the
original arrays.
So if we call that, you can
see we get back the same
documents again.
In a single stage using
addToSet, but this is sort of
a special case for that.
OK, so, the answer is yes, I
can reverse a double unwind
using two pushes in a row
although I have to be kind of
careful about how I do it
because it's a little tricky.