In this problem, we asked you
to figure out the average
population of cities in
California and New York that
have populations individually
over 25,000.
And we also asked you to
consider a city that appears
in both states to be
a separate city.
So if the same city name appears
in both states, it's a
separate city.
Now, it's a little tricky
because of that, but it's
fairly straightforward once
you sort of pull it apart.
I know that for a lot of people,
some of the English
itself was probably the
most challenging part.
Now, we see that the
answer is 82,541.
So let's go through
this step by step.
The first thing we do is we want
to look at the states,
California and New York.
Because this problem only refers
to those, so we can
immediately filter
out by that.
Then, we have to group by city
and state in order to separate
out the cities from the
two different states.
That is, that a city that
appears in two different
states is a different city
and it will be considered
separately if we have the ID
for this grouping be state
comma city, which is
what we've done.
And then, remember, we're
looking at these zip code
level records, and there
are multiple zip
codes in the same state.
We then take the population in
each zip code and add it to
that entry by state
comma city.
Now, we want to filter out
only for cities that have
population greater than 25,000,
so we do a matching
step right here.
And we look for population
greater than 25,000.
That's the match.
And population is the field we
named here, so this field and
this field correspond
with each other.
And now, we just need to get the
average population across
all those cities.
So we need to do
a new grouping.
And this time, we're going to
group by ID null, which is a
way of getting a summation or an
aggregate across an entire
collection.
And we're just going to get the
average of the pop field.
Let's look at that and see
what the answer is.
And I've already run it here.
You can see that the answer
is 82,541.46,
or just 82,541 rounded.
And that was the answer
to the problem.