In this problem, we asked you to
figure out who the easiest
grader on campus is.
Now, by easiest grader we meant
the person who has the
classes, or the class, with the
highest overall average.
And to figure out the class
with the highest overall
average, you need to first
figure out the average for
each student, because there
are variable number of
assessments for each
student, and then
average those numbers.
So it was just a double group
by to figure it out, and a
single unwind.
So let's go through
that step by step.
First of all, this is the
way a document looks.
And I'll show it to you
here on the terminal.
So you have a student, and he
or she has, let's see, an
exam, a quiz, a homework,
a homework, a homework.
And we need to figure out the
average of these assessments.
Now, we also stipulated that we
are not to include the quiz
scores in the calculation.
So we're going to have to do a
little bit of filtering to not
include the quiz scores
in the calculation.
And we're going to get the class
ID which has the highest
average student performance.
So let's go through that.
All right, we start by
unwinding the scores
collection.
That makes sense, because we
want to figure out the average
for each student.
Then, we filter and make sure
that we don't look at any
document that has a scores.type
of quiz.
Now remember, when we were
unwinding the scores
collection, the scores was
originally an array of items
that had type in them.
And now, once they're unwound,
it's going to be scores.type.
We flattened it out
by one level.
So we just want to filter out
anything that's not a quiz,
and then we're going to get the
average for that grade of
that student.
We're going to group by the
student ID and the class ID,
because we want their average
performance in that class.
And then we're going to get the
average score that they
achieved using this
average operator.
And we're going to
name it average.
After that, we're going to go
through and we're going to
calculate the average
for each class.
So next stage of the pipeline
we're going
to do another grouping.
And we're going to group by the
class, and then take an
average of the average that we
had previously created in the
previous stage of
the pipeline.
Now at this point, we have a
bunch of documents that have a
class ID and an average score.
And we can just rank those
from highest to lowest.
And the one with the highest
average student performance
should be the one that we
consider to be easiest.
And if we do that, we can see
here if we scroll up, that the
answer is that class ID 1.
Here it is, right here.
Here's the result.
Class ID 1 has the
highest average.
Average of 64.5.
And class ID 1 was the
accepted answer.