OK, welcome to week 7 of
MongoDB for developers.
This week we're going to be
doing some interviews with
users of MongoDB, and today I'm
here with Jon Hoffman from
Foursquare.
They were an early and big user
of MongoDB, so thanks for
coming here today Jon.
Yeah, thank you for having me.
So we're going to do this
pretty casually.
I have some questions I would
like to ask you about your use
of MongoDB at Foursquare.
I guess first we should talk
about what Foursquare is,
because some of our
international students may not
be familiar with it.
Can you describe it
really briefly?
Sure, Foursquare
is two things.
It's a social utility.
It's a way to tell your friends
where you are and find
out where they are, and then
we also recycle that
information and aid in social
discovery of your city.
So if you're looking for a new
restaurant, or a bar, or any
type of place in your city, you
can use the app to search
for that sort of thing,
and we'll give you a
recommendation based on where
your friends have been and
where you've been in the past.
And is it primarily a mobile
application then?
Yeah.
So you use it on your
smartphone--
like your iPhone, your
BlackBerry, or your Android--
and you use it while
you're on the go.
So give me a feeling for
the scale of this?
Like, approximately how many
check-ins occur, and what is
the rate of check-ins and
that sort of thing?
So people let each other know
where they are, or check-in
about five million
times per day.
Wow
Yeah.
All right.
And what's the main role of
MongoDB in the system?
So MongoDB is our primary
data store.
We use it for almost
everything.
Every time someone checks in--
all those 5 million check-ins
every day gets stored MongoDB.
We store the user's account
information in Mongo, we store
all associated information
like information about a
place, tips that people
have left--
almost everything is
stored in Mongo.
That's great.
What's your role there?
Just so people know.
So I manage the storage team,
where we focus on online
storage and offline storage.
And online storage is our Mongo
database build out.
So describe the evolution of
the use MongoDB, from the
beginning versus how
it's evolved.
Can you give us a
sense of that?
Sure.
So Foursquare started in 2009,
and the prototype for
Foursquare was actually
built on top of MySQL.
And then they had to be a
rewrite when things started to
get serious.
So we started to rewrite the
application in Scala, and we
switched from MySQL
to Postgres.
That was fine for a little
while, but at some point we
realized that we're going to
need to split our data up
amongst multiple servers.
And that would involve getting
rid of a lot of the features
that you have in a relational
database, like joins and
transaction integrity, so that
we'd have to move to some
other type of system,
either on top of SQL
or something else.
So we looked at a few options,
and we knew some people who
were using Mongo.
We started moving some things
over to Mongo in 2010.
And we started with just
a few collections.
So we moved over the database
that stores venue
information--
information about places like
restaurants and bars.
We moved that over to
Mongo, but we didn't
do the switch overnight.
What we did was we started
writing all of our data to
both places--
both to SQL and to Mongo.
And once we were satisfied that
things were stable, and
we knew what we were doing, we
slowly migrated the reads over
from SQL to Mongo.
So you were basically running
both systems in parallel.
Exactly.
And writing to both systems,
so you weren't dependent on
Mongo for awhile.
You kind of got comfortable with
it, and then you switched
over once you were certain that
it was working for you.
Right, we need to get confidence
in the technology
and make sure that all of the
data that was supposed to be
there was there.
And once we had that, we
switched things over.
OK, so at this point, did you
turn Postgres off entirely at
this point?
We actually still left
it on just in case
something went wrong.
So we still had rights
going to both places.
It's just that the read location
was now Mongo.
And we left that on for at least
a few weeks before we
were confident that we
could turn it off.
What's your implementation
language?
You said it was Scala?
Yes, Scala.
And were you using just our
driver, or is there some other
intermediary layer that you
used to talk to Mongo?
So just some background
on Scala for
people who don't know.
Scala is a statically compiled
language that runs
on top of the JVM.
So you write code in a
syntax that's a bit
different from Java.
It kind of combines
object oriented
and functional styles.
But it compiles down to Java
bytecode, and it's completely
backward compatible with
Java libraries.
So the driver that we're using
was just 10gen's own Mongo
Java driver.
OK.
So the students all know that
MongoDB is schema-less, and we
talk a lot about that being
good in terms of agile
methodology and letting you
evolve your schema over time.
Can you tell us a little bit
about how your schemas has
evolved over time?
Whether or not it has been
helpful, or whether the schema
has been fairly static
over time in Mongo.
Sure.
So it depends on
the collection.
Some of our collections have
remained stable over time, and
some of them haven't.
And I can give you an example
of our biggest collection,
which the check-ins
that we store.
This is thing that we get 5
million a day of, and at this
point we have over 2 and 1/2
billion of these things.
And when we first started
putting data into the
collection, we didn't have a
good sense for how much space
it would end up eventually
using.
We could have done the math
ahead of time, but we didn't
think to, because we were
kind of new to Mongo.
And at some point we realized
that we were storing data in a
less than completely
efficient way.
So we were able to rewrite the
records while the system was
still live, so that involved
going through a batch job that
ran through and removed certain
bits of data, added
other data.
We added new field names, in
some cases, that were shorter,
new keys on the documents that
were shorter and were going to
take up less space.
And the way we did this is, we
continued to have old field,
we added a new field, and then
in our application code, we
were able to handle both,
depending on what existed.
So the new field name would take
precedence over the old
field name, but it would still
be able to read the old field
name if that's all
that existed.
In that way, we were able to
have this migration process
running without taking
any downtime on that.
So it was almost like a lazy
migration where it would--
were you actively
migrating data?
Or was it just faulted in when
you used that document you
would update it to
the new schema?
So it was both.
So for new data, it could be
written with the new schema,
but we don't update old
data very often.
So we had to run a
batch process.
And over a few days-- it maybe
even taken a few weeks to
rewrite all the data--
we slowly rewrote these keys.
So let's talk a little bit
about performance.
On your most active collection,
do you know how
many indexes you have, just
in order of magnitude?
Do you have 1, 5, 10, 100?
Well you can't have 100, but how
many indexes do you have
on the most active
collections?
I think the most active
collections have
fewer indexes actually.
Makes sense.
Yeah because those are the
ones that are most
sensitive to rights.
They have very well defined
access patterns.
So for our check-ins collection,
I think we have
three or four indexes, and
that's the biggest one.
And then for some smaller
collections where we be a
little bit more loose in our
access patterns, where we're
not as sensitive to rights,
I think the most number of
indexes we have still
would be under 10.
Do you use our geospatial
indexes?
We do.
So when we migrated our venues
collection, which is one of
the first things we migrated
from Postgres to Mongo, one of
the big benefits of Mongo
is that it had built in
geospatial indexing.
So Postgres has that as well,
but it wasn't as easy to use,
and we weren't as familiar
with it.
So when we were on Postgres,
we were just doing own very
crude bounding box queries, like
get me the venues where
the latitude is between this
value and that value, and the
longitude is between this value
that value, which works
up to a certain point.
And when we moved to Mongo, we
switched to using the built in
geoindexing, and we were able to
handle a lot more load on a
single machine.
Do you use the 2D model?
Or do you use the new
spherical model?
At the time-- this was a
couple of years ago--
so at that time, we were
using the 2D model.
And currently, I think we're
still using the 2D model on
collections that have
geoindexing.
OK.
Right.
Which still means that with the
way you used to be doing
it with latitude and longitude
bounds, you
were getting boxes.
And so now you're getting
circles, but they might be
ellipsis, because the lines of
latitude and longitude might
not be equally spaced,
I guess.
And we sometimes have
problems with that.
Further from the equator,
I guess.
Right, exactly.
So in very northern cities, like
Reykjavik, Iceland, we
have problems where the amount
to work the database has to do
to find a certain bounded area
is just a lot higher than in
other places in the world.
Interesting.
So while we're on the topic
of performance, how do you
monitor the system to make
sure you're getting good
performance--
find your slow queries?
What is your standard way of
making sure that a developer
is writing queries that hit the
indexes and that no one's
going to mess up the performance
by putting in a
slow query that's frequent?
So in our application layer,
we're using a library that we
wrote in-house called Rogue.
And this is a Scala library.
And it allows you to define a
schema for each document.
It also allows you to statically
define what the
indexes you're using
on the database.
And in the code itself, when you
write a query that doesn't
use an index, you'll actually
get a compile error--
That's pretty cool.
--in your application code.
And there's a way to override
that, of course, because
sometimes you do want to do a
full scan query, but if you
don't specify that, you'll
get a compile error.
And you won't even be able
to run your code.
Index selection is not
completely obvious.
We have a Query Optimizer, and
sometimes there are several
different plans.
How do you know, for any given
query, what index MongoDB
would use without running it?
So first of all, when we're
designing a collection, we go
through an internal review
process where people describe
the data they want to store,
what the query patterns are
going to be, what the update
patterns are going to be, how
they correlate to other things
that we already know something
think about.
Like, are they adding something
that will correlate
to some action, like something
that will be
accessed on every check-in?
Or something that will
be accessed on every
recommendation query.
So that way we understand the
usage, and then we can decide
what indexes we want to build.
And once we have that, we also
know what queries we're going
to be executing.
So one of the problems that you
could have in Mongo, is
that you could execute a
query and it could use
an unintended index.
And we've seen that
happen before, but
it's a very rare case.
Like, very often the index
that's used is the one that we
expect to be used.
So you have it statically
mapped, basically?
We have it statically mapped,
but Mongo has some
intelligence built in where the
decision of what index to
use you can sometimes
be ambiguous.
And I believe there are
heuristics within Mongo based
on the amount of time that a
query takes using an index
which is another, it'll decide
to go with one or the other.
That's right.
That's what it does.
And sometimes we've seen that
make the wrong decision.
Do you hint in that case?
Yeah in that case, we'll add a
hint onto the query so that we
knew that we are always going
to use the right index.
And does the developer need
to write the hint?
Or is it automatically built
into this interface layer so
that, as long as--
do they have to write the hint,
or is it written for
[INAUDIBLE]?
Yeah, so the developer
will right the hint.
And because we have the indexes
statically defined as
this part of our schema
definition, all they have to
do is say like, dot hint, and
then have reference this
static defined index.
OK.
All right.
And then when you want to roll
out new code, do you keep a
system running?
Do you quiesce parts of
the system to do that?
If you have to migrate the
schema our change the schema
slightly, how do you deal with
that in the running system?
So we've had a few cases where
we've done more complicated
migrations than the check-ins
migration
that I described earlier.
So in the check-in schema
rewrite, we were able to use
the same schema definition
within our application on top
of the changing document,
because it didn't change in a
drastic way.
But in some other cases, we've
done very, very drastic
changes, and it would
be too risky to kind
of do that in place.
So what we've done in those
cases, is created an entirely
parallel collection of data.
So an example of this is
our friends graph data.
We started off with a friend
graph that basically just had
one record for each
relationship.
So if I'm friends with you,
there'd be a relationship that
points to that--
in that direction.
Like, me to you-- my user
ID to your user ID.
And there'd be another record
that points from you to me.
And that way, when we did a
query on who are my friends,
we'd just be searching
on let's say the
from key in this record.
And when we're doing a query on
who are your friends, we're
also searching on the from key,
and there'd be just be
two separate records for each
side of the relationship to
make the querying easier.
We realized that that
was using--
that kind of representation of
the friend graph was using a
lot more space than it
needed to in Mongo.
So we basically de-normalized
that friend graph.
So instead of storing one record
per relationship, we
stored one record per user, and
inside of that record we
had a list of all of the
friends that they had.
So for your friend record,
there'd be a list of each user
ID that your friends with.
And the same for my
friend record.
Now, the friend relationship
in Foursquare is
an asymmetric one?
Or is it a symmetric one?
I can follow you without
you following me back.
For the most part,
it's symmetric.
We do have some rare cases
where it's not.
But the process of rewriting
that schema was fairly
complicated.
So what we did was we basically
had both schemas
running in parallel, and in
order to keep them in sync, we
utilized the Mongo
oplog itself.
We wrote an application that
tailed the oplog for all
modifications to the original
collection and then
transformed those into the way
that they should look in the
new schema.
That was a pretty involved
migration.
So that's a good segue, so we
haven't gone over too many
operational issues in this
course because it's not the
DBA course, but I want to give
the students some idea of
operationally what
you look like.
So first of all, you
run sharded, right?
Yeah.
And you run on AWS?
So we have a split environment,
actually.
Our application servers run on
AWS and some other internal
sources, but our Mongo database
servers are actually
in our own colocated servers.
And that's been an evolution for
you, because you did run
them on AWS.
So we started off on AWS, and
then we've recently migrated
over to our own racks.
Right, and I've seen some talks
from Foursquare talking
about that.
Some of the early problems were
with EBS performance.
So EBS is the elastic block
store at Amazon.
It's essentially a network
based file system.
And you weren't getting the
performance you needed, and
there were other problems.
And so you talked about
migrating away from--
I saw this maybe six months
ago-- away from Amazon just
for that part of it.
Has that been a good
migration?
Did it help you solve the
problems you were having when
you went to dedicated
hardware?
Yeah it did.
So the problem that we are
having with EBS was that
because it's a network service,
every once in awhile
you'd see very great variations
in the latency for
doing disc operations.
And in addition to that, you'd
see just extreme variations
where the I/O would completely
lock up on the machine, and
that's because there's some
sort of background process
running on the data
to re-mirror it on
Amazon's side of things.
And no application deals
with the disc
completing locking up.
No, not easily.
Applications just do not
expect that happen.
So there could be an I/O error
maybe that an application
knows how to deal with, but an
application does not deal well
with indefinite lockups of I/O.
And Mongo doesn't deal
with that well.
And the problem we had was that
Mongo has this wonderful
replication feature of replica
sets where you can have a
primary, and multiple
secondaries, and ideas that
your rights go to the primary.
You have multiple secondaries.
If one of these servers goes
down, you have redundancy.
So if the primary goes down,
there will be an election and
a secondary will take over
and become a primary.
Within a few seconds, you'll
have a new place
to take your rights.
If one of the secondaries
goes down, that's fine.
Queries will be routed to
the other secondaries.
But that failover mechanism
relies on some sort of hard
failure, like the process died,
or the machine died, or
it's inaccessible
on the network.
When the process is simply just
extremely slow because
the disk is no longer
returning I/O calls.
Mongo doesn't know how to
deal with that well.
So what we would see is that
this wonderful failover just
didn't function because of these
problems of running on
top of network discs.
And would you see flapping?
Would you see--
would the system think that a
replica was gone, and it would
try to pull it out and it
would come back and?
No what we would see, actually,
is depending on
where the problem occurred, we
would just have queries timing
out on the back end.
So if our application tried to
do a right, and the primary
was having a problem, that
right would time out.
If they're trying to do a
read to a secondary--
those would time out.
Do you use safe mode?
Right concern--
do you call get last error
to make sure that
your query is complete?
Yeah we do, actually.
We run GetLastError with SAFE,
WriteConcern SAFE.
And is the new system that you
co-located, does it use solid
state drives, or does it
use spinning disks?
Yeah it uses solid
state drivers.
I guess Amazon didn't have solid
state drives when you
made the decision to make
that transition.
Is that true?
That's true.
Do you have any experience with
trying to use solid state
drives at Amazon to see if
you get the same result?
No.
The information that I have from
other people is that they
actually work as advertised.
So we're running solid state
drives on our own machines,
and I assume that the
performance characteristics
would be somewhat similar.
So that actually would have
solved our problems with
running on Amazon, if we
had access to that
technology at the time.
But there are additional reasons
for moving into our
own co-located servers.
And the biggest one, besides
this reliability concern,
which was has actually since
been addressed, is the cost.
So we think that because we're
at a certain scale, we can
dedicate a certain amount of
money to purchasing a fixed
set of capacity and actually do
things a little bit cheaper
than on Amazon.
That really didn't make
sense until we got to
be a certain size.
Yeah, certainly.
When you're small, the thought
of adding one person to handle
these things dwarfs the cost
of any slight markup that
Amazon has over doing
it yourself.
Right.
Yeah.
I guess when you get
to a certain size,
that's no longer true.
I thought maybe we would go over
the life of a check-in
and do that in front of a white
board, if that would be
OK with you.
And we'd move to a whiteboard,
so you can show everybody--
give them a high level view of
what happens when someone
checks in, relative
to MongoDB.
Sure, all right.
OK well, we'll be right back.
OK, so welcome to our
acoustically challenged
conference room.
You're going to take us through
the life cycle of a
check-in, showing us how it
interacts with MongoDB.
So, a check-in is something
that would be done on your
iPhone, or your BlackBerry,
or your Android device.
And what you're doing is you're
posting a certain
amount of information over to
Foursquare's application
server, and then we're doing a
back and forth with our Mongo
databases to store
that information
and render your result.
So I'll walk you through the
basics of how that happens.
There's basically three
actors in the system.
There is the user's
device over here,
which could be an iPhone.
Then there is our application
server over here, and as I
mentioned, this is code
written in Scala.
And it's running on top of
the Mongo Java driver.
And then we have our Mongo
database over here.
So the first thing that happens
is the user taps on
their device, they locate the
venue that they're at, they
click on that, and they
click check-in.
And the information to gets
posted over to our app is a
token for authentication, a
venue ID, and some lat, long
information from the
device about where
they are right now.
So when the application has that
information, the first
thing it needs to do is to
authenticate the user.
So it takes that token that came
over, and it executes a
query against Mongo--
token.
So it's basically just doing a
simple find query where the ID
is the token.
And the result that it gets back
is a record that has a
mapping to the user
ID for that token.
OK.
So it gets the user ID, which
is an integer of some sort.
Right.
So the user ID is an integer.
So now for Mongo, we
get the user ID.
And the reason the user ID is an
integer and not a standard
Mongo object ID, is because
we're coming from a legacy of
a SQL system where the ID was an
auto incrementing integer.
And because of the pervasiveness
of the user ID
as a foreign key, it would've
been a lot of work to migrate
over, so we left this
as an integer.
And the user name is changeable
on your system then?
Yes, so the user name
is changeable.
So our document within Mongo
for a user record has the
underscore idea as an integer,
and there's fields for first
name, last name, email,
et cetera.
So once we have this user ID on
the app server, we want to
look up this user record that
has the more detailed
information about the user,
because one of the things
within the user record is
their last check-in ID.
And it turns out that we
need that later on.
So then we do a query to Mongo
with the user ID, and what we
get back is this fat
user record.
Gotcha.
OK.
Go to the app server--
it goes to that.
That's on the app server now.
The next thing that we need to
do is we need to take this
venue ID, and make sure that
it's a real venue.
If it's not, then we'll return
an error to the user.
So we execute a query
with this venue ID.
And the venue ID is a standard
Mongo object ID.
So we send a query over with the
venue ID, and we get back
a venue record.
Or not-- in that case we fail.
And keep in mind that these
are different collections.
So this would be a collection
called oauth tokens, this is a
query against a collection
called users, this is a query
against a collection
called venues.
Which of these are shorted?
So all of them are
sharded actually.
I'm simplifying things a bit
here, but some of these are on
completely different
Mongo clusters.
So we have the venue information
stored on one
Mongo cluster and the
user information
on a different one.
And these Mongo clusters are
full sharded systems with
Mongo S routers, and multiple
shards, and replica sets
within each shard.
But just for the flow, I'll
leave those details out.
So after we have the venue
record, we basically have
everything that we need to
record the check-in.
So that's what we do.
At this point, we can create
a new check-in record.
So we can create a record,
and we store that
check-in over to Mongo.
So we do an insert operation.
And we do this with a
WriteConcern SAFE.
This other stuff--
well this is the first write you
did, so the other ones are
just reads.
So right, WriteConcern
SAFE, right?
So at this point, we've stored
the check-in, but we need to
do a lot more work.
One thing that we do
is we calculate
rewards on your check-in.
So if you've ever checked in at
Foursquare, you know that
sometimes you get a badge
for doing a check-in.
You might get points, we'll give
you information about how
long it's been since the last
you've been to a place, how
many miles it's been since
your last check-in.
In order to do that, we need
a lot more information.
So one thing that we need is
actually your entire check-in
history up to that point.
So to calculate certain badge
rewards, we need to know how
many times have you been to this
particular place or to
this type of place
in the past.
So we'll do a query here.
So there's no real result
here, but we'll do an
additional query to get
your check-in history.
And what this is, is a query
on the user ID against the
check-ins collection.
So the way that the check-in
collection works is we have
one document per check-in,
and then there's a
user ID in each document.
We have an index on user ID, and
the collection is actually
sharded by user ID.
So we'll do a query against
the user ID, and we'll get
back multiple check-ins.
So a query on user ID, and
then we get back many
check-ins documents.
OK.
You pull their entire history
if they have check-ins?
Yeah, so we pull their
entire history.
If they've checked in thousands
of times, we get
thousands of documents.
Each one of our documents
is about 85 bytes.
Wow, that's small.
So you've really worked on
keeping those small.
Yes, we did a lot of work to
make sure that the keys within
each document are often
a single character--
were possible.
We're storing the absolute
minimum of data.
We have a few Boolean fields
on there, but instead of
putting each Boolean in
it's own key, we have
basically a bit set.
So we're storing one long on the
document, and we're doing
some bit arithmetic
to write to a
particular bit in that long.
So, does that make it harder to
develop, that you've made
all the key names one character
in the documents?
It doesn't, because we have this
statically defined scheme
that we've written for
each document.
And in our application code,
we have very convenient
humanized names for
these fields.
I see.
So those names are not really
seen by developers very much.
So developers won't see that the
venue ID field within the
checking record is just a v.
What they'll see is dot venue
ID on the check-in.
And that way, things
are manageable.
It would be a very difficult
situation if you have to
remember that v was venue ID in
some cases, and maybe it's
something else in some
other cases.
Would you like a feature in
MongoDB that would take care
of this type of mapping for
you and keep smaller--
Yeah ideally, Mongo would
somehow compress that
information itself.
And then we wouldn't have
to manage that.
So it would be convenient if
there was a feature to do
that, but you're doing
it for us, basically.
Right.
Yeah.
I think there's room for
improvement there, because
even these one letter keys are
still duplicated, in our case,
a few billion times.
So you'll have a few gigabytes
of data just for storing each
character in the key name.
You probably need some
delimiter, because the schema
can be different in
each document.
It's an interesting problem.
Yeah I think it's one that's
on the horizon to fix, and
there are possible solutions
out there.
But hopefully a future version
of Mongo will have that.
And it's usually not a problem
until you end up getting into
the hundreds of millions or
billions of documents.
For someone just getting started
with Mongo, if your
library doesn't support aliasing
short key names to
long key names, it's probably
better to stick with a human
readable name.
At least think about the type
of scale that you're
going to grow to.
Yeah I think that one of the
benefits of MongoDB is the
readability of the data
when you get it out.
It does hurt you a little bit to
have to have it translated
because you look at
the document.
If you're just doing some
debugging, or snooping around,
it's almost obfuscated.
Yeah we've had to be disciplined
in using our own
tools to do investigations,
because if you look at a
check-in document--
just the raw data for Mongo--
if you use the console and pull
up a document, you have
these kind of ambiguous
names for the keys.
Oftentimes it's pretty obvious,
but you also have
this flag, which is a long,
which is a bit set, which no
human I know of can interpret
themselves.
So you need a computer
for that.
We usually don't use
the Mongo console
to bring back document.
We'll bring up a Scale console
and use our own application
code to bring back a document
if we want to
manually inspect it.
If you had to do it again, would
you use Scale again?
Yes, I think Scala has been
really great for developer
productivity.
It's something that I think a
lot of developers get excited
to use, because it combines a
lot of benefits that you get
from a statically
typed language--
all the benefits you get from a
statically typed language--
with some of the flexibility
that you would have in a
language like Python or Ruby.
I think the most important
feature that leads that
flexibility--
that kind of dynamic language
style flexibility--
is the ability to create
closures in
line with your code.
So an example of that is if you
have let's say, a list of
check-ins, and you want to
convert that into a list of
venue IDs, because that's the
input for some other function.
In Java, what you would
have to do is--
you would create a new array
list, and then you would write
a for loop, and then in the body
of the for loop, you'd
add check-in dot ID
to that list.
So you'd have like four
lines of code to do
this very basic operation.
Maybe there's an opportunity and
therefore a bug, like an
off by one error if you started
your for loop on the
wrong index or you put the wrong
comparison operator,
something like that.
So in Scala, instead of having
to write these external
looping functions, the
collections have built in
transformation methods and
iteration methods.
So a collection will have a
dot map method on it that
takes a function that converts
each item in the collection to
something else.
So the code to convert a list
of check-ins into a list of
IDs basically looks like
check-in dot map.
And then an inline function,
which in Scala could just be
as simple as like, underscore,
dot venue ID.
And then in that one line
you'd have that
transformation.
I think that you can do that
in a lot of other languages
like Python and Ruby, but then
you don't have the benefits of
static compilation.
You can't get a lot of the other
features that make us
productive like statically
checking that our Mongo query
syntax actually will yield a
sensible Mongo query, because
the way that we create queries
is by building up upon
statically defined fields
in our schema.
But it runs in the JVM.
Yeah this runs in the JVM.
So it is a dynamically
executed language.
No.
It's actually just a syntax
that gets compiled
into Java byte code.
So at the time that your
application is running, the
JVM doesn't really know that
it's executing Scala.
It's just executing
Java byte code.
It's the combination of this
compiler that takes a
different type of syntax, and it
converts it into byte code
and a library.
All right.
So this point you've got all
the previous check-ins, so
what happens next?
So over here-- and I'll gloss
through this bit-- but we
calculate things like what
badges they may have won, what
points they may have gotten, and
basic informational bits,
like the times of the last
check-in, the last time
they're there, maybe the
number of miles they've
traveled since their
previous check-in.
So I'll just gloss over that,
but we're basically
calculating rewards here.
The output of those rewards
might be information that we
store back into Mongo.
So for every check-in where
you've scored some points,
we're writing a score document
back into Mongo.
If you won a badge, we'll write
a record of that back
into Mongo.
So we might do a few
more writes here.
But at this point, we have all
the basic information to
return a result back
to the user.
So they've checked in, it's
been successful, we've
calculated their rewards.
Now we return a result back to
the user, and we basically
have all the information that
we need to do that.
We'll return the check-in--
the ID from their check-in.
And the important thing to
realize here, is that when we
inserted this check-in,
we actually
created the object ID--
the unique identifier for that
check-in-- on the client side.
So we don't--
Kind of like what we do with
BSON object IDs almost.
Well they are BSON object IDs.
Oh they are?
Yeah.
The object ID for the check-in
gets created client-side, so
we know what it is before
it hits the database.
So we have this check-in ID,
we have the venue that they
were at, we have the result of
this reward's calculation, and
at this point, we return a
result back to the user.
This is extremely simplified
version of what
we're actually doing.
I can tell you that here maybe I
described six or seven Mongo
operations, but on average we
actually do something like 40
or 50 Mongo operations.
So do you have--
do you cache Mongo with
memcache or anything?
Or do you run directly
against it?
No.
So we query directly
against Mongo.
And are you stateless in your
application servers?
Like--
I'm sure you have load balances
in front of your
application servers, right?
Yeah.
So am I locked to one
application server during a
session, can my requests go to
this application servers over
a period of even microseconds,
and it won't matter because
they're stateless.
How does that work?
Yeah, exactly.
These app servers--
the servers that handle
our API requests--
which are requests from the
devices like iPhones,
Blackberrys, Androids,
they're stateless.
And we have tons of them.
You'll post a check into
us and get a result.
And that might go to app server
one the next time that
you issue a request to
us, that'll go to a
different app server.
And there's a reason for
a state to be stored on
[INAUDIBLE].
Is there a session state?
Do you have a collection for
session state so that these
application servers can go
from request to request?
No.
As far as the API is concerned,
all the session
state would be handled by
the client application.
So if this the iPhone
application, it's maintaining
what's going on on
your own device.
It knows where you are
in some process.
OK.
All right.
Thanks.
Sure.