Let's start out with a simple example
of aggregation in MongoDB,
to motivate how this stuff works.
Now, I'm gonna start out
with an example
from the SQL world,
SQL world of relational.
Let's say we had a products table,
and that products table had
a name, category, manufacturer,
and price for each item.
So this is a table of electronics items.
Might be an iPad,
which is a tablet from Apple,
with a price of $499.
If I wanted to get a report
of how many products
there were from each manufacturer,
the way I would do that in SQL
is select manufacturer, comma,
count star, from products
where I group by manufacturer.
And this would give me
a report that would provide me
the number of products
from each manufacturer.
Again, that's select manufacturer,
count star, from products,
group by manufacturer.
There's a comma right here.
Now if you don't understand SQL,
this is not critically important,
but if you do, it might help you.
The report that we'd get
would look something like this.
We would have a manufacturer
and then the count star for each one.
So we would have a little report that said,
okay, Apple has two products
and Samsung has three products.
So it's this "group by" clause
that is very interesting,
along with this aggregation function,
which in SQL was count star.
Alright, how do we do that in MongoDB?
Let's go and look at a collection
that is very similar
to that table from the relational world.
Here we have a table of items,
that are exactly the same as the ones
that were in the other relational table.
Where each one has a name,
and, say, Kindle Paperwhite,
and the category, tablets,
and the manufacturer, Amazon,
and there's like six
or seven things in this collection
it's pretty small,
I just created it now.
How would we aggregate
so that we could find out the number
of products from each manufacturer?
The way we would do that is as follows.
I put this collection in a database
called aggregation
so that doesn't matter,
that's where I put the collection.
We would call the aggregate function,
and this is how you
would do it in the Mongo shell,
and this unit we're going to focus
mostly on the Mongo shell
because it maps
very cleanly to the drivers,
and I don't think it adds a lot
to explain how it works in the drivers,
but let's say we do db.products.aggregate
and again, products is the collection,
alright, I want to do a group-by
and then I would have a $ group operator,
and then I want to
group by manufacturer,
and I want to get the count,
and the way I do that, we'll explain
how this works a little bit later,
is we create a new key
called num_products
and we sum for each one, one.
And we're not gonna explain
exactly how this works,
right now, because
I want to go through it
in the following lessons.
I just want to give you
a high level overview
of the aggregation framework right now.
But I want you to notice a few things
about this command.
The first is that the dollar group operator
is in its own document.
So, $ group right here.
The second is, this is an array.
And there could be other operators,
and we're going to go
through how that works.
But for right now we just have the one.
So, I had open parentheses
and I had an open array here.
And then I have a document
with dollar group.
The value for the dollar group operator
has a couple different parts.
The first part is underscore id.
and you can kind of think of this
as creating a new collection.
where we're going to
group by manufacturer.
Manufacturer was a key
in my collection ,
but now it's data to this, it's a field,
and as a result, we
have to prepen this dollar sign
and the whole thing
needs to be quoted.
And then it's going to create
a new field called num_products
that is going to call
the dollar sum operator
and add one for each one.
We'll go through exactly how this works,
but let's just see it work
and see what we get.
Okay, we get back five documents.
And each document
corresponds to one row
that we might have gotten back
if we'd done a group
by manufacturer in SQL.
So for instance, the first document
is Amazon, num_products two,
second document is Sony,
num_products one.
The third document is Samsung,
num_products two.
So this is just a simple overview
and the example
of how you would group by manufacturer
in a collection to get back
aggregation results.
Now, it's your turn to write a query.
Here's the quiz: Let's say you had
a collection of products,
just like the one I just showed you,
and you wanted to count
the number of products,
not by manufacturer, as I just did,
but by category.
So you just need to go back
and look at how that query works.
Have the resulting key be called
num_products, just as I did.
You just need to change
the column name here
from manufacturer to category,
or I should say, the key name.
That's all that's required
to get this to work.
And we'll explain how it works
in subsequent lessons.
I'd like you to type that below.
And just so it makes it easier
for us to grade it,
if you could double quote
all of the key names,
that would be helpful,
that's not strictly speaking necessary,
and I didn't double quote everything,
but just double quote it all
and that will make it better.