Aggregation uses a pipeline in mongoDB.
And if you're familiar with the unix world,
you probably know what pipes look like.
For instance if I wanted to look in a
directory and find a size of
every sub-directory in it
du - s * piped to sort -n
that would numerically sort the size
of sub-directories
and print them on my screen.
So, that's the Unix world of pipes.
And we have a similar idea
of a pipeline here.
At the very top is your collection
and, for instance,
that product's collection is sent through
document by document.
The documents are piped through
this processing pipeline, and they
go through a series of stages,
and then we eventually
get a result set.
Now, the one stage I showed you
is the group stage,
which is going to do the aggregations.
But there are lots of other stages.
There's a potential sorting stage
and a matching stage
we filter for documents.
I'm gonna go through each one
real briefly to explain how it works.
But these stages can appear
multiple times inside the pipeline.
If you recall when I showed you
that aggregation command,
there was an array inside
the function call.
And the reason there was an array
is that each of the items in that array
is a stage of the pipeline
that is gonna transform that collection.
Okay, let's go over each of these
pipeline stages quickly
and talk about what it does.
The first one is $project.
Now, just to be clear,
you can have these pipeline stages
appear more than once in the pipeline
and they also can be
in many different orders.
But what project is gonna do
is it's going to reshape the document.
It's gonna select out certain fields
and also potentially select one out
from deep in the hierarchy
and bring it up to the top.
So, the reshaping of the documents..
And for every document
that comes into the projection stage
one document is gonna leave
the projection stage.
And so, we say this stage is 1:1
in terms of its handling of the documents.
Another stage is $match.
Match is a filtering step
where you can select out
only the documents
that you wanna analyze
in the aggregation.
So, for instance, in the previous example
where we had documents
that had a different manufacturers,
we might decide only filter
on the manufacturer
being Samsung or Apple.
And so, this is going to be
an n:1 filtering.
Where we're going to reduce the number
of documents potentially.
The next operator I wanted to discuss
is the Group Operator.
This is really central
to aggregation itself.
This is going to allow you to do
the aggregation.
I'm gonna write 'aggregate'.
And, inside the group stage
you could use things like sum and count
that will group together the documents
and perform these aggregation functions.
So, by its nature, this is an n:1 stage
where we're gonna reduce down
the number of documents
whereas we go through this stage.
Now, you can also sort your documents,
which does pretty much what you'd expect.
Sorts the documents in a particular order.
Sorting by itself is a 1:1 operator.
Every document that comes in
comes out on a maybe different order.
And, once you finish sorting
documents in a pipeline stage,
it could be interesting to..
Let's say skip forward in the documents,
and that just skips
much like you would when doing a query.
If you sort, you might wanna skip
forward from the result.
Let's say, skip 10 or skip a hundred.
And then, by its very nature,
skip is going to be an n:1
transformation.
Which is that some documents are
gonna enter that are not going to exit.
You can limit the number of documents
that you send through the next stage.
And limit works very naturally with
sort and skip.
So you might sort by something
and then skip the first hundred
then limit yourself to 20.
And this limits the number of documents
that goes through the stage--
that come out of the stage, I should say.
And again, this an n:1 transformation
where we're gonna reduce down
the number of documents.
Now, in order to group by something
in a hierarchical document
that may in fact have array of items
we need to, somehow, flatten this data.
And the way we're gonna do that
is with the Unwind Stage.
And that's gonna essentially
normalize our data, alright?
Let me show you how it works.
Let's say you had tags
inside the document,
and you had "red", "blue", and "green".
If you put the document through
an unwind stage, you would wind up with
three documents: one that had tags: red,
one that had tags: green,
and one that had tags: blue.
Everything else with the document
will be the same.
So, we unwind on tags.
So, this creates an explosion of data
but it makes it possible to run
the group by's that we wanna do
and the aggregation functions
that we desire.
So, this is gonna expand the number
of documents we have.
If any given document at there's..
n items in an array
we're going to get
n documents out.
So, these are the main operators that
we're gonna use in aggregation.
Normally aggregation puts all of its
output, returns it directly to you
instead of the documents in a cursor.
But if you wanna redirect
those documents to another collection,
you can do it with the the $out stage
and name a collection
that should get the results.
So, this is all about taking the output
of the aggregation.
1:1, everything that comes in goes out.
And then, some stages that
we're not gonna heavily get into
in this particular course
but you can read them online,
are $redact and $geonear.
These operators are both...
The redact operator
is a security related feature
that can be used to limit the
what document certain users see.
And, the geonear stage
allows you to perform
location based queries
to limit the documents that come through
the pipeline stage based on location.
Alright, so, now that you know
what stages exist in
the aggregation pipeline,
it's time for a quiz.
And, I think this quiz is gonna be
pretty straight forward.
Which of the following are stages
in the aggregation pipeline?
Check all that apply.
Match, Transpose, Group, Skip,
Limit, Sort, Project, and Unwind.
Just check all that apply.