Now we understand how to use
the match pipeline stage in aggregation.
But what if you want to do something
a little more complicated than match
and you want to do a full text search?
Well, it turns out that full text search
and aggregation are two great tastes
that go great together in MongoDB 2.6.
Now let me show you how to use
full text search and aggregation together.
Here I have the collection that we used
before to show how full text search works.
We have a bunch of documents--
each one with a key, "words",
with a bunch of different words.
And if we want to do a full text search
on "words", we would need to have
a text index on "words".
And, in fact, we do have that index.
You can see that there's a full text
search text index on "words"
right here, "words" inside the collection.
And that'll let us do a full text search.
So how do we do
an aggregation that uses this?
Here is a simple aggregation example.
And in this aggregation example
we're going to have a match phase
and that match phase is going to specify
that the text needs
to search for tree and rat.
And if you recall, these documents are
all full of these randomish words.
So tree and rat appear here,
tree appears here, dog appears here,
obsidian appears here, shrub, etcetera.
So we're using the same syntax
we'd use to do a find command
and a full text search.
We're going to use the match pipeline
stage and we're going to specify
the text operator and that we're
searching $search for tree and rat.
And that's essentially an or term.
It's going to look for tree and rat
anywhere in the string.
And then, just for the simplicity
of printing out the result,
we're going to use a projection phase
and that projection phase,
we're going to pull out words
and we're going to suppress _id.
And that's just to print out
the results in a little cleaner way.
So let's see what that looks like.
Alright, so, text_agg.js was
the file that I just showed you
and I'm going to run it.
And we can see that, when we did that,
we got basically all things
that have rat and tree in them,
or rat or tree in them, I should say.
So "rat shrub granite", "cat tree ruby"--
capitalization doesn't matter
with full text search.
We got a whole bunch of results that are
related to rat and tree, or rat or tree.
And just to point out
what may not be obvious,
the words, these random words,
were in the "words" key,
but the "words" key doesn't appear
over here in the actual match term.
Because with full text search you're going
to have a maximum of one full text index
in each collection and you don't need
to specify the key that holds it.
You can just specify that you
want it to be a text search,
looking for tree and rat.
Now we talked about a way
of having MongoDB order the results
from full text search in a way
that weights the ones that have both terms
more highly and shows those first.
And you can do that
as well using aggregation.
And here is that file.
So, in this case, we run
the exact same match phase to start.
We're going to match on tree and rat.
And then we're going
to run a sort pipeline stage,
and in that sort pipeline stage, we're
going to sort by this textScore.
So we create a new key score,
which is defined as the meta information
of textScore, which is what
comes out of the engine
as it does the full text search.
And so now we're sorting by this textScore
for each document that was
discovered with a full text search
and this should give us a sorted array.
And, right here, we're just going
to again project "words" and _id
suppression so that we
can get a cleaner result.
So let's see what that
looks like when we run it.
Alright.
And the difference here is,
in this case, the ones that have
both rat and tree appear first
because they're the strongest matches.
So "rat tree ruby", "rat tree granite",
"rat tree obsidian"--
you see these right at the top.
When we did it without the sort,
then you can see that even
the documents that contain both terms
sometimes were more deeply
ordered into the list.
Now the last thing I want to point
out about this full text search
within aggregation is that the match phase
that includes the full text search
must appear first.
And the reason is that once you go
through another pipeline stage
like a grouping, there'll no longer be
the required full text search index
on the collection, if you will.
If you think about it,
every time a pipeline stage exists,
then you go from one set of documents
to another set of documents
and instead of documents
that's past the first stage,
won't have that full
text search index on it,
and, hence, you can't do this match on it.
So you need to have that match
with the full text search term be first.
Okay, it's time for a quiz.
Which of the following statements are true
about using a $text operator
in the aggregation pipeline?
Text is only allowed in the $match stage
of the aggregation pipeline,
$text is only allowed within a $match
that is the first stage
of the aggregation pipeline,
$text can be used without
an underlying full text search index
when used in conjunction with aggregation,
and the results of $text are always sorted
according to search match quality.
So which of the following are true?