The aggregation
subsystem allows you
to specify certain
options that will change
the behavior of
aggregation, and I
want to talk to you
about how those work
and when you might
need to use them.
So the first one is
explain, and explain
lets you-- instead of
running aggregation query,
get the query plan
that would be used
if we ran the aggregation query.
So that's useful in optimizing
aggregation operations.
The next one is
allowDiskUse, and this
controls whether or not the
aggregation framework will
use the hard drive for some
of the intermediary stages.
By default-- and
we'll go over this
in a later lesson
on limitations--
any given stage of aggregation
is limited to 100 megabytes.
Certain stages like projection
run the document straight
through and don't
use a lot of memory,
but certain stages
like, for instance,
sort-- which will by default
sort in memory-- if you exceed
100 megabytes the
aggregation will fail.
And so if you know you want
to do a large aggregation
and you're willing to accept the
performance hit of using disk,
you can specify that the
aggregation can allow disk use.
And the last one has to do with
the use of cursors and cursor
size.
And we're going to use
that one in a way that's
slightly different
than you might expect.
And I'll show you as we go
onto the lesson what that does.
OK, let's talk about
how you some of these.
You all remember the ZIPS--
the ZIP code collection
that we showed
earlier, which has
a bunch of ZIP codes
and their populations.
And we might want to
aggregate on the state--
that's the US state-- and what
population exists in the state.
So to do that, we do
a grouping right here.
A grouping where
the underscore ID
is the state-- $state-- and then
the population is $sum; $pop,
which refers to the population
field of the ZIP code
collection.
And just to remind you what the
ZIP code collection looks like,
let's take a look at that.
Let's look at the
ZIP code collection.
Db.zips.find0ne().
Just to remind you what the
ZIPs collection looks like,
each document contains
an ID with a ZIP code,
and then a city and a state.
And if we wanted
to aggregate based
on the population
in each state, we
could do it by grouping
on the state-- underscore
ID is a state-- and then
creating a new field called
population, and having that
be the sum of all the dollar
pop fields from each document.
Dollar pop held the
population and a ZIP code.
But let's say we don't
want to do the query
but simply explain it.
Well, here's how
you'd add an option.
So right here you can
see that the first part
of this aggregation query is
an array of aggregation stages,
and in this case is only one,
which is the group stage.
But there could be more.
And after this array we
have another document,
and we have this
explain keyword true.
And this explain keyword
true tells MongoDB
that it should, rather
than run the aggregation,
give you an explanation
of the query plan.
So let's go through and see what
would happen if we use that.
I put this aggregation
query into this text file,
so I'm just going to
redirect it into the shell.
And you can see when we run
it, that rather than get
the answer, what we get instead
is this large document which
contains all this information
about what indexes were used
to satisfy different parts
of the aggregation query.
And of course if I
remove this right here,
if I remove it-- so now I
just have the aggregation
query itself without the extra
options in that document.
Then if I run it
again, then I will
get the aggregation results,
which are very simple.
It's the population
of all the states.
This is the first bundle of
the iterator, first page,
and you can see the
population of each state
and what it is, as of the date
that this data was current.
OK, so that's how you
would use explain.
If you wanted to use disk
during the aggregation query,
it would work similarly.
You would put right
here-- allowDiskUse=true.
And don't forget
to add this comma.
So this is really a second
argument to aggregate,
and then it'll work fine.
And you shouldn't notice
any difference in-- sorry
about that.
Let's go through that.
I made a small mistake.
It's not allowDiskUse=true
when creating a JSON document.
So if you wanted to-- instead
of explaining, allow disk use,
you would set up this
allowDiskUse:true as a document
that follows the array, which is
the first argument to aggregate
of all the stages.
And if we run that, we
see the exact same result.
Might have been a tad
slower, but of course you
can't see it for
this small problem
because it's using disk.
OK, so one thing to
point out real quickly
is that there's actually
two forms for aggregation
that are acceptable
historically.
In one form, you have
an array of stages.
Stage, stage, stage.
In another form,
you have just this.
Aggregate, and then
in parentheses,
just-- no array, just
stage, stage, stage.
And each of these stages is
of course a JSON document.
So only this form
of using an array
to hold your pipeline
stages allows
you to add aggregation options.
This one does not.
So this one, you
cannot add options to.
So you don't use this
older form if you
are hoping to add options.
And the reason is
that in this form,
the option would go
right at the end,
and there would be no way
for MongoDB to differentiate
whether that's another stage, or
the options of the aggregation.
And of course, the way
that we specify the options
is by having an array of stages.
Stage, stage, stage.
And each one is different.
I mean, it's called
stage two, stage three.
And then after that, in
this JSON document right
here, we've got our options.
And that's what I showed
you on the screen before.
You can see that
I had, right here,
these stages in an array, only
one, and then another document
that contained my first options,
allow disk use and true.
OK.
So that's the way
you specify options.
And this is specifying those
options using JavaScript.
And the next part,
I want to show you
how you specify the
options using Python, which
is interesting for a different
reason as I'll explain.
OK, it's time for a quiz.
Which of the following
aggregation expressions
properly allows disk use
when performing aggregation?
And you can see there
are four choices here,
and they're subtly different.