Okay, and the answer is the second one.
The second one is properly specified.
You can see here the aggregation stages
are in an array, and 'allow disk use'
is specified with out a dollar sign
because you don't use a dollar sign
when specifying this literal for this option.
Now, the first one's wrong because
there's a dollar sign there
and it won't work, and you can try it
to confirm that.
And the third one's wrong because
'allow disk use' is specified properly
without a dollar sign, but we've taken the
pipe line stages out of the array.
It's the older style specifying a
navigation and it won't work with options
'cause mongoDB doesn't know whether
this is a pipeline stage or options.
And the last one is wrong, even though
it does use an array.
It uses this dollar sign
which is not the right way
to specify allowing disk use.