The main benefit of embedding
data from two different
collections and bringing it
together into one collection
is performance.
And the main performance benefit
comes from improved
read performance.
Now, why do we get improved
read performance?
The reason is the nature of
the way these systems are
built, the computer systems are
built, which is they often
have spinning disks, and those
spinning disks have a very
high latency, which means they
take a long time to get to the
first byte.
They often take over one
millisecond to get to the
first byte.
But then, once they get to the
first byte, each additional
byte comes pretty quickly.
So they tend to be pretty
high bandwidth.
So the idea is that, if you can
co-locate the data that
you're going to use together
in the same document, embed
it, then you're going to spin
the disk, find the sector
where you need this information,
and then you're
going to start reading it.
And you're going to get
all the information
you need in one go.
And it also means, if you have
two pieces of data that would
normally be in two collections
or in several relational
tables, but instead they're in
one document, that you avoid
round trips to the database.
Because now, in one round trip,
you can go in, you can
read the data, and you
can get back out.
Same thing with a write.
In one trip, you can go to the
database, you can write the
data you need, which would
normally potentially go into
multiple different parts of the
system and parts of disk,
write one location on the disk,
and then get back out.
And the only real caveat on this
is, as I said earlier, if
a document winds up getting
moved a lot more often because
you've brought the data together
because the document
needs to be expanded, then you
could create a problem.
You could slow down your writes
because of the embedding.
So again, it all comes down to
your access patterns with
MongoDB and trying to design
a schema around the access
patterns that you see in your
actual application.