Now I'd like to talk to
you about GridFS.
If you want to store large files
inside MongoDB, you're
limited by the document size
limit of 16 megabytes.
But, MongoDB has a special
facility called GridFS, that
will break up a large
file into chunks.
And store those chunks
in a collection.
And it will also store metadata
about these chunks in
a secondary collection.
So, you have a collection that
tells you about the chunks and
then a bunch of chunks that
are stored within MongoDB.
So how does that work?
Well, let's take a look.
I have a video file that
is too big to be
stored inside a document.
It's about 100 megabytes.
And it won't store easily
inside MongoDB.
And we can see this
file right here.
Let's look at it.
And there it is at
100 megabytes.
So what do we do?
Well, I've written a program
called using GridFS, that's
going to store that file
inside MongoDB.
So here's how it works.
We get a connection to
the test database.
And we have our own metadata
collection that we create
called, videos_meta.
We don't need that, but I just
wanted to store information
about everything I stored
into the database.
And then I get a new order
pointer to GridFS, giving it
the db handle and saying that
I want it to put all those
chunks into a collection
called videos.
And then I open a file
descriptor in Python to my
video mp4 file.
And I open that up
as readable.
And then I get the ID of
a new GridFS file.
I put the file into GridFS,
right here, giving it as an
input the file descriptor of the
open file that I want to
read off disk.
And it returns to me
the underscore ID
of the GridFS object.
And then I just close
my incoming object.
And then, just so I can keep
track of stuff, I also store
that ID that I got from GridFS
into that collection that
referenced up here, called
videos_meta.
I just insert that ID and
the file name, so I
know what it is.
So let's see what happens
I try to run that.
Python, gridfs, and it's going
to take a few seconds because
it writing a hundred
megabyte file.
And there we go.
It says the ID of the file is.
So let's go into Mongo
and see what's there.
So I'm going to run Mongo.
Use the test collection.
Show collections.
All right, I see four different
collections there.
One of them is called
system.indexes.
I'm not going to worry
about that one.
One of them is called
videos_meta.
Now that's the one I created.
So I'm going to look at that.
And that tells me that we stored
away the videos that
MP4 file and that the grid_id
was this object ID right here.
And then, I see two
other collections.
I see videos.chunks
and videos.files.
Now videos.chunks is what
MongoDB created with GridFS to
put away this data.
So let's look at the
videos.files collection.
db.videos.files.find.
And we can see that it's its own
metadata collection that
talks about the object
that it created.
And then the upload date.
And then the lengthy object,
which was 100 megabytes.
And then the fact that
it's stored it, I
guess as a md5 hash.
It's probably a hash to make
sure that the integrity of
document was not lost
in the translation.
And then, I won't show you those
chunks because they're
really big, but I will look at
how many chunks are in there.
So db.videos.chunks.count.
And we can see there
are 419 chunks.
And I guess if we want to
look at one we can.
Just kind of scrolls
off the screen.
And you can see it's
a bunch of binary
data that's been encoded.
And that's how you use
GridFS if you want
to store large files.