All right, in this homework
problem, we asked you to go
through a collection of student
grades and remove the
lowest score for each student.
We start out by importing
the collection.
I'll do that now.
And now I'll connect to Mongo
and use the school database
and look at the data.
OK, here's a document.
So we asked you to remove the
lowest homework score, and our
strategy is going to be to
iterate through the entire
collection, to look at the
scores, to find the lowest
homework score-- for instance,
in this case, it'd be the
score right here--
and then we're going to write
back out the score's array
into the document.
And that's my strategy for
solving the problem.
I do not know of a way to just
remove this item from the
array inside mongod and even
if I did, I'd probably be a
little hesitant to use it
because I don't know that the
intervening record
has not changed.
So I feel more comfortable
just rewriting the entire
array, because I'm not
sure that if I see it
as the third item--
zero, one, two, three--
that it's still going to be the
third item when I go back
there, in a real
running system.
OK, so let's go through
the program I wrote
to solve this problem.
I call it drop_lowest.
It's written in Python.
You can see here, the first
thing it does is call
remove_lowest.
It gets a cursor to
students.find--
it basically just finds every
record, every document in the
students' collection--
it goes through them and it
prints out some debugging
information.
I solve the problem just like
you, so I often put print
information in my programs.
And then what it does, is it
finds the scores in the
document, and then it has a
helper function to find the
lowest score item, and if
lowest is not none--
OK, this is really just an error
checking, because find
lowest should always find the
lowest score, but if for some
reason it couldn't, it would
just print out an error
message here.
If lowest is not none, then
it says it's going
to remove this grade--
again, this is error
checking--
and then it calls
scores.remove.
This is a Python function
telling it to remove the
element lowest from
the score's array.
And then it just calls update.
So updates for the
_id student _id--
just updating the record
we're looking at--
set the scores to the scores
and that's it.
Now one thing I didn't show you
is the helper function,
find_lowest.
It finds the lowest score in
an array, but it's not
particularly hard to figure
out how that works.
It sets lowest to
none to start.
It has a sentinel value of 101,
because it knows it's
going to find something
lower than 101--
because I know what the
bounds of the scores
are on these records--
and then it iterates through the
scores and if the one it's
looking at is of type homework
and lower than the bound, then
it found a new bound and it sets
lowest to the item and
lowest score to the score.
So it just goes through this
and when it returns, it's
going to return either none, if
it couldn't find even one
homework, or it's going to
return the lowest homework.
So that's how the
program works.
Let's run it.
All right, it removed
a bunch of data.
And then I go back to my
homework assignments and there
was some validation here, it
told me I should find 200
students, and that if it did the
work correctly that this
should be the record
for Demarcus.
So we will see if
that is true.
And the scores I should find
are 47, 44, and 39--
and 47, 44, and 39--
indeed, I do find those.
And then it suggests that I run
this aggregation query--
and we're going to go over
aggregation next week, so I'm
not going to really go over
how this works, but it's
basically the equivalent of
doing a GROUP BY in SQL--
and we find that now the highest
average in the class
is this student with _id 13 and
they have a 91 average.
And that is the answer
to the problem--
13.
All right.
So that's how that works.