Let's talk about one to
many relationships.
So a one to many relationship is
where there's two entities
and there's many, many entities
or many entities that
map to the one entity.
So for an example, you have a
city and you have the people
or persons who live
in that city.
So an example would be New York
City, which has 8 million
people in it.
How are you going
to model that?
Well, we could go through it and
think about different ways
you might want to do it.
So, you might say, well, I'm
going to have a city
collection.
And in that city collection,
I'm going to have the
attributes of the city,
like the name of the
city, and its area.
And then I'm going to have the
people that live in the city
as an array.
But that won't work.
Because, of course, there
are way too many people.
8 million people and all their
documents and all their
information, it isn't going
to fit inside this.
So, as a result, you
can't do that.
You could say, well, I'll
flip it on its head.
So instead, I could say, well,
I'm going to have a people
collection.
And the people collection, in
each document, I'm going to
have a name, like Andrew.
And then I'm going
to have the city.
And that's going to be
another document.
And it's going to have a name,
like New York, and an area,
and everything else.
Now the problem with this design
is that if there are
obviously multiple living in New
York, so what I've done is
I've duplicated this data in
multiple documents, which is
going to open me up to
inconsistencies because I have
to keep the city information
updated across all the people
who live in the city.
Now, in certain designs, that
might be acceptable.
But I probably wouldn't
recommend it in general.
So given that, what's the
best way to do it?
Well, in this case, where there
truly is one to many,
one city with many people, the
best way to do it is probably
to use true linking.
So we'll use true linking.
So for true linking, we're
going to have a people
collection.
And in that people collection,
we're going to have something
like the name of the person,
like Andrew, and then,
probably, my city, which let's
assume that the city names are
unique, New York City being
unique, and other
attributes about me.
And then, in the city
collection, I would have an
underscore ID being New York
City, and other attributes
about the city listed out.
So, in this case, I would
link from the item
where there was many.
So, I would have a collection
of the many, the people.
And I would link into the
one, into the city.
And again, knowing we have no
foreign key constraints, you
just have to make sure that
you're consistent about it and
that you don't put a city in
that isn't also an underscore
ID for the collection
that it refers to.
So that's a fine solution
for one to many.
And it requires two
collections.
So that requires two
But what if it isn't
one to many, but
instead it's one to few?
Which is still a one to many
relationship, but is actually
a lot easier to model
inside mongoDB.
So the example I gave you before
was these blog posts
and the comments.
And you saw, when we went over
the schema for the blog, that
there are multiple comments
that go to one blog post.
But it isn't very
many of them.
So it's blog post, sorry,
to comment.
There's is one of these
and maybe 10 of these.
And, so in that case, it's
feasible to have a collection
of the one.
So to have a post collection,
which is what we did.
And then, within each post, you
had the name of the posts,
and then somewhere you had
an array of the comments.
And then, that array contained
all the comments, but there's
only a few of them
for each post.
And again, we don't have the
duplication of data problem
because every comment is only
within a single post.
So in this particular model, it
works very well to have a
single collection.
And we're going to have a single
collection of the one,
of the posts.
And then put the
many embedded.
So those are the two different
ways to handle the one to many
relationship, depending on
whether it's one to few, or
one to many.
If it's truly one to many than
two collections works best
with linking.
And if it's just one to few,
well, then you could probably
get away with a single
collection, like we did in the
blogging example, where
you just embed the
items within it.
All right, so it's
time for a quiz.
So, when is it recommended to
represent a one to many
relationship in multiple
collections?
And the answers are, always,
whenever the many is large,
whenever the many is actually
few, or never.
What's the answer?