In this second homework
assignment, you're going to be
working on our blog
project again.
Now, this time, you're going to
be adding the insertion and
retrieval of the posts from the
posts collection so that
it can show posts and
take new posts.
So here I have the finished
version running.
And I am going to create
a new account on it.
And now I'm going to
create a blog post.
And this is what yours is
going to have to do.
And I'm going to create my
first blog post here.
And this is the body
of my post.
I'm going to add some tags.
And now I'm going
to submit it.
And it's going to bring
to the permalink for
this post right here.
This is my blog post posted
here, by me is the body of my
post posted under
foo, bar, baz.
And now I'm going to go
to the blog home.
It's going to show that post.
If I want to create another
post, I can do that.
My second post, I'll
make that bigger.
And now I'm going to
submit it again.
And now I'm going to go
to the blog home.
And you can see this
is the blog home.
So the URLs that
you need to get
working for this homework--
and we're going to leave the UI
in so you just need to do
the Mongo parts of it--
is that you have to allow the
person to create a new post.
And you have to allow
the viewer to
see the list of posts.
And this gets the last
10 most recent posts.
You can search for XXX again
inside the code to find the
parts you need to work on.
And then, if you click on one of
these links for the post--
this is the most recent post.
I'm going to click on the title
of this right here.
Then it's going to bring
me to the permalink.
So it says, my second post is
the permalink in the URL.
And again, this part's all
implemented already.
And that permalink's going to
show you the body of the post.
And there's this UI stuff to
allow you to add a comment.
But we're not going to worry
about that for this homework.
That's the next homework, to
worry about the comments.
And that's what you have to
get running for the second
homework this week.