In this assignment, we asked you
to modify the code so that
the blog will accept posts.
And I want to take you through
how you do that.
All the changes happen in the
BlogPostDAO.py file, which I
have up in front of you here.
And the first one is
in insert_entry.
So in insert_entry you need
to insert the post.
And the line that was missing
is right here.
You need to call
self.posts.inset(post).
And we built the post
for you over here.
So you just needed
to insert it.
That's all there was to that.
Now to get the posts--
for instance, for the
blog home page--
you needed to add this line
and call self.posts.find.
But you needed to sort them by
the date descending and limit
them by the number of posts,
which get called with 10.
You have to call it with
a limit as well.
And this type of way of
specifying a sort is an
alternative way to
specifying it.
Instead of using tuples,
you can do it like this
in Python as well.
And I thought that was
a little bit easier.
All right.
So the last place that you need
to make a change is in
this code over here,
get_post_by_permalink.
And in this case, you
just need to call
self.posts.find_one
right here.
And you to specify that the
permalink is the same as the
permalink that was sent in.
So this is the permalink key,
and this is the value.
And this is the variable,
permalink.
And that's all there
was to that.
And if you make those
changes, then the
blog will accept posts.