In this problem, we asked you
to modify the blog code so
that it would accept comments
on the blog posts.
Now, there's only one place you
to make a change, and it
was in blogPostDAO.py.
But the flow of control starts
in blog.py where we have a
handler for a new comment.
And, if you remember, the
comment form is at the bottom
of the post permalink page, and
when this gets called with
a post request, it pulls
different form elements, which
are hidden values in the
form, out of the page.
And then it retrieves the
post by permalink.
So right here, if for some
reason a fake permalink was
passed in, it wouldn't
get the post.
So if we can't find the post,
it redirects immediately to
post_not_found.
Otherwise, what it does is it
makes sure that the name and
the body is filled out, and
then it adds comments by
calling posts, add comment,
with the permalink, name,
email, and body.
That goes right into
blogPostDAO.py.
And after that's completed, it's
going to redirect back to
the permalink page with a get
request so that you'll see the
post itself, the blog post, with
a comment on the bottom.
Let's see what happens
in blogPost.py.
There's only one place you
needed to work here, and it
was in the add comment
function.
You needed to add this update,
and you needed to look for a
document with a permalink
matching the permalink that
was passed in, and then push
a new comment on to
the comments array.
And then just for safety,
we have upsert=False.
Although since we just checked
to make sure that that
permalink corresponded to an
existing blog post, it should
find a document.
But if for some reason it
didn't, it won't insert it
because upsert=False.
And manipulate=False does is it
tells the driver not to add
an underscore ID field if one
doesn't already exist.
But I don't think that matters
in this case because with
upsert=False it won't insert
anything unless it finds an
existing document.
OK.
This is the only place you need
it to work in this file.
In terms of getting the comments
out of the blog, that
sort of happens naturally
in the existing code.
Because in get_posts--
and you did write this
to find the posts.
But we've already had the code
to assume that the comments
are present and pass them in and
add them right here as it
created this new array of
dictionary elements, each one
containing a post.
So you kind of get
that for free.
Same thing on
get_post_by_permalink which is
the other place that it
would need to happen.
And get_post_by_permalink, it
looks for the post, and then
it returns it.
And if there's a comment
in it then the template
will display it.