Now, let's create a small
replica set on just this one
computer that I'm using so
you can see how it works.
Now normally when you create a
replica set, you're going to
put one of the mongods on each
of the physical servers so
that there's some real
fault tolerance here.
And you might very well
run them all onto
the standard port.
But we're going to do it
just on a single node.
And to do that, I'm going to
have to run them on different
ports so that they don't
conflict with each other.
So I've written a small
script here called
create_replica_set.sh, and it's
going to be available for
download if you want
to download it.
And it's going to create three
directories, /data/rs1,
/data/rs2, and /data/rs3.
And they don't exist right
now, so it will actually
create them.
And then it's going to start
three mongod instances.
Now, it has to declare each
one is part of the same
replica set, so minus
replSet rs1.
And this is just telling it that
it should put its log in
a log file called 1.log.
And then this is its dbpath
where it's going to put its
data files.
So again, /data/rs1.
And then it's going to choose
a port where it's
going to listen on.
This one is going to get the
privilege of listening on the
standard port.
And then it's going to
fork which is going
to allow it to return.
And that way I don't have
to run these each
in their own shell.
So these are commands that
are going to work
with the bash shell.
On Windows it'll be slightly
different, but this will work
on most UNIX machines.
So we're going to run bash and
then create_replica_set.sh.
And then it started them all.
And we can see what's in
one of the log files.
So we'll look at 1.log.
So basically it's just warning
me that it's not totally
configured yet.
So at this point I have three
servers running, but they're
not initialized yet to know
about each other.
Because if you'll notice in that
script, I didn't tell the
first one about the second
one or the second one
about the third one.
So there's no way these guys can
act in concert right now.
They're basically just
independent, and they're
running on a port.
And so now we need to
tie them together.
So to do that we have to
actually give a command inside
the mongo shell.
I'll show you what those
commands look like.
OK, so we have to create
a configuration.
And this configuration looks
like this document that is an
arbitrary name, config, here.
I have to name it with _id equal
to the repl set name
that I gave to each
of the mongod's.
And then I have a members array
which is going to name
three members.
And these IDs are arbitrary.
They have to be unique.
And then these are the hosts.
They're going to be part
of the replication set.
The first one is 27017, and
second one at 27018, and the
third one at 27019.
And I also, for this first one,
decided to have it be
delayed five seconds with
respect to the other ones.
So it's not going to get its
data for five seconds after
the other machines, so we can
more easily see what's going
on with replication.
And in order to do that the
replication subsystem requires
that you not allow it to
become the primary.
So I set priority
equal to zero.
And then I just call
rs.initiate--
this is a mongo shell
command--
with that configuration
document.
And now I just get the status
to see what's going on.
Now I'm going to pipe that into
one of the mongo shells,
so I want to connect to--
I can't actually run this
initiation command on 27017
because you can't initialize a
replica set from a host that
cannot become primary and this
one can not become primary.
So I'm going to have to do
it connecting to 27018.
So another thing to note for all
you UNIX folks out there.
So you'll notice that I didn't
call this local host.
I called it Andrews-iMac.local.
I didn't have a lot of luck
on my Mac using local
host as the host name.
I'm not sure why.
This is what the machine thinks
it's named, and that
seems to resolve with
getaddrinfo, the UNIX command.
It's needed to map
names to IPs.
So I used that.
And I'm going to connect
to it, --port 27018.
And if I do that, I just
get the shell.
I'm just in the shell
for this mongod.
Now instead I'm going to read
in this initiation script,
init_replica.js,
and that should
initialize my replica set.
So it says it should come online
in about a minute.
Let's connect to it now,
again, and then run--
oh, look at that.
So you see something different
happen for the first time.
Now we connected to
the server port.
Instead of just saying normal
shell prompt, I get this
[? rs:1SECONDARY ?]
telling me that I'm
in the secondary.
rs is going to give me my
replica set status.
I'm going to do that.
And if I do that what I find
out is that I've got three
nodes in my replica set, two
of them are in a recovering
state, and one of them, the one
I'm connected to, is in a
primary state.
So that's probably going to
resolve itself momentarily.
So let me just look again,
and now it's up.
So secondary, primary,
secondary.
Perfect.
So now that's all good.
But now I'm on a secondary here,
so I won't be able to do
any rights.
So I'm going to disconnect
from this and go to the
primary which looks
like it's at--
oh, I am on primary.
Sorry.
I was initially on secondary.
It changed the prompt, I guess,
because now I'm primary.
Is that true?
Let's go back here.
Yes, when I first connected, it
thought I was a secondary,
but as soon as it brought the
replica set fully up it made
me the primary.
OK.
So, good, I'm the primary.
So if I disconnect and connect
to one of the other ones, I
should see it be a secondary.
And it is a secondary.
And if I connect to the final
one, which is a 27019, I
should see that it
is a secondary.
OK.
And if I try to write to
the secondary, I'm
going to have no luck.
Let's write to the primary.
So I'm going to get off
there and then I'm
already using test.
db.people.insert name Andrew.
Let's see if that document
gets inserted.
I inserted it.
And now let's go to one of the
secondaries and let's see what
is in the collection.
Now what does it say?
It says, I can't query this
because I'm a secondary, and
you can't query secondaries
by default.
So how do you do that?
Well, there is a command called
rs.slaveOk(), I'm
sorry, rs.slave0k which
is going to allow this
connection.
Remember, what we have right
now is mongo shell
attached to a mongod.
And you have to set for this
connection that you are OK
with reading from a secondary.
And then once I do
that, I should be
able to do the query.
So let's see.
If I do the find I see
there's my object.
So you can see that now my
object got replicated to a
second server.
And if I go to the last
server, then I
should also get it there.
So let's see what rs.status()
looks like.
So my secondaries are at
port 27019 and 27017.
So I was on nine so
let's go to seven.
And let's give it an
rs.slaveOk() command, and then
let's do db.people.find().
And we'll see that that
has been replicated.
And so that's just the basics
to show you how you create a
replica set inside mongo.
And I'm going to put these
scripts up in the lesson files
this week, so I really encourage
you to do this
yourself so that you can play
with it and see how they work.
Now let's do a quiz.
Here's the quiz.
Which command, when issued from
the mongo shell, will
allow you to read from
a secondary?
db.isMaster(), db adminCommand
readPreference Secondary,
rs.setStatus('Primary'),
or rs.slaveOk()?
Which one will let you read
from a secondary?