We're going to go over building
a shared environment.
Now, this is something that is
probably more of a DBA task.
But if you want to develop on
your own computer and play
with sharded environments,
then you need to
be able to do this.
And it looks little bit daunting
at first, but it's
not actually as bad
as it seems.
So once you go through it,
hopefully you'll be able to do
it yourself.
I definitely suggest you
download the script that I
wrote and give it a try
on your own computer.
And if it doesn't work, just
play around, and you can
probably get it working
in not too long.
So we're going to
create a sharded
environment with two shards.
And each one is going
to be a replica set.
So this would be shard 0.
And shard 0 is going to contain
this replica set right
here of these three nodes.
I'll put an R for replica set.
And then we're going to create
another one, shard 1.
And it's going to have its own
replica set of three mongos.
These are all going to
run on my computer.
You would never do this this
way in the real world.
We're going to have to play
around with port numbers,
because obviously you
can't reuse the same
port in the same host.
So that's probably also
something you wouldn't do in
the real world.
And then, I haven't talked about
yet, but you're going to
need some config servers.
So these config servers are
little mongo servers that keep
track of where the different
shards are.
And they're not running
in a replica set.
There's actually some
sort of agreement
protocol between them.
And there's a two phase
commit when you want
to move things around.
In production, you typically
used three of them.
In development, you can get away
with using one of them.
But I'm going to use three of
them just for good practice.
And again, these are
also mongods.
So you can see here, I've
got 1, 2, 3, 4,
5, 6, 7, 8, 9 mongods.
And then, my old router--
my mongos--
that's going to talk to
these guys for me.
And then my application
over here--
it would actually talk
to my mongos.
All right.
So let's get started and see
how we would do that.
So the first part of this is you
have to figure out where
you're going to put your data.
So I put it in /data
on my computer.
And that's where I am now.
And the way I decided to do
it was I created three
subdirectories-- shard0
and shard1.
Actually, I created one for
shard2, but I didn't building
anything there.
And in shard0, I've got a
directory for replica
set 0, 1, and 2.
That's actually the first node
of the replica set, the
second, and the third.
And then in shard2, I have
the same thing--
shard1, rather--
the same thing.
And these are empty to start.
But these directories are where
mongo is going to put
its data directories for
each of those nodes
in the replica set.
And then I did the same thing
for the config server.
But let me show you my script,
and you can see how it works.
All right.
So I created a script called
init_sharded_env.sh.
And it's a bash script,
essentially.
It's a little wider than this
window, so forgive that.
It's going to be a little
hard to read.
But it's pretty straightforward.
First thing we're going to do
is we're going to start a
replica set and tell it that
it will be a shard.
So how do you do that?
First, I created the
directories--
shard0/rs0, shard0/rs1,
and shard0/rs2.
And then, I made just a regular
old replica set.
So I started him out and I told
him he's a replica set.
And here's his log path.
And I give a log file so I
can keep track of these.
Here's the data path.
I've given him a port, so these
servers run in ports
37017, 37018, and 37019.
And I told it to fork.
And also told it that it's
eventually going
to be a shard server.
So you have to do that
to make it work.
So it's got both the minus
replSet flag and the minus
shardsvr flag.
And after you run these three
servers, they don't really
know they're a replica
set yet.
And so this is the same
as it was last time.
So this next part of the shell
script is something that's
familiar to shell programmers
from yesteryear.
It's called a here document.
Basically, it says to
invoke mongo-- which
is this mongo shell--
and connect to 37017--
so it's going to connect
to this guy--
and then take this document from
here to here and just run
it into standard input
for the mongo shell.
So this is going to be the
command that creates the
replica set.
I didn't want to create a
separate JS file, so I just
put it all into the
shell script.
Basically, it's a config file.
It says s0.
Here are my members right here
at 37017, 37018, and 37019.
And it creates a config
document and it calls
rs.initiate.
And that's it.
And now, at this point one of
my replica sets that's going
to make up my shard0
is up and running.
I do the same thing
for a shard1.
I create the data directories,
if they don't already exist,
for shard1/rs0, shard1/rs1,
and shard2/rs1.
And then I start these three
servers with minus replSet s1,
because these are all going to
be part of the s1 replica set,
which is going to
be the shard1.
I give it some log paths, and
then I give the correct data
path for each of
these servers.
I create some non-conflicting
port numbers-- in this case
47017, 47018, and 47019--
and the minus shardsvr option
for each of them.
And again, I do the same trick
in this shell script, which is
going to be running
against Bash.
I just specify that I want to
run mongo and I want to
connect to 47017, which
is the first one.
And please input into them the
mongo shell this document
right here, which is going
to initiate the
second replica set.
So at this point, I have two
replica sets, but I now need
to start my config servers
so that I can get
this thing all initiated.
So I do that over here.
I create three different
directories for my config
servers in this mkdir
command--
one for each of the mongods.
And then, I run these three
separate mongod commands.
And again, I give
non-conflicting ports--
57017, 57018, 57019.
And I tell it to fork.
And I tell it that it
is a config server.
OK?
And now, we're with three
pieces, but they don't
necessarily all work together.
We have two replica sets.
They've been initiated.
We have some config servers.
But what do we do to actually
get this thing to work?
So what I do is I start on
mongos on the standard port.
There's no port number
given here.
And I tell it that this
is its log path.
I tell it where the config
servers are.
So the way mongos works, you
just tell it where the config
servers are.
And now, I need to get
this all working.
So the way this works is I call
mongo and I don't give
any port specification.
And what that's going to do is
it's going to connect to the
mongos, because the mongos is
running endlessly on the
standard mongod port.
So it's a little weird to think
of it as listing on a
mongod port, but that's
what it does.
If you have an application on
mongo, it stands in for mongo
and redirects.
So it lists them on the standard
port in this case.
So just a little warning--
I tried, on my Mac, to not use
the standard port for mongos
and have it listed on some other
port, and I never got
that working.
The issue was I was able to
get this part working.
I got mongos running, but I
couldn't get my mongo to
connect to it.
So I gave up on that and then
went to the standard port,
which is probably the
good idea, anyway.
But just so you realize--
I'm not sure if its a bug or if
it has to do with the fact
that I was all on local host.
But it didn't work.
It's fine.
It works its way.
So again, I run the
mongo shell and
send everything here.
Now, these are the commands
to add these two shards.
And this is going to bring
it all together.
So the mongo shell is talking
to the mongos.
The mongos knows about
the config servers.
The problem is the config
servers don't know about the
shards, which are
replica sets.
So they have to know about it.
So this ties it together and
makes it so that it all works.
Db.adminCommand--
add a shard, s0 slash one
of the hosts in it.
This is essentially
a seed list.
So this is a seed
list, and it'll
discover the rest of them.
And then add another
shard, s1.
Again this is a seed list.
If we gave it one of the nodes
in the replica set, it'll
discover the rest of them.
And then I had to enable
sharding on a
database, so I did.
I enabled it on a
test database.
And then I said I wanted to
shard the collection, test
that grades, which it's the
grades collections that I've
been playing with in the
previous lessons.
And I said that the key for
that is student_id:1.
Now, just a word of warning,
if the collection doesn't
exist, then mongod will do it
fine, and it will also create
an index on student_id,
which I'll talk
to about in a second.
It's a requirement that there
be an index on the starting
prefix of the shard key.
But if the collection does
exist, then before you'll
allowed to shard it, you need
to have created that index.
So if it's a brand new
collection, you've never done
anything before and you know
that from the beginning that
you want to shard, which
is probably unusual.
The more usual case is probably
that you have a
collection on a single
replica set.
You decide you want
to shard it.
And so what you're going to do
is you're going to bring up a
second replica set, some config
servers, you're going
to bring it to a sharding
configuration, you're going to
enable sharding on the database,
and then you're
going to have to make sure
there's an index on whatever
you want the shard key to be.
So in fact, I actually got an
error when I did this in the
shell because I hadn't created
that index yet.
But in this case, if you're
actually running my script,
the test.grades collection
won't exist yet.
So you should be OK.
But I actually imported the
collection first, so I
actually ran into the problem.
Anyway, so that's it.
And then after that, this thing
should be up and running.
So I ran all that
on my computer.
And I won't run it for you right
this second, because I
already imported the data, so
it would be a little bit
inconvenient.
And I will show you
what it looks like
when I now run mongos.
So if I run mongo--
oh, by the way, I'll just show
you all the stuff running.
So those are my mongods.
There should be nine of them.
Let's count them.
10 of them--
I'm not sure why there
are 10 of them.
Oh, it's the rep itself
is the 10th.
Sure.
So there are nine of them.
So we're going to run mongo.
And it's going to connect to
the default port on local
host, which is to connect
to the mongos.
So now, for the first time,
you're seeing this, which is a
mongo shell reporting that's
actually connected to a mongos
versus a mongod.
So that's a new thing right
there, and you should just
take note of it.
That tells you that you're
connected to a sharded
environment.
And then, if I look at all my
shard help commands, I can see
what they are.
Of course, the help one
I just ran and add
shard, enable sharding.
I can get the status of
the shard system.
Let's do that--
sh.status.
So a little hard to read--
what it's telling me is that
there are two shards right
here up and running, each
one a replica set.
Looks like it discovered all
of the hosts in the replica
set, which makes sense, because
it was a seed list, so
it discovered the
rest of them.
And then there's the database,
there's the admin database,
which is not partitioned, the
test database, which is
partitioned, meaning
that it is sharded.
And then it's telling
you the chunks.
We talked about those chunks.
So from $minKey, which is the
lowest possible student ID
that you could possibly
represent in the database all
the way to 1, it's going
to put that on s1.
And then it shows you-- you see
the ranges of student IDs
and the different shards
they're on.
If I then go to the grades
collection and ask for its
stats, it'll also tell
me that it's sharded.
So you can see here that it
reports that it's sharded
true, that it's got looks like
two million documents in it.
It's pretty big, actually,
right now.
Its size is looks like 432
megabytes, I believe.
Well, that's not that big.
And then you can see here, it
talks about the shards that
exists and the number
of documents
on each of the shards.
Looks like it's pretty well
balanced, I guess.
Let's see.
Size--
2.3--
yeah, 200 megabytes, I think,
on each of these servers.
And if I do a query on it--
so I'll do a query--
grades.find()--
the document looks similar
to what you've been
playing with all along.
You remember this structure.
And if I do an explain on it,
you can see that I'm going to
get more information
than I got before.
In particular, I'm going to
find out that to do this
particular query, it looked at
the shard s1, parallel sort.
And I don't think it looked at
shard s0, which makes sense.
And so that tells you how
efficient was-- whether it had
to go to multiple shards
to answer it or
just to go to one.
And you can see that once it got
into this shard, it used
the BtreeCursor student ID
index, because remember, there
is an index on student ID.
There had to be an index on
student ID for me to shard on
student ID.
Now, if I do a query that
doesn't include any criteria,
it should have to go
to all the shards.
So I'll do that.
All right.
So here, you can see it went
to both shard s0 and s1 in
order to answer this query, and
that once was in there, it
used the basic cursor,
because there
was no criteria specified.
So that gives you an idea of
what a sharded environment
looks like.
And hopefully, you'll create one
yourself so that you can
play with it and understand
how it works.
And we'll talk more about it.
Now, let's do a quiz.
And the question is, if you
want to build a production
system with two shards, each one
a replica set with three
nodes, how many mongo processes
must you start?