Let's talk about how
you choose a
shard key in practice.
This is important because it's
going to determine what kind
of performance you get from
a shard configuration.
The first thought is that you
need to make sure that there's
sufficient cardinality.
By that I mean there is
sufficient variety of values.
So for instance, if you decided
to shard on something
where there's only three
possible values, then there
would be no way for Mongo to
spread it across let's say,
100 shards.
So you have think about
whether or not there's
sufficient cardinality for it
to be a proper shard key.
And you can often solve that
problem by putting in a
secondary part of the key, which
has more cardinality
than the first part
of the key.
The second thought is that you
kind of want to avoid hot
spotting in writes.
And hot spotting in writes,
just the way the
implementation works today, will
occur for anything that's
monotonically increasing.
And I can explain why that is.
So if you did sh.status,
and you looked at those
configuration chunks when we
went through that earlier part
of the lesson, you may have
noticed that the first one was
set to min key to some value,
and then there were a bunch of
values for all the
other chunks.
And then the final one was some
value to max key, which
is the maximum possible key.
And the problem is that when you
do a insert of something
that has a larger value than
has ever been seen before--
for instance, if you decide to
shard on the key underscore
ID, and it's a BSON-ID.
BSON-IDs increase pretty
much monotonically.
And if you look at them you'll
notice they'll just keep
increasing, increasing,
increasing.
That's because the high
part of them is
actually a time stamp.
And so what's going to happen
is that every single one, as
it gets inserted, is going to
be larger than the maximum
thing that's ever been seen
by the collection before.
So it's always going to be
assigned to the highest chunk.
And what this means is that if
you think about it, if you've
got these 10 nodes, or whatever
number of nodes you
have in your shard, and you
start doing inserts, and
you're inserting, you're
inserting, you're inserting.
The inserts are just going
to continue to just
hammer this one shard.
And then eventually maybe
it'll re-balance.
But then it will go to
some other shard.
It doesn't matter, it's always
going to hit one shard.
Now if the writes are of
low enough frequency--
and again, it's always the
question of what your access
patterns look like--
that might be OK.
But if the writes are really
frequent, then
maybe that's not OK.
So you ideally want to think
about a shard key that isn't
monotonically increasing, but
has sufficient cardinality.
And those are two good basic
criteria to think about for
your shard key.
So I'll give you some examples
and you can think about it a
little bit.
Well let's say that, for
instance, we were thinking
about sharding an order
collection, billions of orders.
They have order IDs, and the
order IDs are monotonically
increasing.
Well you probably don't want
to shard on the order ID.
Now could you shard on the
vendor the order is with?
Well, potentially.
If the vendor has enough
cardinality, that might be a
good choice.
Now could you shard
on the order date?
The order date has a problem,
that it's probably going to be
increasing.
And we're going to get some hot
spotting on the inserts.
So that's probably not
a great choice.
Could you shard on vendor
comma order date?
And the answer is yeah.
And it might work pretty well.
Because it's probably got
lot of cardinality.
And it isn't going to be-- even
as you add orders for
multiple different vendors,
different higher order
vendors, so they're going to be
split amongst the different
shards, due to the vendor order
ID being different.
And that might have sufficient
cardinality to be a good index
again, depends on your
access patterns.
Let's think about another one.
So let's say you built a
photo sharing system.
And each user has photos.
And you keep track of some
information in the user's
collection, all right, with the
username, and some other
identification information--
maybe a list of albums, probably
some other photos
collection.
Could you use user name
as your shard key?
And the answer is yes.
It's probably got a lot of
good properties to it.
If you think about it, if the
system is mostly parallel with
respect to the user,
then you've got
these different MongoDBs.
And if I'm doing something for
username Joe, it'll map to
this shard.
And if I'm doing it for username
Bob, maybe it maps to
that shard.
And that nicely runs
in parallel.
I like to think about
how was the
problem naturally parallel?
And if it's naturally parallel
against some particular
characteristic, that might be
a good one to shard against.
Because that's going
to give you nice
parallelism in your operation.
Alright, so that's a few
thoughts about the selection
of a shard key.
Truth is, you have to do this
kind of carefully because it
is very hard to redo it.
Because you can't change it,
and they're immutable.
So think about it hard
before you do it.
And make sure that
it makes sense.
This is the kind of thing where
it could make sense to
set up a separate machine.
And do some testing, and the
access pattern analysis,
before you finally
commit to one.
All right, let's do a quiz.
All right, so let's say you're
building a Facebook competitor
called Footbook, that
will be a mobile
social network of feet.
And you've decided that your
primary data structure for
posts for the wall will
look like this.
So you have a username, toe guy,
with a the post time and
a random thought-- "I'm looking
at my feet right now."
And it's visible to
these things.
So thinking about the tradeoffs
of shard key
selection, select the true
statements below.
Choosing post time as a shard
key will cause hot spotting as
time progresses.
Choosing usernames as the shard
key will distribute
posts to the wall well
across the shards.
Choosing visible to as a
shard key is illegal.
And choosing post time as a
shard key suffers from low
cardinality.