Welcome to Application
Engineering.
This is week six.
This week, there are
three main topics
we're going to go over.
The first one is the durability
of writes--
and this is the durability of
writes on a system with a
single Mongod instance.
Next is achieving availability
and fault tolerance, which
we're going to do through
replication.
And the last is achieving
horizontal scalability, which
we do through sharding.
Let's start with the durability
of writes, talk
about the way Mongo works.
In a system where you have a
single Mongod instance, you
probably have your application
running-- maybe
on a separate box.
And it's going to have various
operations that it's going to
perform on the database, like
inserts and updates--
and you've been writing
stuff like that.
And then there's also the Mongo
shell that really is
also an application, if
you think about it.
And it does inserts
and updates.
And inside here are the
drivers inside your
application--
or really, probably, compiled
against them, or linked to
them, or available via some
sort of dynamic library.
And in a sense, the drivers
are also inside the Mongo
shell, or some version
of them.
When you call an update, or an
insert, or something in the
API within Mongo, that is not,
by default, acknowledged.
Or we don't wait for an
acknowledgement on that.
We send that, and we sort
of fire and forget it.
Fire and forget it.
Now, there are some historical
reasons why this was the case,
and I'll talk about
those in a moment.
So if you want to know that
your write actually was
received by the server--
that it got it, that it
processed it, that it--
not that it completed it, but
that at least it didn't
violate any indexes--
And that it seems OK,
syntactically, then you issue
the getLastError call, which is
inside the low-level API to
the database.
Now, the Mongo shell issues one
of these getLastErrors for
you every single time you
do an update, an insert.
So when you call insert, it
calls insert, then it calls
getLastError.
That's why when you violate a
unique index inside the Mongo
shell, you immediately
get the error.
Inside an application,
traditionally, it depended on
how you invoked it.
Now, we talked about this
thing called safe mode--
which has essentially been
deprecated at this point, due
to a release that we
did last week.
So I'll talk about that.
I'd say the word "safe" mode
has been deprecated.
The way it works is pretty
much the same.
Inside the application, inside
the drivers, you decide
whether or not you want the
drivers to call getLastError
for you when they make
a request to Mongod.
And we set safe equal to true,
which told the Python driver
to call getLastError after
every single operation.
There are two parameters that
can be specified inside
getLastError that I want to go
over and talk to you about.
The first one is the w
parameter, and the second one
is the j parameter.
Now, the w parameter determines
whether or not
you're going to wait for the
write to be acknowledged.
So w = 1 will wait for the
And that's what we're mostly
going to worry about right
now, the idea of just waiting
for the write to be
acknowledged.
Now, that doesn't mean that
Mongo necessarily did the
write to disk.
There's still a window of
vulnerability there.
It may have gotten the write,
and then made a change in
memory, and then power fails,
and then that write would be
lost forever, and you
wouldn't see it.
So it's not particularly
durable.
The second parameter is
the j parameter, which
is short for journal.
And if you set that to 1 or
true, then what will happen is
getLastError will wait until the
journal commits to disk.
So, what's a journal?
If you're familiar with
databases, you probably know
what a journal is, but I'll
review it real briefly.
So, a journal is a log on the
disk that has a list of the
operations that you're
performing to the data.
And once you commit it to the
journal, even if the database
reboots or power is lost, the
journal can be replayed, and
those operations applied
to the data itself.
So, essentially, once it's
committed to the journal, if
you assume a disk is persistent,
then it is a
persistent write.
So we can say that we want to
wait on every single write for
the journal to complete, and we
want to wait for it to be
acknowledged.
And so, looking at the two
different values, right--
I'll go through this--
we can leave these at 0.
And if we leave them both at 0,
then what's going to happen
is-- this is the old world.
This is fire and forget.
Now, if we set this to 1, but
we leave this at 0, then
what's going to happen is that
we are going to wait for a
simple acknowledgement
from Mongo that it
received the write.
All right?
So, that's going to give us a
whole other class of errors.
Errors like, if it violates a
primary key constraint, you'll
find that out.
And if we set it like this, then
what we're going to do is
we're going to wait for the
write to commit to journal.
OK?
And the idea of setting
it to this pretty much
does the same as this.
If you assume that you want to
wait for it to be journaled,
it ignores the fact that you
said, I don't want to wait for
the acknowledgement.
There are some other
settings for w--
other flags for w-- and w is
more complex than just that.
But for now, that's sort of
where I want to leave it in
terms of what the w parameter
and the j parameter do in the
getLastError command.
So these settings-- w and
j, collectively--
are called the write concern.
And the write concern is, how
concerned are you that your
writes are really completed
before you
get a response back?
Now, this whole area is pretty
much controlled by the
drivers, because, in the
underlying API, it's going to
send an insert over the
wire to Mongo, right?
Big M. All right?
And that's the way that works.
And then, in order to make sure
that write completes, the
driver then has to send a second
getLastError command,
which it will do
on your behalf.
Now, when we set safe mode equal
to true, we were setting
w equal to 1, journal
equal to 0.
That was safe mode-- when we
set safe mode equal to true
earlier on in the course.
Now, for a long time, if you
didn't do anything at all,
this was what you got.
But recently--
last week--
we made a big change, so that,
by default, if you use the new
recommended driver methods--
which I'm going to show you
later on in this week--
then you're now going
to get this.
But if you really want to make
sure that you're committing to
disk before you go on, this is
what you should be using--
w = 1, journal equals 1.
All right, so that's a whole
bunch of stuff that I kind of
threw at you, and it's kind of
complicated, but we're going
to be going over it more
than once in this week.
But what I really wanted to
emphasize is that there's this
concept of your write concern
and your journaling mode.
And there's a whole bunch of
modes inside of the drivers
that let you choose these.
And that, by default, inside the
lowest levels of the API
in Mongo, the operations
are not acknowledged.
So it requires a second call to
getLastError or something
to make sure that they've
been acknowledged or
committed to disk.
And that you can have the
drivers do that for you.
And the Mongo shell does
a little bit of
that for you, too.
It actually calls getLastError
automatically when you call an
insert or an update.
All right.
So, let's do a short quiz.
Provided you assume that the
disk is persistent, what are
the w and j settings required to
guarantee that an insert or
update has been written
all the way to disk?