Now that you've learned how to
use the write concern modes,
and you know how to set j equal
to 1 and w equal to 1,
you might think that you can
pretty much guarantee that a
write will complete or not
complete inside Mongo, and
you'll find out whether
it was true or not.
If that gives you a level of
certainty in the world.
Unfortunately, it's
not exactly true.
And the reason is that there
are network errors.
So for instance, let's say that
you did an insert, and
that insert was specified with a
connection that had j equals
1 and w equals 1, such the
driver issued a get last error
on your behalf.
And the write did complete, but
unfortunately, before it
completed, the network
connection got reset.
TCP reset, there's some
intervening network problem.
In that particular case, you
don't know whether your write
completed or not, because you
didn't get an acknowledgement
that it completed.
So if you'd gotten the
acknowledgement that it
completed, you'd be sure
it had completed.
But the fact that you didn't
get the acknowledgement
doesn't guarantee it
didn't complete.
And this is important to
remember in a client server
application, which is that
there are these network
errors, and you can never
be completely sure
what exactly happened.
Now, it depends on your
application whether that's a
problem or not.
You can often check to see
whether or not the write
happened after if you need to.
But even if you're protecting
your inserts with try
exception blocks, and making
sure that you get all the
exceptions, sometimes you'll
get an exception, but the
write will complete.
Now, if you get no exceptions
and it says the write
completed, well then
you're fine, you
know the write completed.
By I just wanted to point out
that there is a certain degree
of uncertainty in any network
based application, such as you
can never be completely positive
when something has
happened or not, because
you may not have
received the response.
Now, you could build something
on top of this to
protect you from it.
You could do another check to
make sure and see if what you
put in really got committed or
not, even know you didn't get
a response.
But most applications
don't do that.
And when the network is working
well, it's very rare
that you might see a network
connection error.
But you could see one, and if
you do see it, you may not
know whether or not your write
committed or not, even if you
specified that you
want to receive
acknowledgement when it did.
All right, let's do a quiz.
So here's the quiz.
One of the reasons why an
application may receive an
error back if the write
was successful.
Check all that apply.
The network TCP connection
between the application and
the server was reset, between
the time of the write and the
time of the get last
error call.
The Mongodb server terminates
between the write and the get
last error call.
The network fails between the
time of the write and the time
of the get last error call.
Or the write violates a primary
key constraint on the
collection and must
be rolled back.