Now that we understand how
replicate sets work, we can
get back to discussing write
concern again, which we
haven't talked about seriously
since we talked about the
single mongod situation.
So the W parameter determines
how many nodes you wait for
before you move on when
you do an insert.
And again, this is accomplished
by calling get
last error by the drivers
with W set.
So in the simple case where
you have three nodes which
we've discussed, three nodes
in a replica set, sitting W
equal to one, if this is the
primary, will just wait for
the primary to acknowledge
the write.
Setting it equal to two, will
wait for the primary and one
other node to acknowledge
the write.
Setting it equal to three, will
wait for all three to
acknowledge the write.
Setting journal equal to one
will wait for the primary to
write it all the way to disk.
Now, how long you wait
is called wtimeout.
So how long are you willing to
wait for your writes to be
acknowledged by the
secondaries?
That's wtimeout which also can
be set in the drivers.
Now these values, collectively,
are
called write concern--
W, J and wtimeout.
And there's actually
three different
places they can be set.
One is that you can set them on
a connection, which is the
way we've been showing them.
You can also set them on a
collection inside the drivers.
I don't think there's much
of a difference there.
I think it's just the semantics
of the driver.
I think either way it's
just the driver
calling get last error.
And the last thing is that when
you actually configure
the replica set, in the
configuration itself you can
set these values.
You can set defaults so that
if no values come in, the
replica set is always
handled this way.
And I think from a system
administration standpoint,
this is probably the
safest thing to do.
Because that way the developers
aren't using a
different default than you're
expecting to be using.
But in any event, you can do
any of the three of them.
There's a couple different other
ways to use W. First one
is that you can say
W majority--
very useful.
And W majority is the one that
will wait for the majority of
the nodes to replicate.
Now, it turns out that W
majority, or W2 if there were
three nodes, is also what you
need to avoid roll backs when
you failover.
If you can imagine if you're
writing to this primary and
you're waiting for the writes
to go here to the secondary,
then in this situation where
the primary steps down this
guy has the writes.
And I believe in that situation
he'll be elected as
primary if he's the
furthest ahead.
Not certain about that, so not
sure it avoids rollbacks in
all those situations.
But that's my understanding,
that W majority is enough to
avoid the rollback case.
It's also important to note that
J, which is wait for a
commit to journal, you're only
waiting for it to commit to
the journal on the
primary node.
You're not waiting for it to
commit to journal on the
secondary nodes.
So there's no guarantee that
it's committed to the journal
in the second node.
So you can imagine some crazy
scenarios where the primary
and the secondary are
both destroyed.
Or maybe this one's destroyed
permanently and this one only
temporarily.
But because you only waited for
W majority and because it
wasn't actually committed all
the way to disk that they
happened simultaneously, then
you might lose that write.
Anyway, so you could set W
majority, you can set W equal
to a number which is the number
of nodes you want to
wait for before you continue.
And then there's also a way to
set W equal to a tag value.
And I'll go into that just
a little bit about
what that might do.
You can label some of these
nodes with tags.
So let's look at the program
that I want to show you.
So this program is setting W
equal to three and if you
recall, one of the nodes
has a delay on it.
And so what should happen is
that it should be pretty slow
to write that when it's waiting
for all three nodes.
And I set a pretty
long time out--
10,000 seconds on that,
and it's only going to
have to wait five.
So let's see what
happens there.
You can see that we're winding
up waiting a full five seconds
between every single write.
And the reason is that the W was
set to three, which means
that all three nodes need to
acknowledge the write.
And because one of the nodes is,
if you remember, running
delayed, he doesn't get the
write for a full five seconds.
You can see it right there.
So one of these guys
is running delayed.
Where is that shown?
Oh, it might only be in
the configuration.
Let's look at the conf--
ah, there we go.
Yes, so in the configuration
rs.conf, you can see that this
one right here is on a
five seconds delay.
Also, just so you know if you
use rs.help you can get a lot
of nice little commands that
deal with replica sets inside
the Mongo shell.
And you can look in the
documentation for all these.
You can Google them and
look on the docs.
All right, so let's do a quiz.
So the question is, if you set
W equal to one and J equal to
one, is it possible to wind up
rolling back a committed write
to the primary on failover.
What's the answer?