All right.
And the first three are true.
These are all potential reasons
why you might not want
to read from secondaries.
The last one is not true.
Reading from a secondary does
not prevent it from being
promoted to a primary
The other thing to consider is
that sometimes, if you're
deploying hardware, you need to
make sure that the hardware
you're deploying for your
secondary is the same level of
performance as your primary.
Otherwise, it could be
impossible for it to satisfy
those reads.
So anyway, it's OK to read from
secondaries, as long as
it's a thoughtful thing to do,
and it's something that you
did based on deliberate reasons,
versus just thinking,
well, it's a generally
good thing.
Because if you have no reason
to do it, you probably just
have your reads go
to the primary.
OK.