OK, let's go over the
implications of replication
for application development.
Now on one hand, the whole idea
of using replica sets is
that they're very transparent
to the developer, and hence
you don't really have to
understand that they're there.
It's supposed to just create
greater availability and fault
tolerance, and not
getting your way.
But there's a few things
you need to remember.
The first one is that
of course, there
are these seed lists.
So you need to remember that
when you're using the drivers,
which are primarily responsible
for [INAUDIBLE]
you to a new node during
failover, after a new primary
is elected, drivers need to know
about at least one member
of the replica set.
So you need to understand
that a seed list exists.
The second is that now that
we're in this distributed
environment, you need to
understand this idea of write
concern, and in particular, the
idea of waiting for some
number of nodes to acknowledge
your writes through the w
parameter, the j parameter,
which lets you wait or not
wait for the primary node to
commit that write to disk.
And also the w timeout
parameter, which is how long
you're going to wait to see that
your write replicated to
other members of the
replica set.
So you have to keep that in
mind, because that is going to
have an implication on the way
you write the applications,
assuming that these defaults
haven't just been put into the
replica set for you.
All right, the next is that
now that there's multiple
nodes for you to potentially
read from, you have to decide
whether or not you want to read
from your primary, which
is the default, most obvious,
and preferred thing to do, or
whether you want to take your
reads from your secondaries.
And if you're going to take your
read from your secondary,
the application has to be
ready to use data that's
potentially stale with respect
to what was written.
And the final idea is that
even though replication
exists, and that you have these
nodes in place to deal
with errors and defaults, and
elect a new primary if needed,
still, errors can
always happen.
And these errors can happen
because of transient
situations like failover
occurring, or they can happen
because there are network
errors that occur.
Or maybe there's actually errors
in terms of violating
the unique key constraints,
or other syntactic things.
And so generally speaking, to
create a robust application,
you need to be checking for
exceptions when you read and
write database to make sure
that if anything comes up,
that you know it.
So that you can make sure you
understand the application of
what data has been committed,
and what data is durable in
your application.
OK, so let's do a short quiz.
And here's the quiz.
So if you sit w equals 4 in a
connection and there are only
three nodes in the replica set,
how long will you wait in
PyMongo for a response
for an insert if you
don't set a time out?
Don't set a w time out?
And I know we haven't gone over
this explicitly, but I
want you to guess what the
answer is based on the fact
that the w timeout controls how
long you're going to wait
for these commits, and there's
only three nodes, and you've
set w equal to four.
How long do you think it'll take
for you to come back and
get some sort of error?
Obviously it's not going to over
commit to four nodes if
there's only three nodes
in the replica set.
So check off the answer.