OK, congratulations.
We are about to talk about
sharding, which is our
approach to horizontal
scalability.
But more importantly, sharding
is the final topic, the final
real, substantive topic, of
the developer course.
So you have made it a tremendous
distance in the
last six weeks, so
congratulations.
At the beginning of this, you
may not have known anything
about MongoDB, and now you can
write programs in MongoDB, and
you understand the aggregation
framework and performance and
replication, and so now the last
big topic is sharding.
So as I said, sharding is the
way we handle scaling out.
And basically, rather than just
have your collection be
on one database, you want to
put it on, let's say, some
number of databases.
It could be quite a large
And the goal is that it be
transparent, that when you do
axes to some collection.
Let's say you had some large
orders collection and there
were billions and billions of
these items, that somehow you
wouldn't need to have
to figure out where
it is in the system.
And it would just work
transparently.
So the high-level approach
to this is that you
set up these shards.
And I'll call them S1,
S2, S3, S4, S5.
And these shards are meant to
split the data up from a
particular collection.
Now, the shards are typically,
in and of
themselves, replica sets.
So we talked about what
a replica set is.
So there might be three hosts
within a shard that make up
this replica set,
let's say R0.
And the shard 1 is actually all
part of this replica set.
So in this case, I showed one,
two, three, four, five of
these shards.
And it might be actually 15
hosts involved, because the
shards are each a replica set.
So you're going to
make queries.
And somehow, these queries are
going to get distributed.
Now the way this works is that
there is a router that came
with your installation and it
is called MongoS, all right?
And you probably saw that
binary when you unpacked
installation for MongoDB.
And that router is what's going
to take care of this
distribution for you.
So it's going to keep some sort
of connection pool or
knowledge of all the different
hosts, and it's going to route
them properly.
So the way we do sharding
is we use it
a range-based approach.
And there's a concept
of a shard_key.
So let's say you have the orders
collection and maybe--
you could imagine a
trivial sharding
might be on the order_id.
And we'll talk more about why
that may or may not be a good
idea as we get further
on in this lesson.
But if you were sharding on an
order_id, let's say that you
queried, and you ask for
a certain order number.
Then the MongoS would have some
sort of notion of the
ranges of order numbers that
are assigned to each shard.
And this is done by way
of mapping to chunks.
So the idea is that your orders
table would be broken
up into chunks.
And those chunks would
have homes.
And they could be potentially
migrated by balancer to make
sure that it's going
to stay balanced.
And again, this is not the DBA
course, so we're not going to
extensively ask you to do
administration on this, but
just so you understand.
So you have the orders
collection and it's broken up
into these chunks of orders
based on ranges of order_ids.
And each of these chunks lives
on a particular shard.
And then when you do a query and
the application sends that
query to a MongoS, and these
MongoSs are then talking to
replica sets, of course, that
are running MongoDs.
These are all MongoDs.
If the query can be satisfied by
a particular shard-- let's
say you say, I want
order_id 10.
It says, OK, let's look
at my mapping.
Order_id 10 maps to this chunk,
this chunk maps to this
shard, and it will route it
directly to the shard.
And then you'll get back a
response pretty quickly.
And the other hand, if the
query doesn't include the
shard_key, and in this case,
the shard_key was order_id,
then what it'll do, it'll have
to scatter this request to all
the servers, send them to all
the servers, and then gather
back the answer and then
respond back to the
application.
So that's the way it would work
if it could not utilize
the shard_key.
In addition, when you're
dealing with a sharded
environment--
and we're going to go through
this a little bit more--
you have to include the
shard_key on any insert.
Because it needs to know where
to put this thing.
So once you declare that
order_id, let's say as a
shard_key it's now illegal to
have a document inside the
orders collection that doesn't
have an order_id, because it
wouldn't know what to
shard to put it in.
Now, sharding is at
a database level.
You could say, I want to shard
or not shard a database.
And even beyond that, whether
you want to shard or not shard
a collection.
And collections that aren't
sharded are going to wind up
right here in shard 0, in
the left-most shard.
And that may change in a future
release of MongoDB, but
that's the way it works today.
So just to review at a high
level, to get horizontal
scalability, what we do is we
shard, which means we break up
a collection onto multiple
logical hosts and that we do
that according to a shard_key.
The shard_key is something
you're going to determine.
The shard_key is some part
of the document itself.
If it was an orders table,
it could be the order_id.
You could also shard_id, which
some people do for certain
collections.
We'll talk about why that may
or may not be a good thing.
Now, for a blog post table, it
could be the post id, anything
you want, pretty much.
And once you make that decision,
then Mongo will then
break up that collection into
chunks and decide what shard
each of the chunks lives on in
a range-based way, and then
any query that you make, which
now has to be routed to a
Mongo OS, will then go to the
appropriate shards to answer
your query.
And by the way, in case you were
wondering, yes, there can
be more than one MongoS.
They're really stateless and
they typically run on the same
server as the application.
And they're handled very
much the same way--
similar to the way a replica set
would be handled, which is
that if one of them goes down,
then it will connect to a
different one.
They're pretty stateless.
So that's not too
difficult to do.
And the MongoSs now
talk to a MongoD.
Once you're in a sharded
environment like this, and the
shards, again, are probably
almost always replica sets,
you no longer connect directly
to the MongoD with your
application.
You may, for administrative
purposes, need to connect to
this MongoD, but generally
you don't.
And if you use the Mongo shell,
which is really just
another application, kind
of equivalent to this
application, then rather than
talk to a replica, you
typically would connect
it directly to MongoS.
And it has a special indication,
in terms of its
prompt, to tell you that you're
connected to a MongoS
versus a MongoD.
So all right, that's sharding
at a high level.
Let's do a quiz about that.
All right, so, the quiz is,
"If the shard_key is not
included in a find operation and
there are 3 shards, each
with a replica set with 3 nodes,
how many nodes will see
the find operation?" And the
answers are 1, 3, 9, and 6.
Choose your answer here.