And the answer is that the
first three are true.
The posttime will cause
hotspotting because it's
monotonically increasing.
The username should be posts
well across the shards.
I think that would actually
be a good choice.
And choosing visible_to is
illegal because, remember, you
can index that is going to be
on the shard or the starting
part of the shard key and
visible_to will acquire a
multi-key index and
that's illegal.
And then, choosing posttime as
a shard key suffers from low
cardinality.
It does not.
Posttimes are going to
be very varied, lots
of different values.
It just happens to be that
they are monotonically
increasing.
It's going to cause hotspotting
on the inserts.
So that's the answer.