OK, in this question we asked
you, which of the following
statements are true about
choosing a shard key?
The first one was the shard
key must be unique.
This is not true.
You can have a shard key
that is not unique.
The second is that there must be
an index on the collection
the starts with a shard key.
So that is true.
And if you start with an empty
collection, MongoDB will put
that index in the collection
for you.
If the collection has data in
it and you try to shard on a
particular key, it will expect
the index to be there, or the
creation of the shard
key will fail.
The next is that Mongo cannot
enforce any unique indexes on
a sharded collection other than
the shard key itself.
And that is true.
The only key that can be
enforced for uniqueness is the
shard key, so keep in mind.
This actually comes up if you
decide to shard on a key other
than the underscore ID key,
because the underscore ID key
must be unique.
But Mongo can't help you keep
it unique if it's not the
shard key on a sharded
collection.
And so it was your
responsibility to keep it unique.
This is not usually a big deal
if you're using BSON IDs,
because they are guaranteed
to be unique.
But if you decide to, let's say,
shard on something other
than the underscore ID, and the
underscore ID itself is
not a BSON ID for whatever
reason, then it's up to you to
keep it unique or bad
things will happen.
The next one is that any update
that does not contain a
shard key will be sent
to all shards.
So that is absolutely true.
The database, if it does not
get the shard key in the
query, will need to send the
query to all the shards.
It's a so-called scatter
gather operation.
So keep that in mind.
And the last one is that you
can change a shard key on a
collection if you desire.
Absolutely false.
It's quite permanent
and immutable.
You cannot change a shard
key on a collection.
And if you want to change a
shard key on a collection, you
would have to essentially dump
data, re-import it in some way
into a new collection with
a new shard key,
which would be painful.