Welcome back.
This week, we're going to talk
about MongoDB schema design.
If you're coming from the world
of relational databases,
you know that there's a best,
ideal way to design your
schema, which is to keep it
in the third normal form.
Now, you can keep data in the
third normal form in MongoDB.
And we'll talk a little bit
about the third normal form
next lesson.
But in Mongo, it turns out that
it's more important to
keep the data in a way that's
conducive to the application
using the data.
So you think about your
application data patterns.
You think about what pieces of
data are used together, what
pieces of data are used mostly
read-only, what pieces of data
are written all the time.
And then we're going to organize
our data within
MongoDB to specifically
suit the
application data access patterns.
And that's a bit different from
the world of relational,
where instead, you try to keep
the data in a way that's
agnostic to the application.
So let's go over some of the
basic facts about MongoDB just
to remind you of them as we
talk about schema design.
The first is that MongoDB
supports rich documents.
And by rich documents,
I mean that it's not
just tabular data.
In MongoDB, you can store an
array of items, or a value for
a certain key can be an
entire other document.
And this is going to allow
us to pre-join
data for fast access.
And that's important because,
as you know, MongoDB doesn't
support joins directly
inside the kernel.
Instead, if you want to do a
join, you're going to have to
join in the application
itself.
And of course, the reason we do
this is because that joins
are very hard to scale.
And we want the system to
be high performance.
So as a result of this, you need
to think ahead of time
about what data you want to use
together with other data.
And if it's possible, you
might want to embed it
directly within a document.
And we'll talk about
how you do that.
The next is that there
are no constraints.
Now, if you come from the world
of relational, you might
remember that you could have a
foreign key constraint and ask
that a attribute of one row in
a table would form a foreign
key into another table.
And we don't have
that in MongoDB.
But it's going to turn it's not
as important as you might
think because of embedding.
Embedding is going to make that
a little less important
than it would otherwise be.
We're going to think about
atomic operations.
We don't support transactions.
But we do support atomic
operations within MongoDB
within one document.
So we're going to think about
how to organize our data to
support atomic operations if
we need them within our
application.
And the final thing is that
there is no declared schema
within MongoDB.
But there's a pretty good chance
that your application
is going to have a schema.
And by have a schema, I mean
that every single document in
a particular collection is
probably going to have a
pretty similar structure.
And there might be some small
changes to that structure,
depending on different versions
of your application.
But mostly, each document in the
collection's going to have
a similar structure.
And even though it's not
declared ahead of time, it's
important to think about that
structure so that the data
schema itself supports all the
different features of your
application.
So let's have a first quiz.
The first quiz for schema design
is what's the single
most important factor in
designing your application
schema within MongoDB?
Is it making the design
extensible, making it easy to
read by a human, matching the
data access patterns of your
application, or keeping the
data in third normal form?
And just check one of those.