OK.
And the answer that you might
want to keep them in separate
collections to reduce the
working set size of your
application.
Because if you're only going
to be accessing part of the
data, you don't want to bring in
both parts of the data set
into memory.
Or you may have a concern that
the combined document is going
to be over 16 megabytes
in size.
Now, this third one here--
to enforce foreign key
constraints.
Now, that's actually a reason
why you might combine them.
Since MongoDB doesn't have
foreign key constraints, well
you keep things a separate
documents.
You know, looking at this case
before, there was no guarantee
that this ID here is a foreign
key into this collection here.
And so it's possible to let
these things become
inconsistent if your program
is not careful.
And that's not an issue if you
have them embedded because
then this relationship that
depends on the IDs being
correct here to tie these
two documents
together wouldn't exist.
So that is not an answer
because, in fact, foreign key
constraints don't exist.
And if you want to avoid the
problem, you would actually
put them together, not
keep them apart.