One of the reasons why linking
and embedding work so well
within mongoDB is
because mongoDB
supports multikey indexes.
I want to talk a little bit
about multikey indexes and why
they're useful within
mongoDB schema.
So, earlier we talked about
a students and teachers
arrangement, where there's a
many to many relationship
between students and teachers.
Where a student has multiple
teachers and a teacher has
multiple students.
And, one of the ways we talked
about modeling it was having a
students collection where we
have an underscore ID for each
student and a name
for each student.
And a teachers collection where
we have an underscore ID
for each teacher and a name
for each teacher.
And then we link these two
across by having a teachers
array in the students
collection, right here,
there's teachers array.
And in this teachers array, we
list out an array of all of
the underscore IDs representing
the teachers that
the student has.
Now there are two obvious types
of queries you might
want to ask of these
collections.
And one is, tell me all
of the teachers for
a particular student.
Now that's pretty
straightforward.
I would just do a DB.find into
the students collection.
And I would pull out the
teachers array and then I
would have this array in my hand
of all of these teachers.
But it's a little bit less clear
how you would find all
the students that have
a particular teacher.
How would you find all of
the students that have a
particular teacher?
So the way you would do that
is you would search in the
students collection, using one
of our set operators, to find
all of the documents where,
let's say, this value and this
value appeared.
But you want that to be fast.
And in order for that to
be fast, there has to
be an index on that.
Now, we didn't talk much
about indexes.
And we're going to talk more
about performance in a future
unit, but it turns out that
mongo supports adding a index
on the teachers key.
And when you index something
that's an array, what you get
is a multikey index where mongo
actually indexes all of
the values in the array
for all the documents.
So I want to show you how that
looks in the mongo shell.
And show you the database in
action when it queries
something that has
a multikey in it.
So, I'm in the mongo
shell right now.
And I'm going to use the
school collection.
I've set up two collections.
I've set up a students
collection and a teachers
collection.
And they look pretty similar to
what I just showed you on
the white board.
So in the students collection,
we've got four students,
Andrew, Richard, Elliot,
and Mark.
And they have a teachers array
indicating which teachers that
each of them has.
And in the teachers collection,
I've got the names
of four teachers-- these are
actually Stanford professors
that were there when
I was there--
and you can see which teachers
each of these students has.
If I would like to index and
create a multikey index on the
teachers array, I can do that
through this command,
db.students.ensureIndex
specifying teachers.
And we're going to get indexes
later, but I just want to show
you this one.
And once I do that,
I can query and
have it hit the index.
So here's a query where I'm
asking the students collection
to find me all the student
documents where the teachers
array has both values one and
three in it, which means I'm
looking for people who had
John Hennessy and James
Plummer as teachers, and
return those documents.
If I do that, you can see, I
find out that Richard and
Elliot both had teachers one
and three, which is John
Hennessy and James Plummer.
Now, did that use an index?
We could find that out by
calling .explain at
the end of the query.
We haven't shown that, but
we'll show it in a future
unit. .explain shows
you the query plan.
And you can see right at
the top, it says cursor
BtreeCursor teachers_1 that
means that mongoDB did in fact
use an index to perform
this query.
And the existence of these
multikey indexes is one of the
reasons why embedding
and linking
works so well in mongoDB.
Because you can still do the
types of queries you might
expect to do in a relational
database and do them fast.