In the third homework this
week, you're going to
implement comments.
So you're just going to extend
the system that you wrote to
permit a person to comment
on the blog post.
So if you click on a post,
you'll go to the permalink
page for the post.
And it says my second post.
And then the person should be
able to add a name, and
optionally an email,
and submit that.
And then you'll see that on the
bottom of this, there's
now a comment.
And I can add multiple
comments.
And of course, it should
support that.
It brought me back to
permalink page.
So you can just keep adding
comments over and over again.
And then you can submit it.
Don't worry about the
UI being rough.
The real point of this project
was to show you the mongo
parts of it, not to have
you worry about user
interface too much.
So that's the basic idea
of this homework.
And for this homework, just like
the last one, we've given
you a validation script.
And it's going to insert
comments into your blog.
And it's going to go check
and make sure that
they can read them.
And then it's also going to
check the collections to make
sure that they seem to be in
the collections properly.
All right.
That's it.