In MongoDB you can have a
key that holds an array.
For instance, if you have tags
keyed that hold cycling,
tennis, and football.
And you can index tags, so you
can call ensure index, and you
can tell the database
that you want the
tags key to be indexed.
Now, if you do that what MongoDB
does is it creates
what's called a multikey
index.
Now, what a multikey index is,
is that rather than create one
index point for each document,
if it sees an array in the
document, it will create
an index point for
every item in the array.
So that if we do a Find where
cycling is in tags, then it
will be fast because it's
able to use the index.
And that only happens
if it's an array.
That's called a multikey
index.
Then you can create
a compound index.
For instance, I can create a
compound index on tags colon
color or something.
And that works just fine.
But Mongo restricts
the queries.
You cannot have two items in a
document that are both arrays
if it's a multikey index.
Now, this is all
dynamic, right?
So when you first create an
index on two things, MongoDB
doesn't know whether or not
there are going to be arrays
in those items.
So it's when you insert the
items that it will stop you
from inserting them
if they're both
arrays and they're multikeys.
And the reason is because of the
polynomial explosion that
you'd have of index points every
single time you added
and subtracted something from
the array if we allowed you to
compound index where both
items were arrays.
So let me make this more
concrete by showing you some
stuff in the shell.
So I'm just going to use the
test database here and I'm
going to actually start by
creating a collection and
insert something into
the collection.
I'll call the collection BBB.
I inserted into BBB
A and B being one.
And I can now, if I want, I can
create an index for that.
At this point I have to set up
a standard compound index.
But what if I tried to insert
something into the index where
it was an array,
which I can do.
So now I'm going to insert
A is 1, 2, 3.
Now at this point it's a
multikey index, and I can also
insert something where, let's
say, B is 1, 2, 3.
Now A is going to be 5 in this
case, and B is going to be the
array 1, 2, 3.
A little extra cone there.
Here we go.
So that all works just fine.
And there's an index in here,
and you can see it, if you
call get indexes you'll see
the indexes we created.
So there's the index that we
created on A and B. But if I
try to insert something where
both A and B are an array into
this multikey index, the
database will cry foul.
It will not allow that.
You cannot index the parallel
arrays B and A.
So there's this concept of a
multikey index inside MongoDB.
Its dynamic.
It doesn't really know there's
going to be array values in
any given key.
But if you start adding arrays
into a key, it's fine.
If it's part of index it will
create next point for every
item in the array, but you
can't do it for parallel
arrays, as it calls it, if
more than one value is an
array in a compound index.
OK, it is time for a quiz.
Suppose we have a collection foo
that has an index created
as follows.
db.foo.ensureIndex A1, B1.
Which of the following inserts
are valid to this collection?
And I won't go through
them, because they're
a little bit detailed.
But figure out which one of
these are valid for the
collection.