Now we know how to create unique
indexes on collections.
The question is, what happens
if we try to create a unique
index on a collection, and
there is more than one
document missing
the index key?
So for example, let's say I try
to create a unique index
on these three documents,
a, b, and c, ab, and ab.
The first document
has a, b, c.
The second document
has a and b.
And the third document
And I want to create
an index on just c.
Well, that's fine for
the first document.
But for the second document,
c does not have a value.
And so the database considers
c to be null.
And for the third document,
the database
considers c to be null.
But unique means each
key could only be
in the index once.
And so if there are multiple
documents where the key is
null, you can't create
the index.
You don't want to drop the
dups, what do you do?
Now again, the problem is that
a unique index only allows
each key to be in
the index once.
And if the key is missing for
multiple documents, they all
map to null.
So this maps to null, and this
maps to null for the key.
And that means that they can't
coexist in the index.
And the answer to this problem
is sparse indexes.
What sparse indexes do is they
only index the documents that
have a key set for the
key being indexed.
So this document would be
indexed, but these two
documents would not
be indexed.
So that has some interesting
implications, because if these
two documents are not indexed,
then if we use the index to
find the answer to a query,
these documents won't be
considered.
But other than that, it works
pretty much as you'd expect.
Let me show you an example
to explain how
sparse indexes work.
Here is a small collection
called products.
And I'll do a db.products.find
on it so you can see them.
And maybe I'll print
them out pretty.
And you can see here--
the first two printed pretty,
the second ones are too small
to be printed in
a pretty way--
that the first two documents--
the first one is a polo shirt.
It's a products collection.
Has a size medium.
And the second one is jeans.
It has a size 32 by 32.
And the third and fourth
documents, one of them is a
DVI-to-VGA cable, and
it has no size.
And the other one is an iPhone
cradle, and it has no size.
Now, if we wanted to create an
index on, let's say, size, and
we wanted to make that
index sparse--
well, first of all, we certainly
couldn't create an
index that was unique.
And I'll show you that.
So we'll do
db.products.ensureIndix on
size, where it is unique.
And you can see that
we can't do that,
there's a duplicate key.
The duplicate key is null.
All right?
So if we wanted instead to
create the index, but to allow
it to be sparse, then
we can create it.
Now, this is a little bit of a
synthetic example because it's
not clear why you'd want a
unique index on the size,
since there's obviously going to
be more than one item with
a size, but it doesn't
have to be unique to
create a sparse index.
So in fact--
well, I'll create it this way.
And now you can see there's
an index on it.
And I can look at it
and see it's there.
It works pretty much
as I'd expect.
It doesn't really change
most queries.
If I do a find and I look for
size medium, I find what I
expected to find, which is the
polo shirt, size medium.
No big deal.
But if I use this new index to
sort, for example, it will not
do exactly what you
might expect.
So let's say I do
db.products.find, let me find
all the documents and
sort them by size.
All right.
That is going to return
two documents.
Hmm, that's interesting.
So there are four documents in
the collection, but if I sort
them by size, I only
get two documents.
OK, that's weird.
What's happening?
What's happening is that if this
index is sparse and there
are no entries for the two
pieces of electronics that
were in the product collection
that don't have a size, and
it's going to use this index
that we created on size, do
the sort, there is no entry
for the documents that
have no size key.
And so they're simply left
out of the final result.
They're basically
filtered out.
That might be a little
bit unexpected.
So again, if we just do a
straight find without sorting
it, we get four documents.
But if we sort it, we get two.
OK.
Very strange, and the reason is,
this is a result of there
being a sparse index on size.
It's an artifact of that.
And if we drop the index--
I'm going to drop the
index on size--
and then I rerun this exact
same query with a sort--
which granted, will now be slow
because I can't use index
to do the sort, but there's
only two documents is this
collection, so it
doesn't matter--
then I get four documents.
So you have to be a little
bit careful with
these sparse indexes.
They will let you create a
unique index, even when
multiple documents in the
collection are missing the
key, but they do change the
nature of some of the queries,
especially sorting queries and
also some items when you're
are filtering.
You can also see different
results.
So you have to be a little bit
wary and realize that if the
index is used that it's not
going to hit the items that
are not in the index.
And we're going to show you
later on how to ask that this
particular index not be used.
So there are ways to work around
this, even if you want
to have the index in the
collection in general.
All right.
Now it's time for a quiz.
Suppose you had the following
documents in a collection
called people with the
following docs.
I have three documents
in the collection.
The first one is named Andrew,
and he has a title of Jester.
And then the second one is named
Dwight, and he has a
title of CEO.
And the third one is named John,
and he has no title.
And then I decided to create
an index on title.
And I decide to make its sparse,
so that there are no
entries in the index for items
where title does not exist.
If you perform the following
query, db.people.find, with
title being null, what do you
think the database returns?
What do you think
MongoDB returns?
And the four choices are--
no documents, because the query
uses the index, and
there are no documents with the
title null in the index.
No documents, because querying
for title null only finds
documents that explicitly
have title null,
regardless of the index.
And you know you can set title
to be null in a document.
Or the document for John,
because the query won't use
the index, so you'll just
get John because
he's missing a title.
Or all documents in the
collection, because title null
matches all the documents.
Or the document for John,
because the ensureIndex
command above here won't
succeed in this case.
And please check the
right answer.