The next topic I want
to discuss with you
is geospatial indexes.
And geospatial indexes
allow you to find
things based on location.
The first model we're going to
discuss is a two-dimensional
model, and then we'll go over
a three-dimensional model in
another lesson.
Now in a 2D world, we've
got a Cartesian plane,
y-coordinates, and you may
have a bunch of different
objects out in that world.
So for instance, you might have
a restaurant here and a
barber shop here and a grocery
store here and a hardware
store here.
And then, you also have,
typically, a person right here
with his little coordinates,
x comma y.
And what you want to know
is, well, what's
closest to this person?
What are the establishments
that are closest to this
person, maybe of
a certain type?
And how do you figure
out where those are?
Now the way we do this is that,
in order to do searches
based on location, first of
all, your document need to
have some sort of x,y location
stored in it.
I'm just going to call it
location, but to be clear, it
is just my name.
And in that, you store an array
of values which are the
x, y-coordinates.
And then once you do that, you
need to also use ensureIndex
to tell the database that these
are locations that need
to be indexed so that
you can search them.
And you do that by specifying
that you want to have there be
an index on location--
again, just my word--
and that the index is type 2D.
And that's the reserve type.
That tells the database that
this is a two-dimensional
geospatial index.
If there are some other pieces
of information you want to
have be a part of the index,
there's a compound index, you
can add that.
So if there's a store type or
something or an establishment
type, you can put that
in, ascending.
That's optional, but it can
be a compound index.
Now, the last part of this is
that you're going to need some
sort of query operator
to work on this.
And there's a few different
query operators, but I'm going
to just tell you about one of
them right now which is the
$near operator.
And so the way you would do a
find on this, you'd say, OK,
find all the locations that
are $near, colon, and then
this would be the x,
y-coordinates of where that
person was standing.
So just to over it again, you
have to have something in the
document right here that
specifies the x,
y-coordinates.
You need to have an index that
tells the database that there
are x, y-coordinates stored
in the document.
You give type 2D.
And then in your find, you can
call the $near operator and
say, oh, find me all the
locations that are near this
particular set of x,
y-coordinates, and the
database will return
them in the order
of increasing distance.
And practically speaking, the
way this is often used is
through a limit.
So you'd say limit(20), and then
that would give me, let's
say, all the shops or the stores
that were closest to
this person standing at
coordinates x,y, limiting to
20 of them.
Let's go through a little
example in the Shell.
All right, I've got a small
collection here that is called
stores, and it has three
establishments.
So you can see the three
establishments right here.
They are Ruby--
it's a barber at location
40, 74--
and then, ACE hardware, a
hardware store, at location
40, minus 74, and then,
Tickle Candy, a food
store, at this location.
I've added an index using
this command--
let me show it to you--
db.stores.ensureIndex,
location: 2D.
And again, I named it location,
but it doesn't need
to be named location.
You can call it whatever
you want, or loc or
whatever you want.
And then type ascending.
I said, oh, wouldn't it be nice
to also be able to filter
and sort by the type of
establishment it is, so I
added that.
You can see all the indexes
that are on there.
So you can see that there's
two indexes on this
collection, the default one
under underscore id, and the
second one, a two-dimensional
index, a compound index where
location is the first
part of it.
And then, type is the
second part of it.
And this is the name
of the index.
And to do a query, here's
a typical query.
So find me every document whose
location is near 50, 50
and you're going to return
them to me in order of
increasing distance.
So I do that, and then it shows
me the three of them.
It says that the one that's
closest to 50, 50 is 40, 74,
and then 40.2, minus 74 is next
closest, and then 41,
minus 75, which makes sense
to me just looking
at them real quickly.
All right, so let's do a quiz.
Here's the quiz.
Suppose you have a 2D geospatial
index defined on
the key location in the
collection places.
Write a query that will find the
closest three places, the
closest three documents, to
the location 74, 140.
Please type it there.