Now let's talk about geospatial
indexes that
consider the curvature
of the earth.
So a spherical model of the
earth, which is the earth we
really live in.
Now in a spherical model of the
earth the locations on the
earth are usually specified
by longitude and latitude.
And the lines of longitude go
from one pole to the other,
and the lines of latitude come
around the earth like that,
and I'll just draw in
the equator in red.
This is my equator in red.
Now if we're closer to the
equator, than the lines of
longitude are further apart.
And as we get the poles,
the lines of
longitude are closer together.
Now, if you have a person
standing anywhere on the
earth, you have a person
standing right here.
You might want to figure
out well what are
the different locations?
Different stores that
are near him?
You can do that using the
spherical model by specifying
a max distance.
That will accept documents that
satisfy that max distance
criteria, and then we want the
database to return the
documents in order of
increasing distance.
That's all good, now this max
distance is going to be
specified in radians.
Let's have a little
math review here.
So if you have a circle, and if
you have a distance, let's
say that's specified
in meters.
This distance d that
I'm showing in red.
Then the distance d, swept by
the arc theta is equal to pi r
where r is the radius of
the earth in meters.
So if you know the distance, you
say oh I want it to be I
want to find every document
within 100
meters of this location.
Then the arc in radians is the
distance you're looking for.
Let's say 100 meters divided
by the radius of
the earth in meters.
And then you get to
the angle theta.
And that's the way you're going
to need to specify any
max distances in this model.
Now the spherical model was
introduced after the 2D model
in MongoDB, and so it uses some
of the same facilities,
even though it is a
spherical model.
In particular when you put an
index on the location inside
the document.
You're still going to say
that it's of type 2D.
Even though I consider this
to be more of a 3D model.
I guess it's only looking at the
surface of the earth, so
you might call it a spherical
model, but you still
call it a 2D index.
And the difference is that
when you query it, you're
going to query it in
a different way.
And let's look at how we're
going to query it.
Now I've got the same collection
here I had before
my stores collection,
and I'll just remind
you what's in that.
I've got three documents in
there, and they've got
location listed as arrays.
Now before I told you they were
xy-coordinates, and that
it could even be yx and
it wouldn't matter.
Because in Cartesian geometry
it wouldn't
matter which it was.
But in this spherical model
it very much does matter.
And these have to be considered
to be longitudes
and latitudes.
So remember-- it's longitude,
latitude.
Not latitude, longitude.
And so we're going to consider
these to be longitude,
latitudes in all these
documents.
Now there is a 2D index already
in here, if you
remember if you do a getIndex
you can see it.
I'll do it again.
Just so that this lesson can
stand alone, you can see that
there's something on location
right here, and its marked 2D.
Although we're going to use it
in a way that gives us a 3D
distance from a particular
location.
The syntax looks like this.
It uses the geoNear command.
And rather than being used
with the find, it's used
runCommand.
Which lets you run
a whole host of
commands to the database.
In this case we're going to
specify that geoNear is the
one we're looking for.
And that we won't have to look
in the stores collection.
Now stores has to be specified
explicitly, because it doesn't
say db.storage here, it says
db.runCommand so that the
database would have no way of
knowing that you want to look
in the storage collection unless
you specify the tier.
And then it's near
this location.
Again it's longitude,
latitude.
I specify spherical is true,
which tells the system--
the database--
that I'm looking for the
spherical model.
And then I specify a max
distance of one radian.
One radian if there's two pi
radians, about six radians all
the way around the earth.
So it's like 1/6 of the
way around the earth.
And if I do that, here's
what I get.
I get this rather convoluted
return document.
And if you look here
in results that's
where the action is.
That's where over here, this
object that's the actual
document from the collection
that satisfies the criteria.
And if I gave a larger max
distance of let's say 3
radians which is half the way
around the earth, at that
point all the documents are
going to satisfy that, and
they're going to be
returned in order
of increasing distance.
So the same one is returned
first, which is the Rubys
Barber 40, 74.
Let's see.
Make sure that's true.
Yep.
That's true, that's good.
So this is still the
closest one.
But now that we've opened up the
max distance, we're also
getting the ACE Hardware store,
and the Tickle Candy
store as well.
And that's how you use
the spherical model.
So just to review-- you store
the location as much as you
did before in a key of your own
choosing within an array
with two values, and it has
to be longitude, latitude.
You ensure an index on the
collection of type 2D,
although we're going to use a
spherical model to query it.
And then we use this runCommand
geoNear with a
bunch of parameters.
That will let you look up
any of these documents.
Find our which documents are
closest to a particular
location, and specifying a
max distance if you want.
Now there are other options to
these, and there are other
details, and limits, and
conditions, and other things
that haven't completely gone
through in this lesson.
So you'll have to look up in the
documentation if you want
to learn more about these
geospatial indexes.
But it's really convenient if
you want to do location look
ups inside MongoDB.