OK, now that we know how to
put documents into the
database, let's figure out how
to get them back out in a more
advanced fashion.
The most basic operation to
query documents out of the
database is called Find.
However, it's often simpler to
just look at a single document
out of the database.
And for this, we have a helper
method called findOne.
All CRUD operations are
syntactically presented as
methods on a collection.
The findOne method, when called
with no arguments, gets
back essentially one document
at random out of the
collection.
This can be helpful for
examining what the schema are
of your documents in
your collection.
So here we have a document with
a field called _id, whose
value is an object ID; a field
called Name, whose value is a
string; a field called Age,
whose value is an integer--
or some kind of number anyway;
and a field called Profession,
whose value is another string.
We can give arguments
to findOne.
In this case, I will hit the
up arrow to get my previous
input and move around
with the arrow keys.
The first argument to findOne
specifies what criteria I'm
looking for in order to count
a document as a match.
That is to say, it's analogous
to the WHERE clause portion of
a SELECT statement in SQL.
The argument that goes
here is a document.
In this case, findOne will only
return to me a document
where the field Name has
the value Jones.
And there is the document
with the name Jones.
This is our first example of
a query into MongoDB that
actually has any kind of
restriction in it.
As you can see, the
specification of what
documents count as a match is
given itself as a document.
This is quite a variation to how
things are done in, say, a
traditional relational
database.
Instead of having a
string-oriented query language
such as the SQL query language,
we actually send the
BSON encoding of this argument
to the findOne over the wire
wrapped up in some message
headers as an operation for
the database to execute.
That is to say, the query that
gets executed in the server is
presented to the server in the
form of a structured document,
as opposed to a sequence of text
that it needs to parse
and analyze.
You might be wondering why I'm
explaining these details.
The reason is that it's often
rather tricky for people to
get used to the mindset of the
query language in the system
being presented as a structured
piece of data as
opposed to a string.
In fact, there is no use of
string-type queries anywhere
within the MongoDB server
processes at this point.
We'll learn a little bit more
about the query language in a
subsequent section.
But for now, I want to tell you
about the second argument
that you can give to findOne.
Remembering the first argument
to findOne specifies what you
want to see, that is to say,
which documents match a
particular kind of WHERE clause,
the second argument to
findOne allows you to stipulate
what fields you want
to get back from the database.
The second argument to findOne
is specified, just like the
first one, as a document.
But in this case, the fields
of this document say what
fields should come back from
the query to the database.
So for instance, I can say that
I'd like to see the Name
field by saying, for example,
Name, True.
And I can say, for instance,
that I don't want to see the
_id field by specifying
_id, False.
When I execute this, I will get
back any documents in the
People collection where the
Name field is Jones.
And I will only see the Name
field and not the _id field.
And of course, I'll only get one
of them because I've asked
for just one of them.
So in this way, the second
argument to findOne is
analogous to the column
list portion of the
SELECT grammar in SQL.
That is to say, it allows you
to specify what fields you'd
like to get back from
the database.
Now, as a bit of a historical
detail, the _id field defaults
to being present in the response
from findOne even if
you don't ask for it.
This is a little bit of
vestigial feature.
MongoDB was conceptually
originally designed with a
number of goals in mind, one of
which was to act as a kind
of object store.
And in an object-store type
environment, it's
extraordinarily common to want
to know the unique identifier
of the object that you're
retrieved from the database,
even if you're only retrieving
selected fields
back from the object.
And so because of that kind of
design, the _id field is
included by default.
But as you see above, you can
explicitly request not to
retrieve it from the database
in a findOne call by
specifying _id, False.
We'll learn a lot more about the
query language as we go.
FindOne was just kind
of an introduction.
OK, let's have a quiz.
Use findOne on the collection
Users to find one document
where the key username is the
string "dwight." And retrieve
only the key named Email.