As it happens, the code that's
on the screen will find all
documents with score
less than 60.
This is something of a trick
question because what's going
on here is somewhat subtle.
In fact, when JavaScript parses
the input that's on the
screen inside the box it will
construct a JavaScript object
initially having a score with
the corresponding value the
embedded document $ gt 50.
And then the second occurrence
of score in that line will
replace the first one.
The reason that we ask this
question is because it's
tempting to code that
sort of thing in at
the JavaScript prompt.
In fact, that's not
going to work.
In order to achieve the desired
effect, you either
have to merge the $ gt and
$ lt into a sub-document
embedded with the value of
score or use the $ and
operator to achieve the effect
of the logical intersection of
those two criteria.
So again, the point is, although
you can key that in
the JavaScript prompt, the parse
is not necessarily what
you might naively expect.
In other languages that have a
similar kind of literal syntax
for hash tables or dictionaries
or whatever they
call them, you might find a
similar kind of effect.
The last one might win or the
first one might win or it
might be a syntax error.