Well, it should look something
like this--
db.catalog.find, and then a
price whose corresponding
selector is dollar.gt.10000
and a reviews.rating whose
selector is dollar.gte.5.
This will match any document
where the price field is
greater than 10,000 and the
reviews field contains an
embedded document that has a
rating that's greater than or
equal to 5.
Now this is a little subtle,
but the querying inside of
arrays that we do is also
applicable with dot notation.
So in this case, even though
reviews is an array of
documents, looking for a rating
inside of the reviews
will also traverse into the
array in what I hope is an
intuitive fashion.
This is a fairly common thing
to do in MongoDB.