OK.
Let's move on to a slightly
different way of looking at
your data--
namely, counting.
Everything that we've learned
about querying so far has been
retrieving documents from the
database, but occasionally,
you just want to get a count of
those documents that match
a particular criteria.
MongoDB has a mechanism for
doing this, which is called
the count command.
And the count command has a
convenient helper syntax
similar to the "find" syntax.
Specifically, if you query for
scores, having say, the type
"exam," then the find method
will retrieve whatever
documents have that
particular field.
And again, if you want, you can
iterate through results
interactively by typing "it."
If you want to merely count the
number of documents that
have type exam, instead of
executing the find method, you
can call the count method.
And there are 1,000.
If you recall how we created
this collection, with that
nested loop in a previous
section, we inserted an exam
document for each student ID
up from zero up to, but not
including, 1,000.
So the count method more or
less performs an analogous
function to what
a query does--
namely, counting up all the
documents that match a
particular criteria.
There's not much more
to it than that.
All right.
Let's try a quick quiz
on counting.
How would you count the
documents in the scores
collection where the type was
"essay" and the score was
greater than 90?