OK, now you know some of the
tricks that are available for
manipulating fields inside of
documents using dollar set,
dollar push, dollar
pop, and so on.
I mentioned earlier that the
update operator in the Mongo
shell actually does four
different things.
Among these are wholesale
replacement of documents,
manipulation of fields inside
of a document--
those we've already covered.
The next thing that the update
operator can do is what we
call an upsert.
And it models a very common,
specific sort of use case.
Let's look at our people
collection again.
Here we have our documents,
various people
having various names.
We already know how to updates
field inside of existing
documents, for instance
db.people.update name colon
Charlie comma dollar set colon
age colon 40, will set
Charlie's age of 40.
As it happens, I know that there
is a document with the
name Charlie.
What if I didn't know that there
was such a document?
Well, if there were no document
with name Charlie,
then this update operation would
have no effect, because
there would be no document
matching with name Charlie.
It's not too uncommon to have
a desire to either update an
existing document or else to
create a new document from the
information that you
have at hand.
And for this, we have
an operation
called upsert in MongoDB.
So for instance, if instead of
updating Charlie, if I wanted
to update George, this operation
will have no effect,
because there is no document
named George.
However, if I add as a third
argument some options to this
update, in particular upsert
true, then MongoDB will
construct a new document from
the information that I've
specified named George
and age 40.
This upsert operation models
the common case where you
might want to update a record
that does exist or otherwise
insert a new record.
Now, there are some
edge cases.
Of course, if the query that you
specify under-determines
the information that needs
to go into the resulting
document, then those fields will
be left out of the result
of the upsert.
For example, if you said
db.people.update age greater
than 50, set name to William,
well, the age greater than 50
is not enough information
to determine what the
result should be.
It under-specifies the answer.
In fact, MondoDB will create a
document in this case, but
it'll have to leave out any
field that doesn't have a
concrete value to fill
in for the upsert.
Nevertheless, the upsert
operation is
fairly commonly used.
For example, if you're merging
data in from a data vendor,
and you don't know whether a
record already exists, you can
fairly straightforwardly use the
upsert operator to either
upgrade an existing record
or create a new one.
Let's see if you caught that.
After performing the following
update on an empty collection,
db.food.update user name colon
bar, dollar set, interests
colon cat comma dog, upsert
colon true, what would be the
state of the collection?