All right, the answer is
that it will succeed.
And it will succeed because that
delete call, right here,
will delete the underscore ID
key that the driver added
allowing a second insert to
occur with a new underscore ID
set by the driver.
Now, the other answers are
wrong, but we'll go through
them real fast.
No, because the underscore will
be a duplicate in the
collection.
That would have been rue
but we deleted it.
No, because the delete
call will delete the
entire record in python.
That is not true.
The delete--
the D-E-L function in python
will remove just that key
value pair from that
dictionary.
So that's why that works.
And the final answer gets it
right but explains it wrong.
It says, yes because the pymongo
driver always adds a
unique ID field on insert.
That is not true.
It does not add the unique ID
field, underscore ID field, if
there is already one in the
record that is set to it.