Let's return to the blog project
that we talked about
in previous lessons and look at
the schema that we're going
to use for that.
So this is the blog running
on my local computer.
And I'm looking for the page for
a particular test post I
just put in.
I have a post with the title,
this is a test post.
And this is the body of it.
And it's filed under
these three tags.
And, over here, I can add
a comment if I want.
Now, if I go here, into mongoDB,
what I've done is
I've shown the document
that corresponds
to that blog entry.
And I want to take you through
it real quickly.
And talk about whether or not
it satisfies some of those
goals of normalization in
the relational world.
So each of these documents
has an ID and an author.
I wrote this blog post.
There's a body, this
is a test body.
There's a title that's down
here, this is a test post.
These are ordered in a weird way
because they were put in
by a Python program and it
doesn't keep the dictionaries
ordered in any particular way.
This is the date here that
the blog post was posted.
And this is the slug, the
permalink, that's going to be
used to display the URL.
Here are the tags, which are
an array of different tags
that this post was
filed under.
And then here are the comments
that people left on the blog.
It's an array of documents
with a
body, email, and author.
So the question is, first of
all, is this susceptible to
the type of update anomalies due
to the redundancy of data
that we saw in that denormalized
table from the
relational world.
And the answer is mostly no,
in the sense that my author
user ID appears only once.
And we use this as the ID
for the user's table.
So the assumption in our blog
design is that the author
name, the username,
is immutable.
If we wanted to change that
we'd have to use a
numerical user ID.
Now this looks like it has
some redundancy of data.
And in a sense it does, except
that these users that leave
comments on our blog
are unregistered.
And so, they could leave
whatever email
address they want.
So if the same user left two
comments, he could leave two
different email addresses.
So we're not necessarily
looking to keep these
consistent.
So I would argue that this
is not a redundancy of
data in this case.
And these tags, they sit here
as strings and they're also
not listed redundantly either.
So, in this case, although
we've embedded a bunch of
information that would be in
multiple tables in a third
normalized form in a relational
world, we've
embedded the data into
a single document.
We haven't really violated
that goal of keeping data
consistent by avoiding
redundancies.
Now one of the other goals,
when you're designing a
schema, of course, is that it
optimized the data access
patterns you're going to
see in the application.
And we do that very well, in
this case, because when we
pull the document out of this
collection to display on the
blog, we have just about all
the information we need to
display it to the user.
We have the date
it was posted.
We have their username.
We have the comments.
We have everything we need
right in the same place.
And, by the way, right here at
the bottom, this is what's in
the users collection, which is
just my user entry, which is
an underscore ID of me, my name,
erlichson, and then an
encrypted password over here.
And those are the two main
collections that are used to
organize the blog.
And you're going to be doing
some more work on the blog
this week for your homework,
and this is the way you're
expected to insert the data.
So it's a good idea to take
a look at it here.
So, anyway, what we've done
here, in this design, is we've
created a design where there
is embedding of data within
the document, and we're no
longer using multiple tables.
And you might argue that it is
de-normalized, but it is
de-normalized in a way that does
not violate many of the
advantages of a normalized
design.
We're not going to get these
data anomalies in this design.
All right, so let's
have a quiz.
OK, and here's the quiz.
Which data access pattern is not
well supported by the blog
schema that we've chosen?
And the choices are, collecting
the most recent
blog entries for the blog
homepage, collecting all the
information to display for a
single post, collecting all
comments by a single author,
or providing a table of
contents by tag, which of those
is not well supported by
the current schema.