Let's talk about 1
to 1 relations.
1 to 1 relations are relations
where each item corresponds to
exactly one other item.
So, for example, an employee
has a resume.
There is one employee
has one resume.
One resume has one employee.
A building has a floor plan.
A floor plan has a building.
A patient has a medical history,
and the medical
history corresponds
to the patient.
Let's look at this first case,
the employee-resume example.
We can model this in several
different ways
to talk about that.
All right.
So we can model the
employee-resume relation by
having a collection of employees
and a collection of
resumes and having the employee
point to the resume
through linking, where we have
an ID that corresponds to an
ID in the resume collection.
Or if we prefer, we can link in
the other direction, where
we have an employee key inside
the resume collection, and it
may point to the employee
itself.
Or if we want, we could embed.
So, we could take this entire
resume document, and we could
embed it right here inside
the employee document.
Put it right there
or vice versa.
We can embed the employee
information inside the resume
document itself.
So, we have all the different
choices, and how you probably
want to do it depends on how
you access the data and how
frequently you access each
piece of the data.
So, some of the considerations
are as follows.
The first one is frequency
of access.
Let's say, for example, that
you constantly access the
employee information and their
biographical information and
other information about the
employee, but you very rarely
access their resume.
And let's say it's a very large
collection, and you're
concerned about locality
and working set size.
Well, you may decide to keep
them in separate collections,
because you don't want to pull
a resume into memory every
single time you pull the
employee record-- employee
document-- into memory.
So, frequency of access has a
lot of impact on how you'd
arrange this in terms of whether
you'd embed it or not.
The second consideration is
which of these are growing all
the time or not growing,
the size of the items.
So, every time you add something
to a document, there
is a point beyond which the
document will need to be moved
in the collection.
And if you knew this was true
for some of the documents but
not for other documents--
for instance , if you were
never going to update the
employee record, but you were
going to update the resume
part of it--
you might decide that you
don't want to incur that
overhead when you write to the
employee record if you're only
going to be updating
the resume.
So that might be another reason
why you decide to keep
them separate versus the same.
And, of course, if the
resume is so large--
if it's actually larger than
16 megabytes, which is the
size of a document--
you might not be able
to embed it.
I mean, it's not likely that
it would be larger than 16
megabytes, but maybe it has some
multimedia information or
there's a lot of historical
information about the person
or event history, it
could have that.
And the final consideration
is atomicity of data.
Well, now there are no
transactions in MongoDB, but
there are atomic operations
on individual documents.
So, if you knew that you
couldn't withstand any
inconsistency and that you
wanted to be able to update
the entire employee plus the
resume all the same time, you
may decide to put them into the
same document and embed
them one way or the other
so that you can
update it all at once.
All right.
It's time for a quiz.
What's a good reason you might
want to keep two documents
that are related to each other
in a 1 to 1 relationship in
separate collections?
Check all that apply.
Because you want to allow
atomic update of both
documents at once.
To reduce the working set size
of your application.
To enforce foreign
key constraints.
Because the combined size of the
documents would be larger
than 16 megabytes.