The next relation we're going
to go over is the
many-to-many relation.
An example of a many-to-many
relation
would be books to authors.
Each book could have more
than one author.
And each author could have
more than one book.
Or another example would be
students and teachers.
A student has multiple teachers,
and a teacher has
multiple students.
So the thing to note in both
these cases and in many world
cases is that, although it is a
many-to-many relation, there
are not a very large number of
authors for each book or a
very large number of books
for each author.
Instead, it tends to
be few to few.
And that's going to allow us to
use the hierarchy and the
rich document structure of
MongoDB pretty easily, whereas
it wouldn't be possible if it
were truly many-to-many.
So let's look at books
to authors.
Although there are probably a
large number of books and
there are probably a large
number of authors, as we said,
each book probably has a small
number of authors, and each
author has a small
number of books.
And so what we can do is we can
link them by creating an
array, write the document.
So for instance, in this
author's document that I'm
showing on the right, I can put
a book ID right in here,
plus the book ID of other books
that this author might
have written.
Now, I could go in
both directions.
And I could, if I wanted, also
create an author's key in the
books collection and
have an array of
authors for each book.
In this case, this particular
book, Gone with the Wind,
written by Margaret Mitchell,
has only a single author.
So I'll just put a single
author in here.
And whether this makes
sense depends a lot
on the access patterns.
If you want to be able to
quickly traverse from a book
to its authors, then it could
make sense, without doing
additional query, to have it
link in that direction.
And vice versa if you want to
start with authors and get
quickly to books.
Now, having them linked in
both directions probably
wouldn't be my preference,
because it creates the
opportunity to have the data
be inconsistent if it's not
tied together well.
But you can do it, if you want
to, for performance reasons.
Now, the other option is you
could just embed it.
So you could, for instance,
rather than have this array
here, we could just
embed the book--
I'm going to cross this out.
And you could embed the book
right in the author collection
and put information about the
book that the author has
written right in here.
But I don't love that, because
what's going to happen is that
the book is going to wind up--
not often, because it doesn't
usually have multiple
authors-- but it could wind up
in the author's collection
multiple times, duplicated,
and open this up to having
update anomalies, modification
anomalies, where the
information doesn't
stay consistent.
Now, if that's what you need for
performance reasons, you
need to embed the book inside
the author collection, then by
all means, do it.
But I'd avoid it unless
you need to do it
for performance reasons.
In this particular case, I'd
make books and authors both a
first-class object.
It's also important to remember
that there are no
foreign key constraints
inside MongoDB, as we
talked about earlier.
So there's no guarantee that,
if you put an ID here, that
it's going to appear
over here.
All right, so next, let's talk
about the students and
teachers relationship.
So students and teachers looks
a lot like books and authors,
where a teacher can have
multiple students, and a
student can have multiple
teachers.
And I'd probably handle
it the same way.
I'd have a student collection,
and I'd have a teachers
collection.
And I'd have the information
about the student listed in
the student collection, and the
information about teacher
listed in the teacher
collection.
And then I would link in one
direction or the other.
And I would have
array of items.
If I want to know the students
for this teacher, I could put
that right in here and find
the students very quickly.
And I might link in both
directions and also have an
array of teachers in my
students collection.
Now, again, you could embed.
At the risk of duplicating data,
you could decide that
you want to put the teachers
inside the student collection.
This is instead of being an
array of object IDs or
underscore IDs that need to
then be traversed through
initial queries in
the application.
You could just put the data
right inside the collection.
Now, that wouldn't be a good
idea in the case of embedding
teachers in the student
collection.
And the reason this there's a
very good chance that you want
to insert a teacher into the
system before he has students.
And you may want to insert a
student into the system before
he has teachers.
And if you do embed like that,
then you are requiring that
the parent object exists
in order to
represent the child object.
And that may not
map to what the
application wants to permit.