One of the reasons that
linking and embedding works
so well within MongoDB is
because of the existence
of a feature called
multikey indexes.
I'm going to talk a little
bit about multikey indexes
and why they're so
useful within MongoDB.
Now, let's say you had a
schema that included students
and teachers, and this is a
schema that we've seen before.
And these are two
example documents
from these collections.
The students
collection might have
a separate document
for each student
with a unique underscore
ID, a name for each student,
and a key for the
teachers, where
the value is a list of the
underscore ID values for all
the teachers that
the student has.
And on the other side, we
have this teachers collection,
which has a document
for each teacher
with a unique underscore
ID, an integer
value, and a name
for each teacher.
And here you can see
we have Tony Stark is
the only teacher in the
collection right now.
And so this says right here that
Andrew has had four teachers
and that one of
them is Tony Stark.
Now, there are two
possible queries,
or I should say two
obvious queries.
And one is, how can I
find all the teachers
that a particular
student has had?
And the other is, how can
I find all the students who
have had a particular teacher?
Now, let's go over
the first one which
is, how do I find the teachers
for a particular student?
Now, that one is straightforward
because I can simply
search this collection.
I can query the
students collection.
I could do db.students.find.
I can specify the
student I'm looking for,
and then return the teacher's
key with its values,
and then I'll know the teachers.
But what about finding
all the students who
have had a particular teacher?
That's a more difficult query.
That query is going to
use our set operators.
And in order for
that to be efficient,
we need to be able
to use an index.
And it's going to be a multikey
index that makes this possible.
So let me show you in
the shell how this looks.
All right.
So we have two different
collections already
set up here.
We have a students
collection, and we
have a teachers collection.
Here's the students
collection, and here's
the teachers collection.
And we can see that the
students collection has
a list of students,
including myself,
and the teachers that I had.
And here in the
teachers collection,
we have a list of
professors, and these
are the professors
that were teaching
when I was at Stanford.
And we can see that,
for instance, I
had the teacher 0
and 1, which are
Mark Horowitz and John Hennessy.
Now, if we wanted to add a
multikey index on this teachers
key, we could do it as follows,
db.students.ensureIndex
'teachers' 1.
And we haven't gone
over indexes yet,
but this is how
you'd create them.
And now the shell
returns information
that before there
was one index, which
was the index on underscore ID
which is in every collection,
and now there are two.
And now we're going
to do a query that's
going to use that
index and be efficient.
So let's find all
the students who
had Mark Horowitz and John
Hennessy as professors.
So Mark Horowitz is 0,
and John Hennessy 1.
So we'll db.students.find
'teachers," now we're all.
There we go.
So now, we do a
query, and we ask,
find me all the
students that had
both 0 and 1 in their
teacher's value.
And we find that it's
me, Andrew Erlichson,
and it's also Richard Kreuter.
He has also 0 and 1 in
the teacher's value.
Now, the question is, how do we
know that that used an index?
Well, there's a little
command that we haven't talked
about yet, but it
works like this.
We can append explain at
the end of this query.
And if we append explain
at the end of this query,
it will tell us what it did when
it was performing the query.
And if we do that,
we can see here
that it returns a
bunch of information,
but what it tells us is
that it used the BtreeCursor
teachers underscore 1 index,
which is a multikey index.
And that's how
multikey indexes work
and why they make linking and
embedding an efficient way
to represent information within
MongoDB when you query it.