One classic problem from the
world of schema design is how
do you represent a tree
inside the database?
Let's look, for example, at the
problem of representing
the e-commerce categories in
a e-commerce site, such as
Amazon, where you might have
home, outdoors, winter, snow.
And the idea here is that you've
got these products.
And they're in a products
collection.
They have a product name
and a bunch of
attributes in the product.
And they have some category,
like say, category seven.
And then, you have some other
category collection, where you
can look up category seven, you
can see the category name,
some of the properties
about the category.
And one way to model it is you
could keep its parent ID,
right here.
And that would be the way you
might do it in a simple
relational database.
But this doesn't make it very
easy to find all the parents
to this category.
You'd have to iteratively query,
find the parent of
this, then find the parent of
that, until you get all the
way to the top.
So an alternative way to do it,
inside mongoDB, is to be
able to list ancestors
or children.
So let's think about that
and how that would work.
So you could decide
to list all the
children of this category.
But that's also fairly limiting,
if you're looking to
be able to look and find the
entire sub-tree that is above
a certain piece of the tree.
Instead, what works pretty well,
and again, enabled by
the ability to put arrays
inside mongoDB
is to list the ancestors.
So let's say I decided to list
all the ancestors of this from
the top in order.
Now, using this one piece of
information I can find all of
the parent categories
of this category.
If I want to list the bread
crumbs and make it easy for
the user to navigate the site.
And again, the ability to
structure and express rich
data is one of the things that
makes mongoDB so interesting.
This would be very difficult
to do in
a relational database.
Now, in terms of how you
represent the data for
something like a product
category hierarchy, again, it
all depends on your
access pattern.
It depends on how you believe
you're going to need to show
the data, access the
data for the user.
And then, based on that, you
know how to model it.
All right, it's time
for a quiz on
representing trees in mongoDB.
Given the following typical
document for an e-commerce
category hierarchy called
categories, and here's the
document that's in the category
collection, which of
these queries will find all
the descendants of the
snorkeling category?
And this is the snorkeling
category right here.
Which of these queries?