OK, so we've shown you
a little bit about
what MongoDB is.
And now I want to take you end
to end on building a small
application within MongoDB and
show you how that works.
So first of all, you have the
MongoD process, and that's the
database server itself running
out of the box.
In addition, you have
the Mongo shell.
The Mongo shell, which I'll also
show you, connects the
MongoD and lets you
interact with it.
Next-- and we're going to do
a lot of our programming in
Python in this class.
And in particular, we're going
to use bottle and PyMongo And
so you've got this world
of an HTTP server--
and remember, we're going to try
to build a little blog--
and within that, you'll be
running Python and the Python
interpreter.
And within that, you can be
running this Bottle framework
along with PyMongo, which
we'll get to.
And Bottle and PyMongo
are going to let
you connect to MongoD.
And then over here,
inside a house
somewhere, you have a user.
And that user is sitting
on a computer--
this is my representation
of a laptop--
and that computer connected
over the
internet to your process.
And there might be some routers
here and Linksys boxes
and network address translation,
everything else.
But that's, broadly speaking,
how it works.
So to give you a flavor of
JavaScript Object Notation,
I'd like to show you the Mongo
shell and then just a few
documents getting inserted
into it.
We'll do that, and then we'll
go back to learning how to
install Mongo.
So let's do that.