Welcome to 101 MongoDB
for Developers.
My name is Andrew Erlichson.
This is the first
day of class.
This is going to be a seven
week class on MongoDB
development.
So we're going to be talking
about all things MongoDB from
a developer standpoint.
In this class, we're going
to write a blog.
We're going to give you most
of the code for that.
You're going to be doing a bunch
of small parts of it
attaching it to MongoDB.
Most folks are familiar
with the blog.
And we're going to have you
write that code, and it's
going to be Python code.
Python is not a requirement
for this course.
If you've never used Python
before, that's OK.
We're going to give you
most of the code.
We're going to teach you some
of the basics of Python.
I guess what probably is a
requirement is that you have
some experience with some other
high-level programming language.
So let's go over some of
the course logistics.
There are going to be video
lectures, much like this one,
and you can watch those
whenever you want.
They're on YouTube.
And we're going to probably
release them on Mondays and
then is about two hours
a week of material.
At the end of every video
lecture, there is going to be
a quiz, well not every one
but a lot of them have
quizzes at the end.
And those are just little
learning checks so that you
can make sure that you
understand the material.
Each week we're going to have a
homework assignment for each
of the seven weeks.
Now, the homework assignments
are going to be a combination
of questions in using the
quizzing engine and also
assignments where you have to
run MongoDB locally on your
computer and download some code,
modify it, maybe write
some queries, maybe write some
code in Python to do some
queries, pretty straightforward
if we ask you
to do that.
You'll be able to use whatever
language you want for these
assignments, not necessarily in
Python, because we won't be
checking the Python, itself.
We'll be checking the results.
And then, the final part of
the course is a final exam
that is like a long homework
assignment.
It's going to be during the last
week of class, during the
seventh week when there isn't
going to be any homework.
So let's talk about the
scoring in the class.
Now, video lectures count
for 0% of your grade.
So you don't actually need to
watch them, but we think you
should, because that's the
whole idea of the class.
And then, quizzes are not going
to count in your grade.
They're just for your
own learning,
because they don't count.
The homeworks are going to count
for 50% of your grade,
and the final exam will count
for 50% of your grade.
Now, in addition, we're going
to drop the lowest homework.
So each week, you have a
homework assignment.
And we're going to look at those
weeks and the one where
you have the lowest score,
we'll drop that out.
For students that get a 65% or
better in the class, we are
going to offer a certificate of
completion from 10gen that
you successfully completed the
MongoDB for Developers course.
It'll look a lot better
than this.
It'll be a PDF file with some
validation information so that
you can prove that it's real.
And you'll probably get that a
week or two after the course
is completed.
All right.
So let's do our first quiz.
What counts toward your final
grade in this class, quizzes,
homeworks, final exam, or
class participation?
Check all that apply.