OK.
So of these four expressions,
only the first
one is valid JSON.
It's in the standard form with
the key, and then a colon,
then the value.
You notice for the second one
that there are commas between
the key and value.
That's illegal.
For this third one here, there
are semicolons separating the
pairs of keys and values.
That's not legal.
And in the third one,
there's actually a
couple things wrong.
But one is that it starts with
a regular rounded brace, and
then finishes with
a curly brace.
The whole thing needs to be in a
set of curly braces, and you
can see the separaters are also
wrong, and inconsistent
between the keys and value.