Now I've learned a little bit
about Python dictionaries and
a little bit about
Python lists.
And of course, they work really
well together because
together, they essentially offer
what JSON does in terms
of documents.
So if you want to do initialize
a new Python, we'll
call it a document, you can do
it pretty much the same way
you would in JSON.
Open up a squiggly brace, give
it a key, this needs to be
protected by a quote
inside Python.
And then if you wanted to have
their be an array within
there, you can do it pretty
much exactly the way
you would in JSON.
That's going to be a list,
interesting in cycling,
running, and golf.
And I will close that.
And I'll show you that
in the shell.
So let's create a new object.
Have that object have a name.
This is the Python shell.
I know it looks a lot like the
Mongo shell, it's so similar.
And on my name's going to
be Andrew Erlichson.
And then I'm going to
put in my interests.
And my interests are going to be
cycling, running, and golf.
I'm going to close that up
and then there they are.
And if I wanted to see my
second interest, I could
dereference it pretty much
as you'd expect.
Interests, sorry, interests,
here is the second item, it
has an ordinal value of one.
It depends what we
mean by second.
And it's running.
Makes perfect sense.
If I wanted to append a new
interest, I could say find
myinterests and append a
new interest, swimming.
I'm not really that interested
in swimming, but I wish I were
more interested in it.
All right, now we look at a
again, and we can see that our
interests are cycling running,
golf, and swimming.
And my name is Andrew
Erlichson.
And as I told you before, Python
does not retain the
order of the keys inside
dictionaries.
So unlike JSON, now they've
switched and now name is now
listed second and interest
is listed first.
And that's the basic way that
dictionaries and lists work
together in Python.
And you can see why we chose it
as an example language for
teaching Mongo because it just
matches so closely to the way
JavaScript Object Notation looks
inside the Mongo shell.
It makes it an excellent
choice for
showing how it all works.
All right, now it's time
to quiz you on Python,
dictionaries, and
lists together.
So initialize a new dictionary
with a single key--
animals, whose value
is a list--
dog, cat, zebra.
Assign the entire expression
to a variable named things.
Type that right here.