Next aggregation expression
that we're going
to look at is push.
Now push is very similar to
addtoset, except that push
does not guarantee that it
adds each item only once.
It doesn't look through
to make sure
it's not already there.
So let's say we wanted to
see what categories each
manufacturer had products in.
This is looking in our little
electronics products database
that we created before-- our
little collection where we
have a document for
each product.
And it has a category
and manufacturer.
And this time, rather than
using addToSet, we're
going to use push.
So if we do that--
push the category--
it shouldn't be too surprising,
the result we get.
What we get, is that we have a
document for each maker or
manufacturer, Google, Tablets,
Amazon, Tablets, Tablets.
But you see these
duplications--
Tablets, Tablets.
And you'll see with Apple,
it's Tablets, Tablets,
Tablets, Laptops.
And that's because there
are four documents
with Apple in it.
And it's going to look
at each one.
And it's going to push this
item onto this categories
array, versus addToSet.
And so they may appear
more than once.
And this is the result.
It depends on what
your goal is.
This might be the right result
or the wrong result, depending
on what you're trying to do.
Now let's do a quiz.
All right.
Given the zip code data set
that we looked at before,
which is explained more fully in
the using dollar sum quiz,
a few back.
You can check it out.
And it has documents that look
like this, again, where each
document is a postal code, or
also known as a zip code here
in the US, and it'll tell you
the population of that postal
code/zip code, the state it's
in, and the city it's in.
What we're going to do is, we're
going to run these two
different queries that are going
to tell us the postal
codes that map to a
particular city.
So we're going to group
by the city.
And we're going to push a
list of postal codes.
And the question is, if we did
it two different ways, once
with a push over here, and once
with an addToSet, would
you expect to get a different
result or the same result for
those two different queries?
That's the question.