Let's go over an example of
using unwind during our
aggregation pipeline.
Now if you remember, we had
the blog posts homework.
We gave you a pretty big
blog post data set.
And here, I'm going to show you
one of the elements from
that blog post data set.
I'm just suppressing the
comments because it makes it a
little bit longer.
You can see here that it's got
an underscore ID in the body.
And it looks like this one
is the Declaration of
Independence.
And then we have the author,
which was a machine.
And then a bunch of tags, which
I pretty much randomly
took from a bunch of nouns
that I got off the net.
Now let's say you wanted to go
through these blog posts and
count the number of times that
each tag appears in a post, or
how many posts were tagged
with each tag.
So we can do that using
an aggregation query.
We're going to unwind
these tags.
And then we're going to group
by the tag and count.
So let's look at how that
works and run it.
So here's my aggregation query
to unwind based on tag.
So let's go through
it piece by piece.
The first thing we're going to
do is we're going to take
these posts and we're going
to unwind them.
We're going to unwind
the tags array.
And now we're going to
group by the tag.
And we're going to count how
many times each tag appears,
using $sum:1.
Now I want to figure out which
are the most popular.
So what I'm going to do here is
sort them by count minus 1.
And now I want the top 10.
So I'm going to limit
them to 10.
And then I want it
to be pretty.
So I'm going to reshape the
document using Project.
I'm going to drop the _id key.
And I'm going to create a new
one called Tag, which is just
the _id key.
I basically--
this is a rename of the _id
key, dropping it, and then
creating a new one
with its value.
And then include the count.
Let's see what happens
when we do that.
Blog_tags.js.
All right.
So we did that.
And what we get is the result.
And we see that the most
popular tag was
"sphynx" with 13 uses.
And then "lunchroom" with 12.
And then "crowd" with 11.
And it goes down from there.
Actually, these are all
about the same.
Now, I used a random number
generator to evenly distribute
the tags across the posts.
So it's not too surprising that
they'd be all about the
same, given that's
how we did it.
Distribution should
be pretty equal.
Let's do a quiz.
And we haven't talked
about this.
We've got to think about
it for a second.
Which grouping operator will
enable you to reverse the
effects of an unwind?
How would you reverse the
Think about that for a second.
And you could try different
grouping operators in the
[INAUDIBLE] shell to do this.