All right, so what is MongoDB?
MongoDB is a non-relational data
store for JSON documents.
And by non-relational, we mean
that it doesn't store its data
in tables, like a relational
database does, and it stores
JSON documents.
Now all databases, of course,
in the world are represented
as big disk-like objects.
Even if we store them on
solid-state disk today, we
always make a database
look like this.
So what is JSON?
Well, JSON stands for JavaScript
Object Notation,
and looks like this.
There's an opening parenthesis,
and there's a
key, and then a value.
So here's a very simple JSON
document, and the JSON
document has the key name
and the value Andrew.
You can create a more complex
JSON document.
I'll show you a slightly more
complex JSON document.
Here's a slightly more complex
JSON document.
This JSON document has three
different keys in it, a, b,
and c, and those are my
attempts at quotes.
You see there are colons here,
and a has the value 4, b has
the value 5, and c
has the value 7.
And these JSON documents are
stored within MongoDB.
But what makes it
non-relational--
because you could sort of see
this similar to a table--
is that they can have
some hierarchy.
So let me show you a way--
JSON document with some
hierarchy in it.
So this is a JSON document with
some hierarchy in it.
It has a key a, value
6, key b, value 7.
And then a key called fruit,
which is an array that
contains the items apple,
pear, and banana.
And that's new.
You could never do that
in a relational table.
So that's what MongoDB is
at its highest level.
It's a JSON document store.
And we're going to see that
that's really useful when
writing programs, because you
may have already seen that
this type of data structure
looks a lot closer to what you
have inside your programs than
relational data does, where
relational data-- and you
guys have all seen
this before, probably--
is a series of tables where
there are column names along
the top and then rows of data.
This doesn't quite match as well
with what you typically
do inside programs.
And this fundamental fact that
MongoDB stores documents is
what makes it so easy
to program in.
Now there's another aspect of
MongoDB that is interesting,
which is that it's
also schemaless.
What does that mean?
Well, "schemaless" means that
two documents don't need to
have the same schema.
So you could store something in
a collection that has the
values a, and b.
And you can see here I've left
off the quotes on a and b,
because they're not always
needed, although it's
safer to have them.
And you could have another
document in the same
collection that has the
values a, b, and c.
OK, it's time for a quiz.
Which of the following
statements
are true about MongoDB?
MongoDB is document-oriented.
MongoDB supports joins.
MongoDB is schemaless.
And MongoDB supports SQL.