And the answer is that MongoDB
deliberately omitted joins,
because joins are
not particularly
horizontally scalable.
Indexes are supported within
MongoDB, and they're supported
because they're very necessary
for good performance and do
not prevent horizontal
scalability.
Secondary indexes are offered,
so strictly by the wording of
the question, they
were not omitted.
But to be honest, they're very
challenging to perform well
across a system which is
horizontally scalable.
And the final one is
transactions across multiple
collections.
And that is specifically omitted
by MongoDB because it
is very difficult to support
transactions across multiple
collections across a system
which is horizontally scaled.