Now we're going to go over
installing MongoDB.
I'm going to show you how to
install MongoDB on a Mac.
And then, in a separate segment,
we're going to have
Dwight Merriman, our CEO
co-founder, showing you how to
install MongoDB on a PC.
He's more of a PC guy, and
I'm more of a Mac guy.
And the installation is the same
for both the DBA course
and the developer course, so
we're taking that segment from
the DBA course.
All right, so how do you
install MongoDB.
It's pretty simple.
We'll start with
a web browser.
And we're going to search
for how to find it.
I'm going to type download
MongoDB.
Let's see where that
brings us.
And you can see that
that brings us to
www.mongodb.org/downloads.
When we get there, there's a
whole bunch of choices that
are listed.
Including ones for OS X 32-bit,
64-bit, and a bunch of
other operating systems.
We're going to go over
the OS X install.
The first row here, the 220
release, that is the
production release, and the one
we're going to go after.
This is a release candidate
over here, and lower down,
there's some other development
releases, and older release
that you can look at.
Normally, you want to go for the
64-bit release, especially
on OS X, because most
OS X are 64-bit.
And MongoDB is limited to two
gigabytes of data in the
32-bit version because it uses
memory mapped files.
That's fine for development.
That's fine for small projects,
but normally you'd
probably want to download
the 64-bit version.
So I'm going to go ahead and
download the 64-bit version.
It's a little bit offscreen in
terms of what it's doing.
But it's downloading about
a 60 megabyte download.
And that's going to show up in
our downloads directory.
And so we're going to switch to
that now, and I'll show you
the downloads directory.
So this is a Mac.
If I want to go to the download
directory, I'd go to
cd ~/downloads.
And what I see there is,
I see the download.
It's actually a couple versions
in here because I've
been downloading it over and
over while I record this.
But I'm just going to go for the
one that's completed and I
want to untar it
using tar xvf,
mongodb-osx-x86-64-bit.tgz.
All right?
Untar that file and see it
impacts it right into the
current director here.
And now I'm going to go into
that directory and see what
there is to see.
And I see that there's a readme
file, and a license,
and there's a binary
directory.
And that binary directory
contains all the executables
I'm going to need
to run Mongo.
The ones we're going to focus
on right now, we're going to
focus on this mongod executable,
which is the
server, and then we'll look a
little bit the mongo shell,
which connects to the server,
so you could perform some
administrative commands and
insert some data, and look at
data, which I've showed
you previously.
So normally, mongod puts
its data in /data/db.
If we just try to run it, it
should come up with an error
message saying that it cannot
find that directory.
Yep, can't find that
directory.
It says you can use --dbpath
to use an alternative
directory, but we just want
to use the standard one.
So I'm going to show you
how to set that up.
So I'm going to open
a different
terminal window here.
And I'm going to become root,
which I need to become to
touch the slash directory
of my disk.
And I'm going to create
a /data directory.
And then I'm going to
create a /data/db db
directory that's mkdir.
And then I'm just going to
make sure I can write it.
I'm going to chmod to world
writable, slash data slash db.
And then I'm just going to look
at it to confirm that it
has the permissions I expect,
which it does.
It's owned by root but it's
actually world writable.
In a production environment,
you might want to have some
more permissions.
But we're just in a development
environment here,
so that's fine.
So now that we have this
directory, and it's world
writeable, we should be
able to start mongod.
So I'm going to go back to
the previous window.
This is just the terminal
window.
And I'm now going
to start mongod.
And there we go.
It's started.
This is the log for mongod.
It's warning us about
a few things.
It's warning us that our soft
r limits are too low.
That's important for production
in terms of number
of processes that can connect,
but it's not important for
development, so we're not
to worry about it.
And it's telling you that
it's putting its data in
/db/journal.
And then it's listing on this
port 27017, which is
absolutely fine, that's
a standard port.
Now we're going to
connect to it.
We're going to go here.
Make sure I'm not root.
I do not seem to be root.
And I know into my download
directory.
And I'm going to find that
Mongo release expanded.
I'm going to bin, and I'm
going to then run Mongo.
Notice that, just a small thing,
I mean, for those of
you who've used Unix before, you
know this, but I ran it by
typing ./mongo versus
just Mongo.
This way if I have a surge
past set on my machine, I
don't want to find a different
instance of the binary than
the one I expect.
So this will specify that the
one I'm going to get is the
one in this directory,
which is what I want.
So I'm going to run that.
It's going to connect, it
actually automatically
connected to the test database,
which is fine.
And I'm now going to create a
names collection by using it.
I'm going to save a very small
document in it with my name.
And now I'm going to do a
names.find to make sure that
it's there.
And there's a document
I just inserted.
So now we've got one document
in the names collection, and
that document has a name, my
name, right here, and it
assigned an object ID
to the document.
And now Mongo is up and
running on my Mac.