OK, let's bring it
all together now
and build a web application.
We have MongoD installed.
And we have our application
layer over here.
And that's going to
be written in Python.
And we have PyMongo installed.
And PyMongo is going to
talk to MongoD via BSON.
And the last part
is we want to be
able to display a
web page via HTTP.
And to do that, we're going
to write a program that
uses the Bottle framework.
So I'll show you what
a small Hello World
program looks like to do that.
So I'm going to open up
the small program in Emacs.
We'll go through
it line by line,
so we can see what it does.
So the first thing
is it important
Bottle and then it
imports PyMongo.
And then it creates
a route for "/",
which means the default
route of the web server.
So when you go to a web
server without any URL,
after the host name
this is what you get.
This is a little
decorator telling Python
that the next function
is going to be executed
when the user hits that route.
And we call that
"index", but there's
nothing special about that name.
And you could, in fact, call
it something else, if you like.
The first step here is
to use the MongoClient
class to connect the
local host at 27017.
That's the default port
that MongoD listens on.
And then, again, we connect
to the test database db equals
connection.test.
And then to the names
collection db.names.
Then we find a single document
using the "find_one" command.
That's going to put that
document into the item
variable.
And then it's going to return,
basically, hello, whatever
is in the names key
of that document.
And this is a Python
convention that the "%S!"
will be substituted by what's
after this percent sign,
in this case, item "name".
Item's a dictionary,
and we're pulling out
the value for the name key.
This is the end
of that function,
which is going to run
when you hit the "/"
route on the server.
And the only thing
left to do is that we
have to tell Bottle to run.
And to do that, we call
"bottle.run" with host
equal "localhost"
and the port equals
8082, which is a high
number port that we
can get to without being root.
So let's run it.
OK, it says it's
listening on local host.
And now let's go to a web
browser and hit that URL.
And we can see it
says "Hello Dwight!"
And if you recall, Dwight
was in the database
in the names collection.
And if we make a change,
it's reflected in the web
application that we just built.
We're going to run
the Mongo shell
and we're going to
pull the document out
of the names collection.
We're going to do that by
assigning a JavaScript variable
j to the result of
"db.names.findOne."
We're going to look at j.
And we see that j is a document
with an underscore ID assigned
by the database and then
the name of "Dwight."
We can modify that
inside JavaScript.
I'm going to change
the name to "Andrew."
And now I'm going to
update the document
by calling
"db.names.save", giving
the value of this
JavaScript variable j.
OK, database tells us that
it matched one document
and that it modified
one document, which
is confirmed now that everything
is as we expect it to be.
And we can see that there is
one document inside the names
collection and it has
a name of "Andrew."
And now if we go back to
our web browser right here
and run it again, it
changes to "Andrew."
So you can see now we have an
end-to-end application that
is written in Python,
that uses Bottle,
and that uses PyMongo,
connects to the database,
and then it can answer
an HTTP request,
and produce a web page.