OK, we talked a little bit
earlier about MongoDB being
schemaless.
And I wanted to go back to that
and show you a little bit
more are inside the shell what
that looks like now that
you've seen MongoDB installed,
and you've seen the shell, and
you've seen us build a small
application end-to-end.
So fundamentally, that
comes down to a
few different things.
One is that, often, in
a relational system,
you'll have a table.
And you'll have certain
columns in the table.
For instance, name,
age, and maybe
city of birth or something.
And over time, you may decide
that you want to keep some
additional piece
of information.
And to do that, you'd have
to expand the table.
And do an ALTER TABLE command.
That's how it works in the
world of relational.
In Mongo, you don't
need to do that.
So in Mongo, different
documents can
have different schema.
And so this means that, as the
system evolves, with agile
methodologies, often you'll work
in short two and three
weeks sprints.
And you'll make changes, and
you'll iterate the system.
We can accommodate that.
So let's look at what
that practically
looks like in the shall.
All right, so let's create a
new collection and call it
users, and then put
something in it.
I'm going to put in a name,
put my whole name.
And then let's say I want to
put my city of birth in it.
I'll say it's Queens.
And I can do that.
Now, if I look in the user's
collection, I'll see my document.
And here it is.
There's a pretty
print command.
It's out of the shell.
It's very useful.
It print things out a
little bit neater.
And here it is, pretty
printed.
But now, let's say
I want to add
another user to the system.
And for whatever reason, I'm
now going to store some
additional information.
For instance, I want to store
a new user whose name is
Richard Kreuter, my
co-instructor.
And I've decided that I want to
store his city of birth as
well, which I'm not sure
about, and I'm just
going to make up.
But I also want to store his
favorite color, which I
believe is red, based on
nothing, just a guess.
Now, if I look in that
collection, I can see that
I've got two different
documents.
And these two different
documents, one of them has
just a name, and city of birth,
and of course this
interesting object ID that
we'll talk about later.
And the other one has
name, city of birth,
and favorite color.
So this permits Mongo to be very
agile because you don't
need to have exactly the same
keys in each of the documents.
And I can evolve it
over time, too.
And I can change to schema
of an existing document.
So for instance, I
can do db.users.
put it into a variable.
And I'm looking for the
object with the
name of Andrew Erlichson.
And I can see the object.
There it is.
Put my favorite color in.
And now, I can look at
Jay, and you can see
that it's been updated.
And now I could do a
db.users.save of Jay.
And now, if I look at this
collection, you can see that
my object has now been
updated to include a
favorite color as well.
This is flexibility that we're
going to take advantage of a
lot as we build systems
using MongoDB.