Many programs that interact
with users use a design
pattern called
Model-View-Controller.
Under Model-View-Controller your
program is broken up into
three basic modules
of functionality.
One is the Model.
And the Model keeps the state.
And this is where mongoDB
would be attached.
And then you have a View.
And the View is what
the user sees.
And the View get updated
by the Model.
And then you have a Controller,
which takes user
input and manipulates
this model.
So you could think about your
business logic being in here.
And this being mostly
code to display
information to the user.
And this being code to
handle user input.
So Bottle has ways of allowing
you to use the
Model-View-Controller
design pattern.
So how would that work?
Well, in an HTML page, the
controller is really the code.
For instance, right here, this
is the page that will get
implemented when someone
fetches the URL slash.
And you don't want to mix code,
which is your Model and
your Controller, with your
View, which has mostly
information having to do with
outputting and displaying
information for the user.
So how do you separate
that in Bottle?
And the answer is that
they have this
concept of a template.
And the template is a View.
So here I've changed this
program slightly so that we've
set up a small list called
mythings, which has apple,
orange, banana, and
peach in it.
And rather than just returning
Hello World,
I'm returning a template.
Bottle.template, and that
template is called
hello_world.
That's the file name.
The filing is hello_world.tpl.
And I'm passing some arguments
to the template--
a user name of Andrew and a
value called things which is
going to hold a reference to
this list called mythings.
Let's look at this template.
OK, so this hello_world.tpl file
has mostly HTML in it.
So you can see here, it's
basically a HTML page.
Doctype, HTML, title,
Hello World!
And this is just a standard
HTML document.
But it has access to some of
the variables that were set
inside the program.
So for example, it can say
welcome username, and it
should print out the username
that was passed to it.
Now these double curly
braces are special.
They tell the template processor
that what appears
within is a Python variable or
some sort of Python expression
that should be evaluated.
And so it actually evaluates
username and and substitutes
the value for username as it
outputs this HTML page.
The other thing that we might
want to do inside one of these
templates is write a
little bit of code.
So for instance, let's say I
want to have that list of
things be printed out
in a bulleted list.
Well, I do that by starting
out with the HTML tag ul,
which will give me
a numbered list.
And then I close it with a ul.
That's the closing ul tag.
And then in the middle, I want
to iterate through this list
of things that was passed
to this template.
And to do that, I want
to write Python
code right in my template.
And the bottle templating
language has the
facility for that.
If you put this percent sign in
the first character of the
line, then it knows what follows
is code that needs to
be evaluated.
So it's going to evaluate, right
here, this as Python
code for thing and things.
And then this next line is just
a regular HTML line, but
with that special substitutional
logic where the
variable thing is substituted
for the string thing here.
And then finally, because this
HTML template language doesn't
depend on indentation to express
its control block, the
way Python does, we
need something, a
hack, if you will.
And the heck is that whereas
before you would have just
indented this expression and
then Python would've known
that this where the
block ends--
because this is not indented,
we have to put this %end in.
And you'll need that for every
single control statement in
Python where there's normally
a sub block
that would be indented.
So that's a lot to take in.
But it's really pretty
straightforward.
What it is is an HTML file, this
is your View, it's all of
your crafty HTML, with us a
little bit of Python code
interspersed either between
these two curly braces right
here or Python code that starts
with a percentage
character in the first column,
which tells the template
processor that this is
actually Python code.
All right, so let's go to our
web server, host 8080.
And when we do that, we get this
lovely little HTML page.
And we can view the source
of that page.
And you can see that this source
is exactly what's in
this file, but with some
substitutions.
So for instance, where this
control flow was, here with
this Python code, now
we have this list
that's shown right here.
And you see I carefully put in
the beginning and the closing
tags for each list item.
And this is just HTML, nothing
too special about that.
OK, there's one other thing you
might have noticed about
this template.
And that is that there are
two different ways of
calling this template.
One is that you can call it with
named parameters, like
username is Andrew and
thing is mythings,
which is this list.
Or you can call it with a
dictionary right here.
That's equally valid.
I'll show you.
I can comment this line out
and use this line instead.
Either one of these structures
will work.
Here I have a dictionary with
username of Richard and things
of mythings and that'll produce
the same result, where
I'll be able to use the variable
username and things
inside my template.
Now the reason why these two
forms are equivalent is that
behind the scenes, Python always
sends your variables
into the function
as a dictionary.
And if I run this one,
you'll see this one
says Welcome Richard.
So let's see if that's true.
Let's go here.
I'm going to restart
the server and
then go to my program.
And now it says Welcome
Richard with
the exact same output.
One other small detail that's
pretty important is that I
didn't show you this, but you
need to put your templates
into a directory called views,
which is right there as a
subdirectory of the directory
that your program runs.
So Python, hello_world.py, that
starts my WSGI server,
and my Bottle based
web server.
And then those templates
are assumed to be in a
subdirectory called views.
And I've got a bunch of views,
including some of the ones
from the blogging project.
And some of those other things
you see is, actually I used
Dropbox, and some of these
things are conflicted copies
of the things that I've
been moving around.
All right, so that's how you
use templates inside Python
and Bottle to approximate this
Model-View-Controller paradigm.