Welcome back to MongoDB
for developers.
This week, we're going
to cover CRUD
and the Mongo shell.
CRUD, which stands for create,
read, update, delete, is a
pretty common acronym for
describing the kinds of
manipulations that you
can perform on
the database's records.
In MongoDB terminology, we call
create "insert," we call
read "find," we call update
"update," and we call delete
"remove." these are analogous,
respectively, to SQL operators
"insert," "select," "update,"
and "delete."
Now one thing that's important
to know about MongoDB is that
CRUD operations, and indeed, all
operations that manipulate
data in the database, exist
as methods or functions in
programming language APIs.
MongoDB does not have its own
query language analogous to
the SQL language that needs to
be expressed as a string
embedded inside a program.
Instead, MongoDB has a wire
protocol, which is relatively
simple, that incorporates an
operation code and arguments
that operation, transmitted
as a sequence of
bytes over the network.
From a programmer's perspective,
you instead
manipulate documents
in the database
using methods on objects--
or functions, if your language
isn't object-oriented--
and those methods transmit
data over the network
according to the
wire protocol.
The actual experience of
programming to MongoDB's CRUD
operations is relatively
pleasant for most programmers,
precisely because you don't have
to manipulate a stringy
language in the way that you
have to manipulate SQL in
customary databases.
The meaning of this will
become clearer as we go
through the rest of this week.
This week, we'll learn the
basic CRUD APIs that are
available in the Mongo shell,
and then the analogous
functionality exposed via the
pymongo bindings in Python.
OK.
Let's have a quiz.
By the end of this week, you'll
know which of the
following--
MondoDB's basic document
creation retrieval
modification and removal
operations, some features of
the MongoDB shell, Mongo, how
to measure performance of
MongoDB operations, how to
manipulate MongoDB documents
from Python, and how to analyze
data in MongoDB
collections.