All right.
Let's learn some more general
things about querying.
As you already know, if you
enter db.people.find with no
arguments, you'll retrieve all
the documents from the
"people" collection.
At this point, the "people"
collection has just two
documents, so it's not that
interesting for doing queries.
Let's construct a collection
that has many more documents
in it with some more different
data for the purpose of doing
some queries.
Here's a fragment of JavaScript
that contains a
nested loop.
The outer loop iterates for
i up from 0, up to but not
including 1,000, and the inner
loop iterates for j up from 0,
up to but not including 3.
And each loop iteration, for the
inner loop, inserts a new
document with the field
"student" having the value
that's i, the field type having
the value that's the
element of the array names at
the current value of j, and
the field score, that is a
round number somewhere
between 0 and 100.
At this point, I have reason to
believe that I have a few
thousand documents in the
"scores" collection.
Let's query for some
of these documents
using the Find method.
As you see, when Find is called
with no arguments, a
whole bunch of documents are
spilled to the screen.
And you can see there are
documents for student 0 with
type "exam" and score 64.
Another for students 0 with
type "essay" and score 24.
Another for students 0
with type "quiz" and
score 31, and so on.
In the shell, when a query is
going to return very many
documents, they're retrieved
in batches.
There's actually two layers of
batching going on, but you can
just think of it as
a batch size of
approximately 20 by default.
In order to page through some of
the documents that you get
back, you can type "it" to visit
some more documents.
Eventually, this iteration will
exhaust all the documents
that come back from the query.
But there are several thousand
documents to go through, and I
really feel like doing
that right now.
In fact, for the duration of
the time that the shell is
holding this query open, there's
a cursor on the server
that might be open until we
exhaust all of the documents
that get iterated.
In fact, the server will close
the cursor after 10 minutes by
default, so there shouldn't
be too much of a threat of
exhausting resources
on the server side.
In any case, for the most part,
iterating through these
documents manually is something
that's a little
tedious to do.
One small tip.
If you want to execute a query
like this, you might want to
tack on to the end a method
called Pretty, which changes
the way in which the shell
prints out the
results of the query--
slightly more readable,
I think you'll say.
For the most part, however,
paging through huge results
sets is not something
that anybody does.