So we've already learned one of
the things that the update
method in the JavaScript
shell can do.
And that's what we might call a
wholesale replacement of the
fields in a document.
This is something of a dangerous
thing to do in many
sorts of applications.
And so typically, you want to
manipulate just specific
fields in a document.
And in fact, the update
operator allows you
to do that as well.
So again, here's my
people collection.
And they have various names.
Suppose I wanted to
give Alice an age.
Well, we can do this in
a couple of ways.
First, I could use a replacement
operation.
However, in order to achieve
the desired effect, namely
adding an age value, I would
need to know all of the other
fields that happen to exist
in the document
where the name is Alice.
And perhaps I don't know
that information.
And so this replacement method
is not a great idea.
Instead, what we want is an
operation that manipulates
only the fields that we specify
and leaves all the
other fields alone.
And for this, update has
various $ operators.
In the simple case, I just want
to set a specific field.
If that field doesn't exist,
it will be made to exist.
So the update that's at the
bottom of my terminal says
find the document where the name
is Alice and set the age
field to 30.
If there is no age field,
one will be created.
If I now query for the document
where name is Alice,
Alice now has an age.
Once I've created this
field age, I can
certainly set it again.
And these sorts of set
operations that change one
number to another are actually
quite efficient in MongoDB.
Further, beyond the set
operation, we have an
operation that can increment a
field that already exists.
It's called $ inc.
Given that I happen to know that
Alice has an age field
that's currently 31, if I update
specifying $ inc of age
by 1, then I happen to
know that the should
turn out to be 32.
And indeed, it is now 32.
So $ set can add or modify
a field in a document.
And $ inc can modify a
field in a document.
In fact, if the field doesn't
exist, $ inc will create a new
field having as its value
the increment step.
So for instance, if I wish to
increment the age for Bob and
one happens not to exist, then
one will be made to exist with
a value that's going to have
the increment step.
In this case, 1.
All right.
Let's have a simple quiz.
Suppose you have this document
in a collection called users.
The username is spelunker.
The country is US.
And the phone is 718-343-3433.
Write the shell command for
updating the country to RU
just for this user.