OK.
So now we've learned the
basic CRUD operations
that MongoDB offers--
Insert, Find, Update,
and Remove.
However, there's a little bit
more that you need to know
about the exact details of
operations into MongoDB.
The shell is an interactive
environment, and so it gives
you information whenever
something goes wrong.
For example, I mentioned before
that the _id field is a
primary key.
It is required to be present,
it's required to be unique,
and we actually make it
immutable, in addition.
If I insert a document with a
particular primary key, let's
say "Smith".
Well, I have reason to believe
that a document got inserted.
I'll tell you a little
bit more about how
you can confirm that.
If I try to insert a second
document with name "Smith",
the shell will give me an
error message back.
In fact, the interactive shell
always checks to see whether
the last operation succeeded
or failed and tells you
immediately if it failed.
So far, I haven't shown you
any operations that fail.
This was a little bit of
malice of forethought.
However, you control
programatically check whether
an operation succeeded or failed
by running a command.
We've actually use some
commands already.
For instance, Count is
actually a command.
In any case, there's a command
called "getLastError", which
returns the outcome of the last
right operation that was
sent on the connection that
you're currently using.
The result of getLastError is a
document, and in case of an
error scenario, the document has
a field E-R-R that has a
non-null value containing
an error message.
Most errors also have a unique
integer code, which is given
the code field.
getLastError is available both
in the shell and in all of our
drivers as a way of checking
whether a write operation
succeed or failed.
In the event that a write
operation succeeds, for
example, I'll insert another
document with a different _id.
In that case, the getLastError
command will tell me that the
error is null-- that is to say
that operation succeeded.
For other sorts of operations,
such as updates, getLastError
can tell me the outcome
of the update.
In this case, I will specify an
update that should affect
all documents in the collection
adding a title field.
getLastError, after such an
update, tells me that the
documents that got updated
already existed and that there
were two of them.
This is how I could find out
how many documents got
affected by an update.
By contrast, if instead of doing
a multe-update I ask for
an upsert--
that is to say and update
operation that will either
update a document with name
"Thompson", if one exists, or
else create a document with
name "Thompson" and title
"doctor", if none exists.
After such an upsert operation,
getLastError tells
me that it did not update an
existing document, but instead
upserted a new document who's
_id is returned to me.
So you see the getLastError
command is a way both to find
out whether a write operation
succeeded or failed and also
to get some information about
the successful write
operations that just happened.
Again, the shell automatically
tells you when a write
operation fails.
So so far, I have repeatedly
said that I have reason to
believe that my write operations
were successful.
That reason was simply
that the shell
did not tell me otherwise.
Finally, if I choose to remove
all people from the "people"
collection, the getLastError
command will tell me that
there were three documents
removed.
n equals 3.
We'll see more of the
getLastError command again in
a future part of this course.
For now, you should understand
that it's the way to check
whether a write operation
succeeded or failed.