Let's go through that simple
aggregation example I showed
you in the first lesson,
in a detailed way.
So, if you recall, we started
with a products collection.
And then we did some grouping
on that collection to get a
results collection that
was shown from
the aggregation function.
Now, here is the collection,
if you recall.
It was this list of products.
And the products have a
manufacturer, and a name, and
a category.
And we wanted to get the number
of products by each
manufacturer.
This was the query, over
here, that we used.
We called db.products.aggregate.
We put it through--
there's only one stage to our
aggregation pipeline.
It was a dollar group, where
we asked to group by
manufacturer.
And we do that by
specifying _id.
And then, we were creating a new
key, called num_products
with the operator dollar sum.
So what logically
happens here?
All right.
So the aggregation framework is
going to run through every
one of these documents.
So the first document it's going
to consider is this one.
And this document has a
manufacturer of Apple.
And, if you recall, we're
going to create-- in our
result set-- we're going to look
for a resulting document
with an _id of the
manufacturer.
And, in this case, it's Apple.
So, as we go through that first
document, we're going to
look and we're going to
say, is there one
with an _id of Apple?
No.
Let's create [INAUDIBLE]
my result set, called
_id Apple.
And then, it also asked to
create a num_products key.
And, what does the num_products
key do?
Well, it said, create
a num_products key
in my result set.
And I want you to add one--
run a sum and add one to
whatever is there.
There's nothing there
to start.
And it seeds it at zero, so
it'll start it-- by adding
one, it'll put it right
there-- one.
So, again, as it's running
through these products, it's
creating a new collection
of the results.
So the group phase doesn't
run the documents from
one end to the other.
It actually processes each one,
grouping it, and then
creating a new set of aggregated
documents.
Let's look at the
second document.
Second document has a
manufacturer of Apple.
And, again, it would go
through, and they
would say, all right.
It's almost like an upsert.
It would look and say,
is there something
with an _id of Apple?
Yes, there is.
Run that sum on it.
It said add one to num_products,
so that's going
to update the num_products
to two.
And it's going to run to the
third document in the
collection.
The third document collection
has a manufacturer of Apple.
So remember we were looking for
a document in the result
set with an _id of Apple.
We do have one.
We're going to add one,
again, to it.
And now we're going to
wind up with three.
Now, the fourth document in this
products collection has a
manufacturer of Samsung.
We're going to look for a
document in the result set
that has an _id of Samsung.
We're not going to find one.
So we're, essentially, going
to, if you will, upsert it,
put something in the result set
with Samsung, as an _id.
And we're going to, again,
create a num_products key.
And this was my name,
it's arbitrary.
And we're going to add
one to what was
there, which is nothing.
So we're going to get one.
And so on and so forth, as we
run through this collection,
the next one is a product
from Sony.
So we're going to look for a
document with an _id of Sony.
We're not going to find one.
So we're going to create it--
_id of Sony.
And then initialize it to be
num_products one because of
that sum operator again.
When we're done, we're going
to get a resulting set of
documents that's going
to run to the next
stage of the pipeline.
And that set of documents is
going to have an _id equal to
the manufacturer of each
of these products.
And num_products is going to be
the number of products that
each manufacturer
manufactured.
You can almost look at this,
again, as an upsert-- or I
like to think of it
as an upsert--
because it's creating documents
in the result set,
if they don't already exist.
If they do exist, it's
just updating them.
It's running that aggregation
operator against the field,
other than _id.
All right.
So that's the way aggregation
works, in a detailed way.
And they all build on this
basic concept of running
through the source collection.
Or the collection is known as
a source collection because
they [INAUDIBLE]
other stages of the pipeline.
But running through documents
that existed, prior to that
stage of the pipeline, and then
building a new set of
documents with an _id,
as specified.
In this case, we called upon
dollar manufacturer to be our
_id, and then running the
aggregation operators on the
other fields that we've created,
other keys, and
values that we've created.
OK.
So let's have a quiz.
Let's say we have the following
collection of stuff.
And you can see here it has some
documents with a, b, and
c, specified for each
of these documents.
And we perform the following
aggregation,
db.stuff.aggregate, group
_id dollar c.
How many documents will be in
the result set from the
aggregate function?