Let's go over what other
expressions exist in the
aggregation grouping stage
of the pipeline.
So, again, these are the
expressions that you can use
in the group stage.
We've already seen sum, a bit.
Sum lets you do two things.
It can count if you add one
each time you see a key.
Or, if you add the value
of the key, then it
can sum up that key.
Average can average the values
of a key across documents.
Minimum will find the minimum
value of a documents of a
certain key.
And, again, this is
as grouped by the
underscore ID that you specify.
Max finds the maximum
value of a key.
Push and addtoset--
these two--
they build arrays.
So if you--
we'll go over this in more
detail-- but if you want to--
every time you encounter a
certain value, you want to
push it onto an array
in the result
documents, you can do that.
This can get large very
quickly with push.
Addtoset does something very
similar to push, but only adds
each one, uniquely.
It won't add it if it's already
there, so this is
usually more useful.
And, finally, we have
first and last.
Now these are special.
First and last require you to,
first, sort the documents, or
they don't make any sense.
Because what first is going to
do is it's going to find the
first value for a key that it
sees across the documents it's
processed during the group
aggregation stage.
And last would be
the last one.
And if you haven't sorted
them, then first
and last are arbitrary.
And I'll show you how to use
these little bit later, too.
All right.
So let's do a quiz.
Which of the following
aggregation expressions must
be used in conjunction with
a sort to make any sense?
Check all that apply.