The next operator we're gonna
go over is the $avg operator
for figuring out the average
value of a key.
Again, we have our products
collection.
And we're gonna figure out the
average price by category, so
the average price, for instance,
of a tablet.
Here's a program that can do
that, or an aggregation
expression that can do that.
We're going to $group.
Our _id is going to be at a
compound document of category
where we're gonna name the key
category and then we're going
to pull the $category
value out.
We're gonna aggregate on
that, on category.
And then we're going to
get the average price.
You can see it says $avg.
And we should name that
appropriately.
So we'll name it avg_price.
There it is.
And we get the average of the
$price expression which is the
price document key value.
So let's go and run that.
So here we are.
We're gonna run it, mongo.
And we're just gonna redirect
input from using avg.js, which
is the file I just showed you.
And you can see that.
And what we get is just three
resulting documents, which
makes sense, category laptops,
the average price, category
cellphones, the average price,
and category tablets, the
average price.
Now it's time for
you to do it.
Let's do a quiz.
So for this quiz, we're gonna
use the same data set we used
in the last problem, which is
a data set of US zip codes,
which are postal codes.
If you did not do the last quiz,
you should go back and
read that quiz for using sum.
That'll tell you about this
data set and how it works.
This is the document out of the
data set giving you the
population of a particular zip
code, particular postal code
as it's called.
And in this case it falls into a
city called Fisher's Island,
and the population is 329.
So, please write an aggregation
expression to
calculate the average population
of a zip code,
which is a postal
code, by state.
As before, the postal code is
in the ID field, the _id
field, and is unique.
And we can assume that the
collection is called zips.
And you should name the key in
the result of the aggregation
expression as average_pop so
that we know what to expect,
average_pop.
And it's gonna be something
along the line of
db.zips.aggregate and then
the whole expression.
Please don't use a compound
_id specification.
Just use what you need to
get the problem done.
Don't rename it.
And put the answer right here.