The last two expressions I want
to go over before turning
to some other topics
is max and min.
Now max and min are so similar
I'm not gonna show both.
But what max does is it picks
out the max value in the
grouping, and it makes
it available for
creating a new key.
So let's say we want to figure
out the max price charged by
any manufacturer in our little
electronics products catalog.
And again, the catalog looks
a little bit like this.
We're gonna figure out the max
price that Amazon charges or
the max price that
Google charges.
We do that by grouping by the
maker, pulling out the
$manufacturer value and then
setting up a new key, max
price with max of $price.
And this refers to
the price key.
So we run that.
And we see that the max price
charged by Google, Amazon,
Sony, et cetera, and Apple,
in our little collection.
Now, note that this is a
little bit limiting.
Because using this technique, I
can't figure out the name of
the product and its max price.
Because I'm grouping by
manufacture and I can't group
by manufacture product.
That wouldn't make any sense.
I want to also pull out the
product that corresponds to
that price.
And max, there's really no
easy way to do that.
But there are some ways to do
that using sort and last and
first, which we're gonna show
after we go through some of
the other pipeline stages that
are available in the
aggregation framework.
OK, let's do a quiz.
Here's the quiz.
Thinking again about this zip
code database that we've been
playing with, let's find the
population of the zip code in
each state that is
most populous.
So we want to group by the
state and figure out the
highest population that exists
in any zip code.
And again, the collection
is called zips.
And write your aggregation
query over here.