One of the neat things about
the aggregation framework
that's even better than what you
have available using SQL
with group by is that you can
run a particular aggregation
stage more than once.
For instance, we can group more
than once in the same
aggregation query, what I'll
call double grouping.
Now, when would this
be useful?
Let me show you a data set that
contains scores for each
student in each class.
So for example, I might have
student ID 1, class ID 397.
He may have several entries--
one for a homework,
one for a quiz.
And let's say that we want to
figure out what's the average
class grade in each class.
To do that, first, we need to
average all the students'
grades within the class.
And after that, we need to
average those grades.
So that looks like this.
db.grades.aggregate.
I'm going to first do a grouping
where I group by
class ID and Student ID.
And I'm going to average
all those scores.
So I'm going to average
And that's going to give me a
bunch of documents that have
the class ID and the student ID
as an underscore ID and the
average for those assessments.
And then we're going to pipe
that to the secondary
grouping, which is going to use
as its underscore ID for
grouping purposes the underscore
ID dot class ID of
the previous stage.
And then it's going to average
those to get a final average.
So let's run that and see
what it looks like.
So it looks like this.
You can see for each
of these class
IDs, I've got an average.
Now, what did it look like
after the first stage?
Let's do this.
Let's just--
going to write this as
a secondary file--
take this out.
I'll take the second
stage out.
All right.
Now, we'll run that.
So after the first stage, what
I have is for each class and
each student, I have
an average.
And then what I need to do is
aggregate on the class and
average those averages.
And there might be a
different number of
assessments for each student.
So I can't just take an average
of everything for the
class ID, I need to do two
separate aggregation stages to
get the answer.
A little tricky, but it's very
useful to be able to do this
as we'll see in other
assignments.
Now, let's do a quiz.
Given the following collection--
and I've just
created this collection--
with the following documents and
the following aggregation
query which has a
double grouping,
what values are returned?
And I'll just go ahead and tell
you that there are two
values of interest in the
final result document.
What values are returned?
Now, you can do this by
reasoning your way through it.
Or if you really want, you can
set up my MongoDB and put all
these documents in and it'll
just tell you the answer.
But it'd be better if you could
sort of reason your way
through it.