OK, we've talked about
aggregation for a while now
and how good it is.
But now I want to talk to you
about some of the limitations
that exist in the aggregation
framework within MongoDB
and how you can get
around them and what
you should think about
when you're using it.
The first limitation
is that by default, we
have a 100 megabyte limit.
That's pretty small
for pipeline stages.
And the way you get
around that, of course,
is by using allow disk use
option, which will get you
around that 100 megabyte limit.
But unless you specify
that option to aggregation,
you will be limited
to that 100 megabytes,
and you will find that your
queries will not come back
if they're very large, and they
have large intermediary results
in the grouping or
the sorting stages.
That's the first limitation.
The second limitation
is that if you
decide to return the
results in one document,
then there can be a
16 megabyte limit.
And since Python does return
the results in one document,
there's a 16 megabyte
limit by default in Python.
And we saw an easy
way around this one,
and that's of
course to simply set
cursor equal to
this empty document,
and then Python
will return a cursor
and you can have aggregation
results that have no limit.
But keep that in mind.
The last limitation I
want to tell you about
has to do which sharding.
So in a sharded system, as soon
as you use a group by or a sort
or anything that requires
looking at all the results,
then what will happen
is that the results
will be brought back
to the first shard.
So we'll talk a little
bit more about that.
A sharded system
has multiple shards.
And this might be
shard zero, shard one,
shard two, shard
three, shard four.
And in fact, each
of these shards
may be a replica set, so
there may be multiple MongoDB
standing behind this one.
So all this represents
let's say a three node
replica set that
is a single shard.
Each of these
might be like that.
So I'm not going
to draw them in,
but they're probably
all like that.
So in that situation, you've
got a Mongo s router in front,
and you got an application.
And that application is going
to send an aggregation query,
and that aggregation query,
if it uses a collection that's
sharded, is going to send
that to every single one.
And some parts of that,
for instance a projection
or a match, could go in
parallel with all the shards.
But if you do a group by
phase for instance or a sort
or anything else that requires
looking at all the data,
then what's going
to happen is MongoDB
is going to send all that
data to the primary shard
for the database.
And the primary shard is
where an unsharded collection
would live.
So initially you'll be
distributing the work,
and then if you start
doing a group by or a sort,
then the results
are going to get
sent to one shard to
get processed further,
so that everything can be
collected in one place.
And so in that
sense, you may not
find the same level
of scalability
in aggregation that you might
find let's say Haddoup, where
there might be greater
parallelism for very
large what's called
MapReduce jobs.
And for those of you who are
not familiar with MapReduce,
it's not really
important right now,
but aggregation is an interface
to MapReduce functionality
within MongoDB, and you may
find that the performance
of a large aggregation
on a sharded cluster
may not be quite
as good as you'd
expect if you are
used to, let's say,
you're running a
large Haddoup job.
Which gets to good
alternatives to aggregation
and they are that you
could use Haddoup,
which offers MapReduce.
Of course you have
to get your data out
of MongoDB and
into Haddoup, which
you could do using
the Haddoup connector.
So the Hadoup connector
could be used to do that.
And there's also another
MapReduce functionality
built into MongoDB, which
has several limitations,
a little bit older.
And I actually would not
recommend using this.
So I don't recommend this
except for very simple stuff.
I generally don't recommend
the MapReduce functionality
built into MongoDB.
Aggregation is a better choice.
So use aggregation not
MapReduce functionality.
But you could also use Haddoup
as an alternative aggregation,
but you have to get data out
of MongoDB and essentially
into HDFS or use our
connector to connect the two.
All right, those
are the limitations
of the aggregation
framework in a nutshell.