OK.
In this problem, we asked you
to go through and figure out
the most frequent author of
a comment on the blog.
And you're supposed to import
the post data set and then use
an aggregation query to
find out the answer.
And the answer is going
to turn out
to be Elizabet Kleine.
So let's see how you do that.
Here's the aggregation query
that you need to run.
You unwind the comments, which
there's an array of comments,
if you recall.
And then you group it by
the comment author.
And then add one every time
you see a comment author.
You create this new num_comments
field.
And the value is this summing,
adding one each
time you see it.
Sort by num_comments minus one
to get it in reverse order.
And I just limited it to 10,
just to make it easier to see.
And if you do that, then the
answer is this right here.
You can see the answer
is Elizabet
Kleine has 503 comments.
And then it goes down
from there.