One thing I want to make clear
is that indexing is not
restricted to the first level
of keys within a document.
So, for example, I've got this
people collection right here,
and [INAUDIBLE] printed
out the contents.
It has a couple of small
documents plus this larger
document down here that has Tim
Johnson and his addresses,
which is an array of addresses,
right here.
And then in the array of
addresses, there's a tag for
what type of address it
is, as well as an
array of phone numbers.
And these are just place
holders, so the numbers one
through five, it's an array.
So, we can actually put an index
on these subparts, these
subarrays, of the document.
So, let me show you what
that looks like.
If you wanted to put in an index
on the address key and
then there's an array underneath
there, and then the
tag in that array you could
do it this way.
And if you wanted to add
one to the phones, you
could do it that way.
And now, if we look at get
index, you'll see there are
these multi key indexes on the
phone's key over here, and the
tag key over here.
So, that's pretty useful if
you're looking to create a
rich document.
And the way it works is Mongo
D will add an index element,
or index point, if you will, for
every item in the array,
and if you change those items
then it would have to change
the pointer in those indexes.
But you don't think much about
it, you just can add the index
in whatever subpart you want and
it will just sort of work
the way you might expect.