The indexes that we've created
so far have not been unique.
A unique index enforces a
constraint that each key can
only appear once in the index.
That is not true for the indexed
that we've created.
Let's create another
collection here,
db.stuff.insert.
And I'm going to
insert a thing.
I'm going to insert a pear.
And now I'm going to create an
index on this collection.
Sorry, I mistyped it.
I need to have the collection
in there.
So we created an index
on this collection.
And I can create multiple
items with thing pear.
So I'm going to put
another one in.
I'm going to put one in
with thing apple.
But what if I wanted to
create a unique index?
All right, if I look
in stuff right now,
I can see my indexes.
I can see I've got this
index on thing.
Let's drop that index.
And now let's try to create
an index that's unique.
So we do that with ensureIndex
command, with now our second
document after the first one
with unique being true.
And this is going to enforce the
constraint that each key
can only appear once.
Now it won't allow me to do that
because, in fact, there
is a conflict.
So let's get rid of
that conflict.
So db.stuff.remove,
let's remove one
of these right here.
I'll remove one of
these pears.
That should do it.
And now if I try to create
the index, I can do it.
And if I call getIndexes on
this collection, I can see
that there's a new field now.
It says unique true for
this secondary index.
And if I try to insert
something, I'm going to show
you the collection again.
And then try to insert something
that violates the
index, like, for instance,
asserting an apple.
I get a duplicate key error
because I can't have more than
one item in the collection
that has a
key with thing apple.
So you'll notice that the _id
index is not shown is unique.
But we know and we've told
you that it is unique.
So this is actually a slight
vagary of the database that it
doesn't tell you that that
particular index is unique.
But if you try to insert into
it, you'll certainly see that
it is unique.
So I'm going to try to insert
into the collection.
I want to do this, id:1, b:1.
So now I'm inserting something
with _id of 1.
An if I try to insert another
documents with _id of 1, I get
a duplicate key error, exactly
the same way as I do on the
index on thing, even though in
fact the database does not
tell you that the index
_id unique.
But it is a unique index.
And so just to review, to create
a unique index you
specify this unique:true option
in the second document
after the ensureIndex.
All right, so now it
is time for a quiz.
Please provide the mongo shell
command to add a unique index
to the collection students on
the keys student_id, class_id.
And please type that
right there.