All right.
So now we know how to create
an index and have it be a
unique index by giving the
unique true option.
Now the problem is, what if you
want to create an index on
a collection but there are
duplicate keys in the
collection?
Now, there is a way to do
this inside MongoDB,
but it's a bit dangerous.
But I want you to
know about it.
If you want to remove the
duplicate keys when creating
the index, you can do it by
giving the dropDups option and
setting it to true, while
also setting the
unique option to true.
So you have to set unique to
true and dropDups to true.
And what this will do is, as it
goes through the collection
and creates the index, if it
finds more than one document
with the same key it will
remove all the documents
except for one.
And there's no way to control
which one it removes.
So this is a pretty big
sledgehammer to solve the
problem, but it will work.
So those documents are
irretrievably deleted from the
collection.
And I wouldn't recommend this,
but if this is what you want,
then you can do it.
Let me show it to you
in the shell.
Here I have a collection, the
collection "things." And I've
done db.things.find.
And you can see there's
three things in here.
Each of them has a key thing.
And there's a pear,
apple, and pear.
So if I want to create an index
on that I can do that.
I'm going to do
db.things.ensureIndex, and put
it on thing ascending.
And now I'm going to offer
unique equals true.
And if I did that, I should
find that it will fail,
because after all, there's
a duplicate.
All right.
So if we try to do that, we get
a duplicate key error when
it tries to create the index.
So let's go through it now
and let's remove all the
duplicates.
I'm going to give the same
ensureIndex command, but this
time I'm going to say dropDups
true to drop the duplicates.
And if I do that, then
the index succeeds.
And if I now look in the
collection, I'll find that,
indeed, one of my two items
for pear-- pear was a
duplicate key--
has been removed.
Now there's only two documents
in the collection.
And if you look and see what
indexes are on the collection,
you'll see there's now an index
in the collection that
is unique true.
And also it noted that dropDups
was true during the
creation, so that
you know that.
All right.
It is time for a quiz.
If you choose the dropDups
option when creating a unique
index, what will MongoDB do to
documents that conflict with
an existing index entry?
Move them to an archive
collection?
Unset the conflicting key so
that they can be indexed and
remain in the collection?
Remove them but write the
deleted documents in JSON to a
special file in the
log directory?
Or delete them forever
and ever, Amen?