And the answer is the first
three are true, and the last
one is not true.
A mongod instance can only build
one background index at
a time per database.
The database server will
continue to take requests, but
you'll be blocked in the
shell that you used
to create the index.
So you might think that that's
an indication that other
people are blocked, but it's
not, you can continue to work.
I'm not sure we told you
that, so you might have
had to guess at that.
Creating an index in the
background takes longer than
creating it in the foreground,
this is certainly true.
And in Mongo 2.2 and above,
indexes are created in the
background by default.
That's not true.
They're still create it in the
foreground by default.
In Mongo 2.2 and above the big
change is that there's now a
pre-database writer lock.
That is the big change.
So that even if you run them in
the foreground, you're only
going to be blocking writers
from the same database, versus
all the databases across
the whole server.