Let's talk for a moment about
index cardinality, which is
how many index points are there
for each different type
of index that MongoDB
supports.
Now in a regular index, for
every single key that you put
in the index, there's
certainly going
to be an index point.
And in addition, if there is no
key, then there's going to
be an index point under
the null entry.
So essentially, you get about
one to one relative to the
number of documents in the
collection in terms of index
cardinality.
And that makes the index
a certain size.
And it's proportional to the
collection size in terms of
its end pointers to documents.
In a sparse index, when a
document is missing the key
being indexed, it's not in the
index because it's a null and
we don't keep nulls in the
index for a sparse index.
So here, we're going to have
index points that could be
potentially less than or equal
to the number of documents.
And finally, here in a multikey
index, which is an
index on an array value--
and an index becomes a multikey
index as soon as you
have at least one value inside
any document that is an array.
Then there may be
multiple index
points for each document.
For instance, if there's some
sort of tags array in a
document, and it's got three
or five or four tags, then
there's going to be an index
point for every single one of
these keys.
And so it could be greater than
the number of documents.
And it could be significantly
greater than
the number of documents.
And this comes up because
indexes need to be maintained.
There's a cost of maintaining
them.
And if anything causes the
index to have to get
rewritten--
For example, let's say
a document moves.
When a document moves-- and it
might move because you just
added something to it that makes
it too large to fit in
the space that the database
has for it on disk, so it
needs to move it to
a new location.
Every single index point that
points to that document needs
to be updated.
Now, if the key is null for a
particular index, well then
there is no update that needs
to happen to the index.
If it's a regular index, well
then yeah, one index point
needs to get updated for sure.
And if it's a multikey index,
and there's 100 or 200 or 300
items in an array, then
they all need to get
updated inside the index.
All right, time for a quiz.
Let's say you update a document
with a key called
tags and that update causes the
document to need to get
moved on disk.
If the document has 100 tags in
it, and if the tags array
is indexed with a multikey
index, how many index points
need to be updated in the index
to accommodate the move?
Put just the number below.