And the answer is the odometer
mileage, right?
Because there's, let's
say most people drive
cars 100,000 miles.
There's 100,000 different
odometer readings that we
could choose from that might
narrow down the car, whereas
the manufacturer, I don't know
how many manufacturers of cars
there are, but maybe
100 or 1,000.
The weight of the car, most
cars weigh under 10,000
pounds, so that's 10,000,
assuming that you don't bring
it out to any decimal points
it's just 10,000 different
possibilities, and there aren't
that many colors.
So I think the odometer mileage
would be the most selective.
So again, this is important to
think about selectivity when
designing indexes because that's
going to help you get
better performance.