All right, and the answer is
that it's the first choice
here, will turn the
most documents.
It will return all three
documents The find doesn't
have any criteria
so it's going to
return every document.
It's going to sort by title, but
we're hinting that we want
it to use the basic cursor, so
it'll find every single one of
these documents.
Even though it's sorted by
title, which is a sparse index
and which does not have an entry
for the third document,
if you recall the
third document
does not have a title.
All these other three items
will not return three
documents, they have
the same problem.
The second one sorts by title
and doesn't give a hint and so
it will use a title index and
the title index is sparse and
the third document does not have
an entry and this will
return two documents.
This one, name does not equal
Kevin, that is every document,
but again sorting by title,
that's going to filter out the
one that doesn't have a title
because the sort is on that
sparse index.
The last one specifically tells
us to hint and use the
title index.
Same problem, it's going to
return two documents.
So only the first one will
return all three documents, so
the first one returns
the most documents.