I want to show you how to use
the hint command in PyMongo.
It's pretty similar to the way
you use it in the Mongo shell,
but there is one small
subtlety that's
worth pointing out.
So this is a small program I
wrote called using_hint.py.
It looks a lot like all the
other programs that we've used
in this class.
We connect to the Mongo
database, and we connect to
the test database in particular,
and then to the
foo collection.
And we're going to do a query on
A, B, and C keys all having
the value of 40,000.
And we're going to do that
query right here and then
we're going to append this
hint command on it.
But what I want to point out
is that, just like when you
want to sort by a particular
index in Python, you can't
just give a dictionary
to specify the index.
You have to give an array
of these tuples.
And so this is an array
of tuples where--
this is not a compound index,
it's a simple index.
But if it was a compound index,
there'd be multiple
tuples here.
And you see the tuple is
parentheses C comma PyMongo.
And if there was another element
to the index then
you'd have a common there
and another element.
And the reason is that the
dictionaries themselves inside
Python are not ordered.
And so in order to send an
ordered list of things to
Mongo D, you have to actually
use this array of tuples.
So it's a slightly different
syntax then you see in the
shell due to the dictionaries
in Python not being ordered.
They are ordered
in JavaScript.
All right, so if we do that--
and I actually called
"explain" at the end just so
we see what we get, just to
confirm that it works.
And I'm just going to run that
query and I'm going to print
what I get.
I'm going to iterate
through what I get.
I'm going to get a document from
the explain command and
I'm just going to
go through it.
So let's do that and
see what we get.
And it's basically
what we expect.
It's the output of an
explain command.
It printed out in Python.
The order of these different
keys are not necessarily the
same as you saw them in the
Mongo shell, again because
Python doesn't keep
them ordered.
But if you look for the cursor,
you can see that it's
using the index on just C
to satisfy this query.
So the hint command worked.