OK, now you have most of the
tools you'll need to
understand the use of indexes.
But before we go on, I want to
point out that just because
you use an index doesn't mean
it's used efficiently.
So certain types of operators,
for instance dollar greater
than and dollar less than, may
use an index but not use it
efficiently because they may
still require the inspection
of a lot of documents.
So you can say dollar greater
than three, and maybe that's
half the collection.
And so it uses the index, but
it's still very slow.
Other things that might not use
the index or if they use
it use it efficiently are
not equals or not
in or doesn't exist.
All of these negative operators
are difficult
because they need to inspect
every element to see if it
satisfies the criteria, and
they might have returned a
large result.
Also when you're searching on
regexes, if you don't give
something that is stemmed
on the left part of
the field, it's slow.
So if you say I want to search
for /abcd/, that really can't
use the index because we don't
have a way to do that full
text search.
If on other hand, you say stem
it /^abcd/ on the left most
part of the string, then it can
use it and it will use it.
Let me give you an example
where the first order
information may be a little
bit misleading.
Let's go back to our students
collection.
I built two of these
collections.
This one has 10 million
documents in it and quite a
few indexes on it.
That's a document in
the collection.
You can see it's got
a student ID and a
class ID and some scores.
And there's more than one
record for each student.
There's a record
for each class.
Let's look at the
indexes on it.
Oops.
When we look at the indexes on
it, we see there's a healthy
number of indexes on it.
We have one on _id; one on
class_id; one on student_id;
one on student_id, class_ID--
all good.
Now, let's do a query that is
reasonably selective but isn't
going to be very fast.
And in particular, let's look
at finding all the students
with a student ID greater than
500 who are in class 20.
There isn't that many
documents that
satisfy this criteria.
And then let's sort it by
student ID and explain it.
And if we do that, we can see
that it's pretty slow.
Took 3.6 seconds.
It used the
student_id_1_class_id_1 index.
Now that turns out to be not the
best choice because even
though it only returned 20,000
documents, it had to scan, it
looks like, 1.3 million index
items, and that is a lot.
So it did not use the most
efficient index.
And you can understand why.
If you use the student_id index,
and I deliberately
choose a student ID that was
somewhere in the middle, half
the records had student IDs
is greater than that.
And so it was going to be very
inefficient to do that.
But on the other hand, if I hint
it and I say, you know
what, use the class_id index.
And I know there aren't that
many students in each class
because I built this data set,
so I have information it
doesn't necessarily have.
And it's the same query.
It's going to use the
class_id data set.
And then, it's going to have
to just manually figure out
which ones are the student ID
that are greater than 500, but
it's still going to
be a lot better.
Wow, that was a lot better.
So you can see here it took
133 milliseconds, and it
scanned 20,000 objects here.
And you don't see any number
bigger than that here, so the
index entries number of scanned
looks like it was
about the same.
So much more efficient to use
this class_id index even
though the class and the student
ID was specified.
And the reason is that the way
we were using that student_id
index was with one of these
operators, greater than 500.
Greater than--
not a particularly efficient
operator to use with an index.
So just keep in mind when you're
thinking about indexing
and whether or not it's using
an index that you have to
consider more than just whether
an index was used, but
also how it was used.
Was it only used for the sort?
Was it used in an inefficient
manner that caused the
database to still look through
millions of records?
All these things are important
when it comes to final
performance.