Let's review what we've
learned so far.
We've learned that indexes are
critical to performance inside
a database and inside MongoDB.
We learned how to use the
Explain command to look at
what the database is doing for
any particular query in terms
of how it's using its indexes.
We've learned how to use the
Hint command to instruct the
database to use a particular
index for a query.
And we've learned how to turn
on profiling and look at the
profiling information to
figure out which of our
queries are slow so that we can
use the Explain command,
possibly use the Hint command,
possibly create new indexes.
But if I want to look at the
high level inside a program
and figure out what it's doing,
how would I do that?
Now, we have some tools
to do that.
And I'm going to show
those to you next.
The first one I'd like to
show you is Mongtop .
Now, Mongtop is named after
the Unix Top command.
It's going to give you a high
level view of where Mongo is
spending its time.
And to show you how that could
be interesting, let me bring
you through two programs
that I wrote.
The first program I call
stress_students.
Now stress_students, which is
right here, is a small program
that connects to the database
and is going to look up a
million student records in
my students collection.
My students collection has
no index, and this
is going to be slow.
So let's run that.
Now here it is, chugging
through these different
student records.
It looks like it's talking
almost a second per record.
And then in this window, I'm
going to run Mongtop.
And I'll run it every
three seconds--
mongotop 3.
Anyway, let's look at that
output together.
I'm going to stop it.
Now what it's saying is that--
and I'm not sure exactly why
it's above three seconds
when the sampling
interval's three seconds--
but it's saying that all the
time is spent in the students
collection.
You'll notice this a row for
each collection that it's
looking at.
And this is great because at a
high level, if I've got lots
of collections, I want to
know where the thing's
spending its time.
And then it's telling me my read
time and my write time.
And it's very clearly dominated
by time spent
reading in the students
collection.
So that tells me that that's
were I should look, right?
And I have profiling turned on,
if I went to the profiler,
I would find there's a lot of
slow queries and that I could
work on this right
off the bat.
So let's look at a different
program which should be
running much more efficiently
because it uses indexes and
see what results we get there.
So I'm going to go back here.
I'm going to stop
this program.
And now, I'm going to show you
a very similar program called
stress_students2.py.
Now, this connects to my school2
database, and there's
another students collection
in there which also has 10
million records.
But they're broken up slightly
differently by class and
student id, and so as a result,
I have to loop.
But every one of these queries
that looks up a student by its
class id is going to hit an
index because I have a
student_id, class_id index on
that in that collection.
And it's nicely selective,
and their student
id is right in there.
So we should expect to get good
performance from this program.
And let's see what the results
are when we run it.
Well, I mean the first thing
you note is that it's just
flying by, so you could just
feel that it's running a lot
more quickly through
the database.
But now I'm going to just run
Mongtop for three seconds and
see what it says.
And it says that in the
interval, 850 milliseconds of
the three seconds, the 3000
milliseconds, are spent in the
school2.students collection,
and it's all on read.
But that's only a small fraction
of the sampling
interval of three seconds.
And what that would leave me to
believe is that this thing
is not even bound by its
performance through Mongo.
And if I look at the activity
monitor on my Mac-- and this
is probably a little small
for you to see--
you can see that there's as much
time spent in Python as
there is in Mongo.
Because of all the I/O and the
loops in there, it's accessing
Mongo very quickly.
And this would tell me that
this program is actually
performing pretty well.
Now if I went and looked in the
profiling logs, I wouldn't
see any slow queries because
there really aren't any for
this particular program.
So that is Mongtop.