Now let's go over mongostat.
Now, mongostat was named
after iostat, again
from the Unix world.
And in the Windows world,
there's a PerfMon program that
you can play with that
does these things
at the system level.
And again, all this performance
stuff, certainly
in a large running system, you
probably have a dedicated
database administrator or DevOps
person that's going to
be worrying about this stuff.
But as a developer, I always
like to be able to just take a
quick look at things.
I work on the small problems, if
not the big ones, just so I
make sure that my code
isn't the problem.
So mongostat is going to
give us a bunch of more
system-level information.
And I'm going to show
you that real fast.
Now, that's going to be a little
hard to show it on the
screen because the fonts
are set very large.
This is wrapped, so
bear with me.
But it's showing you a bunch of
information about how many
queries there are per second,
updates per second, and
flushes per second.
The one that most people are
most interested in or find
most interesting about this
report is this idx miss
percentage.
And idx miss percentage, this
is actually the miss rate to
the index in memory.
So it isn't whether or not
you're using an index.
It's when an index is accessed,
whether or not it
hits memory or not or it
has to go to disk.
Because as we discussed earlier,
having your index in
memory is going to be
critical in terms of
performance in Mongo.
So if you can't get your index
into memory, then you're going
to have a big problem.
So this is telling you whether
your index is in memory.
And a lot of folks will look at
this to figure out whether
or not they're getting good
performance at a high level.
But you have to be a little bit
careful about this because--
let me show you--
in the case where we had these
two programs, PerfMon and that
students.py which was missing
the right indexes.
This thing is dirt slow.
And we'll run mongostat, and
let me show you this here.
It says locked db index miss
percentage right here.
This is the second line.
This is a 0.
We're not missing the index.
Whoa, we're not missing
the index?
That doesn't make any sense.
And the reason we're not missing
the index, of course-
it's true--
is that this program is
not using an index.
This program is just scanning
the collection
over and over again.
So we're not missing an index.
So mongostat, which is very
interesting in large running
systems because usually you
will run out of memory for
your indexes, but this program
doesn't even use an index.
So therefore, this doesn't tell
you anything interesting.
What's more interesting, of
course, is that there were
slow queries and that all the
time in the database was spent
in that one collection.
Now let's run the other program
which we know performs
well and see what it tells us.
That's flying by.
Now let's run mongostat there
and see what it says.
And here--
again, it's wrapped.
But this is the line
right here--
it says idx miss, we are
not missing the index.
I don't understand.
How could you not be
missing the index?
Well the reason is
this program is
not missing the index.
This program has an
index that is--
we learned how to get
the index size.
I think it's a gig or two.
If you can look at the activity
monitor to see how
big Mongo is right now,
let's do that.
It says that it's 2.85 gigs.
And mongostat will
also tell you.
See, mongostat tells you
that there's 2.85
gigs of data resident.
And this is a Mac that has
12 gigs of memory,
so it's not a problem.
So this won't point us to any
place where we could improve
that program.
Now the reality is I don't
know how to improve that
program except for do something
algorithmically
smarter because it is hitting
the index every time.
But it'll be difficult for me
to show you a program that's
going to miss the index in my
12 gigabyte machine unless I
deliberately create something
that's humongous and
deliberately going to miss it.
If you go into documentation,
you can see some snapshots of
large running systems that
do miss in their index.
But I just wanted to make you
aware of this mongostat
command which can be used at
the highest level of your
system to look at the overall
performance of your Mongo
installation.