All right, in this assignment
you're going to be
making the blog fast.
We've given you the code for
the blog in blog.py and
user.py in the views, and we've
also given you a data
set of 1,000 posts.
Very patriotic posts if
you're an American.
We have the Gettysburg Address
here, and we also have the US
Constitution and the Declaration
of Independence,
and the Bill of Rights.
And all these posts have 50
comments on them and they have
a bunch of tags on them.
Now, there's three pages
you need to make fast.
You have to make the blog
homepage fast, which gets the
most recent 10 blog posts
and prints them out.
You also need to make
this page fast.
This is a page that will search
for the most recent 10
posts for any given tag.
I just clicked on tempo, so now
all these posts are going
to have tempo in them.
If I click on refund, then
all these posts will
have refund in them.
And the final page you have to
make fast is the blog post
page, which is referenced
by permalink.
I'll show you the permalink's
right here.
And then, it brings up the post,
just one post along with
the comments in the post and
there are 50 comments.
You need to make this
page fast as well.
Now, you don't ever need to run
the blog project for this
homework assignment, but you
might want to because you
might want to see the data.
But another reason why you want
to take a look at it is
that the queries that we're
going to check you on are the
ones that are inside the code
that produced these pages.
And you don't need to rewrite
them from scratch you can just
look in the blog.py file and
see what the queries are.
Now, the idea is that these
queries should only scan as
many documents as they return.
So if it returns 10 documents
it should scan 10 documents.
If it's returning
one document, it
should return one document.
And our validate program.
What it does is it runs these
queries, it gets the explain
output, and it makes sure that
you've added the right
indexes, so that this is fast.
And that's the assignment
for this week.