OK.
And the answer is that in order
to make the queries
fast, the home page, the look
up by tag, and the permalink
page, you need three
different indexes.
So, to make the homepage fast,
you need an index on just the
date field because that's
what the homepage does.
And I did it date descending,
although you could do it date
ascending and it will reverse
it for that purpose.
To make the permalink page look
up fast, you just need a
index on permalink.
And to make it fast to look
up all the posts from a
particular tag and then order
them by date, you need a
compound index on
tags comma date.
And I made it descending on
date, reflecting that we're
going to show them
in reverse order.
Although, if you had made it
ascending on date, Mongo can
still manage to use that index
in the case where you're
sorting only by date and you're
looking up only one tag.
So that's the answer to
this problem, and I
hope you got it right.