All right.
So now, I'd like to show you
a large collection and the
effect that indexing can have
on the performance.
I'm going to start the Mongo
shell here, and I'm going to
use the school database and,
in particular, the students
collection.
Now, this is similar
to what we had in
the previous lessons.
I'll show you a document
from it.
You can see that we have here a
student ID for each record.
And there's, actually, also
an underscore ID which is
an BSON object ID.
And then there's an
array of scores.
And then there's a class
for each student.
Now, I have inserted 10 million
records into this
collection.
And this is a pretty
fast computer.
This is a recent iMac.
It actually has a solid state
drive and a bunch of memory.
And I've been playing with the
collection so it's probably
cached in memory.
So let's see how slow it is to
find something in the middle
of the collection or really
anywhere in the collection.
So let's go look at
db.students.find.
And let's look at
student ID 5.
Student ID5 should come
up pretty early in the
collection.
But because I'm using find
and not find one--
Sorry about that little typo.
Because I'm using find and not
find one, even though it's
going to find that record pretty
early in the process,
it took a couple of seconds
to find the object,
two or three seconds.
Now if I did a find one where
the database could be
satisfied by the first one it
fines, then you'll see, whoa,
that was really fast,
very fast.
And if I did a find one on the
record five million, five,
one, two, three, four,
five, six, that
should be fairly slow.
Because it has to go through the
entire collection or half
of the collection to find one.
And if I do a find, which is
always going to search the
entire collection because there
could be more than one,
we're going to get to the
slowest case again.
It has to go through the entire
collection to make sure
that there's not more
than one record with
student ID five million.
Let's say we wanted
to put an index on
this and make it faster.
We can do that.
This is how we're
going to do it.
So we're going to call the
ensure index command.
And we are going to give it the
fields, the key, that we
would like to index on.
And we're going to tell it
that we want to do it in
ascending order.
So let's go back through
this so you can see
each part of it.
db.students is the collection
name, ensure index, and then
asking to put the
index on Student
ID, and make it ascending.
So we're going to do
that in real time.
We're going to wait and see
how long it takes to index
those 10 million rows.
Now, right now the database is
actually going through and
it's looking at every single
row, and it's building an
index for every single row.
So this could take a
couple of minutes.
We're going to just skip forward
and wait in the video
and get to the end of it.
So you're not having
to wait for it.
OK, some time has elapsed
now, and the
index has been created.
Overall, it took about
two or three minutes
to create that index.
So let's see how much faster
it is to query the database
now that the index is created.
So we're going to the
same find we did
before, same find command.
We're going to look for
a document with
student ID five million.
We're going to pretty
print it.
And we expect this to hit the
index because student ID was
the key in the index.
So let's just run that.
Wow, that was fast.
So we can see it came
back immediately.
Before we had the index, it took
up to five or six seconds
to do this query.
But now, that we have an
index, it's immediate.
And you can see that if we call
it with seven million,
also extremely fast.
But if we make a query that
can't be index, like something
that asks for everything
with class of--
Well, we could say class of
seven million, there isn't any
class with seven million.
But that won't matter, because
it can't know that.
And you can see, it's going to
take a long time to tell us
there's nothing.
So indexes are really important
in terms of the
performance we get from
the database.
Let's look at that in ensure
index command again.
So in that ensure index command,
we called it with
student ID colon one.
Now, if we wanted to include
the class, we could've
included it like this.
And in this case, it's a
compound index which is going
to be made up of student
ID comma class.
And I've decided to make the
student ID ascending and the
class descending.
So ascending versus
descending.
So it doesn't make much of a
difference when you're searching.
But it makes a big difference
when you're sorting.
Because if the database is going
to use the index for the
sort, then it needs to be
in the right order.
Now, if we had other sub parts
of this document we wanted to
index, we could continue.
We could make it a three part
index if we wanted.
Of course, it takes more space
and a little bit longer to
build it when you do rights.
Now, in terms of using the
index, if I had an index on a
student ID comma class and I
specified just the class,
well, it couldn't use the index
because it needs to be a
left subset of the field.
If I specified student ID and
class, I could use the index.
And if I specified just
student ID, I
could use that index.
OK, let's do a quiz.
So please provide the Mongo
shell command to add an index
to a collection named students
having the index key be class
comma student name.
Now, this is very similar to
what I just showed you.
But I just wanted to get you
into the practice of typing
these ensure index commands so
that you are used to doing it
in the shell.