Now I'd like to show you how
you find out what indexes
exist in your database.
Now, if I call
db.system.indexes.find, I will
find all the indexes that are
in this database, and I'm in
the school database right now.
And if I do that, you can see
that there's a bunch of
collections I haven't really
talked about, because they're
not part of this lesson.
But you can see the one right
here, this is the one that's
most interesting here, which
is that there's an index on
student ID right here in the
students collection.
And this index is called
studentID_1.
And this is the index that
we built together in the
preceding lesson.
You can also see all the indexes
on _ID, because every
collection by default
has index on _ID.
Now, if we want to see more
detail about the index for a
particular collection, we can
call db.students.getindexes.
Now I'm naming the collection,
and I'm going to get all the
indexes on it.
And if I do that, I find out
that there are two indexes on
this collection.
One of them is the one that
we built over here.
It's a student ID index.
And the other one is
the one on _ID.
Now, although we didn't talk
about it, and I'm not going to
go over it again, so I'll just
mention it real quickly.
But if you want to drop an
index, you can do that by
calling drop index and naming
it exactly the way you named
it when you created it.
So if I want to kill the index
that we created together, then
I can do it just like this.
I want to drop that index, and
that'll drop the index out of
the system.
I named it wrong.
Excuse me, one second.
Little typo there.
And there it was.
Says there was an index, there
was two indexes, and now
there's one.
And if I go back, and I look
in the indexes now, you can
see it's missing.
And if I do that find command
again that I did before, I'm
going to go back and find it.
Then I should see that it is
once again slow, because the
index is not there.
You can see it's kind of slow.
So again, you can find all the
indexes for a collection, for
a database using this
system.indexes.find.
Now if I use a different
database, for instance if I
use a test database and do the
same command, then I will see
a bunch of different indexes.
These are a bunch of different
collections that I've created,
and I was just playing around.
Let's see, there's a lot
of indexes on those.
And that's the way you discover
what indexes exist
inside the database, and
inside the collection.