We've learned about the Explain
command, which is how
we figure out what the
database is doing
when it does a query.
But what does the database do
to figure out which index it
should use?
Let's say you have a collection
with three
different indexes on it-- an
index on A, an index on B, and
an index on C. We'll call that
query plan one, query plan
two, and query plan three.
And you specify A, B, and
C, all three of them,
when you do a query.
Now, the database can use this
index, or it could use this
index, or it could
use this index.
It can't use up all three.
It can only use one of them.
What it does the first time we
do this query, it'll run those
three query plans in parallel.
And time will start, and these
query plans are running.
And as soon as one completes,
then Mongo will return the
answer to the query and memorize
that it is in fact
query plan two, which uses
index B. That's going to
satisfy those types
of queries.
And this is kind of cool because
it's basically running
experiments on your actual data
to figure out which index
it should use.
And you don't have to do
anything to make this happen,
it just happens behind
the scenes.
But I just wanted you to
understand that broadly.
And every hundred or so queries
it will forget what it
knows, and it will run another
experiment if it has to, to
choose between those
indexes again.
Just to review, if you have
a compound index on--
I'm going to do it differently
this time--
on D, C, B, A in that order--
if you have a compound index,
then in order for the database
to use this index, you have to
specify some left subset of
these items.
So if you specify just D,
it can use the index.
If you specify D and
C, it can use it.
If you specify D and B, it can
use it but it only really uses
the D part.
If you specify C and B, it
cannot use it because it
didn't have the D
part included.
And this is true whether or not
it's using it to do a sort
or whether or not it's using
it to do a find.
And although I didn't say this
explicitly, you should realize
of course that find, findOne,
update, and remove can all
benefit from indexes.
OK, let's do a quick quiz.
This should be kind
of review for you.
Given the collection foo with
the following index, A, B, and
C, which of the following
queries will use the index?
And you can see the
four choices here.
Check all that apply.