And the answer is, if there's
an index on a, and b, and c,
then the first one can't because
it's b and c that's
specified and the a
is not included.
The second one can, because
a is specified.
The third one can't use it to
satisfy the find because c is
what's specified in the criteria
and that's not a
leftmost set of this index, but
it can use it to satisfy
the sort, right here.
Because it has these items
in sorted order, a, b.
Now, the last one looks similar
to the third one and
that's looking for c, which of
course, it can't use index to
search on, and then it sorts
on a minus one b.
Now, the database can't use the
index because this sort
order is not the same as the
index that's sorted.
So, the index is sorted in a
ascending, b ascending, we've
asked for a descending,
b ascending, and so
it can't use it.
Now, interestingly enough, if we
had specified just a minus
one, even though the index is
sorted on abc, it knows that
it could just reverse it and
get a minus one out of it.
And if you try to do that, if
you create a situation like
this, and you do the explain
command, you'll see that
refers to a reversed version of
a, b, and c, which you can
use to satisfy a query like
this, if only a is specified
in descending order.
Just a little interesting
tidbit.
All right.