If you want to tell MongoDB
exactly what index to use, you
can do that using
a hint command.
Normally, Mongo makes it's own
decisions of what index to use
based on analysis it's done of
the various query plans, but
you can tell it what to use.
And the way the hint command
works is, in the shell, you
would append it to the
end of the query.
And you'd say hint, and then
you'd give a JSON document
that specifies what
index you want.
So this would be--
I want the a ascending index--
the comp index is a ascending,
b ascending,
and let's say c ascending.
Use that index, please.
And if you want the database
to use no index, and to use
the cursor that goes through
every single document in the
collection, you can hint that
you want it to use what's
called the natural index.
And that is specified with
$natural:1, ascending.
That's my curly brace,
sorry about that.
Now, let's see what that looks
like in the shell.
I have the foo collection again
in the test database.
It's got 10,000 documents
in it.
Every one of them has
an a, b, and c key.
And you can see the pattern of
the data here, where a is
zero, b is zero, c is zero.
I've created some
indexes already.
Now I'm going to find
those for you.
And here they are.
You can see there's an index on
just a, there's an index on
just b, and there's an
index on just c.
There's also an index on d.
And there are no documents
with d in it,
interestingly enough.
So now let's do a find.
And if we just use a go
find and we don't
give any hint command--
I'll do that first.
And this query that I'm using
prints out one document.
Let's explain that query.
We can see that it uses
the BtreeCursor a.
So it uses the a index--
the index on just a.
But if we don't like that, we
can tell it to, let's say, use
no index, and then it will use
the basic cursor, and inspect
every document.
It inspects 10,000 documents--
kind of slow.
Or we can say, we really want
it to use the c index, which
is also a find index.
And if we do that, it'll
find one object.
Again, it's really fast because
those are all really
equally good indexes for
this particular query.
So we use the c index
with those bounds.
What if I tell to use
it the d index?
Now, d index doesn't have any
documents that satisfy the
criteria, so I'm going
to do that.
I'm going to say hint, let's
use the d index, please.
Let's find it using
the d index.
If I do that, then I find it
uses the d index and it still
returns the document.
And what if I do a new
ensureIndex command and I say,
give me an index on e, but let's
make that one sparse?
So I'm going to say, create
an index on e
and make that sparse.
It's actually going to take a
little bit of time because it
has to go through all
10,000 documents.
It did that, and now I'm going
to hint on e, say I want you
to use the e index to
satisfy this query.
Oh, look at that.
I actually get the
wrong answer.
All a sudden, I've
got no document.
If I hadn't given any hint,
I get one document.
But if I hint on the e index--
I mean, you could argue whether
that's the wrong
answer or not.
But the reason is because the
e index is sparse, and it
doesn't have any entries in
it for documents where
there is no e key.
And if you recall, none of these
documents have an e key.
There's not a single e key in
any of these documents, so it
returns nothing, interestingly
enough.
OK.
Now it is time for a quiz.
Here's the quiz.
Given the following data
in a collection--
and we have this people
collection with three
documents--
name Andrew, title Jester, name
Dwight, title CEO, and
the third document just
has the name John.
In the following indexes--
so you can see the indexes that
are on the collection--
which query below will return
the most documents?
And I won't go through them
verbally, because you can read
them on the screen.