OK.
Let's move on to the
Mongo shell.
Mongo shell is an interactive
JavaScript interpreter that
has built-in functionality for
connecting to and manipulating
data in a MongoDB database.
Assuming that you have a MongoD
server already running
on this machine, to connect to
it from the shell, it suffices
simply to say "Mongo".
When the shell starts up, it
prints out a banner that
includes the shell's version
number as well as the name of
the database that you're
connected to.
I recommend getting into the
habit of reading these pieces
of information.
They're useful for detecting
unexpected connections or
version skew between
servers and shells.
Generally speaking, it should be
possible to use any version
of the shell with any version
of the server, but
occasionally we add new features
either to the shell
or to the server, which might
require the agreement
inversions between
the two pieces.
So it's a best practice
to try to keep
these versions in sync.
As for the name of the database,
it's all too easy to
type the wrong database name in
or the wrong host name in,
in fact, and connect
to someplace
that you didn't expect.
So, just as a sanity
check, I recommend
reading these banners.
As I mentioned, the Mongo
shell is an interactive
JavaScript interpreter.
This means that you can key in
fragments of JavaScript and
have them interpreted or
evaluated immediately.
For example, I can write a
simple loop, and when I press
Enter, this fragmented
JavaScript will be submitted
to a JavaScript runtime,
evaluated, and its output will
be printed to the screen.
The choice of JavaScript as an
interaction language was made
some years ago, and it was
motivated by a desire to have
a language that was easy enough
for people to use,
common enough that there are
references for it out there,
and relatively convenient
for simple sorts
of scripting purposes.
Now, to make life easy, the
shell has some functions that
make retrieving and editing
previous input relatively
straightforward.
For example, if I want to get
the previous line of input, I
can hit the Up arrow and I can
move around, for example, with
the arrow keys and change the
input to the JavaScript shell
to comprise a different
program.
Here, I've produce different
output than the
previous time around.
The editing keys that the shell
supports are designed to
be similar to those of say, the
Bash shell, which comes
along with many Linux
distributions.
The keystrokes that are
available there are modeled
after the Emacs Editor.
So, for example, if I hit the
Up arrow to get a previous
line of input, I can go to the
beginning of the line with
Control-A, probably also with
the Home and End keys, if you
have those on your keyboard.
I can move around with either
the arrow keys or with the
Bash or Emacs customary keys,
Control-F, Control-B. I can
move to the end of the line with
Control-E, or perhaps the
End key, and now I've input yet
a third program for the
shell to execute.
So far, of course, I haven't
actually connected to the
database, I'm just evaluating
fragments of JavaScript.
Within this course, our use of
JavaScript is going to be
relatively simple, so if you
happen not to know the
language very well, I hope what
I've shown you so far is
at least recognizable.
The syntax of the languages is
intentionally modeled after
languages such as C or Java,
and most people find
JavaScript relatively
easy to pick up.
If you happen to be a JavaScript
expert and you
catch me doing things that
happen not to be stylistically
desirable JavaScript, I
apologize in advance.
In addition to some of the
command editing features that
the shell has, we also have a
variety of built in helpers.
For example, if you type in
"help", you can see a list of
topics that you can visit.
For example, I can say "help
keys" to see some information
about the key bindings
that are available.
You might familiarize yourself
with some of the other Help at
your leisure.
Further, the shell has
the ability to
complete tokens of input.
For instance, having typed in
the beginning of this loop, if
I want to have the shell
automatically complete a token
that starts with P-R-I, can
type "pri" and then a tab.
And the shell complete out, as
far as it can, provided that
pri uniquely identifies
[? sums ?] prefix of tokens
that exist in the JavaScript
runtime.
What I mean by that is that if
pri does not identify any
token that happens to be defined
in JavaScript yet,
then it won't have completed
anything.
However, I happen to know that
there's a function called
Print in the JavaScript runtime,
and so by typing
"pri" followed by a Tab,
the shell will complete
that token for me.
These sorts of things are
fairly convenient for
interacting with the
Mongo shell.
Now, in case you haven't
familiarized yourself with
JavaScript before, I want to
tell you a few things about
the syntax that will
be relevant.
In JavaScript, variables are
assigned more or less the way
that you might expect.
X = 1 assigns the variable
x to be "1".
Y = abc assigns the variable
y to the string "abc".
And z = left curly brace, the
letter a:1 assigns the
variable z to be a JavaScript
object consisting of the
property named "a" corresponding
value "1".
This is analogous to building
something like a dictionary or
a hash table or a map in
some other languages.
I can refer to the properties of
a variable in JavaScript in
one of two .
If I say "z.a", I will retrieve
the property of the
variable z whose name "a",
in this case, 1.
Alternatively, I can say "z"
followed by a square bracket
followed by the name of the
property that I seek as a
string followed by a closing
square bracket.
These two have similar purposes
but have some
differences as well.
In particular, the dot notation,
z.a, does not permit
a variable property look up.
The a is treated as a literal
even though the z is treated
as a variable.
By contrast, if I assigned the
variable w to be the string a,
then I can look up using the
square bracket syntax a
property inside the object z
whose value comes from a
variable at run time.
In this case, looking up the
property in z whose name is
the value of the variable w.
So these two syntaxes, the dot
notation and the square
bracket notation, serve slightly
different purposes in
JavaScript.
Superficially, the dot notation
is typically thought
of as being a look up properties
or methods or
instance variables within an
object, whereas the square
bracket notation treats the
object more as a piece of
data, like a dictionary, and
looks up corresponding
associations between
keys and values.
None of these things are
strictly speaking how the
JavaScript language talks
about itself, but that's
particularly important
for the purposes of
understanding the shell.
In any case, this has been a
brief overview of the shell
and the JavaScript language.
We'll be seeing some more
JavaScript as we go through
the rest of this week.
OK.
Let's have a quiz.
What is the following fragment
of JavaScript output?
There are four lines here.
The first of them assigns the
variable x to the object whose
property, a, has the value 1.
The second one assigns the
variable y to the value that's
the string, a.
Given that, what do these
last two lines do?
Place the output in
the Output box.