Let's learn a little bit more
about inequality comparisons
in the query language.
We've already seen some
examples where we do
inequality queries on
numeric values.
The inequality operators can
also be applied for string
valued comparisons.
Let's add a couple more
documents to the people
collection so that we
can see things in a
little bit clearer view.
db.people now has a half dozen
or so documents in it, every
one of which has a name.
The inequality comparison--
$ gt, $ lt, and so forth--
can be applied to strings just
as they can be to numbers.
The query on the screen
retrieves all documents from
the people collection where
the name field is
lexicographically less than
the capital letter D.
And then likewise, you can add
some more constraints such as
lexicographically greater than
the letter B. Note that the
string Bob is lexicographically
greater than
the letter B simply because
it's longer.
A couple of notes about
locales and
locale-aware sorting.
Right now MongoDB has exactly
zero knowledge of locales.
In effect, the comparisons that
we perform for $ less
than, $ greater than and so
forth are going to sort
according to the total
ordering of
the UTF-8 code units.
That is to say, according to a
lexicographic sorting of the
bytes in the UTF-8
representation of the string.
This happens to be
correct only in
the POSIX or C locales.
That is to say, MongoDB compares
and sorts things in a
Ascii-betically correct
fashion.
If it so happens that there's
a locale for which sorting
things in UTF-8 byte order
happens to be correct, then
MongoDB happens to agree
with that as well.
A future release of MongoDB is
likely to have better support
for locale-aware sorting,
collation, and so forth.
Further, it's important to
understand that MongoDB is, in
fact, a schema-less database.
That is to say, different
documents within the same
collection might have different
value types for the
same field.
This isn't a recommended
pattern, but
nevertheless it's possible.
For example, if I insert into
the people collection a
document where the field name
has as its corresponding value
the number 42, the database
will perfectly
happily store that.
I now have eight or so documents
with string values
for the field name and one
document with a numeric value
for the field name.
All comparison operations in
MongoDB are strongly typed and
dynamically typed too.
That is to say, if I perform
the inequality comparison
that's at the bottom of my
terminal window, I'll only see
documents where the name field
is a string that's less than
the capital letter D and greater
than the capital
letter B. I will not see any
documents where the field name
has the numeric value 42, or
any other numeric value.
That is to say, these sorts
of comparisons, range type
comparisons, do not
span data types.
So if you happen to take
advantage of MongoDB's
polymorphism by storing
different data types for the
same fields--
which is not a recommended
pattern, by the way--
but if you should happen to take
advantage of it, you need
to understand that comparisons
of this sort will not cross
the data type boundaries.
In effect, if you want to query
for documents where the
name is in a certain
lexicographic range of strings
or in a certain numeric range of
numbers, you'll need to use
a more complicated query
syntax, which we'll be
visiting in a subsequent
section.
Let's have a quiz.
Which of the following will find
all users with a username
between F and Q?