OK.
Let's start working with
documents that are slightly
more complicated in structure.
First, let's create a document
that has an embedded array
inside it somewhere.
For example, I've now got two
documents in a collection
called accounts, one for George
and one for Howard.
And George has an embedded
array for favorites.
And the array contains
the strings
ice cream and pretzels.
Whereas Howard has an embedded
array for favorites containing
pretzels and beer.
Suppose I wanted to query for
all documents where the
favorites array contained
pretzels.
As it happens, MongoDB, in its
query operations, is somewhat
polymorphic.
In particular, if I write in the
following query then you
can think of the execution
of this query as
happening as follows--
for every document in the
accounts collection find the
field called favorites.
If the field called favorites
has a string value and the
string value equals pretzels,
then the document matches and
should be returned
from this query.
If the document has a field
called favorites and the value
of the field favorites is an
array, then check inside that
array to see if any of the
elements in the array is a
string that's equal to
the string pretzels.
In which case, the
document matches.
That is to say, our matching is
polymorphic over arrays and
non-array type values.
So when I hit enter, you will
see querying for pretzels
returns both documents.
By contrast, querying for beer
returns only Howard.
This is a very common idiom in
MongoDB to embed an array of
things like strings or IDs and
to query in exactly this
fashion for any document that
has a particular element
inside of a particular array.
We do this automatically.
Now an important thing to
understand is that there's no
generalized recursion
going on here.
The matching is more or
less exactly as I just
described to you.
If the field favorites has as
its corresponding value an
array that contains nested
content within it, none of
those nested content is going to
match the string pretzel or
the string beer.
are
The only level of depth that
you might say we look at is
the top level within the array
that's the value of favorites.
We don't recurse into any
kind of arbitrary depth.
There is no operation in MongoDB
for recursing to find
a particular field with a
particular value at an
arbitrary depth in
the document.
We will look only at the fields
that you specify or if
the corresponding value of the
field is an array at the top
level elements of the array
that's the value of the field
that you specify.
Nevertheless, this
is a very common
idiom to use in MongoDB.
Of course, this matching can be
combined with other sorts
of matching, for example
favorites is beer and name
greater than H or favorites
includes pretzels and name is
greater than H. And so it
combines with other query
operators or operators on other
fields in a hopefully
intuitive fashion.
Did you get that?
OK, let's have a quiz.
Which of the following four
documents would be returned by
this query?
db.product.find tag
colon shiny.
ID 42 name Whizzy Wiz-o-matic
tags awesome shiny green.
ID 704 name Fooey Foo-o-tron
tags blue mediocre.
ID 1040 name Snappy Snap-o-lux
tags shiny.
ID 12345 [? Quaxinator ?]
tags the empty array.