Let's go a little bit further
into our examination of
querying for arrays by finding
out about one more operator
that's specific to looking
at array contents.
Just as a reminder, we have the
following in our accounts
collection.
Let's embellish it slightly
by adding some more data.
At this point, we have a handful
of accounts containing
various combinations
of favorites.
Again, as a reminder, if it's
a little hard to read these
things because they're longer
than the width of the
terminal, you can tack dot
pretty on to the Find
operation in order to get them
to print out in a slightly
more indented format.
So we have a variety of
combinations of favorites.
Suppose you wanted to query for
all those documents that
have both pretzels and beer
in the favorites array.
Well, there's an operator
for that.
The $all operator matches any
document that has all of the
specified elements inside the
array in the field that you're
looking at.
And the operand to the $all
operator is a array.
And the elements inside that
array can occur in any order
in the corresponding field
in the documents.
So for example, Howard has
favorites pretzels comma beer
in that order.
But Irving has favorites beer
comma pretzels comma cheese in
that order.
Another way of putting it is
that the operand on the
right-hand side of the $all in
the query has to be a subset--
possibly not a strict subset,
possibly equal to the set--
of the things that are the
values in the field that's
queried for in the Find.
That is to say, Favorites has
to contain beer and pretzels
in any order and may contain
some other things.
Finally, there's one more
operator that has to do
tangentially with arrays.
Although it's not specifically
about querying inside of
arrays, although you can use it
with the feature that Mongo
has to look into arrays.
Specifically, just like in SQL,
Mongo's query language
has an operator $in, which takes
a list of strings and
returns only those documents
where the corresponding
field-- in this case, Name--
has a value that's either
Howard or John.
That is to say, it's an
enumeration of all the values
that you're looking for
for the given field.
This feature composes, in a
hopefully intuitive fashion,
with the examination inside
of arrays that you've just
learned that MongoDB does.
So for example, if I look for
favorites $in beer or ice
cream, I should find any
document having a Favorites
field that contains beer
or contains ice cream.
And that appears to
specify everybody.
OK, let's have a quiz.
Which of the following documents
matches this query?
db.users.find, friends, $all
of Joe, Bob, favorites $in
running, pickles.