So let's learn a little bit
more about what's going on
behind the scenes when
you execute a query.
So far, we've been executing
queries and seeing results
printed out to the screen.
In fact, this is a convenient
behavior for an interactive
shell like the Mongo shell.
But what's actually going on
when you execute a query such
as db.people.find, and press
Enter, is that a cursor is
being constructed and returned
in the shell.
The shell is configured to print
out cursors by iterating
through all of the elements that
are retrieved from the
cursor and printing out
those elements.
But you can hold on to a cursor
just as you could hold
on to any other value in the
programming language.
Now, in order to avoid printing
out the result of
this assignment, which is going
to be the cursor, I'm
going to tack on something
completely meaningless, like
this null value.
At this point, "cur" is
a variable that's
holding onto a cursor.
Cursor objects have a
variety of methods.
For example, the hasNext method
returns "true" so long
as there's another document
to visit on this cursor.
And the next method returns
the next document to be
visited on this cursor.
And so by holding on to cursor
objects and manipulating them
directly with hasNext and next
methods, you can control the
manner in which you
step through
the sequence of documents.
This is not something you tend
to do very much from the
shell, though you can.
Instead, it's a much more common
operation to do in a
programming language, such
as something like Python.
You can, for instance,
programmatically step through
all of the documents to be
visited, and that while loop
that's close to the bottom of
my terminal window, is, in
effect, the default behavior
of the shell when it's
printing out a cursor object--
except that the shell, by
default, batches up the result
documents into groups of about
20 so that it doesn't
obliterate your terminal by
printing infinitely many
documents if you have very
large query results.
But there are some more methods
that you can use to
modify the behavior
of a cursor.
I'll establish a new cursor,
again, by going
back up in my history.
So long as you haven't actually
stepped through the
cursor or checked to see if
there are any documents left,
you can impose limits.
For instance, the limit method
will instruct the server to
return only that many documents
for this cursor.
Limit also returns the cursor,
and so in order to avoid
printing things out at this
point, I'm going to tack on
this mysterious null.
At this point, I'm modifying the
query that's going to be
sent over to the database
server.
Until I actually retrieve some
documents or check to see if
there any documents left on this
cursor, no transmission
has been made to the database
and no query has been executed
yet on the database.
If I actually do go ahead and
start retrieving documents
from the database, the query is
sent over with the Limit as
part of the transmission
to the database.
And so you see, having tacked
a limit on to this cursor, I
only get five documents back
from the database even though
there are approximately 8
documents in this collection.
There are a couple more methods
that you can tack on
to cursors.
The Sort method instructs the
database to return documents
in an order that's specified by
the argument to the sort.
For instance, if I want my
documents to come back in
reverse order by name--
that's reverse lexicographical
order, by name--
I can say name:-1 as an
argument to the sort.
This cursor modifier,
like the limit
modifier, returns the cursor.
And so in order to avoid eagerly
printing out the
results of this query,
I'm going to
tack on the null again.
At this point, if I iterate
through the result documents
using this WHILE loop, I should
see my results in
reverse order by name.
And indeed, I get them in
reverse order by name,
remembering, again, that the
sorting that we perform is
lexicographical according to
the byte encoding of UTF-8
representation of the strings,
which is to say, in effect,
Ascii ordering.
And finally, the integer
is presented last.
You can put these two things
together, Limit and Sort, more
or less in the way that
you might expect.
I'll establish a cursor
again and tack on both
a Sort and a Limit.
Let's say three.
Because these cursor modifiers,
Sort and Limit,
return the modified cursor, it's
possible to chain them
together in this fashion.
And now, if I step through the
documents on this cursor, I
should see them sorted in
reverse lexicographical order,
and I should only see
three of them.
And indeed, there they are.
It's important to understand
that the Sort method and the
Limit method modify the
information that's transmitted
over to the database.
I can't apply these methods to
a cursor after having begun
retrieving documents from the
database or even checking
whether the cursor has next.
This is because the Sort and the
Limit need to actually be
processed inside the
database engine.
They're not processed by
ordering the documents in
memory in the client, they're
processed by server-side
ordering and limiting.
There's one more important
method that you need to know
about that modifies cursors,
and that's called Skip.
Just like sort and limit, it
modifies a cursor and returns
the modified cursor.
And so if I set up a new cursor
and tack on a Sort, and
a Limit, and a Skip, then the
instructions are sent over to
the database to retrieve
documents from the people
collection, ordered in reverse
lexicographic order by name,
skipping over the first two
that are visited in that
ordering, and showing the only
three documents after the
first two are skipped.
And there we are--
Fred, Edgar, Dave.
It's important to understand
that Sort and Limit and Skip,
which are quite analogous to the
Order by Limit and Skip in
SQL, are processed in
the same order--
first the Sort, then the Skip,
then the Limit in the server.
They're not processed
in the client.
Despite the fact that the method
calls appear to be
modifying a client-side object,
they're actually
modifying the instructions
that get
sent over to the database.
OK.
If you got all that,
let's have a quiz.
Remember the "scores" collection
that we came up
with before--
having a student number, a type
field, and a score value.
Write a query that retrieves
exam documents--
that is to say, documents where
the type is "exam"--
sorted by score in descending
order, skipping the first 50,
and showing only the next 20
that occur after the first 50.