OK.
As I mentioned, the Update
method in the JavaScript shell
actually performs
four operations.
We've seen three
of them so far.
It can do a wholesale
replacement of a document, it
can manipulate individual fields
within a document, it
can perform an upsert
operation--
which is either an update or
an insert if no document
already exists that matches
the specified criteria--
and finally, it can update
multiple documents.
I've been intentionally sneaky
and always performing updates
specifying a criteria that
matches exactly one document
or zero documents in a
collection so far.
But, in fact, the update
operator can affect more than
one document at a time.
So again, to look at the People
collection, we have a
variety of people with
various names.
If I wanted to give every person
some new field, I can.
The empty document acts as a
selector which matches every
document in the collection.
This is also true for Find.
And, for instance, I might
want to set a new field.
Maybe everyone here
is a doctor.
Now, an important difference
between MongoDB and relational
databases is that by default,
even if the first argument to
update is a query specification
that would match
every document, the Update
method only actually affects a
single document, namely,
whichever one happens to be
the first one that it finds.
If I want the update method to
affect all documents in the
collection, I have to
supply an option.
And from the JavaScript
shell, that option is
called "multi" "true".
If I do not supply the Multi
option to the Update method,
then the Update method will
affect just one document.
In fact, which document
it effects is somewhat
underdefined.
By specifying multi:true, then
this update will traverse
every document in
the collection
and add a new field.
And now, everyone has a title.
It's important to understand
this detail.
The default behavior of an
updates query in SQL is to
update every record the matches
the where clause, or
every record in the table if no
where clause is specified.
The default behavior to update
in MongoDB is to update just
one document in the
collection.
You must specify an extra
argument in the JavaScript
shell in order to update
multiple documents in a
collection.
Some of our drivers for
different programming
languages actually split this up
into two separate methods.
One perhaps called Update and
the other called Multi Update.
In the JavaScript shell,
you simply have to
add an extra argument.
Now, let me say something
further about the actual
semantics of what happens when
you perform a multi-document
write operation such
as a Multi Update.
Inside of MongoDB, there's
a single thread for each
operation that's
being executed.
So, for instance, this Update
operation will happen
sequentially inside of
a single thread.
However, every write operation
that affects more than one
document is carefully coded in
a cooperative multitasking
fashion to occasionally yield
control to allow other
operations to affect
the same data set.
In particular, the Multi Update
that you see on the
screen affected approximately
10 documents.
It would be possible if there
were other write operations
coming into the system for that
specific update operation
to affect, say, three documents,
and then pause to
allow other operations to
proceed, and then pick up
again, affect our more
documents, and then pause, to
allow other operations to
proceed, and then, finally, to
finish out the last three
remaining documents.
We call this pausing yielding
because in point of fact,
there's a shared resource that
different write operations
share, which we use to sequence
write operations.
It's basically a kind
of Mutex Lock.
Now, what's important to
understand about the
concurrency consequences of what
I'm describing is that
write operations, even if they
affect multiple documents, are
not isolated transactions.
Instead, they might affect an
arbitrary number of documents,
then yield, allow other readers
or writers to operate,
and then pick up again to affect
some more documents.
In general, it's not possible
to have an isolated write
operation that affects multiple
documents inside of MongoDB.
However, we do guarantee that
an individual document
manipulation is always atomic
with respect to any concurrent
readers or writers.
That is to say if you send an
update to the system that will
affect 10 documents, then
whenever that update operation
is affecting any individual
document, no reader or writer
operation in the system will see
the document half updated.
This atomicity guarantee allows
you to build things on
top of MongoDB.
For example, if it were strictly
necessary for your
application to have some kind of
isolation between different
threads, you could, for
instance, construct a locking
tight mechanism, treating a
designated document in the
database as a shared resource
that writer operations needed
to acquire--
perhaps by updating it--
before they performed
any operation on
the ordinary data.
And indeed, this actually turns
out to be a trick that
goes on inside of sharding
architecture.
In any case, from a semantic
point of view, a Multi Update
operation is simply
an update that
affects multiple documents.
From a concurrency perspective,
it's important to
remember that MongoDB does not
offer isolated transactions
while these updates
are happening.
OK.
Let's have a quiz.
Recall the schema of the
"scores" collection.
Documents have an _id, of
course, a student number, a
type field, and a score field.
How would you give every record
whose score was less
than 70 an extra 20 points?