OK.
We've covered most of the
operations that you can
perform through Insert,
Find, Update.
Let's move on to deleting
documents from the database.
This is actually relatively
simple.
You have essentially
three options.
First, each collection has
a method called Remove.
And Remove works very
much like Find.
It takes an optional first
argument which specifies what
documents to remove.
That argument has exactly the
same semantics as the first
argument to Find.
If you specify no argument, then
all the documents in the
collection will be removed
one by one.
If I specify an argument-- for
example, name colon Alice--
then the Alice document
gets removed.
Or I could give a range, name
greater than the capital
letter M, in which case,
say, William is
removed, as well as Thompson.
Further, as mentioned, if no
argument is specified to
remove, then the documents are
removed from the collection
one by one until the
collection has
no documents left.
Next, if you want to remove
all documents in a single
pass, in a somewhat more
efficient manner even if the
collection is very large, you
can drop a collection.
The difference between dropping
a collection and
removing all the documents in
the collection is really
mostly an implementation
detail.
Removing all the documents in
the collection requires a
one-by-one update of internal
state for each document that
happens to exist in
the collection.
Whereas dropping the collection
requires freeing up
some much larger data structures
inside of the
database's data files.
Which, although still
proportional to the size of
the collection in terms of the
number of documents, is going
to have constant factors that
will make dropping the
collection vastly faster than
removing documents from the
collection one by one until
the collection is empty.
However, collections can
have some metadata
associated with them--
for instance, indexes--
which get discarded when the
collection is dropped but
which remain in existence when
a collection has all of its
documents removed.
If you have an unusual situation
where you need to be
frequently getting rid of all
of the contents of your
collection, the most efficient
way to do so would be to drop
the collection and then
immediately recreate the
indexes that ought to exist
on that collection.
As a further detail, Remove,
just like a multi-document
update, can affect an arbitrary
number of documents,
namely whichever documents
happen to match the first
argument to the Remove.
Just like a multi-update,
multi-document remove
operations are not atomic
isolated transactions with
respect to other readers
or writers.
That is to say, if you happen
to remove, say, 10 documents
from a collection, a concurrent
read or write
operation might see the state
of that collection halfway
through that Remove operation.
That is, after five of the
documents have been removed.
You'll need to take some
measures of your own if you
really need to isolate readers
and writers from
each other in MongoDB.
However, as mentioned in the
case with Update, each
individual document removal is
atomic with respect to a
concurrent reader or writer.
No client will see a document
half removed.
Let's have a quiz about
deleting documents.
Recall again the schema of
the scores collection.
There's an _id, a Student field,
a Type field, and a
Score field.
How would you delete every
record whose score
was less than 60?