This is Andrew Erlichson
here again.
I'm going to take you through
the same CRUD operations that
Richard showed you.
But I'm going to show them to
you using Python and PyMongo,
and then get you ready for your
homework for this week,
which is starting to build
that blog project that we
talked about earlier.
So just to review real quickly
what we're going to do here.
You've just gone through in the
Mongo shell and learned to
create, read, update, and delete
operators from Mongo.
The Mongo shell talks
BSON to MongoD.
And now we're going to
do the same thing in
Python using PyMongo.
PyMongo also talks by
BSON to MongoD.
And we're going to write
some code here.
So to get started with that, the
first thing we have to do
is get some data into
the database.
This is something that already
exists in your world because
you've been watching the
lectures linearly.
But I don't have it on my
computer, so I'm going to do
it real fast.
So this is a JavaScript program
that I'm going to pipe
into the Mongo shell.
It's just going to create 100
students and create three
different types of assessments
for them, example, homework,
and quiz, and randomly
assign them some
scores insert them in.
Let's do that together.
I'll run Mongo and redirect
standard into the file.
This is something that is
probably pretty familiar to
anyone in the Mac
or Unix world.
So we'll do that.
And we get back the
standard out.
It connected to the 2.2 version
of the database,
switched to the school database,
and then said
goodbye to us.
Let's confirm the data
is in there.
And let's use school, and
then do db.scores.find.
And there there's
data right here.
And then we'll pretty
print it.
We can see here it is.
Just a bunch of students, and
each of the students has a
different type of grade, a
homework grade, an exam grade.
These are some random numbers.
And we let the driver assign
IDs for the objects.
And these are just BSON object
IDs in each of these.
So let's get started.
We're going to show you a small
file that I wrote to do
Find and Find One.
Let's start with the
Find One code.
This is the top of the file.
Using _Find.py.
I know a lot of folks have
requested that we give you the
code that we're using in the
lessons, and I will try to do
that this week.
So we start by importing
PyMongo, importing sys, do
some error reporting, getting a
connection to the database,
local host.
Safe equals True, so that the
calls get less error on our
behalf and gives us any errors
that occur during our queries.
We connect to the school
database, and then to the
scores collection right here.
And then this is the
Find One code.
We'll go back to Find
code in a second.
The Find One code, it
sets up a query.
It sets up a dictionary which
student ID being 10.
Some things to note on this.
One is that 10 has no decimal
point after it because we want
it to be an integer in Python.
The second is that student
ID is in single quotes.
Now that would not need to be
the case in the Mongo shell.
It would be optional.
But in Python it is
not optional.
A string literal that
is the key to a
dictionary must be in quotes.
So we put in quotes.
Then we're going to
get the document.
We're going to assign the result
to this variable doc.
We're going to call Scores--
which is a handle to
the collection--
.Find_one(query).
Things to note here is that the
function to get a single
document from the database using
Find One is find_one.
If you recall on the Mongo
shell, it was findOne, all one
word, uppercase on the O. That's
one of the pluses and
minuses to the drivers
inside Mongo.
The plus is that they are
written using local
conventions for each language.
So if it's typical to use
underscores in a language,
then that's the way the driver
is written so it seems
familiar to the people who
know the language well.
On the minus side, the
drivers vary a bit.
So you might need to look in the
API documentation to learn
how to do any particular thing
inside your driver.
This exception only gets
called if it fails.
We won't worry about it.
And then it prints the
doc right here.
One of the great things about
Python is that it's pretty
flexible about printing
complex objects.
So let's give that a call
and see what happens.
I'm going to go back
to my terminal.
I'm still in Mongo here so
I'm just going to quit.
And now I'm going to call
Python using Find.py.
And we can see it calls
Find One right here--
just get that up
on the screen--
calls Find One, which prints
out Reporting For Duty.
And then it prints out one
document that got from the
collection Student ID 10 with an
ID of a BSON object ID and
the type being exam.
You'll notice that it printed
it out as a floating point.
And I think that's an automatic
conversion that
happened during the
string conversion.
But that's not indicative of it
actually coming out of the
floating point.
I believe was converted
for the printing.
Because in fact, that is a
integer inside the database.
If you recall here, you can
actually see them right here.
They're integers.
They're not floating
point numbers.
That's how Find One works.
So the next question is, well,
how does Find work?
So Find, as we talked about--
let's change our function
here to call Find.
There's another function
that we wrote.
And Find sets up a query where
the type is an exam.
And again, Type is quoted,
and then Exam is quoted.
And now we're going to do
scores.find, the collection
name .Find in the query.
And that's actually going to
give us back a cursor.
Not an integrator.
I shouldn't have really
named it that.
I probably should have
named it a cursor.
And I can change that.
So it gives us back a cursor.
And then right here we go
through and we iterate through
that cursor.
So for every document in the
cursor we just print the doc.
Now I don't want to print out
hundreds of things, so I just
have little check.
And once it prints ten of them,
it breaks from the loop.
So it just sets sanity to
zero, and increments it.
And then if it's greater than
ten it breaks, just make sure
that not too much gets printed
to the screen.
So let's run that and
see what happens.
So we're going to call
Python using find.py.
And now you can see in this case
that we get a whole bunch
of documents, and the documents
are all type Exam,
because that's what
we queried on.
And a bunch of different
scores come out.
So that's how you use the
Find commanding and
iterate through a cursor.
So it is now time for a quiz.
And here is the quiz.
So here's a code snippet right
here that should be familiar
to you from this lesson.
It's going to establish a
connection to the database,
and it's going to get a handle
to the school's database, and
then scores collection.
And then it's going to
do something here.
and then it's going to print
the document that it gets.
Now, this is a test
of a Find One.
So what would be the line of
code that would have to
replace this XXX so that
we could put the
document right here?
So if you put that line
of code right in
here, that's the quiz.