OK, and the answer is only
the third one is correct.
And in the third one, notice
that there's two documents
sent to the find command.
The first one is empty, which
finds all of the students.
And it projects out that it
wants the student underscore
ID field key from the document,
and suppress the
underscore ID.
The first one is wrong because,
if you'll notice,
there is no query
document here.
It actually puts the projection
as the first document.
This is going to find everything
with student ID one
and underscore ID zero.
And then the second one is
wrong for two reasons.
First, it doesn't put this
projection document as a
second argument to find, and
also, it doesn't suppress
underscore ID.
Our third one is correct.
And the fourth one is wrong only
because it doesn't quote
these literals, the student
underscore ID and the
underscore ID.