Next, let's talk about how we
use the dollar greater than
and dollar less than operators
from inside Pi Mongo.
Here's the same function
I had before.
I defined my own find
command here.
And here, I defined a query,
this is a Python dictionary.
Again, we're going to look for
things with type is exam.
In this case, we're going to
also constrain it to have a
score which is a dollar
greater than 50
and less than 70.
Now, you'll notice again, that
the quotes are around these
operators in the dollar GT and
the dollar LT to make it work.
And then, we just go through
and we do the find on the
collection.
Which, of course, collection
is defined for the file.
Get a cursor and then go through
it one by one and
print it out.
And if we do that--
This is the file I was using
find using greater
than and less than.
That's the file.
You can see that it will print
out the documents that are
satisfied by the query.
So there you go.
So time for a quiz.
Here's a snippet of code very
similar to the code I was just
showing you, and let's
see how carefully
you're paying attention.
You have to substitute and
figure out what you should put
in to do a query for all of the
quiz scores in that scores
collection where the score
is greater than 20
and less than 90.
And it's a multiple choice
question, you could just
choose one.