Now it's time to turn
our attention to
our good friend regex.
You all remember regex when we
went through the Mongo shell
using regular expressions
to look into documents.
Let's go into the Mongo shell
now and take a quick look at
the document structure that
exists inside these Reddit
stories that we imported.
So just looking here you can see
that there seems to be a
whole bunch of stuff, like a
title approved by, hidden
field, subreddit id, a whole
bunch of good stuff.
So let's just say we wanted to
find everything with a title
that had Microsoft in it.
It looked like there were a few
stories on the Reddit home
page with Microsoft in it.
To do that for the Mongo shell
it would look like this.
We would call it db dot stories
dot find, and we'd ask
for titles that matched
regex Microsoft.
And I'm just going to project
just the title key and
suppress the id key
for simplicity.
And you can see there are one,
two, three, four of them.
And they also appear on Reddit's
technology homepage.
To do this inside Pymongo this
is what we would do.
I've got a little program
that's going to do it.
This is using regex dot py.
Now that we're using the Reddit
stories, it's going to
connect to the Reddit database,
which I imported,
and look at the stories
collection.
Everything else is the same.
You could see here in the
document it says right here
that we're going to look for
things with title when dollar
regex is Microsoft.
And you'll notice here that the
dollar regex has to be in
quotes, although it wasn't
in the Mongo shell.
I have a projection.
I stop calling it
the selector.
I'm calling it the projection.
It's probably more accurate.
And you can see in this
projection we're going to ask
for title and/or suppressing
the underscore id field.
So then I go through and call
scores dot find with that
query with this projection
inside Pymongo.
Let's see what we get
when we do that.
So I'm using underscoring
regex dot py.
I'm going to quit from Mongo and
go using just underscore
regex dot py.
And I see that it prints out
pretty much the same
information, just formatted
slightly differently, because
we're depending on Pythons
built-in print command to
print out these dictionaries.
So that's it.
That's how it works.