All right.
Let's talk about using
dot notation inside
PyMongo in our queries.
Right here, I'm in the Mongo
shell, and I pretty printed
these stories that are on the
Reddit Technology homepage.
And I noticed that some of them
have a subtype called
media, and another subdocument
called oembed.
And right here is a subdocument,
and it has a type
key with a type of video.
I said, all right, so I guess
some of these stories are
videos, and this is the
way it's expressed in
Reddit in the JSON.
So let's find all the stories
that are videos.
So to do that, we're
going to go here.
And we wrote a small script
called using dot notation.
And it's similar to the other
ones that we showed.
Import pymongo, import sys,
get a connection to local
host, and then here, connect
to the Reddit database, and
the stories collection.
And then, what I want to do is
do a query, where I'm looking
for media.oembed.type
is video.
And you can see here,
I single quoted this
media.oembed.type key.
It's going to reach into the
document and look and find
things that are of type media.
Now, the interesting thing about
this, of course, is not
all the documents
even have these
subdocuments inside them.
So it's pretty flexible, and it
can do a query and look for
the ones that, where there is
no subdocuments of this
structure, it simply won't
return anything.
And then, we're going to project
and select out the
fields media.oembed.url.
We want to see the URL and
suppress the underscore ID.
Standard notation here.
We're going to do a find, with
the query and the projection
in a try-catch block.
And then I'm going to print
out the first 10 of them.
So let's do that using
underscore notation dot py.
I'm in the Mongo shell here.
I'm going to quit, and then,
let's see, Python using dot
notation dot py.
And I do that.
And then you can see that what
I get is I get the two
documents returned.
And what it returns is a
document that has a media key,
and the value is another
document with an oembed key.
And the value of that
is another document
who has a URL key.
And then these are the URLs.
And they're YouTube URLs, just
to watch these videos.
So we were able to look into
the structure of the Reddit
pages posted on the technology
page, and find the ones that
were videos, and print out
the links to the videos.
So OK.
It's time for a quiz.
All right.
So we haven't exactly gone over
this, so you'll have to
kind of figure it out.
In the following code, which is
essentially the code that I
just showed you, what do you
think will happen if the
document that matches the
query doesn't have a key
called media.oembed.url?
So for some reason, there is a
document with a type "video,"
but it doesn't have a URL
inside that subdocument.
So the question is,
what happens?
And the choices are
multiple choice.
That PyMongo will throw
an exception.
Or maybe PyMongo will return
an empty document.
Or maybe PyMongo will return a
document with the following
structure--
media, oembed, URL with
an empty document.
So basically, it'll show you the
full set of subdocuments,
but then and empty document
in the very center.
Or there's not enough
information to know.
So please check the answer
that is correct.