Now we're going to go
over Skip, Limit,
and Sort inside PyMongo.
And you've already seen Skip,
Limit, and Sort inside the
Mongo shell.
Now if you recall, the way Skip,
Limit, and Sort work--
and this is true in
most databases--
is that the Sort
happens first.
And after that, Skip, and
after that, the Limit.
So Sort first, then
Skip, then Limit.
It really doesn't matter what
order you give them, that's
the way it works.
Let's go back to our program and
check out how it works in
practice here.
So I'm going back to the
schools collection now,
schools database and the
scores collection.
And I've done a Find here.
The query is a Null Document.
And you can see I've
sorted and I've
skipped and I have limited.
And you can see this is the
syntax for doing these.
The Skip is easy.
You put an integer inside
the parentheses.
The Limit is easy, and the
Source a little more
complicated.
In this case, it's sorting
by student ID and then by
PyMongo.ASCENDING.
This is a constant inside the
driver to indicate that it's
an ascending sort.
So now if we did that,
then let's see
what document we get.
So let's go here, and I'll
clear the screen.
And you can see that I get the
one with student_id 1.
Now, if I go back into
this program and I
change it up a bit.
This time I'm going take this
and I'm going to do
the Skip over here.
And then I'm going
to do the Limit.
And then finally I'm going
to do the Sort.
And I already have the Sort
written out in this next line,
so let me just bring it over.
Now, I'm going to save that.
Don't pay attention
to this line.
It's commented out right now.
I'm going to show you something
about that next.
And you'll notice here
I'm printing out
every doc on the cursor.
I took all that stuff about
limiting it to ten documents
because now I'm using limits
in the query itself.
This is the same query, but this
time we're deliberately
doing the Skip first, then
the Limit, then the Sort.
And let's see what happens
when we run this.
So before you can see, we got
I'm sorry student_id 1.
And now I run it, and once
again, I get student_id 1.
Wow.
That's kind of weird.
Seems almost strange, right?
I mean, you can see very clearly
that I'm running the
Skip and the Limit before
I run the Sort.
But I told you that the Sorts
always happen before the Skips
and the Skips always
before the Limit.
So how does this work?
Seems a little weird.
And of course, the secret is
that the database doesn't
really run the query
until you start
iterating through the cursor.
And that's actually also true
in the Mongo shell.
So in order to allow you to
cascade these in any order,
the query is postponed until you
actually start iterating
through the results.
And then the first time you
start iterating through the
results, that is when the query
is truly run to get the
first result.
The second thing I wanted to
show you is that the syntax
for sorting is a little
different than it is in the
Mongo shell.
So if you look here in
the second line--
which I'm now going to
un-comment out--
if I wanted to do a complex sort
or a sort on more than
one key with a primary and
secondary key to the sort--
if I want to do that, then
instead of putting a
dictionary in here, or a JSON
document with multiple items
as I would in the Mongo shell,
instead I have to use these
Python tuples.
So these are pairs, and
this is an array.
So, student_id,
pymongo.ASCENDING, comma,
score pymongo.DESCENDING.
And we haven't talked about
those tuples at all in Python.
It's not a structure
we went over.
But this actually is a
divergence from the way the
Mongo shell works.
So compare this syntax to, for
instance, the one that we were
seeing in the Mongo
of a shell.
Before, if you recall, you would
sort these in Mongo by,
use school, you would do
db.scores.find.sort, and then
you would use a single
JSON document here.
You could do student_id
positive, and then ascending
sort, and then Score.
Let's say negative indicating
a descending sort.
See here, we have a document
here where the order matters.
And then we can run that
and we'll get--
well, I'll limit it
to two documents.
And you can see here that we get
two documents out, sorted
first by student_id, and then
by score descending.
And that's a very different
syntax then we're seeing
inside Python.
I just want to point that out,
that that is a divergence from
the Mongo shell in terms of the
way you express the sort.
So that was a lot to take in.
Let's do a quiz.
So let's say that we had the
following documents in a
collection.
And you can see I've got four
documents here with IDs 0, 2,
3, and 4, with the values
10, 5,7, and 20.
If I perform the following
query, cursor =
things.find().sk
ip(3).limit(1).sort on value
descending--
this value and then we
sort it descending--
which of these documents would
the database return?
Select only one.
It's a multiple choice
question.