OK.
We've come a long way
in this unit.
What's left is to talk a little
bit about inserting,
updating, and removing data in
PyMongo, which is pretty
similar to the way it works
in the Mongo shell.
So we won't take that long,
although there are some
subtleties to the insertion.
And then we're going to talk a
little bit about the blog, and
the work you're going to
do for that on the
homework this week.
And that's it.
So let's get started talking
about insert.
So I've written a small program
here in Python that's
going to insert two documents
into the database.
Now, in the first case, I've
named this document Richard.
And you can see that it doesn't
have an underscore ID.
And in the second case, I have
another document named Andrew,
and it does have an
underscore ID.
Now, if you recall from the
first unit, the PyMongo
driver, and the drivers in
general, will set an
underscore ID and create a BSON
object ID if there's none
set in the data that comes
into the insert.
So after we insert these, we're
going to look and we're
going to print out, inside
Python, the value
of these two records.
And what I'll do is I'll just
print them in the same order
that I'm inserting them.
All right, so let's do that.
So we're going to
run the program.
And once we do that, we can
see that it prints out the
first one, the one
for Richard.
And in that case, the driver
added an underscore ID, and a
BSON object ID.
And in the second case, where
I already provided one--
underscore ID is Erlichson,
it didn't add one.
So that's interesting.
Now what happens if we run
the program again?
What would you expect
to happen?
So let's do that.
And the answer is that the first
insert succeeds with a
new object ID.
Different from the first,
because the driver just
happily added a new one.
But the second insert, where I
had specified the ID, that's
going to fail.
And we can confirm that by going
into Mongo, using the
schools collection, and then
looking at that collection,
people dot--
I think it's school.
And then looking at the
people collection.
And when we do that, we can
see that, in fact, Richard
appears twice right there.
And I appear once, because that
was a duplicate key error
when I tried to insert
that again.
All right?
So as an aside, the reason why
the driver is created the
underscore ID and not
the database--
it's kind of historical.
But it was to allow a
very fast writes.
You could send a write to the
database with a unique
underscore ID, and then not
wait for the response.
Now, we have safe mode set to
true, so we're waiting for a
response anyway.
So it doesn't really matter.
And also, if you've been
following this, or if you're
aware of the default mode being
safe mode equal false
inside MondoDB, I just wanted
to let you know that in the
coming weeks, one of the plans
for MongoDB is that safe mode
is going to be set to
true by default.
So that sort of obviates the
need for the object ID being
set by the driver, but it always
has been that way.
So I'm guessing it's going to
probably remain that way.
But that was the original reason
why the drivers were
creating the object ID.
It was to allow you to send a
write to the database and not
wait for a response, and know
what the ID was going to be
when it succeeded.
OK.
So it's time for a quiz.
So here's the quiz.
In this code right here, which
looks similar to the code that
we just went over, where we have
a document set to my name
and some interests, if
I try to insert it--
I have a first insert here,
and then the delete of the
underscore ID here, and then
a second insert here--
what do you expect to happen
with the second insert?
All right?
Do you expect to succeed,
and what is your
explanation for that?
And there is one answer to
this question right here.
And here are the answers.