OK.
Now we're going to talk about
updating data in PyMongo.
And there are several different
ways to do that.
One is to use the Save
command, which is a
convenience method
that combines
inserting and updating.
If there's an ID set, it
assumes it's an update.
But if there's no underscore
ID set when you call Save,
then it assumes it's
an insert.
The other way is to do
a wholesale update.
And we've seen those
in the Mongo shell.
This is where you identify which
document you want to
update, and then set the entire
document to the new value.
And finally, you can do a
selective update using a bunch
of different modifiers.
And in this little lesson,
I'm going to
focus on the set modifier.
So let's talk about
the little scores
collection we've been using.
I'm going to show you a program
I've written that
looks at the scores collection
and makes some
modifications to it.
So here's what I want to do with
the scores collection.
I want to add a review date.
And I want to do that in
three different ways.
So first, let's do it using
Save, and I'll show you how
that works.
So what I'm going to do is I'm
going to find a document where
student ID is 1, and
type is homework.
And I'm going to get that
document and I'm going to put
it into the score variable.
And then I'm going to use Python
to set a review date in
the dict that comes back
from the find_one.
So I set it up, and now
I'm actually calling
datetime.datetime.utcnow.
I've imported datetime at
the top of this file.
I haven't shown you that before,
but that's how you'd
get a date that will wind up
being an ISODate and BSON
inside MongoDB.
So it's a good function
to know about.
And then I'm going to update
the record with the
convenience method Save.
So I'm just going
to call Save.
And what you'd expect that to
do is you'd expect that to--
since there is going to be an
underscore ID field from this
find_one, it will do a wholesale
replacement of
everything except for the ID
itself, which is underscore
ID, which is immutable
inside Mongo.
And then it's going to do a
find_one to find the same
record, and it's going
to print it out.
And it's going to
show you that.
OK?
So that's one way of
accomplishing adding a review
date to a document.
That's with the Save command.
But let's look, there's another
way of doing it, which
is using a traditional update.
So to do that, it's
very similar.
We're going to call score
= scores.find_one.
Find the homework with
the student ID 1.
And then, again, we're going
to set a review date.
But now, rather than
call Save, we're
going to call Update.
And we're going to call Update,
we're going to specify
our criteria that we're
looking for this
record right here .
And then after that--
right here, this record--
and then after that we're going
to set the document to
what is in the score dict
right here, which is
everything I got out before.
Now, if you've thought about
this carefully, you'd realize
that there's actually an
underscore ID in this dict.
And so it looks like I'm
trying to update the
underscore ID, but Mongo is OK
with you trying to do that, as
long as the underscore ID you
put in here is the same one
that exists in the
document already.
And that is the same one, so
it won't cause an error.
If you tried to set an
underscore ID that was
different in this document, then
it would actually fail.
And after that we're going
to find it, and see if we
successfully added a review
date to that document.
And then, the final way of
doing this is using Set.
Now, using Set is more efficient
in the sense that
we're only going to update one
small part of the document,
rather than writing the
entire document.
Now, these documents are very
small, and it really doesn't
matter whether you write the
entire document or write a
small part of it.
But if the document were very
large, you wouldn't want to
write the entire document when
you could just be writing a
small part of it.
So let's see how you do that.
Well, if you're going to use Set
to do it, again, you do a
find_one to find the document
where student ID is 1.
Then we're going to, once again,
use Update, but this
time we're going to use
the set operator.
So the criteria is the same.
We're going to find the document
with student ID 1,
type homework.
But now we're using Set.
And notice the single quotes
around the $set.
And we're going to set
review_date equal to utcnow.
And then, once again, we're
going to find the record and
we're going to print it out.
So I have this program set up
to run three different ways,
using Save, using Update,
using Set.
And then there was that
one small function--
there is one other function
I wrote called
remove_review_date.
And that's just going to remove
every review date from
every record.
And I'll show you
how that works.
It actually demonstrates
the use of multi.
So I'll show you that.
Here's remove_review_date.
We're going to, again, get
a handle to the database.
And then we're going to call
score.update, all documents,
unset, review_date,
multi=true.
And this is a slightly different
syntax than doing in
a Mongo shell.
It's a named parameter here.
If you remember, in the Mongo
shell, it's the fourth
argument to the update.
The third one is whether it's
an upsert, and the fourth is
whether it's a multi-update.
So this is just to remove the
review dates from all the
records, all the documents, to
make sure that it's clean.
All right.
So let's run it, and let's
see what happens.
OK.
So what happened?
Well, it removed all
the review dates.
Now it's going to try another
command using Save.
Before it pulls out this
document, you can see that it
doesn't have a review
date on it.
It has a score of 21.995,
et cetera.
And then after I do it using
Save, now it's got a review
date with a datetime.
And you can see the way that's
displayed inside Python.
It looks slightly different if
you do it in the Mongo shell.
So that worked just fine.
And then, removing all
review dates again.
And now, not using Save, but
using a wholesale update, you
can see that, again, the review
date is missing when I
first pull the document out,
And present when I do the
second find_one.
And you can see the time is
changing, which is fine.
That's what you'd expect,
because this is happening over
and over again that I'm removing
the review dates, and
then adding a new review date.
And then finally, using a Set
command, where I'm only
setting that one key.
It works exactly the same way.
I pull out the document.
Again, the review date is
missing because I've already
removed it.
And then after that, I set it,
and then I can see that the
date has been set.
And once again, the date is
slightly different because
some time has passed between
those updates.
All right.
So now it's time for a quiz.
So here's the quiz.
In the following code fragment,
what is the Python
expression in place of xxxxx
to set a new key
"examiner" to be Jones?
Please use the Set operator.
And you can see this is
very similar to the
code I showed you.
But now, there's an update here,
and we've left out what
you need to put in here
in Python to set the
examiner key to Jones.
So you're going to
put that in here.
And that's the question.