Let's talk about upserting
in PyMongo.
Now if you recall from the
lessons we did on the Mongo
shell, an upsert is an update
where the database will
automatically insert the data
if there is no document that
matches the criteria.
So it's a convenient way of
being able to combine two
different actions.
And I've written a small program
to demonstrate how
upserts work in PyMongo.
So let's take a look at that.
OK.
So in this program which I
call using_upsert.py--
and I'm going to provide all of
these files to you if you
want to run them on your
own computer--
we're going to connect to local
host, and safe equals
true, and go into test database,
and look at things
collection.
And we're going to do the
following actions.
First we're going to drop
everything into things
collection.
Now there's actually two
different ways to do this.
You can do things.remove.
with an empty document to remove
all the documents.
Or slightly more efficiently if
the collection were large,
but this is obviously a very
small collection, you could do
things.drop and that drops
the collection.
And after that, I'm going to
do two different upserts.
Now I call update.
And I'm looking for thing
that has a key of thing
and a value of apple.
And then I'm going to set
color red, upsert true.
OK?
And the other thing I'm going
to update in my things
collection is I'm going to
look for a thing with the
thing value of pear.
And then I'm going to set
the color to green.
And I'm going to upsert
equals true.
And in this case, I'm suing
the set command.
In this case, I'm just setting
the document--
I'm saying the attribute
of the document that
I want right here.
And then I'm going to find the
apple and print it out.
And I'm going to find the pear
and I'm going to print it out.
So that's the whole program.
So let's see what we get.
All right.
So here's the result of
running this program.
And in the case of the apple,
it pretty much is what we'd
expect, which is that there's
color red, thing apple.
And then a underscore IDs
that's a BSON ObjectId.
But with the pear, there's
nothing there.
Wow, that's kind of weird.
There's nothing there.
So why is that?
So let's look back at the
program and see if we can
figure out what happened.
So with the apple, we used
the set command.
And it did what we expected,
which is that it inserted
something with a thing
of value of apple
and a color of red.
But with the pear, we didn't
use a set command.
So we didn't actually get a
document with thing set.
So the reason why this statement
here returned none
is that there is nothing with
thing pear in the collection.
And I'll show you the collection
so you can see it.
So we're on Mongo and
db.things.find.
And here's what's in
that collection.
You can see we have
the apple-- thing
apple, color red--
but for the pear, we just
have color green.
Thing pear is not there.
So when we ran this statement
right here, we inserted
something into the database with
color of green and thing
colon pear.
The thing attribute, the
thing key, did not get
set into the document.
And so that's an important thing
to remember when you're
doing upserts is that it
generally just sets the
document equal to what's
on the right.
The exception being that if you
use a set command, then it
will use the criteria on the
left in the query document as
a part of what's inserted.
OK.
So it's time for a quiz
on upserting.
So suppose we'd like to upsert
the following document into
the collection stuff.
_id bat, friend ball,
cousin glove.
Which of the following
statements would work?
And I won't go through
each one right now,
because they're small.
But which of the following
statements would work?