Let's go over some of the
internals of the blog project.
There are only three collections
that will ever be
created in this project
during the course.
One is the post collection.
The other is the users
collection.
And the final one is the
sessions collection.
You'll see that in this
week's homework you
don't yet have posts.
So just users and sessions.
Let's go through the files.
Let's see what's in
the directory.
There's a blog.py file.
That's the main file that's got
the controller in it that
controls your UI for the blog.
And then there's a session
data access object,
abbreviated sessionDAO.
And then there's a userDAO file,
contains all the code
for accessing the user's
collection.
And then there's a bunch of
views in the views directory,
which are the HTML templates
that we're going to be
combining with some of the
outputs from your functions to
produce the UI.
And then you'll also have
a validation program to
validate the blog.
I'm going to take you through
these using PyCharm.
And PyCharm is an IDE
from JetBrains
that you can download.
It's not free.
But we actually have an
evaluation license for the use
of the students, which is in
the forms for the course
starting in April.
Hopefully JetBrains will give
us another one for the
subsequent courses.
It's a 90-day license.
So you can play with it.
And then if you like
it you can buy it.
And if you like it you
don't need to use it.
You don't need to use PyCharm.
You can also use Emacs or
Vim or Sublime Text.
They'll all work.
But the nice thing about PyCharm
is that, aside from
the syntax highlighting that you
get from all editors, it
gives you some feedback when
variables aren't used.
And it tells you about
code doesn't
follow Pythonic idioms.
For instance, if you say if
something equals none--
and typically you'd write if
something is none in Python--
it'll point those out.
You can see them along
the right here.
There's these little yellow
things that tell
you and warn you.
Some of the warnings are
not actually correct.
But a lot of them are
useful warnings.
And as a novice Python user, I
think this stuff can be really
interesting.
If you're experienced in Python,
you probably already
have your habits set.
And it probably doesn't
matter.
Let's go through the code.
The first thing I wanted to
show you was blog.py.
And blog.py is the controller.
It has all of these different
functions that get called as
handlers for requests to
particular URLs for your blog.
And the way these are done
in Bottle is again these
decorators, where the function
is decorated.
You can see right here, this
decorator bottle.route slash
says that this next function
that follows is going to be
used to handle calls to the
main URL of your blog.
This particular function is not
yet implemented in this
part of the class.
We're going to get
to it later on.
It's just a placeholder.
Although it is going to return
a template file.
A template says this
is a place holder.
And I'll get to those templates
in a second.
You can see here that in order
to have a user sign up for the
blog, this is the
sign up route.
Then, in this case, there's
nothing to do except return
the sign of template.
And actually it sets some
starting values, and gives
them to the template
as a dict.
That's the sign up template.
Let's look at the sign
up template.
So that'll call this template.
And you can see this template
has some minimal styling
information.
And it's an HTML template.
And then you can see
here that this is
basically an HTML file.
But there are particular places
where bottle will make
substitutions for Python
variables.
In particular, this double brace
is an indication that
this value is going to be
replaced by the variable value
when it runs.
So that's the way that works.
Let's go back to
blog.py again.
And then when the user does
something, typically it'll
call into one of these
other classes.
For instance, this right
here is the log in.
It takes a log in.
It gets username and password.
It calls validate login.
And to do that it calls
users.validate_login.
And users will set up--
this looks a little confusing,
actually.
Let me explain that.
The very bottom of the program,
you can see that this
essentially [INAUDIBLE]
in bottle.py.
You can see that it sets
up a user's variable.
And it creates a new instance of
the class user Data Access
Object, user DAO, giving
it the database.
And the same thing
for sessions.
And so when you see it call to
users like that, for instance,
in process log in, what you're
seeing is a call into this
user DAO object.
I'm not going to show you
that object right now.
Because that's what you
have to work this
week for the homework.
And the code is completed
in my version.
So I'm not going to
show you that.
I will show you the session
DAO object.
And the session DAO object you
will not need to work in.
You can see how it works.
We haven't really gone over how
classes work inside Python.
So if you are new to Python,
I'll explain it.
This is the class declaration.
This _init, this is the
constructor for the class.
This is what gets called when
you create a new instance of a
session DAO.
And you can see we passed
in a handle [INAUDIBLE]
database.
So it just saves it off, and
then creates a handle to the
sessions collection.
Start session does something
pretty straightforward.
It creates a new dictionary with
username and session ID.
Session ID is a long,
random number.
And it tries to insert
it into the sessions
collection, for example.
I think that's the basics
of how this works.
You can see this week that
there's templates for some
paths that you'll need to get
working, like the login, and
the sign up, and the
welcome page.
But there aren't templates for
displaying blog posts, or
adding comments.
Because that comes
in later weeks.
So we don't have
those here yet.
And there's also a missing
DAO object.
The blog post DAO object is
not yet given to you.
Because you're going to get that
in a later week, as well.
And again, I was working inside
PyCharm here, which you
can download if you'd like.
Or you can use a regular text
editor to do your work.