OK, in this problem, we asked
you to work with the grades.gs
collection and to import it into
your MongoDB instance.
So let's start by doing that by
running mongoimport minus d
students minus c grades,
bringing in grades.gs.
We did that, and it says it
imported 800 objects.
Excellent.
Let's connect to the database
and use students, and then
we're going to show
collections.
OK, let's look at
db.grades.find.limit 1 pretty.
Pretty.
Print it.
We can see what the
data looks like.
It looks like there's
a student ID and
a type and a score.
All right.
We asked you to find the lowest
student's score above
or equal to 65.
So to do that, here is
the query right here.
I'll take you through it.
We're going to look for
everything with type exam and
with a score that is greater
than or equal to, using gte
operator 65.
Then we're going to sort it by
score ascending, and we're
going to limit it to five.
We do that, and we see that
the student that has the
lowest score greater than or
equal to 65 is student ID 22.
And that is the answer
to this problem, 22.