All right, we know
how to find data
in a database using
"find" and "find_one."
Now I want to show you how
to project certain fields out
of the documents you
get from a database.
Now, projection is very similar
to the way you use "select"
in a relational database.
And that lets you specify
which fields you want back.
Let's say, you have a
document with an "_id" of "1",
and a key of "a" with a value
of "2", and a key of "b"
with a value of "3", and a key
of "c" with a value of "4."
And you want to find that
document in the database,
but you only want to
see the value for "a"
and the value for "c."
You can do that
using a projection.
And the way you do it
is when you call "find",
the first parameter in
"find" is the filter,
the actual query itself,
to figure out which
documents you want to return.
The second parameter
is going to be
a document that specifies which
fields you want to return.
This is the projection.
So let me show you
concretely how that works
by showing you a small program.
Now, here's a small
program that's
going to go into
the same database
and the same collection
we've been using,
which is the School database
and the Scores collection.
And we're going to call "find."
We have a function
called "find."
And that function
is going to set up
a query with type "exam."
And you'll see that's
just a Python dictionary,
and "type" is, again, a
string literal and "exam"
is a string literal.
And they're both quoted.
And so I'm saying I want
to find the documents where
"type" is "exam."
And then I don't want to get
all the fields from a document.
Instead, I only want
to get the "student_id"
and I want to
suppress the "_id."
So when you give a field and
then you have a "1" here,
that means included.
When you have a "0",
it means excluded.
Now, normally, for projection
if you don't include a field,
it won't be included.
But "_id" is special,
unless you suppress it.
By giving it a "0"
value, you will see it.
So then we run the
query right here.
We call "scores.find."
Here's the query.
And here's the projection
that we laid out.
And if there's an exception,
we handle that here.
Otherwise, you print
out the contents
that we find inside
the collection.
And again, we just
print out the first 10.
And this is just us calling
the "find" function.
So let's call that and
see what it looks like.
So I'm going to invoke
the Python Interpreter,
invoking the Python Interpreter
using the program we just
wrote which is called
"using_find_with_projection."
And if we do that,
we see that we
get the documents with
"student_id" and nothing else.
And if we went back in here and
we didn't suppress the "_id",
even though we didn't include
it, we're going to see it.
So now we run this again.
And now we have all the
"_id"s for each document.
And that's the way
projections work.
Now, if you wanted to
figure this out yourself,
you could look in
the documentation.
The one thing I want to
really emphasize in this class
is that the documentation is
a great source of information
on both PyMongo
itself and MongoDB.
So I'm going to
do that real fast
so you can see how that looks.
So I would probably start
at api.mongo.org again.
And I'll click on Python.
And we're running the beta
driver, the 3.0beta0 driver.
So I'm going to click on that.
For you, the 3.0
driver may be released
by the time you watch this.
I want to wind up at
this documentation.
This documentation is
a lot of information.
The part that's most interesting
is the API documentation.
And the API
documentation is laid out
with all the different
classes inside.
But most of the things
that we're interested in
are actually methods in
the Collection class,
because we're calling
"find" and "find_one",
and these are all on
the Collection class.
So I'm going to go in
there and look at that.
And then I'm just going to
search inside it for "find."
And I get a few instances.
Oh, and there it was.
So here's the
actual Find command.
And you can see the Find
command takes a filter.
That was what we call the query.
And then it takes a projection.
And it tells you
all the parameters
that you can put in here.
Now, projection,
you'll see here,
it's shown as a name parameter.
So you could have done
it as a name parameter
versus a positional parameter.
I could have said
"projection=", but I didn't.
And you can see, if you
look under "find_one",
you'll see that it tells you
that the arguments themselves
are the same as from "find."
Let's say, he had the keyword
arguments come from "find",
so you could just
go there if you
want to see his arguments,
which is where we just were.
Now, this is very
useful if you're
trying to figure
out what something
does inside PyMongo is to
go into the documentation
and look at the
API documentation
to see it and find out
what the parameters are.
And there's a lot of parameters
that we haven't event
talked about yet that you
could explore yourself
or we'll get to a lot
of them in the class.
All right, now it's
time for a quiz.
Let's talk about projecting
result from "find."
Which of the following--
these are Python statements--
which of the falling
could work using PyMongo,
depending on variable names,
to project just the student
ID from the Scores collection?
All right, just a student ID
from the Scores collection
using a Find command.
So which of the
following of these
is the correct
syntax to do that?