Let's talk about how you use
the greater than and less
than operators inside PyMongo.
And you already learned
about these operators
when using the Mongo shell.
And you can review that now if
you're not familiar with it.
I've written a small
program very similar
to the previous programs.
It's going to run
a query once again
against the scores collection
in the school database.
And this time,
the query is going
to be that it's looking
for documents of type exam
with a score, and
you see it's quoted,
is dollar greater than
50 dollar less than 70.
And this condition is
a document basically.
And it's the value
for the score key.
That's the way it's specified.
And you can see
there's a comma here.
And you can put these
in either order.
It could be less than
70 and greater than 50.
It wouldn't matter which
order you put these in.
Then it runs this query.
And then it prints out.
It's going to print out
the first 10 documents.
So let's run that
and see if it works.
All right.
So I'm going to invoke the
Python interpreter on find
using greater than,
less than .py.
And when I do that, I get
out a bunch of documents.
They're all of type exam.
And they're all
between, the scores
are all between 50 and 70.
The student IDs are
varied because we had
no criteria for the student ID.
All right, now it's
time for a quiz.
And here's the quiz.
In the following
code below, very
similar to the
code we just wrote,
we have one line missing.
Tell us what the line would
be to search for all the quiz
scores that are greater
than 20 and less than 90?
So it's pretty similar to
what we did in the class.
And you can see
here is the code.
And here is the X's.
So here is the missing code.
And you're going to
need to figure out what
that line of code would be.
And here are the choices.