I want to show you how to
use regular expressions
inside MongoDB with Python.
But before I do that, we
really need some better data
to play with.
And so to do that, I'm going to
pull in some data from Reddit.
And I think this illustrates
one of the real strengths
of MongoDB, which is how easy
it is to ingest data, especially
data that you don't
quite understand
the structure of before
you start playing with it.
So this is Reddit's home
page-- Reddit's technology
homepage from today.
And we're going to pull in
these stories to MongoDB.
Let's see how we would
start thinking about that.
So first of all, Reddit has
this nice feature where if you
append .JSON to your URL-- you
see I just put .JSON at the end
of that URL-- then it's going
to show you a .JSON version
of their home page.
And this is pretty overwhelming.
And the data looks
pretty complicated.
So let's see if we can sift
through this a little bit
to figure out what
the structure is.
So to do that, I'm going
to go into the terminal.
And I'm going to curl this URL.
So it was www.reddit.com/r
/technology/.json.
And I'm going to put that into
a file called reddit.json.
Alright.
So I did that.
And now I have that file.
And it's still
pretty complicated.
So how can I make it better?
Well, it turns out there's
a built-in system in Python
for dealing with JSON.
So I'm going to cat that file,
reddit.json, and redirect it
to Python, and to a
module called json.tool.
And this minus m runs
the module as a script.
And then I'm going to
just send that to more,
and take a look at that file.
Alright.
So that's much better.
So with that little
command I was
able to pretty
print this JSON file
and start inspecting
the structure.
And I did this a little
bit before I recorded.
And it looks like
what we have here
is the JSON document with data,
with a subkey called children.
And in there is an array.
And then these
documents that come
after all seem to be
stories, where the story is
under the data key.
So you can see here we have
a story, the permalink,
and the title, I think, is
the thing that's interesting.
Japanese scientists have
succeed in transmitting energy.
This was the first story
you saw on the page.
And then here's another story.
Et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
So I can figure out what
the structure is here.
And I should be able use
that to pull data in.
So let me show you a
program to do that.
Here's the program that's going
to read this data directly
from Reddit, and
put it into MongoDB.
It uses some modules
that we're not
going to use very often, or
even at all in this class.
So you don't need to
really understand them.
But urllib2 is the one.
And the JSON one as well.
And the ulrlib2 is going to let
us do a web request to Reddit.
And the JSON one is
going to parse the JSON.
So we make a connection to
local host from MongoDB.
Some place to put the data.
Make a connection to the
Reddit database inside MongoDB,
which of course, we
haven't used before.
But it will be auto-created
as soon as we put data
in the collection.
And then a stories collection.
I've run this
multiple times, so I
needed to drop the stories
collection beforehand
to make sure
everything was empty.
So I did that here.
And then I found
the Reddit page,
which is the one
we showed before,
which is
reddit.com/r/technology/.json.
And I opened it using urllib2
to get a handle to that page.
And then I need a parsed
version of this page.
So I call the JSON module that
I imported, and I load it up,
and I read the whole thing.
And that's going to create
a bunch of documents
that I can iterate through.
Now we already know what
the structure of this page
is, because we pulled
the URL and read it.
We put into a text file.
And we put it through a
version of the JSON module
so we could see it.
And so we know what's
really interesting
in each of these documents
is we need to look at,
in the parsed version, really
it's just the first document
that we need.
We just need whatever
is in data children.
So parsed, data, children.
That field itself,
the value is an array,
which is each of the stories.
And I learned that by just
inspecting by hand what
was brought back from Reddit.
OK.
So once I have each of the
stories in the JSON document,
now it's really simple.
I just call insert
one on each one.
And that's it.
And I look inside each one
and pull the data element out,
because I noticed that there
was sort of an extra level
hierarchy there that
I don't care about.
If you go back to the original
file, you'll see that.
So let's run this
and see what we get.
So we're going to
python read_reddit.py.
And if I do that, it runs,
runs without incident.
And now we need to look
inside the database.
So we're going to start Mongo.
We're going to use
the Reddit database.
And then we are going
to look at db.stories.
We'll do a find one on that.
Alright.
So we did a find one on this.
And the first document
in the stories collection
inside MongoDB now is the story
on Japanese scientists finding
a wireless way to
transmit energy.
So that's great.
That's exactly what we wanted.
And if we find a whole bunch
of documents, which we can do,
then it's not going
to be formatted.
I'll do it pretty.
There we go.
Now we have multiple stories.
Each one its own document.
Perfect.
Now we finally have some
data that we can search,
and we can use for the
subsequent lessons.