Now we're going to talk about
regular expression matching
within queries in MongoDB.
This is the $regex
operator, and you already
went over that in
the Mongo shell.
Now we're going to show you
how to do it using PyMongo.
And to illustrate
how this works,
we're going to use a
data set that we just
brought in from Reddit.
So what we want to do
is we want to inspect
this data-- inspect the data
we brought in real quickly.
It was in the Reddit
database, and it
was in the stories collection.
All right, so I'm looking
at a single document--
one of the stories
that was brought in--
and we can see here that it
has lots of different fields,
but one of the ones that
looks most interesting to me
is the title field, which
has a long description
of the title of the article.
And that's what we're
going to search on.
Let's say we wanted to find
all the articles about Apple
and Google.
So the regular
expression syntax is
something that I don't
always remember perfectly,
and so I often start with
Google on things like that.
Now, this is actually not really
a PyMongo topic exactly, it's
actually more of a
MongoDB manual topic,
and the reason is that the
regular expressions are
parsed entirely by the server.
So I'm searching
for MongoDB $regex,
and when I do that I get a
bunch of links here from Google,
and the first one is
the $regex syntax.
And if I go there I can see
how to do a $regex search.
This becomes part of the
filter itself in the query.
And you can see that I
first specify the field
that I want to search--
let's say title--
and then I have a
document which has to have
a $regex expression in it.
And the value-- this is the
actual regular expression here.
Now, you can either put
it in these slashes,
or you could also
put it in quotes.
In Python, we're just
going to use quotes.
And then you could
also take some options,
and I looked at the
options real quickly
and the most
interesting option I saw
was case insensitivity--
right here-- which
you could use to do a
case insensitive search.
Now, it says that it uses
the Perl regular expressions,
and so you could separately
Google for that if you
want to remember exactly what
the Perl regular expression
syntax is.
But let's go see a
small program that
can actually read this data.
OK, so here's a
small program that's
going to read these stories
and print out the ones that
are about Apple and Google.
This is very similar to the
other programs we've written.
Imports PyMongo and sys--
this is a Python program--
connects to the database
using MongoClient,
then connects to
the Reddit database
in the stories collection.
And over here we specify query,
and the query is a document,
and the document
is-- the first part
is that we say that we
want the title of the story
to be a regular
expression, to match it
against this regular expression,
$regex-- this is quoted,
you can see here--
and I specify that it
has to be Apple or Google--
and the bar signifies an
or-- and then I want it
to be case insensitive.
I have a projection specified,
I want to get the title out
of the document, and I
want to suppress the _id.
So that's about it.
We call stories.find
with the query--
this is the query-- with this
projection, the projection
being that we want to
get the title only.
We check for
exceptions, and then we
print out every document.
Let's go and see what we find.
I'm going to invoke the Python
interpreter on the script.
OK, and when I do that I get
stories about Apple and Google.
I get a story from Apple here
about an outage yesterday,
and iCloud services,
another one from Google
about warrants in emails,
and some other stuff
from Google and Apple.
And that's how
regular expressions
work inside MongoDB queries.