All right, we've come a
long way in this unit.
And now it's time to talk
about inserting, updating
and deleting data using PyMongo.
Now, this is an area where
the PyMongo driver deviates
from the Mongo shell.
And the reason it deviates
from the Mongo shell
is that there is a new
specification called
the CRUD specification
that all the drivers are
working to conform to that
simplify the inserting,
and updating and deleting data.
And as a result, some of the
things you saw on the shell
are going to be different
than some of the API
calls in the driver.
And there's also
some differences
between that and what
the actual commands are,
the underlying commands
that go to the server.
Now, these are
implementation details
that you don't really
need to understand.
But they are
sometimes interesting
for historical reasons, and you
can look in the source code,
because it's all
open source, to see
the way the
different things map.
So I'll be mentioning some of
these differences along the way
to give you an understanding of
the way it all comes together.
So for inserting, in PyMongo,
we've got insert_one,
and we have insert_many.
And for updating, we've got
update_one and update_many.
And these are function
calls, the method
that exists in PyMongo.
This inserts one document.
This inserts many documents.
This updates one document.
This updates many documents.
We also have replace_one,
and replace_one
replaces one document.
And then finally,
for deleting data,
you've got delete_one
and delete_many.
On the server, a lot of
these map to the same thing.
So the insert_one actually
maps to the insert command
on the server.
The insert_many uses what
we call the bulk API.
The update_one
function in PyMongo
uses the update command, as
does the update_many command.
And the main difference
is certain flags
that are sent to update.
And replace also uses
the update command.
And if you remember,
there was something called
Save from the Mongo shell.
Save doesn't exist in PyMongo.
Now, it used to be that to
get these different types
of behavior, updating one
versus many, versus replacing
the entire document, there
are subtle differences
that you have to be aware of in
the way the server interprets
the arguments themselves
and the flags.
And in PyMongo this is
very much simplified
by you calling update_one,
update_many, or replace_one,
which really removes
any ambiguity of what
you're trying to accomplish.
And the same thing with
delete_one and delete_many
that I believe map to
remove on the server.
Now, if you go through the
documentation for PyMongo,
you're going to see some
of the older calls as well.
You're going to see
an insert command,
and an update command
that map to these server
commands directly.
But you'll also notice if
you look in the documentation
that those are
marked deprecated.
You could still use
them if you really want,
but we highly recommend that you
use these newer ones, which are
much easier to reason about.
Now, with that sort of long
explanation out of the way,
let's talk about insert_one and
how we're going to use that,
because that's what this
lesson is actually about.
It's about Inserting
one document.
So I've written a program
called using_insert_one.py,
which you can
download if you like.
And this program is going
to insert some documents.
And it's going to put them
into the school database,
and it's going to put them
into the people collection.
And the two documents
that it's going to put in,
the first one is called richard.
And you'll notice that
the first one, richard,
doesn't have an _id.
And the second one,
andrew, does have an _id.
OK, and now we're going
to try to insert them.
And we're going
to insert richard,
and we're going
to insert andrew.
And we're going to catch
any errors that might occur.
So the question is,
what do you think
is going to happen we do this?
So let's go into a shell
and run this program.
OK, so pretty straightforward,
it inserted both documents.
And then I believe it read
them both out of the database.
So tried to do to insert_ones,
inserted richard and andrew.
Each of those were
Python dictionaries.
And then it just printed
out what it had inserted.
And if we go into the
database now, use school,
and then do db.people.find(),
you're going to find that there
are two documents in there,
exactly as we'd expect.
It added an _id for
Richard's document,
because he didn't have one.
And for mine, I had specified
it, so my _id is erlichson.
All right, now what if we try
to run this program again?
What would happen?
Ooh, that didn't work out.
So we try to run it
again, and this time we
get a duplicate key error.
Now, why does that happen?
And if we look inside
the collection,
we see that there
are three documents.
Richard seems to
be in there twice.
I'm only in there once.
OK, so it looks like, for
some reason, I didn't get
added a second time.
Now let's look
back at the program
and see if we can
understand that.
The reason is that
_id must be unique.
So when we try to insert
me the second time,
we ran the program
a second time,
we have a conflict on
the unique index for _id.
It said erlichson is a conflict.
Whereas, for Richard's document,
because we didn't specify
an _id, the driver added
one, used an object ID.
And so he got in there twice.
Now, because the richard insert
is ahead of the andrew insert,
Richard got in there twice.
If we had switched the
order of these two,
then the exception that
was raised by my insert
would have brought
us to this block,
and we never would have
gotten to Richard's insert.
So that's how insert_one works.
All right, now it's
time for a quiz.
This is a quiz on insert_one.
Here's some code, not that
different from the code we
looked at in this lesson,
where we have a document
and it has me again, and
my interests-- running,
cycling and photography.
We try to insert that document,
we delete documents _id,
we try to insert it again.
And the question is, do you
expect this second insert of me
to succeed in this case?
Check the answer.