OK.
To remove data using
PyMongo, you're
going to use the delete-one
and delete-many calls.
And they do pretty
much what you'd expect,
which is that if you
provide a filter,
and specify what documents
you want removed,
delete-one will
delete one of them,
and delete-many will delete
as many as match the filter.
Let's look at a short program.
Now you might remember that
we have the student grade
data before.
And I want to remove a
particular student record.
So this program is going to
remove the data for student
one, and then find all the data
for student 1 and print it out.
So how does it do that?
Here's the removal code.
You give it a student ID.
And it connects to
the school, database,
and the scores collection.
And then it calls delete-one,
which student ID being student
ID passed in.
This is the literal student ID.
And this is the value
of the variable.
And then it's going to
print the number removed.
And that's going to come
from result.deleted_count.
So notice that when
we call delete-one,
we get back a result.
And the result is a
structure that includes
a number of items deleted.
It's under deleted_count.
After that, we call
find_student_data
at the bottom.
And find_student_data
is going to find
all of student data pertaining
to a particular student.
It's gonna call find
for a student ID,
with the student ID value
for the student ID variable.
And it's gonna
iterate the documents,
and it's going to
print them out.
And that's it.
OK.
So let's see what happens.
Alright.
We're going to invoke the Python
interpreter on this program,
which is called
remove_student_data.py.
And you can download this.
OK.
So it called delete-one.
So it removed one record.
And then it searched for
the data for student ID one,
and it found two
more items in there.
And the reason it found
two more items in there
is that if you recall,
this grade data
has multiple items,
both quiz and homework
for each of the students.
So I think there were three
documents for every student.
Now if we change this
program to call delete-many.
we should get rid
of the other two.
So let's do that.
Alright.
Now we remove two.
And we look for the
data for student ID one,
we get back nothing,
which is what we'd expect.
Now how do I know how to
print out the number removed?
Well, I didn't actually remember
this when I was recording this.
And once again, I went to our
documentation and looked it up.
And I want to show
you how that works,
because I think that it's
so important that you
be able to use documentation.
So I went to api.mongodb.org.
I clicked on Python.
I clicked on the 3.0 beta 1.
Now last time I recorded
this, it was 3.0 beta zero.
So there's been another release.
And I went here to
the API documentation.
I know that the delete-one
call is something that's
part of the collection class.
So I'm going to go
here, and then I'm
going to look for delete-one.
And if I go to
delete_one, it says
that it returns a DeleteResult.
And if I look at the
DeleteResult, and I click here,
then it says the DeleteResult
has a deleted_count.
You don't have to understand
what those are right now.
But this is how I figured
out how many items I actually
deleted with the call.
Alright.
Now it is time
for a quiz, which,
if you've been listening,
should be pretty easy.
Alright.
Here's the quiz.
When you're removing
data with PyMongo,
when you perform a delete,
you get back a structure,
and it tells you how
many items were deleted.
The name of the field that
contains that information
is which of these four?
num_deleted, num_removed,
deleted_count,
and removed_count.
Which one?