Welcome to week six.
This week we're going to do
application engineering.
The two major topics are
replication and sharding.
Replication is a technique for
introducing a degree of fault
tolerance to MongoDB,
asynchronously replicating
your data amongst multiple
nodes running MongoDB.
And what we're going to talk
about is what you need to know
as an engineer, as a developer,
dealing with a
replicated environment.
The next topic is sharding.
So sharding is the way we
scale out in Mongo.
We allow you to split
a collection up
amongst multiple instances.
And you're going to need to
know a few things as a
developer to deal with
sharded environments.
Firstly, you're going to need to
know how to create a shard
key and how to write queries
that work in a sharded
environment.
So we're going to
talk about that.
So let's get started.