A site that you should
definitely know about now that
you're leaving our course
is api.mongodb.org.
This is the main directory of
all the drivers and the
various versions of the drivers
that you'll be using
as a developer.
Now, I didn't tell you about
that earlier on in the course
because I didn't
know about it.
And I didn't know about it
because I myself have been
learning MongoDB for the last
few months, and I wasn't aware
that we had this high
level site.
So I want to take you through
that now and show you the
changes that have occurred to
the Python driver in the last
two weeks, and also just
about every other
driver that we support.
So if you go to api.mongodb.org,
you can see
all the different
drivers listed.
I'm going to click on Python.
You can see that the current
version is 2.4.
You probably have
2.3 installed.
You should update to 2.4 using
the instructions on the page.
I think it's easy_install
-U for Mac users.
I did it earlier.
If you click on 2.4, that
looks familiar to you.
But sometimes Google will point
to the older driver, so
it's good to start at
api.mongodb.org.
And now I'm going to
go down to API.
And you can see that one of
the major classes is the
connection class that we used
earlier in the class to
connect using Python.
And if we click on that, it
warns us that, in fact, it is
deprecated and that we should
use mongo_client instead.
Now, there is some version of
mongo_client for every single
one of the drivers we support.
This was a major roll out last
week to change our defaults so
that we acknowledge rights to
the database and don't fire
and forget anymore.
If we click there onto
mongo_client, we get all the
various options for that.
Now, in the Python driver,
you don't see the words
WriteConcern very often.
And WriteConcern is not used
consistently in our
documentation, but it's taken to
mean, as far as I can tell,
the combination of [? WJ ?]
and sometimes wtimeout
parameters taken together.
But you can see all the
different options that you can
give the driver.
W is the one we've been talking
about, acknowledging
the writes.
We'll get to wtimeout as soon as
we get to replication, talk
about what that is.
J is whether or not you're
going to wait
for it to be journaled.
And there's a few others,
and I want to go
over them right now.
But let's go over a program so
you can see what a program
looks like using the
new drivers.
Since we've been writing in a
different style for the entire
course, I want to make sure you
guys get to see the most
recent one.
So here's a small program that's
written using the new
MongoClient class versus the
connection class that we used
earlier on in the course.
C equals Pymongo.mongoclient.
The host is the host
I'm connecting to.
W equals 2, and J equals true.
DB equals CMO101.
People equals DB.people.
And then I do some inserts.
And this is an alternative to
using the connection class.
The difference here is that even
if I gave no W equals 2,
if I did not specify w equals
2 or J equals true--
and I'll specify W equals 1,
since we've haven't gone over
replication yet--
even if I just left this blank,
the default would be
[? w=1, j=false. ?]
And that's a change
from before.
Before we specified safe mode
using the old connection
class, which gave us
[? w=1, j=false. ?]
And now [? w=1, j=false ?]
is the default for
all connections.
And the old connection class
is going to deprecated, so
you're encouraged to
use this new one.
OK, hope that wasn't
overly complicated.
I want to go back to the
driver site now.
I want to show you some of the
other drivers, in particular--
and there's a little bit of
inconsistency around this, so
you should realize it.
If you go into the Java driver,
it too now has a new
MongoClient class.
I'm going to click on
there for you fans.
Here's MongoClient.
It's a new class that was
released just last week.
Again, it's the new suggested
default so that you get J
equals 0, W equals 1
on new connections.
Now, to build the options
to MongoClient, do this.
And you can see one
of the options--
there's actually a
builder for this.
We haven't gone through
Java in this class.
Some of you are Java
developers--
I'm sure you're familiar
with this idiom.
But if you look here, there's
this concept of WriteConcern.
And this WriteConcern here,
again, this is a further
elaboration of what those
different modes do.
I've gone over W equals
0 and W equals 1.
You can see there's actually a
meaning for W equals minus 1,
don't even report
network errors.
And 2+, waiting for
the secondaries
and the replica sets.
We'll get to that in a second.
wtimeout, which we'll
talk about later.
And the J option.
So the interesting thing about
this for me is that it's
called WriteConcern, which sort
of grabs it all together
as a concept.
And I haven't seen that in the
Python driver, per se.
But generally speaking, when
people talk about WriteConcern
in MongoDB, they're talking
about the J and W parameters,
and maybe the wtimeout
parameter.
Talking about whether or not
you wait for writes to be
acknowledged, and whether you
wait for journaling on the
primary node that
you're hitting.
And then we'll get to the rest
when we get to replication.
All right, so just to summarize,
there is a new
class out there, I think in
all the drivers, actually,
called MongoClient.
And it replaces the previous
connection methods.
And the difference is that it
by default calls get last
error with W equals
1, J equals o.
All right.
Let's do a quiz.
In a 2.4 release of Pymongo
a new connection class is
introduced that automatically
sets W equals 1
and J equals 0.
It essentially defaults to what
used to be called safe
mode and replaces the old
connection class.
What is the name
of that class?
MongoSafe, SafeConnection,
MongoClient, or
FireAndRemember?
Check the right answer.