OK.
And the answer is it takes
a really long time.
So it probably, I actually tried
this on my computer, it
took at least 10
minutes or so.
At that point, you're subject to
the TCP timeout, which can
be extremely long.
Because basically, you've said
I want to wait until I get an
acknowledgement from
four nodes.
There's only three nodes, and
so it'll just time out.
So just generally speaking, this
is just a reminder that
you need to set the w timeout
if for any reason you think
there's a possibility that the
number of nodes that you're
asking to commit to, or
not commit to, but get
acknowledged from is greater
than the number that are up.
Like, if you put w equals 3, and
there's a possibility that
you're running in a state
where there's only two
nodes that's up.
All right.
That's it.