All right, so there's a couple
more things I wanted to show
you about JSON and the Mongo
shell before we move on to
building the rest of our
first application--
our very small application.
The first is that as we talked
about earlier, we can create
documents, which have some
hierarchy in them.
So in this one, I'm going to
create an "a" key, a "b" key,
as well as a "c" key.
Or I'll just call it fruits
again, or fruit.
And then I'm going to put in
that array, 'apple,' 'orange,'
and 'pear' and close
the parentheses.
I'm going to save that
into the collection.
Now if I do a db.thing.find,
I'll find
my document in there.
As you can see, again,
heterogeneous nature of the
collections.
So now we have a document with
"a," "b," and an array,
"fruit," with "apple," "orange,"
and "pear" in it.
And it can be nested
any way you want.
You might imagine that if I
was creating an address
record, for instance, I could
do something like this.
With my name is Andrew, and
my address, I could put a
sub-document right in here with
the street being "elm
drive" and the city being "Palo
Alto," and the zip being
94305, which I think
is Palo Alto's zip.
Maybe we need a house number
there, so we'll do a house
number, 34.
And I'm going to close that up
right there, and I'm going to
close that up.
Ooh--
I can see an error already.
I can go back in the shell and
see right there I didn't
actually make the whole
thing a JSON document.
So I'm going to put that in.
I'm using Emacs.
This is a Control-F to go
forward in the shell.
I think that, that's a
sub-document within the document.
So I need two closing
parentheses, and then I can
close it out.
And there we go.
And now let's look at
db.things.find, and let's do
it in a pretty way.
And there's a little Pretty
command inside the shell that
lets you print them out
in a pretty way.
And you see there, it's actually
scrolled off the
screen, but you can see this
final document I added has an
ID that's been assigned by the
database, a name of Andrew,
and then an address, which
is itself a sub-document.
And this sort of shows you the
hierarchy that can exist
inside MongoDB.
And we're going to get to this
later, but this is really well
suited to programming, because
when you have data structures
inside code, this is
the way your data
structures look, right?
They've got some hierarchy
to them.
They often have dictionaries.
This is really a dictionary,
if you think
about it, within Python.
They often have arrays, and you
can express that directly
inside Mongo so there's no
mismatch between the way the
data's expressed inside the
tables and the way the data is
expressed inside your program.
All right, let's do a quick
quiz based on what we just
learned and, again, try to
identify what valid Mongo
documents look like.
OK, next quiz.
Which of the following are
valid JSON documents?
You can check all that apply.