We're going to talk about
installing MongoDB on Windows,
so let's just go do that.
So we're going to go over to
the MongoDB site and just
download the tarball, or the
zip file, if you will, with
the MongoDB binaries.
The MongoDB site to downloads,
and then we'll pick which
downloads we want.
You'll see different
versions here.
Generally, you're going to want
the first one, which will
be the current production
release.
The even numbers for
the middle digit
are the stable releases.
The odd numbers for the middle
digit are the dev branch.
And here we see the release
candidate for the next stable
release, which will be 2.2.1.
But that's still a release
candidate, so
we'll stick to 2.2.0.
Over here are the
Windows builds.
Generally, you always want
to get the 64-bit build.
In MongoDB, the storage engine
uses memory map files, so for
larger databases, you need
the 64-bit binary.
So always default to that.
Use that in production.
If your desktop development
machine is
64-bit, use this version.
Because if that were the case,
both of these will work on
your desktop, but you'll want
to use this and just be
[? cluster ?] reduction.
If you do have 32-bit operating
system on your
desktop, that's OK.
For development, this
will be fine.
So grab whichever of these
is appropriate.
And of these two, you'll see
there's a special build here
under 64-bit called 2008+.
If you look at the bottom of
the page by the asterisk,
it'll give you more details
on this release.
If you click, it's going
to download it.
This release uses a new API
in Windows called Slim
Reader/Writer Lock which makes
the server perform a little
bit better, so use this
if you have a
newer version of Windows.
That would be Windows Server
2008 R2 and higher and Windows
7 and higher on the desktop
client side.
So I do have Windows 7 here,
I think, so I've
just downloaded this.
So now, if you click here,
it will download it.
I'm going to flip over to
Explorer, and we'll see what I
downloaded hopefully.
And here it is, under my
downloads directory.
So inside a zip file, it had the
readme and such, and then
the binaries are in here.
So what I'm going to do is put
this in a more convenient
location, so let's
go over here.
I'll just make a directory.
You could put this wherever
you like.
You may not be able to put it
off the top directory if you
don't have the right
privileges.
Let's try this, though.
Mongodb2_2.
And then we'll go back over to
here, and I'll actually open a
window for that.
I'll just drag and
drop these over.
So I'll grab all these,
drag them into here.
I'll extract them from the
zip file permanently.
OK, now we'll close this.
So we've now got these in the
directory called mondodb2_2,
so now we can go run it.
So it's pretty much
that simple.
We'll see the files here.
I think the key files here are
the mongod.exe, which is the
database, mongo.exe without
the D, which is the
administrative shell, and
mongos, which is the sharding
controller.
So to start the database, run
mongod.exe, and then to access
it for DBA and administrative
operations, use mongo.exe.
So let's do that.
Now, we'll need a directory to
put the files in, and the
default directory is backslash
data backslash db.
You can use whatever you want
if you specify the db path
command line setting,
but let's just
use the default here.
So I'm going to do that, and
then I'm going to make a
subdirectory under there
called that.
And that's the default, so
that way it's present.
We'll be all set.
The main database is mongod
without the B--
the D is for daemon--
[INAUDIBLE] .exe.
So there's that.
So if you like, you
could do this.
You can see what version
you have.
You can also do --help and get
a lot of details on the
command line options.
I will run this now, so just
mongod.exe, or just like that.
Run it.
We've created our data
directory, I believe.
Yeah, datadb exists, so
let's give this a try.
Access, and we're up.
So the database is running
now on my local machine.
It turns out this is a 32-bit
machine, so I've actually went
and grabbed the 32-bit version
of the binaries, because the
operating system
here is 32-bit.
But we're up and running.
So now, if we go over
to a different
window, we can try it.
So if you have some development
tools and clients
for your programming language,
you could try that now.
In addition, we can just go into
the administrative shell,
which is called mongo,
and connect to it.
So the mongo shell is sort of
just an administrative shell
like you might use with
another database.
So, we're just going
to connect here
to the local host.
By the default, it will connect
to local host in the
test database, and then you can
see the options here to
connect to whatever
you'd like.
So if I do this, that's sort of
equivalent to just running
it by itself.
And here we are, connected.
So we did connect to our server
here, and there is a
variable predefined called
db, which represents our
connection to the server.
So at this point, we could do
something like show dbs or
show collections in our
current db, and
there are not any.
So we could do something-- we
have the test database here
we're working with,
db.mycollection.insert.
And there we have some data
in there, so that's that.
Now we could exit the shell
with Control C, or
we could type exit.
And if we look in data db, we'll
now see that there are
some files over there.
Now, it is possible to
run MongoDB, v the
server, as a service.
There's a Windows service.
There's some command line
options for that.
And if we look in the Help,
or you could look in the
documentation, you
could find that.
I think you will see them--
scroll up.
There you go, Windows Service
Control Manager Options.
So I find that when I'm doing
development on a development
box, I just run it as
a foreground process
and not as a service.
On the server, you're probably
going to run it as a service.
So just doing something like
this I find perfectly adequate
on my [? devs ?] box, and same
thing when I run the mongos
process, for example, which is
the sharding controller.
But it can be done this way,
if you like, so just make a
note of that.
So I think that's it.
We have it installed.