Now that we have MongoDB
installed on our Windows
machine, next, we need to get
Python installed, because
we're going to use Python
in this class.
You may already have
Python installed.
And if you do have Python
installed, then that's great.
You don't need to install
it again.
But if you don't, you'll
want to just Google
for download Python.
And then if you go to the first
link right here, you'll
see that it's this
python.org page.
And we're going to go
for the Windows
installer right here, 2.7.3.
I'm going to click on it
and download that.
And then I'm going to show
that in the folder.
And I'm going to double
click on it.
I actually previously
downloaded it.
I'm going to run it.
Install for all users.
Python, Python, security
check.
Say yes.
All right, that is super.
So now what it does by default
is put that right into your C
drive, Python 2.7.
And what you're going to want to
do is add that directory to
your path just like we
did before so that
we can get to it.
So let's do that.
So we're going to go here,
type Computer.
And go to System Properties.
I'm going to go to Advanced
System Settings over here and
do Environment Variables.
Go down to my Path Variable.
It's right there.
And I'm going to edit it.
I'll go to the end of it.
The separator, again, seems
to be a semi-colon.
So type C drive, so it goes
in C drive, colon
slash Python 2.7.
So I've done that.
I'm going to say, OK, OK,
OK, and kill that.
Now, if I bring up a terminal
window, command prompt, and
type Python, I get the
Python interpreter.
Print hello world.
And it prints hello world.
Excellent.
So now we have Python installed
on our computer.
Next step is that we need to
get PyMongo installed.
And we need to get the small
bottle framework installed.
So in the next lesson, I will
show you how to do that on a
Windows machine.