OK.
The next step for us is
to install bottle.py.
This is the web framework we're
going to use to build
the blogging software.
If you're a Mac user, and
you've already installed
Bottle in the previous
segment, you
can skip this part.
This is for Windows
users only.
So I've gone into Google and
I've typed bottle.py into the
Google search engine.
And I'm going to click on
the first link here.
The first thing you notice is
that it says, this is a
preview release of 0.12 dev.
So where is the stable
release?
Well, if we go down here,
it says, stable release.
Ah, stable release.
And it makes the suggestion that
I would download it and
install it by running
easy_install, minus U, bottle.
But if you try that, you'll
quickly find out that you do
not have easy_install installed
on your Windows
machine because you do
not have setup tools.
So how do you get the setup
tools that will give you the
easy install that would let
you install Bottle?
Well, "download setup tools."
And when I did that in my
Google search engine--
Now, this was customized
to me.
So you might see slightly
different results.
But you need to go right here.
And it makes some suggestions
for how you're going to get
setup tools, which is going
to give you easy_install.
You probably have a 32-bit
version of Python, even if you
have a 64-bit machine.
Because it does run
32-bit binaries.
They suggest that you run
the .exe installer.
And so we will do that.
We'll go down.
And we are running Python 2.7.
That's what we downloaded
before.
So we're going to go for this
installer right here.
And now I'm going to run that.
And I'm going to agree
to the terms.
I'm going to say yes,
absolutely.
I would like to.
Oh, by the way, it said that
my Python executable is in
Python 2.7.
And it's going to put this stuff
in lib site-packages.
So that's fine.
Now I'm going to install it.
And now I am finished.
So I'm going to now go back
to my other window
and see what it said.
It said, "easy_install
-U bottle." OK.
Well, let's go and get a new
window, see if easy_install is
in my path now.
It's not.
It's in the Python directory.
So let's just go into there, cd
slash, cd Python 27, cd--
what did it say?
Scripts, I think.
So that's going to put
it in Scripts.
So I'm going to go into
the Scripts directory.
And there it is.
There is easy_install.
So I'm going to do
easy_intall, dot
exe, minus U, bottle.
OK.
That is great.
So now Bottle is installed.
And what version
did it install?
It said it had installed
version 0.11.3.
And going back to the page, that
is the stable release.
So we are happy with that.
So that is the way you
get Bottle installed.
And then in the next segment,
you can confirm it works using
the same Hello World program
that you use on a Mac.
It will work on both
platforms.
OK.