All right this segment is
provided for all the Windows
users out there who want a
little bit of help installing
PyMongo on Windows.
If you are a Mac user,
you don't need
to watch this segment.
It is for Windows users.
So let's see how this works.
I have a Windows VM here,
running on my Mac.
So it doesn't really matter
that it's virtualized.
But the window looks
a little weird.
That's what's going on.
So I'm starting out by going
to api.mongodb.org.
And that has a whole list of
different languages that we
support and the drivers.
And we're going to go into the
Python driver right here, into
the current one, which
is Python 2.5.
The screen's a little
bit small here.
Hopefully you'll be
able to see it.
We're going to go to
the installing
and upgrading section.
And you can see here that they
recommend that when using MS
Windows that you use
one of the Python
packaged installers here.
So we're just going to
go here to that.
And go to the bottom.
And see what's there.
And find the right one.
So let's see.
We are running PyMongo 2.5
when this was recorded.
And we want to find
the Win32 binary.
And we want to find the one for
Python 2.7, which is what
we've installed here.
It looks like this is it.
So I'm going to just click
on that and download it.
And then I'm going to run it.
It's going to bring
up this installer.
And looks like it finished.
So to test it, I have
a small program.
The program looks like this.
Again, a little bit small, but
I'll go through the details.
It's a very simple program.
It just picks up to a single
value from a collection.
Import PyMongo.
Then from PyMongo, Import Mongo
Client, right here.
And then we're going to connect
to the database, using
the Mongo Client class, and
then specifying that we're
connecting to local host,
and under the
default port of 27017.
We connect to the test
database, db equals
connection dot test.
And to the Names collection,
names equals db dots names.
And then we call Find One and
pass the return value to the
item variable.
Then we just print
that value out.
So let's see what happens
when we try that.
Python's been previously
installed.
So I call Python,
pymongo_getting_starged.py,
which is the program I just
showed you in Emacs.
And then we'll run that.
And when we do that, you
can see right here.
It says Andrew, which is what
is in the collection.
If we go in here, we call
Mongo and db.names.find.
There it is.
So there's the document.
And you can see right here it's
underscore id, which was
assigned when it was inserted
and then the name Andrew.
And the program printed out my
name right there when I ran
the program.
So now how PyMongo
is installed on
this Windows machine.
And you can do it the same
way on your computer.