OK.
Let's bring it all together
now and build a web
application.
We have MongoD installed.
And we have our application
layer over here.
And that's gonna be
written in Python.
And we have Pymongo installed.
And Pymongo is gonna talk
to MongDB at BSON.
And the last part is we want
to be able to display a web
page, via http.
And to do that, we're going to
write a program that uses the
bottle framework.
So I'll show you what a small
Hello World program looks like
to do that.
So I'm going to open up this
small program in emax.
We'll go through it
line by line so we
can see what it does.
So the first thing is
it imports bottle.
And then it imports Pymongo.
And then it creates a route for
/, which means the default
route of the web server.
So when you go to a web server
without any URL after the host
name, this is what you get.
This is a decorator telling
Python that the next function
is going to be executed when
the user hits that route.
And we call that index.
But there's nothing special
about that name.
And you could, in fact, call it
something else if you like.
The first step here is to use
the MongoClient class to
connect the local
host at 27017.
That's the default port that
MongoD listens on.
And then, again, we connect
to the test database.
db=connection.test.
And then to the names
collection.
db.names.
Then we find a single document
using the find one command
that's going to put
that document
into the item variable.
And then it's going to return,
basically, Hello whatever is
in the names key of
that document.
And this is a Python convention
that the %s will be
substituted by what's after
this percent sign.
In this case, item name.
Item's a dictionary.
And we're pulling out the
value for the name key.
That's the end of that function,
which is going to
run when you hit the /
route on the server.
And only thing left to
do is that we have to
tell bottle to run.
And to do that we call
bottle.run with host=localhost
the port=8082, which is a high
numbered port that we can get
to without being route.
So let's run it.
OK.
It says it's listening
on local host.
And now let's go to
a web browser.
And hit that URL.
And we can see it says
Hello Dwight.
And if you recall, Dwight was
in the database in the names
collection.
And if we make a change--
I'll do it over here.
Call Mongo.
Use test.
And then we do var j=
2 db.names.findone.
We can see the j is Dwight.
We could do j.name=Andrew.
And then we can do
db.names.save j.
And now Andrew is saved
into the collection.
Let's take a look and make
sure that's true.
It says Andrew is
now in there.
And now if we go back to our web
browser right here and run
it again, it changes
to Andrew.
So you can see, now we have an
end-to-end application that is
written in Python, that uses
bottle, and that uses Pymongo.
Connects to the database.
And then I can answer
an http request and
produce a web page.