All right, let's revisit
JSON now and talk
about what it can represent.
And then we're going to get to
why it can represent it.
There are only two basic data
structures inside JSON, and
they are arrays and
dictionaries.
Now, we all know what
arrays are.
Arrays are lists of things,
and dictionaries are these
associated maps.
So they can be combined
in arbitrary ways.
So an array inside JSON is
represented using these square
brackets and then a list
of items between.
And a dictionary is represented
using the curly
braces, and it's a bunch of
keyword and value pairs.
And then there's a keyword,
colon, and then a value.
And there could be arbitrary
numbers of these
separated by commas.
Those are the only two data
structures inside JSON, and
they're all just combined.
And they can be nested
in arbitrary ways.
So I can create a very
deep document.
So I can create a document,
for instance.
At the top level there has
to be a dictionary.
And I can create something
with a name,
and that has a value.
And then I could have a
city, and it can have
another value here.
And then I could put-- for
instance, if this is just a
collection of people and their
cities and maybe their
interests--
can have another key here
called interest.
And that could turn out
to be an array, and
it's got square brackets.
And then I could put
things in here.
And each of these in itself
could, of course, be its own
dictionary, which means it would
be represented using the
curly brace.
So we're going to build up
everything from these two
basic data structures.
The two basic data structures
are arrays and dictionaries.
Now we're going to go through
and show you each of these and
teach you how to write them.
And then we'll go from a higher
level and show how
they're used in data
representation relative to
relational databases.
All right, time for
the next quiz.
Write the JSON for a simple
document containing a single
key, fruit, that has as its
value an array containing
three strings, apple,
pear, and peach.
You're just going to write the
JSON document for that.