If you want to know more about
JSON, JSON is a standard.
And you can look it up
at www.json.org.
And this document over here,
this webpage, shows you JSON.
It's the same as I've told you
about, but there's some slight
different nomenclature
that I'll go through.
So rather than call it a
document at the highest level,
they call it an object.
And you can see that an object,
or document, can have
an arbitrary number of keys and
values and a colon between
the key and the value.
And then there's a comma between
each set of them.
And then the value can be a
bunch of different things.
If you go down the page, you
can see a value can be a
string, a number, or an object,
or it can be an array.
And then an array right
here is explained.
An array is just the sequence
of values that are separated
by a comma.
So this is essentially a more
formal representation of what
we've been talking about.
But you can see that this
standard allows for an
arbitrary nesting of arrays
and documents, or objects,
within the array.
And the value can be either an
array or another document.
And you can create these data
structures that are quite
complex and that map pretty
well to what you might see
inside your code.