If we wanted to model this blog
in a relational system,
you'd probably have tables that
look a lot like this.
And I'll take you through each
table and what it does.
So there would be
a post table.
And the post table would contain
the post itself as the
body of the post, as well as the
title of the post and the
date that it was posted.
I haven't put the types here.
Although we'd have to
specify the types in
a relational system.
And then there would probably
be a post ID, and then some
sort of author ID that
points to the author
that created the post.
The second table is
the comments tabe.
It's a critical table.
It would have the comments
that people
made on the blog post.
And this would be the name of
the commenter, the comment
itself, their email, and
probably an ID to identify it.
So it can be associated and
related to the posts.
And then the way this would work
is, there would also be a
tags table here which would have
the tag ID and the names.
And these are relations
tables over here.
So for instance, this post table
connects to this tags
table through this
post tags table.
This post tags table includes
the posts and all of the tags
that have been associated
with the post.
This post comments table
would relate this
table to this table.
And then, over here, this author
ID would be used right
in here, in this table.
It's a pretty standard
relational system
for building a blog.
You might decide to make it
a little bit more compact.
This is the fully denormalized
version of that.
You might be willing to put
the post ID right into the
comment system, since a comment,
probably, is only
associated with a single
blog post.
But this is the basic way
that you would build it.
So thinking about that, and now
it's time for a quiz, the
question is, how many tables
do you need to access to
present the front page
of the blog?
So that's the quiz.
So there are one, two, three,
four, five, six
tables in this system.
And if you wanted to present the
front page of this blog,
you would have to do a bunch
of selects, obviously, and
joins between these
different tables.
How many tables would you have
to access to present the front
page of the blog?
OK, time for a quiz.
Let's look back at that blog
schema that we just created.
And let's assume that our blog
can be modelled with the
following relational tables.
And you can see them here--
authors table, posts table,
comments table, post comments,
tags, and post tags.
If you want to display a blog
post with all of it's comments
and tags, how many tables
would you need to access
within the system?