Let's talk about modeling
our blog in MongoDB.
So we've seen how we might
model it in relational.
But now let's talk about how
we might model it in Mongo.
So it's a lot easier because
you could imagine that we'd
have a collection called,
let's say, posts.
And I'm going to show by example
what would be in the
posts collection.
So we might have a post title,
like, free online classes,
along with the body itself of
the post, which I won't show,
just put some ellipses in for
that, along with the user name
of the-- let's call
him the author.
And for that, I'm going to put
my name right into the
collection.
I'm not going to put an ID in.
And the reason is, and I'm going
to show you, that we're
going to use this as the ID for
our other collection, the
author's collection.
So we have a title
of the post.
We have the body the post.
We have the author
of the post.
We need the date that
it was posted.
And we'll have some iso date
here, we'll talk more about
types later on.
And then we'll probably
want some comments.
But in Mongo, we can embed them
right in the document.
So the comments keyword
is right there.
I open up an array.
And then I'm going to
have a document.
And it's going to have a name of
my poster, Joe Biden, along
with his email, if he gave it,
joe@whitehouse.gov, along with
the body of his comment, which
we'll just call it comment.
And we can have multiple of
these comments right here in
the document.
It might be very natural
do that.
And it is very natural
to do that.
Tags work the same way.
So rather than have a separate
collection of tags, we'll just
put the data right in here.
So I'll have a tags keyword
in this document.
This is the highest
level here.
It's the same level as
title and comments.
And I'll put tags right in--
cycling, education, startups.
So I probably only need one
more collection from this.
I probably need some sort
of authors' collection.
And this authors collection
is going to have things
like my user name.
But rather than have it called
username, this is what we're
going to do.
We'll get to this this
a little bit
later, how that works.
In the authors collection, we're
going to keep the user
name, but we're going to do is,
we're actually going to
make the _ID of the object
be the user name.
We haven't talked too much about
this yet, and we'll get
to it later.
But every document needs to have
a unique ID inside Mongo.
The system will assign a unique
identifier to the
object if you don't
assign one.
But if you have a natural,
unique identifier that can't
be duplicated inside the object,
you can use that.
So in this case, the username
has to be unique in the
system, so we're going to
use that as the ID.
And then, probably have the
password, which will be some
sort of encrypted and hashed
version of my password.
And you might have some
other information
about the user as well.
And that's it.
I mean, that's the basic
structure you need to
represent the same data inside
MongoDB that took six tables
inside the relational system.
And it's hierarchical.
So every post will have a title,
an author, a date,
comments, which will
be an array
of the JSON on documents.
If the email is missing from any
given comment, if doesn't
need to be there, you could
leave it out because since
MongoDB is schemaless, it's
flexible about that.
The tags, I could put the
tags right in here.
I can have multiple listed.
So I've sort of turned the
relational model on its side,
and I've taken things that would
be embedded in separate
tables, and that would
probably related with
relationships, and I've put
them right into the same
document as a list or
as a subdocument.
It's very convenient.
All right.
So that's how you'd model this
blog inside the document.
All right, time for a quiz.
Given the document schema that
we proposed for the blog in
this lesson, how many
collections would we need to
access, to display, the blog
homepage, which would include
top 10 blog posts, and their
comments, and the author.
Enter your answer here
by choosing one
of these four answers.