We're going to get to schema
design a little bit later in
this course.
But I wanted to just introduce
some of the questions that
arise when you're designing a
document oriented schema.
With relational, it's pretty
straightforward
to design the schema.
You typically go for the third
normal form, and then maybe
you combine a few things.
But with mongoDB and document
oriented designs, how do you
know whether to embed or not?
For example, in the schema that
we finally decided on for
this problem, the post
collection had a tags array
right inside it.
And the tags array had tag names
that potentially might
be duplicated across the
different posts.
So y embed that versus put
it into a separate tags
collection.
You have the same question
for the comments.
Why did we embed those verses
having a separate collection?
And the answer is, because
they're typically accessed at
the same time you access
the posts.
It's very rare that you would
need to access the tags
independently of accessing a
post or access the comments
independently of accessing
a post.
And the comment itself doesn't
apply to more than one post.
Now, it is true, in the case of
the tags, if this is, let's
say, cycling, and
this running.
If we wanted to change the
word cycling to biking in
every single post, that would be
kind of tedious since it's
not relationally connected.
But this is an unusual change
to make it, something you're
not going to make
all the time.
And so it makes sense that you
would put these tags directly
into the post collection
itself.
And generally, when you're
deciding whether to embed or
not to embed, it's going to be
the way you access the data
that's going to decide that,
along with some other
practical considerations.
For example, in mongoDB,
a document can't be
more than 16 megabytes.
So if you were going to have
more than 16 megabytes of
comments, which would be
extremely unusual, then you'd
have to put the comments
themselves into a separate
collection.
So now it's time for quiz.
In which scenario is it
impossible to embed data
within a document?
That is, in which scenario do
you have to put the data in a
separate collection?
Check all that apply.