All right, so we're going to
use Python in this class to
build a blog.
And that you can use whatever
language you want, but Python
is going to be the language we
use for all the example code.
And it's going to be the one
we go into most deeply in
terms of drivers.
So if you know Python,
that's great.
You can skip this part.
It's completely optional.
If you don't know Python, then
we're going to do a small
tutorial on Python in the
next few lessons.
You can learn it, or there are
lots of resources online to
learn Python.
But this should be enough to get
you started and using the
language if you're an
experienced programmer in any
other language.
So Python is a scripting
language.
It was created by Guido
Von Rossum.
It is named after Monty Python's
Flying Circus.
It strives to be readable.
And I think it is actually quite
readable compared to a
lot of other languages.
It is garbage collected, which
means you do not need to worry
about managing your own
memory, which is nice.
And it is dynamically typed.
And there's a bunch of other
features and aspects of
Python, but we won't go into
them right this second.
Also, just generally speaking,
if your experienced with Perl,
Perl sort of believed that there
was always more than one
way to do everything.
And Python looks more toward
creating idioms to do things
in a standard way so that
the code is readable and
understandable by
someone else.
So let's get started.
The first thing we're going
to do is run the Python
interpreter interactively.
And normally, you're going to
create a Python script and
you're going to edit it
with a text editor.
And then you'll run it.
But in this case, for this
lesson, we're actually going
to run interactively.
So I started the Python
interpreter by typing Python.
And then I'm going to use
the print command to
print Hello, world!
And you can see how
that works.
And you can see that strings
in Python are represented
within double quotes.
If you want to concatenate two
strings, you can do that using
the plus operator.
So Hello Dwight.
And you can do this using
multiple strings.
You can see how this puts some
spaces in to make this a
little bit more readable.
Print Hello Dwight
and Richard.
That's the first lesson.
Here's the quiz.
Right an expression to
concatenate two strings, hat
and pin, in Python, to
the string hatpin.
And we're just looking through
the expression here, so no
assignment to a variable
or anything else.