Next, I'd like to show you how
you check whether a particular
item is in a list.
Let's say that we have a
list of three fruits.
A equals apple, pear, orange.
We want to know whether or not
pear appears in the list.
We can use the in operator.
Pear in a.
That evaluates to true.
How about grape?
Grape in a, evaluates
to false.
And then I'll teach you the
conditional statement to test
this, since you normally
won't be in the shell.
You could say, if pear
in a, colon--
there's a colon required at the
end of the if statement.
And so here's our conditional
statement, pear in a, and then
the colon at the end,
I'm going to indent,
print, there is a pear.
And the statement, and then it
prints, there is a pear,
because there was a pear.
And if we do that exact same
test, but with a fruit that
was not in there,
like a grape, if
grape in a, then print.
There is a grape.
It prints nothing because
there is no grape.
This is very useful when you get
data back from Mongo and
it's in an array, and you want
to check whether a particular
item is in the structure,
you can use the in
operator to do it.
Here's the quiz.
Let's talk about Python lists
and checking for inclusion.
Given a Python list called
fruit, write an if statement
to check whether apple
is in the list.
Type your answer right here.