Let's talk about list slices.
List slices allow you to
access parts of lists.
If you have a list a, and you
want to get part of the list,
you could specify a start:end.
Now the start is the starting
index into the list where you
want to return a value.
And indexes in Python
lists start at zero.
And then end is the ending value
you want to return or
the ending index, I should
say, but again, it's
exclusive of this.
So for example, if you say a
0:1, that's just going to give
you the very first element
in the list.
So if you think of them as
this being the zero-th
element, one element, two
element, third element.
You say I want 0:1, it's going
to get you the zero-th element
all the way through the first
element but exclusive of the
first elements because it
doesn't include that.
So we say a 0:3, you'd get 0,
1, 2, and not the third.
And a 2:3, that's going
to give you--
it's the zero-th element, the
first element, the second
element, so it's going to
give you this element.
And then it's not going to give
you this element because
it doesn't give you
the end point.
a 2:4, that's the fourth,
remember they start at zero--
0, 1, 2, 3, 4, we'll give
you, let's see, 0, 1, 2.
So it would give you
this element.
And then it would give
you this element.
And it wouldn't give you this
element because it's exclusive
of the ending point
that you specify.
And the final thing you need
to understand about this is
that if you leave out a value,
at the beginning or the end,
it assumes the beginning
or end.
So if we say a 2 colon, that's
going to be the second element
all the way to the
end of the list.
If you say a :4, that's going
to be the beginning of the
list all the way through
the element with
the index of three.
0, 1, 2, 3.
Let's look in the shell,
see how this works.
We have a list here and we've
put in elements that have the
same values as their ordinal
positions inside the list, to
make it easy for us.
We're going to say a, give me
the zero-th elements through
the third element.
And that provides 0, 1, 2
because, again, it's exclusive
of the third element.
a 2:3, that provides just the
element with index two.
If we put 2 colon but don't give
an end, now it's going to
apply the entire rest
of the list.
So we get the rest of the
list, 2, 3, 4, 5.
If we specify the beginning of
the list all the way to the
sixth element, now there is no
sixth element, of course, it's
exclusive of the
sixth element.
So it's going to
be 0 through 5.
And that's at the beginning
of the list.
We should get the entire
list back and we do.
And then, if you leave at the
beginning and the end, then
you get the entire list back.
That sort of makes
logical sense.
So that's how these
list slices work.
And they're very useful because
you're often looking,
in Mongo, if you get back up a
bunch of items, and let's say
you wanted to print the first
one and then print the rest of
the list, you could do it very
easily using a slice operator.
All right, now it's time
for a quiz on the
slice operator in Python.
Let's say we have the list
apples, orange, pear, grape,
kiwi, and we want to figure out
the slice notation that
will returned just the
sublist orange, pear.
Orange, pair.
Type that right here.