Let's go over Python dicts.
So Python dicts--
Python dictionaries, are very
similar to the JSON objects
that we saw earlier.
Now there are some small
differences, and I'll show
those to you.
You initialize dictionary
much the same way you
initialize an object.
So if I wanted to create a small
dictionary in Python,
assign it to the variable a, say
a equals squiggly brace,
and then name:bob and
age colon 20.
That just works.
Now one difference between a
Python dictionary and a JSON
document is that Python doesn't
retain any order for
the items inside the list.
So it doesn't have any notion,
let's say, name being an
earlier key than age.
And so, as a result, inside the
Python drivers, you'll see
that they don't use the exact
dictionary class.
They use something that
is very similar to the
dictionary, but retains the
order as needed for JSON.
If I want to reference
something, I
use a square brackets.
That's a very similar notation
as for the lists.
So if I want to get the name, I
say a, square bracket, name.
Now if I use this on the right
side of an expression, I'm
going to get back the name.
And if I used it on the left
side of the expression, I'm
going to wind up assigning
to the name.
So if I say, that's Jim,
that's going to be an
assignment, and if I say that's
the variable b = a of
name, well, if I do it after
that, then it's going to
assign b, Jim.
You can also remove an item from
the dictionary much in
the same way you remove
something from an array.
You can use delete functions,
like, say delete a of name,
and it will delete that.
Now, it needs to exist
in order for
that to be legal call.
And we'll talk about how you
check about whether or not
something is in a dictionary.
So let's go into a terminal
window and take a look at some
of the things we just did.
I'm going to create a dictionary
with name colon
myname, city_of_birth
colon Queens.
And now, if I just print out
that expression, I'll see
what's there.
If I printed out g of name,
I'll get Andrew Erlichson.
If I set g of name, equal to
Dwight Merriman, then that'll
change my dictionary.
If I want to know all
the keys that are in
here, I can call g.keys.
But look what happened there.
That's what I talked
about before.
It gave me my city of birth back
as the first key-- this
is a list-- and my second
key as name.
This is the opposite order we
put them into the list.
And that's why I said that
Python does not retain the
order of the keys but JSON
does-- a small subtlety.
If I want to remove something,
I can do that.
I'm going to delete g is
the name of the list,
name, that's fine.
If I delete an item that's not
in there, that is an error.
I'll show you that.
That's an error.
However you can check, using
the in operator, whether or
not a particular key is
in the dictionary.
So I could say city of birth
in g, and that's true.
If I said foo in g,
that's false.
And I can use that exactly the
same way I used it when I was
checking inclusion in lists.
Now, you'll notice that when I
use the in operator in a list,
it goes through each of the
items in the list and checks
whether or not the value
is an item in the list.
When I use the in operator with
a dictionary, it checks
whether or not the item I'm
checking is a key in the
dictionary.
So it looks for city
of birth as a key.
It did not look for
it in the values.
OK, so that's the way
dictionaries work in Python.
Time for a quiz.
Initialize a new Python
dictionary name colors with
the key pairs sky, being
blue, sea, being blue,
earth, being brown.
Type your answer right here.