All right, now we're going
to go over how for
loops work in Python.
For loops are a control
flow structure
that's in most languages.
And I'm sure you're familiar
with for loops if you've used
Java, or C, or C++.
We're just going to look at how
they work inside Python.
To do that, we're going to
switch to editing a file
versus using the Python
interpreter
from the command line.
Because I want to show you
a few things about that.
So we have here list of fruit
which I've initialized with
apple, orange, and grape.
And there's a comment here,
starting with a pound sign, to
initialize the array.
Then we have a secondary array,
new fruit, a secondary
list that's been initialized
to be empty.
And then here's the for
loop right here.
For item in fruit (colon).
Now item is a variable
name that I chose.
It has there been declared
before because you don't need
to declare anything
inside Python.
It's all dynamic.
And then inside this loop, you
can see, it's important that
we indent because the control
flow is applied through
indentation in Python.
And I've indented here and
printed each item as I find it
in the list.
So I expect it to print out
apple, orange, and grape.
And then I also will
append the item to
the new fruit list.
So new fruit.append item.
And then at the end, I just
print new fruit, which depends
on Python's ability to print
lists and dictionaries
without, really,
any assistance.
Now you'll notice that there's
some syntax-based
highlighting here.
And this is the eMacs running
in Python mode.
I would definitely suggest that
you used some sort of
editor that can do syntax-based
highlighting, and most can.
It makes it a lot easier
to find bugs.
You'll also notice that there's
an extra line here.
And that'll have no impact on
the execution of this loop.
This is within the loop body
because it's indented at the
same level as the proceeding
statement.
All right, so let's
see what happens
when we run this thing.
All right, I'm going to run
it by typing Python,
for_loops.py.
And does pretty much
what we expect--
prints out apple, orange, grape,
and then prints out the
new fruit list, which is
apple, orange, grape.
So that's great.
Let's change it so that new
fruit is not indented.
Let's see what happens.
Let's save it, which, in eMacs,
is crtl-X, crtl-S. Then
I'm going to go back
here and run it.
And now, I still get apple,
orange, grape, but then, when
I print out new fruit,
I just get grape.
So what happened there?
And what happened there is that
rather than have this
append executed every time
through the loop body, it's
only being executed once with
the final value that item took
when the for loop excited.
And so it prints out something
that has one
item in versus three.
So again, in Python this is
probably the most unusual
thing if you're used to Java C,
or C++, is that the actual
indentation matters.
It indicates to the Python
interpreter whether or not
something is part of the
proceeding block or whether or
not it's its own block.
All right, now they know about
for loops, I'd like you to
tell me what this
code prints out.
And put it right here.
Type what it prints
out right here.