We've looked at how we would
iterate through a list.
And we've looked at how we
would iterate through a
dictionary.
But what if it was a more
typical JSON document, which
has a dictionary at the outer
level and then, often, an
array or a list within it.
So how do we do that?
So here I have a person record
with a name set to my name and
a favorite color set to blue,
and a hair color set to brown.
And then the interest key is
actually set to a Python list.
And this is Python code sitting
inside a file on my
disk called for_loop_dict.py.
So I want to iterate through
this structure,
so how do I do it?
Well, I know a little
bit about the data.
And I'm going to use
that knowledge to
iterate through it.
So for key in person, I can
get each key that's in the
person record.
I don't know what order I'm
going to get them in.
I might get name.
I might get favorite
color first.
But I check it.
And if key == and that's the
equality conditional inside
Python, if it == interests,
well then I know that I'm
looking at the list.
So then, just for clarity, I
print the word interests, and
then I have a secondary
for loop.
And again, you can see this is
indented at the same level as
the print statement, indicating
that this is part
of that block.
And then for each interests, and
again, I just made up that
variable name, inside
person key--
now at this point key is equal
to the word interests.
So for each interest in,
essentially, this array, print
a tab, just to make it neater.
And when it's double quoted, it
will interpolate and find
these types of characters
within that are special
characters, for instance
backslash t is a tab.
Print the interest is, and then
it concatenates it with
the interest that it got
right from this array.
So it concatenates it
with the interest.
And its course iterating
through the array--
cycling, running, biking.
Now, if it's not looking at the
key with value interests,
well then it just does a normal
thing it did before,
which is just, prints
the top level key.
And then it dereferences
it person key.
All right, so let's see
what that does.
So I go here, and now I'm going
to run this program.
And it does pretty much
what you'd expect.
The first key it finds is hair,
which was not the first
key put in, but that's OK.
And it prints out that
the value is brown.
And then it winds up finding
the interests.
And so then it iterates through
that inner list.
And it prints out interested in
cycling, running, biking.
These are in the same order they
were put in because lists
are certainly ordered
in Python.
And they were ordered
in JSON as well.
And then it finds the favorite
color value, blue, and the
name value being Andrew
Erlichson.
So using this type of technique,
you can print out
any complex data structure that
comes out of MongoDB.
Now you could also do it using
introspection, if some of you
have heard of introspection,
checking whether something is
a list or is a dictionary.
And you could do the
appropriate thing.
But often the code understands
the schema enough that it
doesn't need to do that.
It just knows that the interest
would always be a list.
All right next quiz.
Let's combine some dictionaries
and lists again.
Tell me what this
code prints out.
This is a named object to set
equal to this dictionary.
And here's some code that does
some checking for inclusion
and then runs a loop.
Type what this code will
print out right here.