Sometimes life does not go
exactly as you'd expect.
In Python it's no different.
And to handle those situations
where an error occurs, there
is exception processing.
And I'm going to talk a little
bit about how exception
processing works within Python
and how you can catch
exceptions that are
raised by code.
So let's go over a very simple
program that divides by zero.
So here you can see, does a
print 5 divided by zero.
And then it tries to print,
but life goes on.
Now, if you try to run this
program, what you'll find out
is that it crashes.
You can see the program
crashes.
And it points out the line that
causes the crash, which
is line three.
And it even tells
you the error.
Now what if you want to handle
that error inside your program
and continue?
How would you do that?
Well, to do that, you would need
to catch the exception.
There's a standard way
to catch exceptions.
Here's the same program with
it a try/except block.
Now you can see here,
it say try, try, and
then it says except.
So it tries to print
5 divided by 0.
And if an exception is
raised, it'll go down
to the except block.
And this is except block without
exception type listed,
so it catches all exceptions.
And then here it just prints
the exception type.
And this little idiom here,
assists.exc_info function
call, 0th element of the
list will print out
the exception name.
You have to import sys
in order to be able
to call this method.
So if this works as we expect,
then after the exception is
raised, we should be
able to go on.
Let's see what happens.
I'm going to run this
new program
with exception handling.
And in this case, you can see
that it prints out exception,
zeroDivisionError.
But then it prints,
but life goes on.
And you're going to be able to
use the same techniques using
try/except to catch exceptions
when trying to store data to
MongoDB, which is important
because if an exception is
raised when trying to store
data to MongoDB, then your
data, probably, was
not stored.
In which case, you might want to
retry or do something else.