OK, now we're going to talk
about how you handle form
inputs in the Bottle
in Python.
Now this is not a full course
in web design, and we're not
going to be testing you heavily
on whether or not you
understand this stuff.
And we're going to give you a
lot of the code and tell you
how it works.
And again, this material is
somewhat optional, but I just
want to give you a basic
understanding of it so that
you aren't seeing it for the
first time in some of the
assignments down the
road in the class.
So when you do get to a page,
in a web page, for instance,
an index page, then it will
produce the content.
In this case, we're going to
have a little form on the page
itself using the form tag.
And then we're going to specify
that, on that page,
the response get posted
to a post handler at
favorite_fruit, and you'll
understand why in a second.
And that generates some code,
which then produces some
output HTML.
So that's the basic flow of how
you handle form inputs in
Python in Bottle.
And let's take a look
at an example.
So, I'm going to run
this small Python
script that I wrote.
And go to the home page for
the web server on 8080.
You can see it says Welcome
Richard, and it says that
there's apple, orange,
banana, and peach.
What is your favorite fruit?
And then if you type in peach
and submit it, it says, oh,
your favorite fruit is peach.
So how do we make that work?
Pretty straightforward.
Here is the code.
This is the fruit
form.py program.
This is the home page at the
route slash, sets up that list
again, and returns that same
template we saw before where
it sets username to Richard
and things to mythings.
And I'll show you
that template.
Here's that template
right now.
You can see that this template
prints out, the title is Hello
World, it says Welcome to the
person, it iterates through
the list of things,
printing each one
out as a list element.
And then here's the new part.
There's now a form within
the template.
And the form has an action of
slash favorite_fruit, which
means that the web browser will
submit your answer to the
favorite fruit URL.
And the method is
post, not get.
It asks if your favorite fruit,
oh, I see that guy
there, we'll just
correct that.
That's what is your
favorite fruit.
There we go.
And its got two HTML form
elements on it.
The first one is a text box
with name fruit, size 40.
Value is blank at
the beginning.
And then underneath it, there's
a submit button.
And then the form ends,
and the body of the
HTML document ends.
And then finally the
HTML itself ends.
So that's it.
And then you can see right
here that there's a new
handler defined, which we
haven't talked about before.
It is a post handler.
So a post handler takes a post
request versus a get request,
and this post request is
at URL favorite_fruit.
And defines a function called
favorite_fruit.
And it has to get the form
element, which it does by
calling
bottle.request.forms.get.fruit,
quotes around the string
its looking for.
That gets the form element
that was named
fruit on the form.
If it's not set, it just sets
it to no fruit selected.
And then it returns this other
template called fruit
selection template, with
fruit set to fruit.
The fruit string set to the
fruit inside they dictionary
it passes the template.
So we just need to look at that
fruit selection template.
That fruit selection temple
is very simple.
It just says fruit selection
confirmation.
And then it says your favorite
fruit is, and it says fruit
right here.
And these curly braces surround
a piece of Python
code, in this case, the fruit
variable that was passed in.
So that might be a lot to take
on at one time, but if you
know anything about web
programming, you know how this
stuff works.
It's fairly straightforward.
And again, for this class,
you're not really need to
understand this because
we're going to give
you most of the GUI.
We'll mostly focus on the
MongoDB parts of it.
But I wanted to make this course
complete so that you
guys could understand what we're
talking about with this
user interface for the blogging
system that we're
going to create in MongoDB.