OK, let's talk about cookies.
And I'm not talking about the
kind you eat, of course.
I'm talking about the kind
that web servers and web
browsers use to identify
users.
So most session management on
the web is done through
cookies, where a cookie is
returned from the web server
to the web browser.
It's a small piece of
information that the web
browser will store away for
the particular web domain.
And then whenever the user goes
to any web page in that
domain, then the web browser
will present the cookie to the
site, which will then,
hopefully, look it up in
Mongo, get a whole bunch of
other information and present
the session to the user.
So let's go through our small
example program and see how we
can use cookies.
Let's say that I want to have
my program here, which says
Hello to Richard, lists
four fruits, asks
you to pick a fruit.
I'm going to say apple
and submit.
At this point, the web browser
has been redirected to the
show_fruit URL and somehow
printed out,
your fruit is apple.
It looks kind of like it did
before, but the difference is,
it wasn't a post, it was
actually a redirect to a page
with a get request, so that I
can reload it as many times as
I want, and it works.
And the way it's done, this is
a little cookie utility that
you can download from Google.
This is Google Chrome.
You can see that there
is a cookie being
presented to the site.
And that cookie has the
word apple in it.
So how does the code
make all that work?
Let's look.
Here we have again, if you
recall, here's our handler,
the post handler, that will take
the form input from that
form that asks them their
favorite fruit.
And in this handler, we do a
get of the fruit from the
form, and then all we do is set
the cookie, bottle that
response, that set cookie,
called fruit, to the value
that we got from the user.
And then we redirect--
this is something you
haven't seen before.
We redirect the browser
to /show_fruit.
That sends a HTTP response to
the browser telling it to
redirect the browser and fetch,
using a get request,
another page.
And if you think about
the whole world of
Model-View-Controller that we
talked about earlier, this has
a nice property that now the
view doesn't need to have any
information sent to it directly
from the controller.
Because what happens is,
instead, we redirect to this
view, and the view then
fetches the the
state, again, itself.
So it's a little cleaner.
And particularly on the web, if
the user ever refetches the
page, you can't refetch a page
that was generated as a result
of a post request without, I'm
sure you've all seen this,
saying, do you want to resubmit
the form information
and reprocess that
form information.
Well, using this method with a
redirection, using a get to
enter the URL, the user can
refetch the show fruit page.
So OK, so that happens.
And then we go down the page and
we can see the route set
up for this get request
for show_fruit.
It's very simple.
And here is the function
show_fruit, which is
arbitrarily named.
And the first thing it does is
it gets the cookie called
fruit and then returns exactly
the same template it did
before, setting fruit
to fruit.
Now what's maybe not clear is
that, when we go from this
line to this line, that involves
a full response and
new request from the
web browser.
So control is not passing
inside the server
from here to here.
What's happening is, there's a
response to the user with a
redirect to the show fruit URL,
and in that response the
browser stores away a cookie.
The browser then does a get
request to /show_fruit.
Since it's the same domain,
it presents the cookie.
And then the web server, when it
processes this get request,
fetches the cookie out
of the request, and
produces the HTML.
I know that might be a little
bit tricky, but this is only
cookies work.
And particularly, this is the
way you get them and set them
inside Bottle.