All right.
We've talked about how
PyMongo works.
And I've also shown you a little
bit about how exception
processing works
within Python.
And I want to bring those two
concepts together right now
and show you how exception
processing and
PyMongo work together.
Now, I've written a small
program here that's going to
create a document with
first name Andrew
and last name Erlichson.
And it's going to insert
it into MongoDB.
So before it does that,
it prints it out.
And then it does the
insert right here.
And then it checks to make sure
that if an exception was
thrown that it prints insert
failed and that it prints
using this sys.exc_info,
it prints out the
exception that occurred.
And then after that, it prints
the document again and then
inserts it again into
the database again.
So let's see what happens when
we run this program.
So we're going to run this
program, which is called Mongo
Exception, and see
what happens.
So let's see.
It printed out the document
before it
inserted it right here.
And we can see here that it's
just last name Erlichson,
first name Andrew.
Then it inserts the document.
And then after it inserts the
document, this document looks
like right here.
Now, this is the second
print statement.
Let me just show you
where that occurs.
So it prints the document
before it inserts it.
And then it inserts it.
And then it prints it again.
And then it inserts it again
and then prints it a third
time after the insert.
Now, when it tries to insert the
second time, you can see
it gets an error, which is
caught in the try-catch block.
And it prints out the
insert failed.
And it gives you the error
itself, which is a
duplicate key error.
That's a little bit unusual.
And then it shows the document
that it tried to insert, which
you can see is the same document
that existed in the
variable after the
first insert.
So let's understand what's
happening here.
So initially, we had
a document with
no underscore ID.
The driver itself added an
underscore ID when it did the
insert into the database.
And then when we went to insert
the same document
again, because the driver also
added it to the variable doc
right here--
so at this point, we printed
after the insert.
It had an underscore ID field.
And then, on the second insert,
it failed because all
the underscore IDs
must be unique.
And as a result, this was a
conflict, because it was
attempting to insert a document
that had the same
underscore ID.
And if we look in the actual
collection, you should see
that it only is in there once.
So let's look and see
if that's true.
So let's look at
db.users.find.
And there's the document.
We can print it out pretty.
You can see there's
the document.
And it's only in there once,
because the second one failed.
Now, if we wanted to really
insert it twice, we have lots
of options.
And one of them would be
to go in right here
and reassign to doc.
So after the first insert right
here, we could reassign
to the document variable,
which will clear out the
underscore ID field.
And now, when we do the
second insert, it
should be just fine.
So let's do that.
Just to get the same
precondition, let's drop the
collection.
And we'll confirm that there's
nothing in there--
nope, nothing in there.
Let's run it.
And now we get no error.
After the second insert,
of course, there is
an underscore ID.
And we look in MongoDB, you
can see I'm in there twice
with two different underscore
IDs right there, two different
underscore IDs.
And the driver has generated an
underscore ID for each of
these inserts, because the
document didn't have one when
the driver got it.
So remember, if you don't
specify an underscore ID, the
driver will add one for you and
will also insert it into
your variable so you
can see it after
the insert is complete.
And if it does throw any
exceptions for any reason in
the insert, then you can catch
them and print out the
exception itself using
this call right here.
So that is how exceptions
interact with PyMongo in
mongod to provide you debugging
information when
writing your Python programs.