OK.
I'm going to go over the
solution to Homework 1.
In Homework 1, we asked you
to download a small tar
file and expand it.
I'm going to do that
right now.
And in that file, you'll
see there are--
there's one directory, a dump
directory, that has a bunch of
subdirectories and then has
one subdirectory, and then
there's some bson
files in that.
That's just a standard
dump file that you
get from Mongo dump.
And then there's 2 py files.
Then I run mongorestore.
On that dump, it created the
m101 database and brought the
collections in.
I'm going to go into Mongo.
I'm going to use m101 and
show collections.
The one we need is called
homework 1.
I'm going to look at homework 1
and see what's inside it and
see that there is one document
with an answer 42.
That's the answer to the
question of "The Ultimate of
Life, of the Universe and
Everything" from Hitchhikers
Guide to the Galaxy.
So that's the answer
to Homework 1.