The goal of this homework was
to make sure that you got
PyMongo and Bottle installed
and that that
would all run for you.
So we gave you a program that
you needed to run from the
command line hw1-3.py,
which starts up a web
server on port 8080.
And then we asked you to
go to a particular URL.
And I'll show you that URL.
And the URL we asked you
to go to was hw1/50.
And if you did that, it would
print out the value of 53.
And that was the answer
to the assignment.
If we look at the program--
we'll take a quick look at this
program-- it uses some
things that are not yet
covered in the course.
And the program was supposed
to be a little bit more
complicated so that it would be
hard for you to run without
actually getting it running--
hard for you to run from the
command line, that is.
But it's not that hard
to understand it.
You can see that the first
thing it does--
it has a function
called get_hw1.
And it's decorated with this
decorator calling into the
Bottle package, basically,
saying that if you go to this
/hw1 URL with any sort of string
appended at the end,
that it will run this function
and hand you the
n value as an integer.
And it makes an int out of that
string and connects to
the funny numbers collection
in the m101 database.
And then it does a skip and a
limit to skip the first n
value, skip the next value,
and then print that
out to the web page.
So basically, when you ask for
the 53rd element, it's saying,
skip 53 of them and limit 1.
So I guess you're getting the
54th element at that point.
And then at the very end of the
program, it runs Bottle in
debug mode and runs it on local
host and port 8080.
And that is what this
program is doing.