OK, let's talk about the
election that goes on when the
primary fails, and the different
types of nodes that
can exist in a replica set.
So first there is the regular
type of node, and that node,
which is the one I showed in the
earlier lesson is a node
that has the data, and
can become primary.
And it's the most normal
type of node.
It can be a primary
or a secondary.
Now, the next type of node
is an arbiter node.
An arbiter node is just there
for voting purposes, and
there's lots of reasons
why you might want
to use one of these.
For example, if you want to have
an even number of replica
set nodes, then you need to
make sure that there's an
arbiter node out there, so that
when one goes down, you
still have a majority,
a strict majority
to vote a new leader.
So that's one reason why you
might want to use an arbiter.
Or if you just want to put
together a replica set, let's
say with three nodes, but only
two of them are real nodes,
and one of them is an arbiter
because you only have two
machines, you can
do that as well.
And an arbiter, of course,
will participate in the
voting, as will a
regular node.
Another type of node
is a delayed node.
That's often a disaster
recovery node.
It can be set to be, let's
say, an hour, two hours,
whatever you want behind
the other nodes.
And it can participate in the
voting, so that's yes of the
voting, but it cannot become
a primary node.
And to achieve this, its
priority is set to zero.
And you can set the priority
of any node to zero if you
want, and it cannot be elected
to be a primary node.
And then the final type of node
is a hidden node, and a
hidden node is a node that is
often used for analytics.
It cannot become the primary
node, so it's not going to be
the primary.
Never the primary.
But it also has the
characteristic that its
priority is set to zero.
And so therefore it cannot
become the primary.
So the other concept is one of
votes, that you can decide how
many votes each of
these nodes has.
We'll assume that every node
has one vote, because in
reality, it's not too convenient
or typical to give
more than one vote to a node.
So you have these different
types of nodes.
A regular node, an arbiter node
that has no data on it.
A delayed regular node that
cannot become the primary, but
can participate in elections.
And you have a hidden node that
can also not become the
primary, and can participate
in elections.
So we'll check that
off there, too.
So as I said, when failover
occurs because for some reason
the primary is not reachable,
then the remaining nodes will
elect a new primary, and then
that node will become primary.
And then the drivers
will reconnect.
And it's pretty transparent
to the application.
We'll go into that, what you
see when that happens.
And then you'll continue
on your way.
All right, so let's
do a short quiz.
So thinking about these
different types of nodes,
which of them can participate in
elections of a new primary
if there's failover?
Regular replica set members,
hidden members,
arbiters, and lawyers.
So check all that apply.