All right, let's talk about how
replication works behind
the scenes.
So, I've connected to two of the
Mongod's right now through
Mongo shell.
One is, I've connected
to the primary--
at 27018, at that port.
In this second window, I've
connected to this the
secondary Mongod at 27019.
And what I'm going
to do here--
just want to get rs.status
again, just to look at the
different configuration.
And you can see here that I am
27018, and I am the primary.
You can also call rs.isMaster,
which will tell you whether or
not you're the master.
So rs.isMaster is true here, and
rs.isMaster is going to be
false here, because I'm
not the master here.
Now, let's go and insert
something again.
So, I'm going to use the
test database again.
And I'm going to look at
db.people.find, and now I'm
going to add something to
it-- db.people.insert--
and I'm gonna add a new name.
Now we'll add Richard to that.
And as soon as I do that,
if we do the find
here, I can see them.
And if I do the find here--
oh, I can't run it yet.
I have to say slaveOK to be able
to read from this one.
And you can see the data's
been synchronized.
So, how does that work?
Well, there is a special
collection, a capped
collection--
which means that it's a certain
size and it will loop
after it fills--
in the local database, which
contains an oplog for
replication.
So--
if we show collections, you
can see it right here.
It's called oplog.rs.
So, I'm going to look at it.
So, db.oplog.rs.find.pretty.
And here you can see that in
this op log we have a insert
into test.people with--
here's the object that was
inserted named Richard.
And if we look at the oplog on
this side, we should see the
exact same item.
So let's do that.
Now, this is a cat collection,
and it's in natural order.
It doesn't need an underscore
ID, because capped collections
don't need them.
And you can see here that this
is the same item here that
came through the oplog.
And the way this replication
happens is that the
secondaries query the primary
and ask it for any of the
items since a certain
time stamp.
And then they are brought up to
date with all the data that
came in the interim.
So, you can also add an index.
And if you do that, then
it will also get
added to the oplog.
Let's do that so that
you can see.
Db.people.ensureIndex on name.
We do that, and we'll
get the indexes now.
See, there's an index.
And if you look here in the
oplog on the other side, we
can see that there's going to
be an index on this side,
too-- and a secondary--
that the index itself--
index creation came through
in the oplog.
And insert into
test.system.indexes.
The way indexes are actually
managed inside MongoDB is
they're just basically
insertions into a collection
to tell the Mongo server
that the index exists.
Kind of cool, actually.
So, that's the way replication
works.
It uses this oplog concept.
All right.
So the question is, what
would happen if I
shut down the primary?
How long would it take for a
secondary to get elected?
So, let's do that.
So let's see how long
failover would take.
So, I'm going to quit out of
this primary, which was 27018.
I'm going to shut it down.
I'm going to grep for
the Mongos running.
And the 27018 looks like
it's right here, 6463.
I'm just going to kill it.
Kill it, 6463.
But let's get ready to look
at this, make sure I
have this one right.
27018, processed ID 6463.
Let's do a rs.status here, and
see how long it takes.
So, right now, everything
is looking good.
27018 is the primary.
We're going to go, we're
going to kill it.
And now, we're going to see
how long it takes a new
primary to be elected.
And you can see that 27018 is
now unreachable, and it looks
like 27019--
this-- is already the primary.
So that was pretty fast.
So, that's how fast failover
takes in this case.
And I think that's
pretty typical.
I think it would take
a little longer on a
large running system.
But that was fast.
All right, so now it's
time for a quiz.
And the quiz is, in the video,
how long did it take to elect
a new primary?
About 3 seconds--
or maybe less, about 10 seconds,
about 30 seconds, or
about a minute?
And so, answer the question.