I want to describe a failover
situation which could result
in a rollback of some data
that was previously
committed to mongod.
So imagine you have three
servers right here.
One, two, and three.
And imagine this guy is the
primary, and writes are going
along to this node.
And they're getting replicated
out, but let's say that you
are writing, and these nodes,
you're lagging behind for a
few seconds.
And all of a sudden, this
node goes down.
So if that node goes down, then
one of these two will be
elected as the primary.
But there are writes on this
node that this node
doesn't have yet.
If the app log hasn't
yet been replicated.
So this guy's going to come up
right here as the primary, and
he's not going to have
those rights.
Then, after a period of time,
this guy might come back up as
a secondary.
So let's say he comes
up as a secondary.
So this Mongo server
comes back up,
number one, as a secondary.
When he comes back up, he'll
look at the primary, which is
this node now to see if there's
anything he needs to take.
And when he does that, he's
going to realize that he has
writes that are not in
the current primary.
And so what he's going to do
with those writes, what node
one is going to do with those
writes is he is going
to roll them back.
So he's going to roll them back
and put them into a file.
And they could be applied
manually if you'd like, but
they won't be part
of the data set.
So this is a scenario where
failover can result in
rollback of some data that had
been previously committed.
Now, there's a way to avoid this
particular scenario for
the most part, and that's by
waiting until when you're
writing to this primary
initially, you wait until the
majority of the nodes have
the data, and then that
vulnerability won't exist,
for the most part.
There's some small corner
cases in outstanding
[INAUDIBLE]
on very strange situations
where it
could potentially happen.
But basically, it
will not happen.
So if you simply set your w
write concern to wait until a
majority of the nodes have the
write, then it won't happen.
And we're going to go through
how that works after we go
through the drivers.
But just so you understand that
in the default case, if
you just set w equal to one, and
even if you set j equal to
one, which means I want to make
sure that I don't return
until it's committed to the
journal on this node, that if
this note was to fail before
he replicated his stuff to
these two nodes, then it's
perfectly possible that you
would lose the rights, because
when he came back up, he'd
roll them back.
Put into a file, a roll back
file, but usually in most
operational situations, that's
never applied, because it's
too complicated do that.
So most people don't do it.
OK, let's do a quiz.
So the quiz is what happens if
a node comes back up as a
secondary after a period of
being offline, and the op log
has looped on the primary?
That's a scenario that
we did not discuss.
But maybe you can reason out
what will probably happen.
And remember, the op log
is a cat collection.
So it's possible that so much
time has elapsed that when you
go to look at the primary, that
it doesn't have any of
the operations that happened
in the intervening time
anymore, because it's
already looped.
It's been 24 hours,
or something.
So what do you think happens
in that situation?
And the choices are the entire
data set will be covered from
the primary, a rollback will
occur, the new node stays
offline, does not rejoinder
the replica set as a
secondary, or the new node
begins to calculate pi to a
very large number of
decimal places.
So what do you think happens in
the situations where the op
log rolls or loops?
The cat collection loops.