Let's talk a little bit about
failover and what happens from
an application standpoint when
failover occurs inside a
replica set.
So let's say you have a three
node replica set.
I'm going to draw a three
And these Ms stand for
MongoDB instances.
And let's assume that this one
is the primary, and that you
have an application written
in Python against Pymongo.
And it's connected to
this replica set.
So what that means is that there
is a connection to the
primary, and normally, by
default in MongoDB, all reads
and all writes go to
your primary node.
There's an option to have reads
go to secondaries in
your replica set, but the
default is that the reads go
to your primary.
And if you want strong
consistency where you can read
what you've written, then you
need to have your reads go to
your primary.
So when failover occurs, what's
going to happen is that
this node is going to die.
And then an election is going
to occur and let's say this
one is now elected primary.
And at that point, you're going
to get a connection to
this guy, and you'll
continue forward.
But failover is not
instantaneous.
Failover takes time.
How long does it take?
Well, it could often take
one second, two
seconds, three seconds.
And during that time when
election is occurring and the
replica set is deciding who's
going to be the primary, you
can't complete reads, and you
can't complete writes because
you don't have a primary
to go to.
Let me show you a program, and
I'll show you how this works.
So I have a program here,
which is a simple Python
program, that's going to connect
to a replica set using
the MongoReplicaSetClient
class.
And it's listing three replica
sets in its seed list and
naming the replica set m101.
And I have this replica set
running on my local machine
already so it's already started
and instantiated.
And I have two functions.
I have a readsome
and writesome.
And they do something
very similar.
The writesome function is going
to go through a range of
a million integers, and it's
going to just write each one
to a collection.
And the read one does
a find one from that
collection over and over.
First let's do this write.
And what we're going to do is
we're going to call writesome.
We're going to start adding
integers to the collection.
And by the way, the collection
is dropped at the beginning.
And then, while that's
happening, we're going to step
down the primary so that we get
a replica set election,
and there's a new primary.
So let's do that.
Let's go to this and run it.
So it's inserting these.
Now let's go to the
Mongo shell.
I'm going to get the replica
set status, figure out what
the primary is.
The primary is at 27018.
So I'm going to connect
to that host.
And then I'm going to
do an rs.stepDown, a
replica set step down.
OK, I did it.
I stepped down the primary.
And in the background--
I don't know if you can see--
but as soon as I did that,
this program quit entirely.
All right, so it got to
inserting and inserted 47
numbers, and then
it just quit.
So if you don't catch the
exceptions that occur when the
replica set is electing a new
primary, the program will
actually terminate.
Now, just to show you that it
doesn't matter whether I read
or write, this is true in both
cases, I'm going to change
this program to do reads.
I'm going to comment out this
statement that dropped the
collection that deleted every
document from the collection.
And I am going to change
this to readsome.
So I'm going to call it again.
Now it's just going to
read the same number
over and over again.
And now, let's, once again,
step down the primary.
I need to figure out where
the primary is.
Using rs.status, it looks
like it's 27017.
So I'm going to exit from
here and connect.
And then I'm going to step
down that primary.
And you can see that as
soon as I did that,
this program quit.
This program that is now just
reading numbers from the
collection, it also quit because
this statement, this
find_one occurred while there
was a replica set
election going on.
And there was no primary, and
we've got an exception.
So I guess what I wanted to show
you here is that if you
don't do anything special,
and there's a replica set
failover, all that failover is
completely automatic, your
program, if it's working with
a database during that time,
will actually terminate.
All right, so it's
time for a quiz.
So let's say we had this insert
statement right here--
db.test.insert.
What will happen if the
following statement is
executed in Python during
a primary election?
You're after a failover has
occurred, and it's electing a
new primary.
And the four choices are, the
insert will fail, but the
program will continue; the
insert will succeed to a new
primary because failover is
automatic within MongoDB; the
insert will fail, and the
program will terminate; or the
insert will succeed, and the
program will terminate.
And pick the best choice.