All right.
So we discussed that if a
primary election occurs-- if
there's a failover in
your replica set--
and you do nothing special, the
program will terminate.
Now we want to do better
than that.
So how do we do better
than that?
What we need to do is catch the
exceptions that might occur.
So here's the same program
written, but in this case
these rights all go into a try
except block inside Python.
So we try to insert
each of these
documents, one to a million.
But if there's a problem, than
what we do is we print out the
exception and we continue.
And we sleep for a half
a second again
between each insert.
So, let's see what happens if
we run this program and then
cause a replica set election.
So, I'm gonna go here.
Now we're inserting
the numbers.
And now we're gonna once
again figure out where
our primary is 27019.
OK, good.
So that's easy.
So, we're gonna just step
down this primary.
And we're gonna see
what happens.
So if we go back to this window,
you can see that we
inserted up to 38.
And now we're getting
a bunch of
pymongo.error.AutoReconnect errors--
exceptions.
And then after a period
of time, look at that.
It's continuing forward.
So what happened?
It looks like it inserted up
to 38, and then it took a
bunch of errors, and it's
starting again at document
where i was 59, 60, 61.
All right.
So this is clearly
an improvement.
Now, instead of the program
terminating, we are catching
these exceptions.
But we're losing data.
So if we're looking to make sure
that every single one of
these inserts occurs, it's not
always going to occur.
Because in certain cases,
instead of inserting we're
taking an exception because
we're trying to reconnect to a
new primary.
And then we don't retry
that actual insert.
So we lose it.
Now, in some applications, it
might be acceptable to lose an
insert now and again, depends
on the application.
But if you actually want to make
sure your insert occurs,
this program's not gonna work
particularly well, except that
it didn't actually terminate
the entire program.
So this is an improvement.
All right.
So it's time for a quiz.
If you catch exceptions during
failover, are you guaranteed
to have your writes succeed?
Yes or no.