I showed you how to detect
failover and continue forward
in your program.
Now what if we wanted to do
better than that, and we
actually want to make sure
that our writes succeed?
How would we go about that?
Well, the way to go about that
is to put our inserts into a
retry loop.
And so this is the same
program, but it's been
rewritten with a retry loop.
So let's go through
it line by line.
Once again, we are iterating
through i
from one to a million.
We're creating a document where
i is one, two, three,
four, five.
And in this case, we're
going to retry
from zero to two times.
We're going to try
to do the insert.
And if the insert
works, great.
We break, which breaks out
of this retry loop.
And we go to the next i value.
But if we catch an exception,
then what happens is we print
out the exception.
And then we print retrying.
And we sleep for a full
five seconds.
And then we retry it again.
And I'll explain in a second
why this pymongo
DuplicateKeyError is separately
broken out.
I'll explain why that is.
But let's see what happens if we
run this program and see if
we do better than before.
So once again, we're going
to run the program.
And now it's running.
And it's printing these integer
values as it inserts
them into the collection.
And now, I'm going to once
again figure out what my
primary is, which is 27018.
And then I'm going
to step down.
So there.
I just stepped down
the primary.
Let's go and see what this
program is doing.
So we can see here that
it says it's retrying.
It's retrying.
And then, OK, what happened
after that?
Well, look at that.
So basically, it looks to me
like it took two AutoReconnect
exceptions and then continued
exactly where it left off.
So it inserted this as
zero through 41.
And then it inserted
42, 43, 44, 45, 46.
Well, this is great.
This is what we're
looking for.
So now even though we had a
primary failure and a replica
set election such that we
elected a new primary, our
program was able to get its
writes done reliably.
So let's see how this
works again.
So what happens is if this write
causes an exception,
then we print out
the exception.
And then we come back in, and we
try it again after waiting
for a full five seconds.
Now, why is this
DuplicateKeyError here?
Well, there's actually a couple
different types of
exceptions you can take inside
pymongo in mongod.
One of them is this auto
reconnect error, which means
that the driver is trying
to connect to a
new replica set primary.
But there's other ones.
There's network connection
errors, for instance.
And sometimes, you may
not know whether or
not your write succeeded.
In particular, your write
may have succeeded.
But even though it succeeded,
you may
have taken an exception.
And that's the nature of the way
the error reporting works
inside mongoDB because the write
goes to the database.
There is no return value from
that at the driver level.
And then the driver calls
GetLastError on your behalf.
And it could be the case that
the GetLastError call doesn't
complete for some reason--
it gets a network error--
but that the write
did complete.
So how do you make this whole
thing item potent so that you
can run it over and over.
So there's a subtlety to the
way this code is structured
that I really want to point
out to you and you
should notice it.
And that is that the document
we're inserting is actually
defined up here outside
the retry loop.
And by doing it that way, when
we do this insert right here,
the driver's going to
assign underscore ID
to this Python dict.
And it's going to try
to insert it.
Well, if the insert was
successful, then that
underscore ID is going to appear
in the collection.
And if you try to insert
it again--
all right, because let's say you
thought it failed because
you got an exception, but in
fact it had succeeded.
If you come through the loop
and you try to insert it
again, then when you try to
insert it again, you're going
to get a duplicate key error.
And if you get a duplicate key
error, well, then all you want
to do is you just want to break
and move on because you
know you already inserted that
document the first time.
So by having this document
defined outside the retry loop
and taking advantage of the
driver's functionality of
inserting an underscore ID field
and because underscore
IDs must be unique inside the
collection, you can basically
run this insert more
than once safely.
Now the reality is even if
we hadn't broken out this
DuplicateKeyError, this would
still work because even if
this DuplicateKeyError was
handled here, if it went
through all the retries--
I mean, it'll be
a little slow.
But if it went through all the
retries, it still wouldn't
insert the document
more than once.
And that's the behavior
you want.
You don't want to insert the
document more than once.
You want to only
insert it once.
So this is properly structured
code that will deal with
replica set failures and
primary elections.
And it is the type of code
you should write in your
applications if they're
production applications and
they're going to be running
with a replica set.
And we definitely recommend
using replica sets in
production.
All right.
So it's time for a quiz.
Is this code guaranteed
to get the write
done if failover occurs?
And I'll just tell you
so you don't need
to read it too carefully.
It's exactly the code that I
showed you in this lesson.
And it's a little tricky.
And I didn't really
quite answer this
question in the lesson.
But see if you know
the answer.
Will this code guarantee to get
this right inserted with
this retry loop the way
it's structured now?