OK.
And the answer is no.
And the reason the answer
is no is that
we retry three times.
And we sleep five seconds.
So this presumes that a new
primary is elected within 15
seconds, which may
be the case.
But it may not be the case.
So if you retry 20 times, and
if you waited longer and
longer each time, then it
becomes very unlikely that the
write wouldn't succeed.
You could probably get that down
in a well managed network
as something that was so low,
it wouldn't matter.
But the point is, in this
particular case, the way it's
structured with just the three
retries and a five second
sleep, it may not complete
because you may go through all
the retries while the election
is still occurring if there
are other problems existing
on your network.
Under normal circumstances, an
election for a new primary is
going to happen within a half
second to a second.