So as we talked about before,
the default within the drivers
is that you're going to read
from the same node that you do
your writes from.
So if this is your primary and
you're writing here, and this
is the replica set, and there
are five of them, you're going
to read from the same node.
But you can override that by
specifying a read preference.
And the read preference says
that you, let's say might want
to read from the secondaries.
Now, there are several standard
read preferences that
are typically set inside
the drivers.
PyMongo's got four
different ones.
The first one is that
you'd like to always
read from the primary.
And that means pretty obviously
that you want to
read what you wrote, and that
it has to go to the primary.
You could say you always want
to read from the secondary,
which means that if there's no
secondary available, that you
actually wouldn't be
able to do reads.
You could say that you prefer
the secondary, but you'll take
a primary if there's
no secondary.
And you can say you'd prefer
primary, but that if there's
no primary available, you'll
take a secondary.
There's also several different
other things that we're not
going to go into too much.
One is that you can say I want
the nearest, and the drivers
have a notion of what the
nearest is by keeping, they
periodically ping mongod's and
they know how far they are
away from each one of them.
So you can say I want
the nearest.
And there's also some
concepts of tagging.
You can assign tags to each of
these, the hosts inside the
replica set.
And then you could say, oh,
I want my reads to go to a
particular set of
tagged hosts.
So this could be good for, let's
say if the primary is
in, let's say California, but
you've got replicas all over
the United States, and you want
to always read from one
that's close by, you could
say, you know what?
I want to read from the New
York data center because I
know this user has his
data near New York.
Now, that's assuming that you're
OK with the idea that
data might be slightly
out of date.
So you could imagine in a
situation where it's a social
networking system,
and it's a wall.
And you don't really care if I
see an update on my wall, as
long as I see them eventually.
Then you could imagine doing
a read that's closer to me
geographically.
So you look inside the driver
to understand where these
different options, I'll
show them to you here.
So this is the PyMongo pages.
You can see that the choices
only exists if you use the
MongoReplicaSetClient,
which is the
alternative connection class.
And if you do that, then you
can set a bunch of read
preferences at the
database level.
And here they are numerated
inside the driver.
And you just need to look inside
the driver for your
particular language to
understand how to get to the
different read preferences.
Again, it's primary, primary
preferred, secondary,
secondary preferred,
and nearest.
And as I said, there's
also a way to do
some stuff with tags.
So I'm not going to go
into it right now.
Now, one thought is that a lot
of folks automatically assume
that reading from the secondary
scales their
performance of reads, but
it doesn't always work
out all that well.
And in fact, that's the
subject of our quiz.
And so I'll ask you to think
about that, and then we'll
talk about it.
So let's go to the quiz.
All right, so here's the quiz.
So you can configure your
application via the driver to
read from secondary nodes
in the replica set.
What are the reasons that you
might not want to do that?
Check all that apply.
And I'll go through the
reasons with you.
So if your write traffic is
significantly greater than
your read traffic, you may
overwhelm the secondary, which
must process all the rights,
as well as the reads.
Replication lag can result.
You may not read what you
previously wrote to MongoDB if
you read from the secondaries.
If a secondary hardware has
insufficient memory to keep
the read working set memory,
direct reads to it
will likely slow down.
Directing reads to it will
likely slow it down.
And then finally, reading from
secondaries prevents it from
being promoted to a primary.
So check all that apply, and
then we'll discuss the answer.