The whole idea of sharding is
that you don't need to think
about it as a developer, in
terms of the collection being
horizontally split amongst
the different nodes.
But the reality is, there are
some things you need to
remember once you're in
a sharded environment.
So the first is that every
document needs to include the
shard key now.
The second is that the shard
key is immutable.
OK, so once you've set the shard
key inside a document,
you can't change it.
So you have to be thoughtful
about where you set it up.
The next is that you need
an index that starts
with the shard key.
So what this means is that if
the shard key is Student ID,
then the index could be student
ID comma class, and
that would be fine.
That would satisfy the criteria
that there needs to
be an index on the shard key.
The index that satisfies
this requirement can't
be a multi key index.
So if it's a multi key index
then you'd need to have a
separate index on the shard key,
or that starts with the
shard key in order to satisfy
that requirement.
When do an update, you have to
specify the shard key or
specify that multi is true.
So shard key has to be
specified or multi.
And, by the way, if you do do
multi, or don't specify the
shard key in the update when you
do multi, then it's going
to send out to all
of the nodes.
And, just generally speaking,
whenever you send a query that
doesn't include the shard key,
it's going to send it across
all the nodes.
So no shard key means scatter
gather operation, which could
be expensive.
So you have to think about it
when you're creating the shard
key and you're sharding the
collection, what is a key that
I'm probably going to
use in most queries?
Because that's the key that
I'd really want to
have in my shard key.
So here's some of the
considerations of sharding on
development that you need
to think about.
Another one, which is maybe not
obvious, is that you can't
have a unique key, no unique
index, unless it's also part
of the shard key.
And the reason is that--
or starts with the shard
key, I should say.
So if the shard key is student
ID comma class, then you could
have a unique index on student
ID comma class comma something
else, which means that basically
its unique on
student ID comma class.
And the reason for this
requirement is that there's no
way for it to enforce the
uniqueness of any index that
doesn't include the shard key
because it doesn't know
whether or not the copies exist
on different shards.
Because the indexes are actually
on each shard.
And so there's no collective
way for the database know
whether that uniqueness would
be satisfied or not.
All right, so these are some
of the implications of
sharding as a developer.
And you need to keep them in
mind as you write queries in a
sharded environment.
Time for a quiz.
Suppose you want to shard the
zip code collection after
importing it.
You want to shard on the
zip code itself.
What index would be required
to allow MongoDB to sort on
the zip code?
So, an index on zip code or
a non-multi-key index that
starts with zip, no index is
required to use a zip as a
shard key, a unique index on
the zip code, or any index
that includes the zip code.
And what do you think
the answer is there?