Sharding and replication are
almost always done together.
So, whenever you've got a
sharded environment-- and here
I'm showing three shards, s0,
s1, and s2, and a mongos
routing them--
the shards themselves
are replica sets.
And their replica sets
because otherwise
they wouldn't be reliable.
So, you just have to expect that
when you're dealing with
a sharded environment, and best
practices dictate that
that's the way you
would set it up.
Next thing I wanted to point
out is that the mongos is
doing what the driver was doing
before in the sense that
the mongos is reconnecting to
members of the replica set.
Because the mongos probably has
a connection all the way
through to the primary node of
the replica set in each of
these shards, and possibly
connections to the secondaries
if it's allowing secondary
reads.
So when there's failover within
a shard, it's the
mongos that's going
to reconnect.
And so the mongos has some
concept now of this seed list
and knows which of these
nodes are part of it.
The next thing that you should
realize is that there's still
this concept of write concern,
and there's still the j value,
and the w value, and the w
timeout, and those are going
to be passed right through.
So, if your application
specifies that it requires
journaling to be true, let's
say, or w majority, a majority
of nodes need to see the write
before it's completed, then
your application's going to
specify that in the driver, or
inside your application,
or next to
your application drivers.
And that's going to
go to the mongos.
The mongos is going to route the
query to the appropriate
shard in the replica set, and
then that j and that write
concern are going to get
reflected in that final write.
So you should continue to think
about having to specify
those in the sense that it's a
replicated environment here
and that those are
still meaningful.
And they're going to apply
to each of the nodes.
Now, so if you get a
multi-update, they've hit
multiple nodes, then in each
node if you said I wanted the
w value to be, let's say, 2
and j to be 1, then this
mongos wouldn't get an
acknowledgement for that write.
It wouldn't complete it until
all the different nodes
completed the write to a
majority of them and then it
was committed to the journal
on the primary of each of
these replica sets.
Those are some things to keep
in mind as you're working in
this environment.
And the final point I'll make
is that usually mongos is
replicated itself, so there's
probably a few of these
hanging out here.
Typically, you run them on the
same box as the application
server itself, because they're
pretty lightweight.
And the driver is just the way
they can take multiple names
of hosts for a replica
set, they can
take multiple mongos's.
And if it can't, for some
reason, attach to a mongos or
connect to a mongos, then it
will connect to another
mongos, and the Python drivers
itself have classes just for
dealing with shard environments,
so you can see
them inside the driver docs.
So that's what I want to point
out to you about sharding plus
replication together.
That you've got these replica
sets here, and you have these
mongos's in front, and
everything you learned before
about availability and
replication still applies, it
just that it's passed through
to the various shard.
All right, let's do a quiz.
So, suppose you want to run
multiple mongos routers for
redundancy.
What level of the stack will
assure that you can failover
to a different mongos from
within your application?
Is it the mongod, mongos, the
drivers, or the sharding
config servers?