All right.
In this question, we're just
asking you some facts about
the replication system
built into MongoDB.
And it was a check all
that apply question.
"Which of the following
statements are true about
MongoDB replication?"
The first one is true. "The
minimum sensible number of
voting nodes to a replica set
is three." If you had two
nodes, then you couldn't
elect a new primary.
And If you had one node, you
couldn't elect a new primary.
There would be no nodes left.
So the answer for
that is three.
"MongoDB replication is
synchronous." That is not true.
It is asynchronous.
It synchronizes in the
background, and sends the
updates to the other nodes.
Using getLastError, and setting
a w parameter, you can
essentially set a fence, and ask
that certain actions occur
before you continue.
But it's still, really, an
asynchronous process.
"The Mongo shell is capable of
attaching to a replica set and
automatically failing over."
So, this is also false.
As we know, you connect Mongo
to a particular MongoD.
And, if that MongoD goes down,
it does not reconnect to a
different server.
That's not the way the
Mongo shell works.
So, that's false.
Oops, sorry.
Didn't mean to highlight that.
The next one is, "By default,
using the new MongoClient
connection class gives you
w = 1 and j = 1." And
that's also not true.
It gives you w = 1 and j = 0.
It will wait for the write
to be acknowledged on the
primary, and it does not wait
for journaling to occur.
The last answer was, "The
oplog utilizes a capped
collection." And that is true.
It does utilize a capped
collection, which rolls at the
end of the collection.
If it needs more space, it
reuses the first space from
the first document in
the collection.