This question, we're asking you
to imagine a five-member
replica set, and figure out
how you would specify that
writes are committed to the
journal, and acknowledge by at
least three nodes, before
you proceed.
So, what things would you need
in the getLastError call,
essentially?
And the answer is that you would
need w = 3 and j = 1.
So you'd want to wait
for three nodes--
if you want to wait for
three of the five
nodes to get the write.
So, the answer is
w = 3 and j = 1.
There isn't a w = 3,
j = 1 answer here.
There's a w = "majority"
and j = 1.
But the majority of five
nodes is three notes.
So that was the answer here.
And these other ones are wrong,
for obvious reasons.
Either w does not
equal 3 here--
here w = 3, but j does
not equal 1.
So we didn't wait for it to be
committed to the journal.
Here, you're waiting for all the
nodes to acknowledge the
write, and here--
this doesn't make any sense.
There is no j = 3 value.
j, if you set it to
more than one--
it's either true or
false, really.
And if it's true, then it waits
for the write on the
primary node.
There's no way to say, you
want to wait for it to be
journaled on the secondary
nodes.
That doesn't exist in MongoDB.