OK, in this problem, we asked
you to create a replica set
and prove that it works.
Now, the hard part about this is
probably that nothing ever
works quite as you hope on a
computer and that lots of
small things come up, and you
have to work through them.
In addition, if you're a Windows
user, I didn't even
give you Windows instructions,
so that's an additional level
of complexity.
I suggested that you create
three directories right here
and that's slash data.
And then, that you run these
commands right here to name a
replica set and define your
logpath as being in your
current directory, use small
files, because you don't want
to use the disk space and,
finally, to use these
different data directories
that we created.
Then, you're supposed to connect
to Mongo and, then,
install this configuration
on the server and,
then, initiate it.
And that's really it.
And then, run this validation
script to prove you did it.
So I'm going to show you
it running on my
computer and how it works.
I have two scripts actually.
The first one is called
create_replica_set.sh.
And what that does is it first
removes all the directories.
So this is probably
not something for
the faint of heart.
But I know that these
are basically
empty, so I don't care.
And then, I create the
directories again.
And then, I run the
three Mongos.
Let's first do that.
So let's go here and I'm going
to start with killall mongod.
I think that's done, but, yeah,
it was already done.
And then, I'm going to call
create_replica_set.sh.
And you can see it runs.
And then, if I look at
one of the logs,
it seems to be running.
So that's good.
ps -ef grep [? for ?] mongod,
and I've got three of them. so
I'm feeling good about that.
And then, I wrote a secondary
script called init_replSet.
And that just has the command
that I told you to type in at
the prompt.
I was doing it over and over
again, so it was easier to put
it into a script.
And so that's the configuration
and
the initiate step.
So I'm going to call that mongo
initiate replica.js.
And there we go.
It should be good.
I'll make sure it's
OK, rs.status.
Looks good to me.
Actually, it's not
totally done yet.
It's in secondary startup
unknown, Let's see.
So I'll run it again.
They're not quite done yet.
So let's see if I just
keep running this.
Recovering and, oh, now, I'm
up at the secondary.
So now, it looks
like it's good.
Great, primary, secondary,
secondary.
And then, I'm going to quit
out of this and run the
validation script, python
validate.py.
And it connects locally
to the replica set
and says that I passed.
It connects to the RSS status
and a few other things.
So it gives me my validation
code, which is congrats, you
rock, 2012.
And by the way, you all rock
if you got all this done.
I think it's been a pretty
intense course if you've never
done MongoDB before and,
certainly, if you don't have
any Python of experience,
as well.
I know for a lot of people,
you're probably experienced.
Some people on the
forums seem more
experienced than me in MongoDB.
So for those people maybe it was
an easy course, but I know
for a lot of you, it was
probably challenging.
So congratulations on getting
to this point.
OK, so that's how this
particular problem works.