OK, we've shown you how
to create unique indexes
on collections, and now
I want to talk to you
about sparse
indexes which can be
used to create unique indexes
when the index key is missing
from the document.
So let's look at
these four documents,
these four documents--
the first one
has the keys A, B, and C, the
second one has A, B, and C,
the third has just A, B, and
the fourth has just A, B.
If we want to create
a unique index on A,
that would work
fine because A has
a different value
for each document,
and A is included
in every document,
so it would work fine.
But let's say we want to
create a unique index on C,
on the key C-- well
the first document
and the second document
both have a C value,
so that will work just fine.
But the third and fourth,
they don't have C values,
and it won't work.
And the reason why you won't be
able to create the unique index
on C, just the unique one,
is that these two documents
right here are both considered
to have a C value of null.
And since a unique index
only allows a value
to appear once in the index, you
would get a duplicate key entry
if you tried to create a unique
index on C for these four
documents.
So what's the solution to that?
Well, you can remove the dupes
when you're creating the index,
but the problem is
that would remove
either this document
or this document,
which is certainly
not what you want.
So instead, you can create
what's called a sparse index.
And what a sparse
index will do is
it will only create index
entries for the documents that
contain the key being indexed.
So if we are indexing
against C, then there
will be no index
entries for this
and there will be no
index entries for this.
So let's go through in
the shell and look at this
and look at some of the
ramifications of using
a sparse index,
and what it means.
OK, if small collection
of products-- and I'll
pretty print it-- and we can
see that the first document is
a polo shirt and it
has a size of medium,
and the second document
is a pair of jeans
and it's got a size of 32x32,
and the third document is
a iPhone cradle, it has no size,
and the fourth document a DVI
to VGA cable, and
it has no size.
Well if I wanted to create a
unique index on size, which
it's a little bit
nonsensical, I don't
know why you would do
that, but let's just
say you wanted to do
it-- and so let's do that
by calling the
db.products.ensureIndex on size
ascending, and let's give the
option unique equals true.
Let's see what happens
when we try to do that.
So what happens is,
we get an error.
And we get an
error because there
are two documents in
this collection that
don't have a size and that both
map to having a size of null,
and that is going to be a
duplicate key because you can't
have null in the
collection more than once.
So all right, what
are my options?
Well my options are
I could, instead,
create this index with
sparse equal to true.
And now it's going to be fine.
Now I'm able to
create the index.
There wasn't one
index before and now
there are two, all right?
And that's pretty
much works well,
but there are certain
things to think
about when you create
a sparse index.
And in particular,
if you use that index
and you, for instance,
sort on that index,
then the results may not
be what you'd expect.
So we would certainly
expect that if we
call dp.products.find, that
we would get all the documents
back, and we do--
that's not surprising.
But let's say we
called dp.products.find
and said sort on size ascending.
If we did that, then we
still get all four documents
back sorted by size.
That's interesting,
that's good, that's good.
But let's see what
index it's using,
so I'm going to use an explain
on this and see what it says.
And it says that it's using
a basic cursor for the index.
So that's the reason why we're
getting all the documents back.
OK, well what if we
deliberately hinted and said
we wanted to use the
index on size ascending.
Now if we did that, then we
only get two documents back.
We did a find, where we would
expect all of the documents,
but we only got two back.
And the reason we
only got two back
is that we're using the index
size, the index size is sparse,
the index on size is missing
the two documents that
don't have sizes,
and so they're not
included when it's returned.
And if you call explain
you'll see that now it
is using this index on size.
So here it is,
BtreeCursor size, we
called explain to tell us that
the query plan and it is using
this index on size, and it's
omitting the two documents.
All right well, well that
was a pretty tortured example
having to actually hint
to use the size index when
the database wouldn't
use it by default,
but what's important
to remember with this,
is that this behavior changed
when we went from MongoDB 2.4
to MongoDB 2.6.
OK?
2.6 was released in April,
2014 and in MongoDB 2.4,
the database even if you
hadn't given that hint,
it would have used that index,
that index on size-- so yes.
In MongoDB 2.6, by default
it doesn't use that index,
and the reason it doesn't
use that index by default,
is that it knows
that if it does,
it's going to omit documents
that would have otherwise
been returned.
So that's not going
to use that index
for the query for the sort.
So this is a change of
behavior from MongoDB 2.4
to MongoDB 2.6, and
I think it's mostly
a change of behavior
for the better,
because you kind of get
the results you expect.
But if you really want to
force the older behavior
you can do so using
the hint command,
and you just have to remember
that you may, in fact, omit
documents that would've
otherwise been returned
by the query if you sort
by a sparse index that
is missing certain documents.
All right, so thinking
about MongoDB 2.6,
let's go and do a quiz.
So here's the quiz.
Let's say that we have
the following documents
in a collection called people,
with the following docs.
You can see, there are
three documents here,
and the three
documents, the first one
has a name Andrew,
a title of Jester,
the second one has
a name of Dwight,
title of CEO, the third
one is the name of John,
there is no title.
There's an index on this
collection, on the title key,
and it is sparse.
So if you perform
this following query,
what do you get back and why?
So in MongoDB 2.6, if you
perform the query and look
for title null, with a hint that
it should use the title index,
what would you
expect to get back?
And the answers are-- well,
it'll return no documents,
because the query
uses the index,
and there are no documents
with title null in the index.
Or, no documents, because
querying for title null
only finds documents that
explicitly have title null,
regardless of the index.
The document for John, because
the query won't use the index.
All the documents
in the collections,
because title null
matches all the documents.
Or, the document for John,
because the insurer index
command won't
succeed in this case.