All right, now that
we've talked about how
to search for locations
using a 2D index,
I want to go over a
more sophisticated type
of geospatial indexing-- a
spherical geospatial indexing
that is also
supported in MongoDB.
Now, to start out, before you
can talk about finding things
in a 3D world, you have to
talk about how you describe
the location of
something in a 3D world.
So the world is
actually a globe,
and this is my poor
representation of the globe.
And locations on the
globe are represented
by longitude and latitude.
So if you recall, latitude
is how far off the equator
is the object.
So for instance, the equator
is at zero degrees latitude,
and you can go all the way from
minus 90 degrees to 90 degrees.
And that's your
lines of latitude.
And then we have the longitude.
And the longitude-- this is a
lot of longitude right here.
It describes a line
that goes from the north
to the south pole.
So in order to
describe the location
of any particular
object on earth,
you need its latitude
and its longitude.
Now, in addition,
we're going to need
a way of indexing
these documents that
have latitudes and
longitudes in them.
And the way we're
going to do that is
a new special type of
index called 2dsphere.
So let's talk about how
we're going to do this.
And I think the easiest way to
get into this is by example.
So I'm going to go through an
example of a few locations that
have been put into
MongoDB documents.
We're going to search
near a location
to find the closest locations.
And we're going to use a
2dsphere index to do it.
So let's start
with the locations.
So here's Palo Alto.
And in Palo Alto we've got
four locations that are near
and dear to my heart.
We've got Fry's
Electronics, where
I used to get small electronic
components before people
stopped building anything,
in the late '90s.
And the Pennisula
Creamery, where
you can get a great
milkshake and a burger;
the Apple store, where you
can spend a lot of money;
and Hoover Tower, which
is a monument right
in the center of
Stanford's campus.
And then there's
one more location
that I put on my little map, and
that is Mount Tamalpais State
Park-- top of Mount
Tam is where I
got engaged, so also a place
near and dear to my heart,
a bit further from Stanford.
And we're going to put
documents into MongoDB
that represent these locations.
All right, the first
thing I want to show you
is that Google Maps is
very convenient for finding
the latitude and
longitude for locations.
So let's look up
Times Square, which
is where we are right now.
You'll see that what Google Maps
will do is, in the browser URL,
it will actually
show you-- and we're
right over here somewhere.
It'll show you the
latitude and the longitude.
Now, it shows it to you in
latitude comma longitude order.
So the latitude is 40.75
here, and the longitude
is minus 73.98.
This is in the
opposite order you're
going to need it when you
specify it in MongoDB.
MongoDB takes a
longitude comma latitude.
All right, so how
are we are we going
to specify the
locations of things?
Well, we use a location
specification called GeoJSON.
And I'm going to show
you that right now.
This is a web page on
GeoJSON, geojson.org.
We implement only a small
part of the specification
on GeoJSON.
But if you want,
you can look at it
and see the full specification.
And in particular,
the parts that we're
going to be most
interested in are the parts
that specify points
and geometries.
And you can see there's
coordinates and lists
of coordinates.
It's kind of a complicated thing
when you've got-- especially
if you want to
describe a polygon.
We're only going to do the
most introductory lesson here
right now.
And then you can go
look further if you
want to see what all the
different possibilities are.
And MongoDB only supports
a subset of these,
like points and polygons.
We don't support some of the
more complicated structures.
All right, so let's
go into MongoDB now
and see our documents.
So I put them in a
collection called "Places."
So here we are.
I'm going to pretty print them.
And we're going to see the
GeoJSON format at work.
So here we have the Apple store.
I decided to specify
the city of Palo Alto.
I decided to put my GeoJSON
location information
into a key called "location."
This is my own decision.
It's arbitrary.
But you can call it
anything you want.
But I called it "location."
And then everything
after this paren
and into this paren,
that's a GeoJSON document.
In this case, I've decided
to describe it using a point.
You could also describe
it using a polygon
if you wanted to
give it some area,
but we described
it using a point.
And the type is a reserved
word, and coordinates
is a reserved word.
Point is a reserved word.
And here are the coordinates
in longitude comma
latitude order, which
I got from Google Maps.
I decided to put that
was a retail store
into the collection.
Again, we've got four
objects in the collection.
We've got this Apple store,
this Peninsula Creamery,
and Fry's Electronics.
And then finally, Mount
Tamalpais State Park.
OK, so in order to
query this, we're
going to need an index
on the GeoJSON documents.
So let's do that--
db.places.ensureIndex.
And it's going to
be on location.
And it's going be
of type 2dsphere.
Never understood why
this is called 2dsphere.
It seems to me that if
you have a two dimensional
sphere, that would be a circle.
But what I think is trying
to be expressed here
is that although
it's a 3D model--
it's a spherical
model-- that it's only
looking at points on the
surface of the sphere
versus up in the air.
So that's why it's
called 2dsphere.
So we're going to add that.
And now there are two
indexes on the collection,
which is all good.
Previously, there was one.
I could show you the indexes.
Hold on, getIndexes.
The indexes are this _id index,
which always comes with every
collection, and then
this index on location.
So what query might
we want to run?
Well, I want to know the
closest things to me,
and I'm standing at Hoover
Tower, in my imagination.
So let's go through that.
I'm going to quit
from the shell here.
And I've got a query
that's been written our
already to be a little
bit easier to follow.
So this query is going to search
the Places collection, right
here, and do a Find.
And it's going to find
documents by location, which
is the field that
we created to hold
the locations of
the various stores.
And it's going to use
the $near operator.
Now, the $near operator
is going to search
for everything near a
point, in this case.
Now this $geometry is
a required operator
and can also give
$maxDistance, which
is the max distance in meters.
I said 2,000 meters.
Find me everything that is
closest to these coordinates--
minus 122.166641 degrees
longitude, and 37 degrees 0.427
blah, blah, blah latitude.
And these are the
coordinates of Hoover Tower
that I got from Google Maps.
So again, just to look at the
format of this, we had a Find.
We specified that we're
looking at the Location field.
We're applying the
$near operator.
And then, we have
a GeoJSON document
that specifies the
geometry of type point
with these coordinates.
And that's it.
So let's see what
we get we do that.
So Mongo-- I'm going
to just redirect
from this file to run a query.
And it looks like we
got back two documents.
And these are going to be
sorted in order of closest
to furthest, which is a
feature of the $near operator.
The first one is the
Peninsula Creamery--
and it is, in fact, closest
to Hoover Tower-- and then
the Apple store, which is also
within 2,000 meters of Hoover
Tower.
Notice that it
eliminated Fry's and it
eliminated Mount Tamalpais as
being outside 2,000 meters.
And just to review that
with you to show you
the map again so you see that
this is the right answer,
remember, we were looking at
things closest to hover tower.
And it said that
within 2,000 meters,
you've got the Peninsula
Creamery at closest location,
and Apple store, next closest.
Fry's and Mount Tamalpais
are off the screen.
Fry's is on the screen, but
out of the search radius.
And Mount Tam is
completely off the screen.
And that's how
you would actually
search for something
using the near operator.
So again, the
secrets are that you
need to know the latitude and
longitude of your documents.
You also need to
create a 2dsphere index
if you want to use
the $near operator.
Some of the operators
don't require
having an index-- like,
for instance, finding
something that's within a shape.
But they all perform
better if there
is an index on the location.
And then you need to, of
course, insert the locations
and perform the query.
OK, let's now do a quiz.
What is the query that
will query a collection
named "Stores" to
return the stores that
are within one million meters
of the location at this latitude
and this longitude-- latitude
39, longitude minus 130.
Type the query in the
box below, and assume
that the stores collection has
a 2dsphere index already on it,
on the key location.
And use the $near operator,
as we did in this lesson.
And if you're looking for
what the documents look
like, this an example document.
Might have an _id that looks
like this with a store-id of 8
and a location of type point,
and these are the coordinates.
So you have to write
that query right here.
And then hit Return and
see if it's correct.
You have to be pretty careful to
make sure it's exactly the same
because we're going to
pattern match against that.