Let's learn more about
the Find method.
As we already learned about
"findone" method, the Find
method can take a couple
of arguments.
The first argument specifies
what documents to return in
the query, similar to a
WHERE clause in SQL.
For instance, I can retrieve
just those documents where the
field type is "essay." And here
we see a bunch of essays
with scores.
Alternatively, I could select
just those where the student
is student number 19.
And there are three of those, as
the logic of the insertion
that we did before provides.
If I want to conjoin multiple
clauses, I can by specifying
multiple field and value
pairs in the first
argument to the Find.
In this case, I'm getting the
document where the student ID
is 19 and the type is "essay."
In fact, this is an
important detail.
When multiple fields are given
in the document that's in the
first argument to find, the
meaning of that query, to the
Find, is that both the fields
have to match whatever the
specified criteria are.
In this case, the student must
be equal to 19, and the type
must be equal to the string
"essay." Further, Find can
take a second argument just
as "findone" can.
The second argument to find
is also a document and can
specify what fields should be
retrieved from the database.
Only those fields will actually
be sent back to the
client application, in
this case, the shell.
For example, I might want to
retrieve just the score.
Again, by default, the _ID will
be returned, even if I
don't ask for it.
If I would like not to get the
_ID back, I can ask for the
_ID to be excluded by specifying
_ID" "false."
In this case, I get back just
the score field from the
document where the student ID is
19 and the type is "essay."
There's a lot more to be said
about the query facilities
that are available for the first
argument to find, but
not a whole lot more to be said
about the second argument
to find, so we might not be
revisiting it very much for
the rest of this course.
OK.
Let's have a quiz.
Supposing a scores collection
similar to the one that we've
just presented, how would you
find all documents with an
essay score that's equal to 50
and retrieve only the student
field from these documents?