Let's learn a few more
query operators.
As you may have noticed, the
people collection I've created
has a number of different
kinds of documents.
Some documents have the fields
_id name, age, and profession,
whereas other documents have the
fields _id and name only.
Further, some documents have the
field name that's a string
and other documents--
well, just one other
document--
has a field name that's
a number.
MondoDB allows you to query
based on the structure and
types of information that's
in the documents as
well as their values.
For example, if I want to
retrieve those documents where
the field profession exists, I
can say db.people.find and
then the argument is a document
having the field
"profession," whose
corresponding value is an
embedded document having the
field $exists with a
corresponding value of true.
And this will return just
"Smith" and "Jones," who have
a profession.
By contrast, I can invert the
query and ask for only those
documents where the profession
field does not exist, and that
gets me the other half dozen.
Next, I can ask for documents
based on the type of a
particular field.
For example, if I want to get
only those documents where the
name field is a string, I can
specify db.people.find, then
an argument--
that's a document having the
field name having the
corresponding value that's an
embedded document with the
operator types-- a and then the
types, unfortunately, are
specified as numbers, and the
numbers are the corresponding
type values out of the
BSON specification.
Take at BSONspec.org in the
specification to find the
numeric encoding of the
different types in BSON.
As it happens, they type for
string is type 2, and this
gets me those documents
where the name field
has a string value.
Finally for this section, there
are more complicated
sorts of queries that you
might want to perform on
strings than just equality
and inequality.
For example, people tend
to like to look
for patterns in strings.
MondoDB supports querying for
string patterns using a
regular expression library--
in particular, the Perl
Compatible Regular Expression
Library, libpcre.
Now, I don't want to spend too
much time going into the
details of regular expressions,
I just want to
show you a couple of examples.
To query for those documents
that have, say, the letter A
in them somewhere, you can
specify the query that's on
the bottom of my terminal.
db.people.find and the
corresponding value that's a
document having the field
"name" whose value is an
embedded document with the
operator $regex and then a
string that will be understood
as a Perl-style regular
expression.
And as it happens, Charlie and
Dave and Edgar all have the
letter A somewhere
in their name.
If I want to be more
complicated, I could ask for
all those documents where the
field name ends with the
letter E, and the regular
expression for that is the
string consisting
of the letter E
followed by a dollar sign.
And there's "Alice," and
"Charlie," and "Dave."
Now, we'll talk more about
regular expressions in a later
week when we talk about
performance optimization.
As it turns out, regular
expressions tend not to be as
optimizable as far as the query
processing goes as more
simple string inequalities.
However, a special case of
regular expressions that can
be efficiently optimized are
those that start with a
carrot, which means that the
regular expression must begin
with whatever follows.
And then after the carrot
contain non-wild card
characters, or literal
characters, such as letters
and numbers.
So for example, the regular
expression at the bottom of my
screen says that the name
field must start with a
capital letter A. We'll see in
a subsequent week that this
can be mechanically translated
into a range query up from A
up to but not including B. And
indeed, this is what MongoDB
does internally.
In any case, those were three
new operators to go along with
the inequality operators that
we've already learned.
$exists asks whether a field
happens to exist inside of a
document, $type checks whether
a field has a particular type
value, and $regex allows you
to do complicated string
pattern matching inside
of fields.
All right.
Let's have a quick quiz.
Write a query that retrieves
documents from a collection
called "users" where the user
name has the letter Q in it
and the document has
an email field.