Let's learn another query
operator, $ and.
Occasionally, but not very
often, you might want to
specify the logical conjunction
of some criteria
with an explicit
$ and operator.
For example, the query that's
now on my screen--
db.people.find $ and and then
the array name greater than C
name regx A--
should match only those
documents where the name sorts
after the letter C
and contains the
letter A in it somewhere.
And there we are.
Charlie, Dave, and Edgar.
As I said, this is a somewhat
infrequently used operator
because most cases where you
might be tempted to use $ and
can be expressed more simply
using the fact you could put
multiple constraints on the
same field in a more
straightforward fashion
like this.
name colon $ greater than C,
regx x A has exactly the same
effect as the preceding
query but doesn't
require the $ and operator.
In fact, there's some
implementation differences
between these two queries in how
MongoDB executes the two.
This query is not particularly
optimizable in any case, but
if it were the second example
would be a bit more performant
than the first.
In any case, $ and is available
and simplifies, to a
certain extent, the
construction of dynamic queries.
Let's have a quiz.
This one's slightly tricky.
What will the following
query do?
Define all documents with scores
between 50 and 60, find
all documents with scores
greater than 50, find all
documents with score less than
60, explode like the Death
Star-- at the end of Episode
4.6, I guess--
none of the above?