OK.
Now we've learned almost
everything there is to learn
about querying the database, so
we're going to move on to
updating documents
in the database.
Let's take a look at our
"people" collection.
In this collection, we have
documents for users named
Smith, Jones, Alice, Bob,
Charlie, Dave, Edgar, Fred,
and, well, Name 42.
Once you have some documents
in the database, it's quite
common to want to be able to
modify those documents.
And so just like we have a
method for requiring documents
called Find, we have a
method for changing
documents called Update.
Now, in the Mongo shell, the API
for updating actually does
four different things.
Right now, we're going to learn
about one of them and
we'll learn about the
rest as we go.
Just like queries are methods
on a collection, updates are
methods on a collection.
And updates take at least
two arguments.
The first argument is a query,
analogous to the
WHERE clause in SQL.
So everything you've learned
about Find is applicable to
querying for documents in order
to perform updates.
So, for instance, let's say I
want to update "Smith." The
second argument to update is a
document, and in the simple
case, whatever you put inside
that document will replace
everything but the primary key
of the document being updated.
So if I say find a document with
name "Smith" and I put
some fields in here, let's say
"name" "Thompson" and "salary"
"50,000," then this update will
replace whatever is in
the document that currently
exists where the name is Smith
with those fields
that I specify
in the second argument.
As you can see, the top line
of my terminal window shows
the _id with a particular object
ID and that had the
name Smith.
The 10th line up from the bottom
of my terminal window
has the same object ID but now
the name is Thompson and the
salary is 50,000.
The other two fields of
information that existed about
Smith are gone.
This use of the update
operator is somewhat vestigial.
MongoDB was originally
designed as a
kind of object store.
And in an object store,
especially for a
dynamically-typed language, such
as, say, JavaScript or
Python, it's sort of convenient
to be able to say I
have a document in the
application, manipulate the
document in the application,
and put it back into the
database disregarding whatever
happens to be in the database
for that document, storing only
those things that the
application currently has
for the document.
This use, however, is somewhat
dangerous, and so in a
subsequent section, we'll show
a somewhat more constrained
way of manipulating fields
inside of a document.
In any case, this wholesale
replacement is
occasionally useful.
For example, if you're merging
data into the database and you
don't know how or can't
conveniently compute the delta
between what's in the database
and what you have from an
external source, then you might
just send the data from
the external source into the
database keyed using, say, a
primary key.
This is not an infrequent
use for this
replacing version of update.
Nevertheless, it's a somewhat
blunderbuss approach to
changing data in the database,
so if you don't need this
approach, you might not
want to use it.
OK.
So let's have a quiz
on this subject.
Let's say you had a collection
with the
following document in it.
_id:Texas, "population"
"2500000," "landlocked:1", and
you issued this operation,
db.foo, where "foo" is the
name of your collection,
.update _id "Texas"
"population" "30000000".
What would be the state of the
document in this collection
after the update?