This lecture
section only applies
to MongoDB versions
2.4 and earlier.
If you're running MongoDB
version 2.6 or later,
you can skip over this section.
And it won't be in the homework.
OK, so now we've learned
the basic CRUD operations
that MongoDB offers, Insert,
Find, Update, and Remove.
However, there's
a little bit more
that you need to know about
the exact details of operations
into MongoDB.
The shell is an
interactive environment.
And so it gives you information
whenever something goes wrong.
For example, I mentioned
before that the underscore ID
field is a primary key.
It is required to be present.
It's required to be unique.
And we actually make it
immutable in addition.
If I insert a document with
a particular primary key,
let's say, Smith,
well, I have reason
to believe that a
document got inserted.
I'll tell you a little bit more
about how you can confirm that.
If I try to insert a second
document with name Smith,
the shell will give me
an error message back.
In fact, the
interactive shell always
checks to see whether the last
operation succeeded or failed
and tells you
immediately if it failed.
So far, I haven't shown you any
of the operations that fail.
This was a little bit
of malice aforethought.
However, you can
programmatically
check whether an operation
succeeded or failed
by running a command.
We've actually used
some commands already.
For instance, count
is actually a command.
In any case, there's a
command called getLastError,
which returns the outcome of
the last write operation that
was sent on the connection
that you're currently using.
The result of getLastError
is a document.
And in case of an
error scenario,
the document has
a field, ERR, that
has a non-null value
containing an error message.
Most errors also have
a unique integer code,
which is given in
the code field.
getLastError is available
both in the shell
and in all of our
drivers as a way
of checking whether a write
operation succeeded or failed.
In the event that a
write operation succeeds,
for example, I'll
insert another document
with a different underscore ID.
In that case, the
getLastError command
will tell me that
the error is null.
That is to say, that
operation succeeded.
For other sorts of
operations, such as updates,
getLastError can tell me
the outcome of the update.
In this case, I will
specify an update
that should affect all documents
in the collection adding
a title field.
getLastError, after
such an update,
tells me that the documents
that got updated already existed
and that there were two of them.
This is how I could find
out how many documents
got affected by an update.
By contrast, if instead
of doing a multi-update,
I ask for an upsert,
that is to say,
an update operation that
will either update a document
with name Thompson,
if one exists,
or else create a document with
name Thompson and title Dr,
If none exists.
After such an upsert
operation, getLastError
tells me that it did not
update an existing document,
but instead upserted a new
document whose underscore ID
is returned to me.
So you see, the
getLastError command
is a way both to find out
whether a write operation
succeeded or failed
and also to get
some information about the
successful write operations
that just happened.
Again, the shell
automatically tells you
when a write operation fails.
So so far, I have
repeatedly said
that I have reason to believe
that my write operations were
successful.
That reason was simply
that the shell did not
tell me otherwise.
Finally, if I choose to remove
all people from the people
collection, the
getLastError command
will tell me that there were
three documents removed,
n equals 3.
We'll see more of you the
getLastError command again
in a future part of this course.
For now, you should
understand that it's the way
to check whether a write
operation succeeded or failed.
The mechanics of
all of these details
have changed substantially
in MongoDB version 2.6 such
that you no longer need to
run the getLastError command.
It's implicit in all
the wire operations.