In this problem, we asked you to
remove the lowest homework
score for each student.
The algorithm that we suggested
was to sort the
scores by student ID and then
by score ascending.
Now, we're only looking at the
documents that are of type
homework in this case.
And if we do that, and we set
the student ID to a sensible
value to start, whenever the
student ID changes, we know
that we're looking at the lowest
score for that student,
and we can just remove it.
So we start by removing this
document right here.
Then as we go through, we notice
the student ID changes
during this transition as
reiterating through, so we
remove that document, then we
remove this document, and we
remove this document.
And we go through all the
students, and we remove the
lowest homework score
for each one.
Let's look at that
as a program.
Here is the program that
I wrote to do it.
It's got two different
functions.
This one removes lowest
function.
It calls grades that
find type homework.
It sorts by the student
ID ascending
and the score ascending.
It sets the student ID to a
sensible value to start.
And then as it goes through each
of these entries in the
collection, if the student
ID is different than the
proceeding student ID, it knows
that it's looking at the
lowest homework score for the
student, and then it calls
remove score on that
Student ID.
And every time through
the loop, it also
updates student ID.
So if we look at the remove
score function right here, it
tries to find a document that
it's being asked to remove the
underscore ID, just prints it
out for debugging purposes.
And then it calls grades that
remove underscore ID equals
the ID that was set into the
function right here.
That's how it works.
Let's watch it work, and then we
just want to call Python on
drop lowest and printed out a
bunch of stuff, but basically,
it removed one document for
each of the students.
And then we asked you to run
some aggregation query, which
we won't explain too much right
now, because there's
actually a separate unit on
this, but I'll take you
through real fast.
The aggregation framework works
as a pipeline, and the
first thing it does is it groups
all the documents by
student ID and finds
the average of
the student's works.
And then it sorts
by that average.
That's a document to
set down a pipeline
sorted by the average.
And then finally, we limit it to
the top one, because one of
the highest grade point
average of the class.
So if we run that, and the
result of this aggregation
framework query is that the
document with the highest
average has underscore
ID, which is
actually the student ID.
Where the framework works,
that winds up in the
underscore ID field at this
end of this pipeline.
And the average of that
student is 96.
So the answer for this
question was 54.