Welcome to week four.
Congratulations on
making it to this point.
This week we're going to
talk about performance.
The performance of
computer systems
is driven by a variety
of factors including
the performance of the
underlying hardware-- the CPU,
the disk, and the memory.
Once you've chosen a
hardware configuration
it's going to be your algorithms
that determine performance.
And for a database-backed
application
it's going to be the
algorithms that are
used to satisfy your queries.
There are two ways
you can impact
the latency and throughput
of database queries.
One is to add indexes
to collections.
And two is to distribute the
load across multiple servers
using sharding.
This week we're going to
talk about performance.
But to make matters
just a little bit
more interesting in MongoDB 3.0
we introduced pluggable storage
engines.
A storage engine is the
software that controls
how the data is stored on disk.
We're also going to talk about
how the choice of storage
engine impact performance.
Now performance is
normally the domain
of database administrators.
But good developers
understand performance
and write their applications
with performance in mind.
And they can de-bug the
performance problems
within their applications.
Let's get started.