Let's talk about the
MMAP storage engine.
We call it MMAPV V1.
It's the original storage
engine of MongoDB.
And it uses the MMAP system
call under the covers
in order to implement
storage management.
Let's look at what the MMAP
system call looks like.
It's right here.
On any Unix machine,
if you man MMAP,
you'll see that it talks about
allocating memory or mapping
files or devices into
memory, causes the pages
starting address and continuing
for at most length bytes
to be mapped from the
object described by the file
descriptor at an offset.
So what does that
really practically mean?
Well, MongoDB needs a
place to put documents,
and it puts the
documents inside files.
And to do that, it initially
allocates, let's say,
a large file.
Let's say it allocates
100 gigabyte file on disk.
So we wind up with 100 gigabyte
file on disk right here.
And this disk may or may
not be physically contiguous
on the actual disk, because
there are some algorithms that
occur beneath that layer that
control the actual allocation
of space on a disk.
But from our standpoint, it's
a 100-gigabyte contiguous file.
If MongoDB calls the
MMAP system call,
it can map this file,
this 100-gigabyte file
into 100 gigabytes
of virtual memory.
Now to do that,
of course, we need
to be on a 64-bit computer,
because you could never
get 100 gigabytes of
virtual memory space
on a 32-bit computer.
You'd be limited to
2 or 4 gigabytes.
And these are all page sized.
So pages on an operating system
or either 4K or 16K large.
So there's a lot of them
that I'm not showing here.
And the operating
system is going
to decide what
can fit in memory.
So if the actual physical
memory of the box is,
let's say, 32
gigabytes, then if I
go to access one of the
pages in this memory space,
it may not be in memory
at any given time.
The operating system
decides which of these pages
are going to be in memory.
I'll just say the green
ones are in memory.
And so when you go
to read a document,
if it hits a page that's
in memory, then you get it.
And if hits a page that's not
memory, let's say this page,
then the operating system
has to bring it from disk--
this is on disk here-- it has to
bring it from disk into memory
before you can access it.
And that's the basics of the way
the MMAP storage engine works.
Now, the MMAP storage engine
offers collection level
concurrency, or what
we sometimes call
a collection level locking.
Each collection inside
MongoDB is its own file,
if you look in data/db.
So what that means
is that if you
have two different operations
going on at the same time
and they are in the
same collection,
one's going to have to
wait for the other one
if they are write, because
it's a multiple reader,
single writer lock
that it takes.
So only one write
can happen at a time
to a particular collection.
But if they're
different collections,
then it could happen
simultaneously.
In addition, the
way this storage
engine works in MMAP V1, we
allow in-place updates of data.
So if a document is sitting here
in this little page right here
and you do an update
to it, then we'll
try to update it right in place.
And if we can update
it, then what we'll do
is we'll mark it as a
whole, and then we'll
move it somewhere else
where there is more space.
So we'll maybe move it
over here or something.
And then we'll
update it over there.
In order to make it more
likely that we can update
a document in place
without having to move it,
we use power of two sizes when
we allocate the initial storage
for a document.
What that means
is that if you try
to create a 3-byte document,
you're going to get 4 bytes.
If you try to create
a 7-byte document,
you're going to get 8
bytes, a 19-byte document,
you're going to get 32 bytes.
And this way, it's
more likely that you
can grow the document
a little bit,
and that space that opens
up, that we can re-use it
more easily.
So that's the MMAP
storage engine.
And you'll notice that since
the operating system is
what makes the decision about
what is in memory versus what
is in disk, we
can't really do much
in terms of controlling that.
The operating system's pretty
smart about managing memory.
So it's usually not
a bad algorithm.
But the database doesn't
get to decide or contribute
its opinion about what winds up
in physical memory versus what
winds up on disk.
And if you're
curious about the way
virtual memory works in general,
just Google virtual memory
and storage systems.
It's the same
algorithms that are
used to manage memory
inside the operating
system for all programs OK.
Now it's time for a quiz.
Which of the following
statements about the MMAP V1
storage engine are true?
Check all that apply.
The first is that MMAP offers
document-level locking.
The second is that
MMAP automatically
allocates power of
two-sized documents
when new documents are inserted.
The third is that MMAP is built
on top of the MMAP system call
that maps files into memory.
And the final one
is that MongoDB
manages the memory
used by each map file,
deciding which parts
to swap to disk.
So check the ones that
you think are correct.