OK, let's talk about indexes
now and their impact on database
performance.
Now, this is an imagined
collection right
here of a bunch of
documents, and the documents
might have the form
shown right here.
This is a collection.
And these documents
might be on disk
in essentially arbitrary order.
And whether you're talking about
[? NMAP ?] V1 or Wired Tiger,
there might be no particular
order to the documents on disk.
Now, if there's no
index and you wanted
to find all the documents
where, let's say, name was Zoe,
you would need to scan every
document in the collection,
and there could be
millions of those.
And this collection
scan or a table scan,
as it's called in
the relational world,
is just death to performance.
It's probably the single
greatest factor on
whether or not your queries
are going to perform well.
More important than
the speed of the CPU,
more important than how
much memory you have
is whether or not you can
use some sort of index
to avoid having to look
at the entire collection.
So how does an index work?
What is an index?
Well, an index is an
ordered set of things.
So imagine that we just had
a simple index on, let's say,
the name.
And so if we had a
simple index in the name,
you can think of it as an
ordered list of things.
For instance, Andrew
might be on the left,
because it's
alphabetically early,
and Zoe might be on the
right, and in the middle might
be Bari and Charlie, et cetera.
And each of these
index points has
a pointer to a physical record.
So it's going to have
some sort of pointer
to a location on
a disc, or maybe
the underscore ID
for the document
so you can find the record.
So Bari record
might be right here,
Charlie record might
be right there,
Zoe record might be right there.
The nice thing about having
something that's ordered
is it's very fast to search it.
Because if it was
actually a linear list
like this-- and it's not
in a typical database.
But if it was linear
like this, then you
could search using
a binary search
and it would take you log
two of the number of items
in this list.
In real databases and in
MongoDB, the actual way
that this index is structured
is called a B-tree,
and looking at what a B-tree
is a little beyond the scope
of this course, but if
you just go on Google
and search for B-tree, you'll
get to a great Wikipedia page
that explains it pretty well.
Because you're going to want to
put these indexes on the items
that you believe you're
going to be querying on,
because that's going to
make querying much faster.
But sometimes we don't just want
to query on, let's say, name.
We also want to query on
name and maybe hair color.
So how would that work?
Well, an index on
name and hair color
would be represented as follows.
You'd write name comma hair
color, and that's ordered.
And if you did that, then
all of the index entries
would be ordered by
name comma hair color.
So for instance, there might be
an index entry for Andrew comma
blonde, and that's going
to be a single index
entry, which I'll represent
by making it green like this.
And then there might be another
index entry for Andrew comma
red.
And again, that's just one
index entry right here.
So we have another
index entry here.
And Andrew, blonde might
refer to this document here.
Andrew, red might refer
to this document here.
And then you might
have one for Bari,
brown hair, and then that's
going to be right here.
And maybe that
points to over here.
And then another
one for Bari, red,
which might be a document
that is over there.
And then in the far
corner here, let's say
I have another index entry for
Zoe, and then let's say red,
and maybe that document
is somewhere over there.
These documents, which I'll
show you where they are,
they're in the order of
name comma hair color.
So you can see that if you
wanted to find, let's say,
all the [? Baris ?] with
a certain color hair,
you could do it pretty easily
because you could, again,
do a binary search
of the structure
and then do it again through
this part of the structure
to find, let's say,
Bari with red hair.
You could also do range queries.
So you could say find me all
the [? Baris ?] with hair that's
greater than or equal to brown
and less than or equal to red.
That would also work.
But if, on the other hand, you
specified just the hair color,
you'd kind of be stuck, right?
Because if I said just find me
all the people with hair color
red, they're sort of
all over the place,
and they're not ordered in a
particular way in this larger
structure, so I can't use a
binary search to find them.
So as a result, whenever
I'm using an index
I need to use a
leftmost set of things.
So if the index were,
let's say, extended
and included the
date of birth, then
I could search on
just the name-- that
would work in this index
because I could just
do a nice little search.
Or I could search on the
name and the hair color,
or I could search on the
name and the hair color
and date of birth.
But I can't come in with just
the date of birth or just
the hair color
because then I have
no way of searching this index.
So let me review
what I just said.
If you have an
index-- and indexes
are going to be described this
way when we talk about them--
of a, b, and c, then
you can search on a,
you can search on a, b.
You can search on a, b, c.
c alone, no.
c comma b, no.
And if you searched on,
let's say, a comma c,
then it's sort of a
partial yes because it
would use the index
for the a portion
and have to search through
all of them on the c portion.
The other point I want to make
is that indexing is not free,
because whenever you change
something in a document which
affects the index, you're going
to have to update that index,
you're going to have to write
it on memory, and eventually
on disk.
Now, the indexes
aren't represented
the way I did linearly.
They're represented as B-trees,
but maintaining these B-trees
takes time.
So as a result, if
you have a collection
and you have indexes
on that collection,
and the writes affect
items that were indexed,
the writes will be slower
than if there was no index.
That's right, indexing actually
slows down your writes.
But your reads will
be much faster.
Now, if you were just
writing and you never
wanted to ever, ever
find a document,
you might not want to have
an index, because then you
can insert the document, it
would be inserted anywhere
on the disk-- it
wouldn't matter where--
and there will be no
index to maintain.
And in fact, one
of the strategies
when inserting a very
large amount of data
inside a database is
to have no indexes
on the actual collection at
all, to insert all the data,
and then after all the data is
inserted, then add the indexes
and then build the indexes.
That way you don't have to
incur maintaining the indexes
while you add data
incrementally.
And the fact that
writes are slower
and the fact that it
takes time to update
an index on every single write
that affects anything in index
is one of the reasons
why you don't just
want to have an index on every
single key in a collection.
Because if we had an
index on every single key
in the collection,
then you're going
to slow down your
writes more, and you're
going to use a lot
more disk space,
too, to maintain those indexes.
I just want to point
out that if you
had 10 million items
in a collection
and there's no index and you
search on something, anything,
you're going to look at
10 million documents,
and that's pretty expensive.
And if you have to look at
10 million documents or 100
million documents and
the amount of memory
you have is much smaller than
the amount of disk or space
that the documents
represent on disk,
then you're going to wind up
swapping all those documents
to memory and creating a
tremendous amount of disk
IO, which is going
to be pretty slow.
And this is why indexing
is so absolutely
critical to performance.
All right.
Now it is time for a quiz.
Which optimization
will typically
have the greatest impact on
the performance of a database?
You can see there are
four choices here.
Adding memory, so that the
working set fits in memory.
Adding a faster drive
so that the operations
that hit the disk will
happen more quickly.
Replacing your CPU with a
faster one, say, twice as fast.
Or adding appropriate
indexes on large collections
that only a small
percentage of the queries
need to scan the collection.
Check the right answer.