Now I'd like to show you a
large collection and the impact
that indexes can
have on performance.
So I've loaded up 10 million
documents into a collection,
and I'm going to show you
that in the mongo shell.
It's in the school database
in the student's collection.
And I'm going to look
at a single document
in the collection,
which is a great way
to get an understanding of
what the data looks like,
assuming it's regular,
and it is in this case.
So you can see each document
has a student ID and a bunch
of scores for the student.
These are four assessments--
an exam, a quiz, a homework,
and a homework.
These are the grades they
got in this particular class.
And so there are 10
million documents,
so there are one
million students that
have each taken 10 classes.
Now, there's absolutely no
indexes on this collection.
So let's see how long
it would take to do
a query on this collection.
And try to find all the
information for student ID,
let's say, 5, which should be
very early in the collection
because we just inserted it.
It was probably inserted
in order on the disk.
I'm running the MMAPv1
storage engine in this case.
All right, let's do that.
All right, that
took a few seconds
to return those 10 documents,
and this is a fast computer.
This is a four gigahertz
core i7 computer
with 32 gigabytes of
memory and a fusion
drive that has a combination
of SSD and spinning disk on it.
So that's a long time.
That's a lot of cycles
for a computer this fast.
So the question is, how
could we make it faster?
But before I do that, I want
to show you a couple things.
First is that there is
an explain command--
that we're going to go over in
a later lesson-- that will show
you the secrets of
what the database is
doing when it executes a query.
And I want to give you a little
foreshadowing of this command.
It runs on top of a collection.
So db.students, students
is the collection.
Explain is the command.
And then you chain
what you want to do.
In this case you
want to do a find.
You can also chain
an update, or delete.
And it's going to tell you
what indexes it would have
used to satisfy this query.
Now, in this case there
aren't any indexes it can use.
And it's going to scan
all 10 million documents,
and it should tell us that.
So if we look through
the output of explain--
and we'll go through it in
more detail in a later lesson--
the interesting part is right
here in the winning plan
section, where you
can see it says
it's doing a collection scan.
It's looking at
all the documents.
And that's going
to be pretty slow.
Now, if we actually did
a findOne versus a find,
then it'll be faster.
And the reason
it'll be faster is
that once it finds a single
document, it can quit looking.
And so since the documents are
probably in student ID order
approximately right now,
that's going to be fairly fast.
And you can see that was fast.
It didn't take very long for
it to return a single document
for the student ID 5.
But we want our general
find to work well,
so we want to add an index.
So how do we do that?
Let's add the index,
db.students.createIndex--
and you'll notice it's camel
cased inside the shell,
lowercase C, uppercase
I. And now we're
going to present the
document to create
index that describes the index.
And in this case,
we're saying we
want it to be indexed
on student ID ascending.
And we'll talk a little bit more
about what that means later.
But we're going to
hit Return, and this
is going to take a while.
So I'm going to time
this off camera,
so that I can tell
you how long it took
on this super fast computer.
Here we go.
OK.
It took about 23 seconds on this
computer to create this index.
And that's important
to note because even
on a really fast
computer, creating
an index takes a while.
Because we have to scan
the entire collection,
create new data structures,
and write them all to disk.
Now that we have an
index, this search
on finding all the
students with student ID 5
should be nice and fast.
Let's see if it is nice
and fast, and it was.
And if we run the
explain command,
we're going to see that
it's now using an index.
So let's see that.
All right, so I ran the
explain command once again.
And you can see now
it says the winning
plan for this type
of query is to use
the indexName student_ID
1, and that's fantastic.
And one little other secret
I'll tell you about explain
is that if we give
it true-- and there's
two ways to give
arguments to explain,
this is actually the older
one-- then it'll actually
run the query as well.
Which means it can tell us
how many documents it actually
looked at in the execution
stage of the query.
And you can see that the
number of documents examined
was exactly 10.
Isn't that pretty cool?
So once it used
the index it only
had to actually look
at 10 documents.
Wow, that's fantastic.
All right, now we could
also add a compound index
to this collection.
And if we wanted to
add a compound index,
we would do it as such.
We would give a second key and
then ascending or descending.
So for instance,
this is the command
you would give to create an
index on student ID, comma
class ID.
Where the student ID
part was ascending,
and the class ID
part was descending.
And this won't affect
the queries we just did,
but it will affect
things like sorting.
Where if the indexes
aren't in the right order,
and depending on how
you specify the sort,
you may not be able
to use the index.
OK.
So now it is time for a quiz.
Please provide the
mongo shell command
to add an index to a collection
named students having the index
key be class, student_name.
And neither of these will
be in the -1 direction.
Type your answer right here.