Let's talk about creating
indexes on arrays.
We call these indexes
multikey indexes.
So imagine you have a
collection of documents
that look similar to this.
This document has name Andrew,
tags photography, hiking,
and golf-- some of my
passions-- color red--
I don't know why,
I just picked it.
And then location, this is also
an array, New York, California.
You can create an index
on tags, and if you
do that, then when MongoDB
indexes the collection
and if this document
were already in there,
then it would create an index
point for photography, hiking,
and golf.
You could also create an index
on, if you wanted, tags, color.
And in that case, MongoDB
would create, for instance
for this document, index
points for photography red,
hiking red, and golf red.
Now, multikey indexes
become multikey indexes
when the database
realizes that there
is a document with an array as
one of the keys of the index,
and there are restrictions on
the use of multikey indexes.
In particular, you can't have
two items of a compound index--
and this is a compound index--
where both of them are arrays.
So for instance,
this index would not
be legal-- tags, location--
if there was already
document in the collection where
both tags and location were
arrays.
And what MongoDB will tell
you is it can't index parallel
arrays, and the
reason is there's
an explosion of index
points that create it
because it has to
create index points
for the Cartesian product
of the items in the arrays,
and it doesn't permit that.
Another thing to remember
is that when you first
create an index if there's,
say, nothing in the collection,
MongoDB doesn't know that there
may be an array, for instance,
in tags in the future.
And so an index only
becomes multikey
when the first
document gets added
and has as its value for
one of the keys an array.
So that sounds kind
of complicated.
Let's go through it concretely
and look inside the shell
to get a better understanding
of how this works.
All right.
So let's start the Mongo shell.
We have a foo collection,
which is empty.
We're going to create a
simple document where a is 1
and b is 2.
OK.
And if we do that,
it gets inserted,
and you can see it's
in there no problem.
Now, if we wanted to
create an index on a, b,
we could do that by
typing db.foo.creatIndex a
ascending b ascending.
There was one index.
Now there are two.
And if we use our friend the
explain command that we're
getting to know better and
better, foo collection,
call explain, and then do a
find where let's say a is 1.
Perfectly reasonable query.
a is 1 and b is 1 we'll say.
We can look here and we can
see that in the query planner
stage of this explain output,
it tells us about the winning
plan, and the winning plan
was to use an index scan
on the index a_1_b_1, and that's
the name for the a, b index.
If we do get indexes,
we'd see that.
And it tells us that it
is not a multikey index.
OK, fair enough.
Well, that makes sense.
I mean, there's not
much in this thing.
We saw that all there is
is the single document,
and it doesn't have a
array at either part.
But now let's insert
something else into here.
Let's insert a document where
a is 3 and b is an array--
3, 5, 7.
Now, if we did that,
now at this point,
if we run the exact
same query we ran before
and we do a Find of a,
1, b, 1, and we run it
through the explain command,
then what output will we get?
Let's see.
Well, once again, it tells us
that it's using this index,
a, b a_1_b_1 index, but this
time it says multikey true,
and if we, of course,
issued this command
without the explain, it would
find exactly no documents
because there are no documents
that satisfy this criteria.
Now let's see what
was in the collection
so we can get a better query.
We have a, 3 and b, 5.
Let's look for documents
that have a, 3 b, 5.
That'll be in there.
a, 3, b, 5.
Now if we did that, then
we'd get the one document
right there.
And again, if we look
at it with explain,
we'll see that that
query also produces
the same result
telling us that it's
using the multikey
index, the index that's
been upgraded to multikey.
And again, if you do get
indexes on this collection,
you'll see that
the index is called
a_1_b_1, which is what we saw
inside the explain output.
But let's say we
did something else.
Let's say that we actually
now inserted something
in this collection where
both a and b were arrays.
Like for instance, 3,
4, 5, and b is 7, 8, 9.
If we insert something
into the collection where
both a and b are arrays,
it's not going to work.
It's going to say I'm
sorry, I can't put anything
into this index where both
a and b are both arrays.
All right, so this makes sense.
I mean, we have this collection,
and we can see what's in it.
We can see that we have
two different documents,
and in the second one, b is a
list or an array and a is not.
Well, what if we wanted
to insert something
where a was a list
and b was a scalar?
Would that be OK?
And the answer is yes
because this is not
a multikey index in a way
that says oh, b always
has to be an array.
It's a multikey index and
allows any combination.
So for instance, a can be an
array, and b can be a scalar,
or b can be an array,
and a can be a scalar,
and they're both legal.
It's just that you can't
have any one document where
both a and b in this compound
index are both arrays.
I hope that's clear.
And the other thing
is that once index
has been upgraded to
multikey, even if you dropped
all the documents out
of this collection,
it would still say it was
multikey when you didn't
explain on the collection.
So the key takeaways here
is that you can add indexes
on arrays, and you can
create compound indexes
that include arrays, but
when you have an index that
is a multikey and where
at least one document has
a value to being
an array, you can't
have multiple values
of a compound index
both be an array.
That's not legal.
All right, it's time for a quiz.
Multikey indexes.
Suppose we have a collection
foo that has an index created
as follows--
foo.createIndex a 1 b 1.
This should seem
very familiar to you
if you watched the lesson.
Which of these following inserts
are valid to this collection?
Check all that apply.