All right.
And the first two are correct.
And we went over
them in the lesson,
which is that you will get a
smaller index if it's sparse.
And you are able to
create unique indexes
when some of the documents
lack the key that you
want to index on.
So that's true.
But the last two are not
true, because the third one
is actually pretty
much a non sequitur.
Your indexes can only be
multikey if they are sparse.
That's not true.
And the index can be
used to sort much more
quickly in all cases.
So this is not true.
The "all cases" part
is what's not true,
which is to say that you can't
use a sparse index to sort,
as I showed you, if using
it would omit any documents
from the final result.
So that's not true.