All right.
We've shown you how to
create unique indexes.
And now, I want to show you how
to create sparse indexes, which
are indexes that can be used
when the index key is missing
from some of the documents.
Now, let's look at these
four documents here.
The first one has a, b, and c.
The second one has a, b and, c.
The third one has just a
and b, and the fourth one
has just a and b.
And you'll also notice that
the a values and the b values
are unique as are the c values.
If I wanted to create
a unique index on a,
that would be no
problem because you
can see that there's a unique
value for a in all four
of the documents, and a appears
in all four of the documents.
A unique index on b
wouldn't be a problem.
But a unique index on
c does pose a problem.
And the reason is
that, if you just
create a unique index
on c, these documents
both have a c value of null.
And hence, it would violate
the unique constraint to index
on c for all four documents.
You actually could
have a single document
with null in it for c-- or
c missing, I should say.
And that would work fine.
But you couldn't have
multiple documents.
Well, what's a
possible solution?
Well, one solution is that you
can specify the sparse option
when creating the
index, and what
sparse tells the database
server is that it should not
include in the index documents
that are missing the key.
So if you say, give me an
index on c, it'll say fine.
These documents go in the index.
But these documents, they won't
even be indexed by this index
because they have
no value for c.
Now, let's see how this
would work in practice.
All right.
I've created a small collection
that I call "employees,"
and that collection has
just a few employees in it.
Actually, four-- let's see.
How many employees does it have?
It has five employees.
It has Eliot, Dwight,
Meghan, Andrew, and Shannon.
There's are real
employees at the company.
And actually, these are their
real employee ID numbers
in the sense that this is what
order they joined the company.
I think Eliot set
up the database,
so he made himself 1 and made
Dwight, his co-founder, 2.
And Meghan Gill was still
here, and she's number 9.
So you can imagine
that we'd probably
want to have a unique
index on employee ID,
and I added one to
this collection.
But you might also want to have
a unique index on cell phone
number because maybe
you want to make sure
that no two employees claim to
be carrying the same cell phone
number.
Well, that would work fine,
except that, you can see,
that Andrew and Shannon
don't have cell phones.
And so if you create
a unique index
without giving the sparse
option, it's not going to work.
So let me show you that.
So first, let's
look at the indexes
that already exist
in the collection
by calling
db.employyes.getIndexes.
And we'll see that there
are two indexes right now
in the collection.
One of them is on underscore
ID, and the other one
is on employee ID and
is, in fact, unique.
So if I just try to add
an index on cell phone--
cell ascending-- and make
that unique, and you can see I
get a duplicate key
error because we
have more than one employee
that has no cell phone number.
However, if I specify
an additional option--
sparse true-- now, I can
happily create the index.
Now, I have an index
on the cell phone.
You can see that I've got an
index on underscore ID and one
on employee ID and one on
the cell phone, which is also
unique, even though both
myself and Shannon are missing
cell phones in this collection.
So we have these five
employees, and two of them
are missing cell phones
in the collection.
Now, interestingly
enough, if you
go through all the
documents and do a Find
and then sort the documents
by employee ID, which
is one of our indexes,
you get a sort
by employee ID, which is the
order I put them in anyway.
So it wasn't that interesting,
but maybe descending
is slightly more interesting.
And that works fine.
And if you ask the database
did it use an index to satisfy
that query by using
the explain command,
which we're learning
more and more about,
we can see that
here, in the winning
plan for this Find
sorted by employee ID,
it sorts the documents using
the employee ID key-- an IXSCAN.
That's going to be
a very fast sort.
And if this collection
were very large,
that could yield significant
performance advantages
because we were able
to use the index.
However, if we do the exact
same type of sort, but instead
of sorting on that,
sort on cell phone--
and we'll just sort
ascending on the cell phone--
then what we're going to
find is, if we look here
at the winning
plan and the sort,
we can see it did a
full collection scan.
It was not able to use that
index on the cell phones.
Now, why is that?
That's because
the database knows
that this is a
sparse index, and it
knows that there are entries
missing, that certain documents
are not indexed.
And if it uses that
index for the sort,
it knows it's going
to omit documents.
And it doesn't want
to omit the documents,
and so instead it reverts
to a collection scan.
So as you keep in mind
that a sparse index can't
be used for sorting if there are
any documents that are missing
from the index--
and that's probably
why you'd use a sparse
index, so it basically
can't be used for sorting.
So keep that in mind.
Now, the good thing
about a sparse index
is that it could use
a lot less space,
and that's one of the
reasons why you might
want to use a sparse index.
And of course, it lets
you create a unique index
when you don't have an entry
in every single document
for the key that you
want to index on.
All right.
Now, it's time for a quiz.
What are the advantages
of a sparse index?
Check all that apply.
The index would be smaller than
it would if it were not sparse.
You gain greater flexibility
with creating unique indexes.
Your indexes can be multikey
only if they are sparse.
And the index can be
used to sort much more
quickly in all cases.
Please check the answer.