OK, you've seen "explain"
more than a few times
during this unit.
But we haven't really gone into
any great detail about what
it does or how it works.
So "explain" is used to find
out what the database is doing
with your query, how
it's executing it,
what indexes it's using, and
how many documents it inspected
when it actually ran the query.
And the thing to
remember about "explain"
is that in all cases when
you use an "explain",
it doesn't bring the data
back from the database.
It may do most of the
work to do the query,
but doesn't actually bring data
back all the way to the client.
So it's really
used to figure out
what database
would do if it were
to complete this
query completely,
but isn't an entire
simulation of what would
happen if you did the query.
Second, a lot of what
we've done in this unit,
shows you how to use "explain"
from the shell, which
is one of the most useful places
to examine the performance
of any particular query.
But you can also use
it from the drivers
and from your
application if you want.
Now, in MongoDB 3.0, we
changed the way "explain"
works, especially in the shell.
We call this "explain"
2.0 internally.
The first thing is that it used
to be that you would call db.--
let's say foo, if there
was a query-- .find.
And then that would
essentially produce a cursor.
And then you would call
"explain" after that.
But in 3.0, we changed
it, so that instead
the preferred method
of using "explain",
is to call db.foo.explain.
And that returns an
explainable object.
And from there, the
explainable object,
you can run a "find' on.
You can also run an "update" on.
You can run a "remove"
on it and "aggregate",
and a few other things.
Most notably, you can't
run an "insert" on it.
So "insert" is missing.
So you can't find out what
the query optimizer would
have done for an "insert."
But honestly, there isn't
much to learn about inserts,
because inserts, it puts
data in the database
and it has up there
all the indexes.
And that's really it.
So there's no 'find"
portion of an "insert."
There's a "find" portion
of an "update", obviously.
"Find" the modifier is allowed
here, including "help."
So they're now helpers.
So if they're inside
the shell and you
call "db.foo.explain.help",
you're
going to get help to figure out
which function you can actually
use with "explain."
And again, this right
here is returning what
we call an explainable object.
Now, in the next
lesson, not this one,
we're going to go
over what parameters
you can give to explain
in terms of verbosity.
But in this one,
we're just going
to use it in its default
form and see what
it produces to understand it.
All right, so let's go
through some shell work
so we can see this thing in
action and understand it.
Let's start the Mongo shell.
And let's fill a
collection with some data.
And I'm going to do that.
I'm going to cheat a little bit.
I'm going to copy
something that's
going to create approximately
one million documents.
And you could see it's a nested
loop of JavaScript 100, 100,
100.
And it's in the "a" key, the
"b" key, and the "c" key.
And so it's also setting the
"_id' value to, I believe,
just an increasing integer.
So we'll do that.
And it's going to take
a little bit of time
to insert a million
objects into the database.
All right, and now that's done.
We edited out some of that time,
but it took about 10 seconds.
Now we're going to add some
indexes to the collection.
Well, first let's look
at the collection,
so you can see
what it looks like.
So I call this "example", so I'm
going to do a "find_one" on it.
Oh, I'll just do a "find"
on it, so you can see it.
And you can see that it's got
data where these "_id"s are
increasing.
And then the "a",
"b", "c" values,
they are going to
go up 100 at a time
until eventually the "b"
value will increment.
There you go-- have
"b" values incremented.
So you can see there's
just a lot of data variant
a, b, and c.
Now let's add some
indexes on this thing.
Let's add two compound indexes,
one on "a, b" and one on "b."
So "db.example.createIndex"
"a, comma 1, b comma 1."
All right, so we're adding
index on a million objects.
That was actually pretty fast.
And now we're going to
add other index on just b.
OK.
Now we've got two other
indexes other than the "_id"
index on this collection.
Now, let's say that we wanted
to get an explainable object.
Well, let's do it this way.
"var exp equals
db.example.explain."
And exp is an
explainable object.
And now we're going to call--
well it's just for grins,
let's just call "exp.help", so
you can see what that produces.
You can see it tells you all
these great things you can do.
I can call "find."
I can call "group."
I can call "remove."
I can call "update."
It's very exciting.
So we're just going
to call "find."
So "exp.find." and we'll
look for one where a is 17,
and b is 55.
And maybe we will also
sort it by b descending.
And we have two indexes on here.
One of them is on "a, b",
the other one's on "b."
So we're not sure
exactly what indexes
are going to get used in
the performance query,
although, you might have
a pretty good guess if you
understand the way indexes work.
And so we'll do that.
And we get a whole
bunch of data back.
And in this form, which
is the default form,
it's going to run it
in query planner mode.
And you can see here, first it
gives you a form of the query
that it used in the index.
And this is an
adjacent representation
of internal representation that
the server uses for the query.
And then it shows you the plan.
This is the winning plan.
The winning plan is
most interesting part,
of course, because the winning
plan is the one that actually
got chosen.
And it's good to
read these things
from inwards to outwards.
And you can see here that it
said at the bottom level here--
and sometimes there are
multiple inputs stages,
but here there's just one-- you
can see that it did an IXSCAN
and used "a" and
"b" of the index.
And the index it
used was "a_1_b_1",
which we know is
the index on "a,b."
If you do a
"db.example.indexes",
you'll see that index.
It's not a multikey index.
And sorry to use it
backwards, which is probably
because of the sorting order.
And right there it
shows you the bounds.
And since we were only
looking for a single document,
it just looked for something
with the bounds 17, 17, 55, 55.
It also showed you the rejected
plans in this case and says,
well, you know, it consider
using the index on just "b",
but that turned out
to be a worse choice
and so it didn't do it.
So this tells you that
the database actually used
the index that we
expected it to use.
Now, there's no magic to
the way we did this by first
creating an explainable object.
We could also have done it this
way-- "db.example.explain.find"
with the same thing.
And this will give you
the exact same result
as first getting an explainable
object for the collection
and then calling
'find", no difference.
You can see here, we
have rejected plan of "b"
and an accepted plan of
using "a_1_b_1" index.
So same exact result.
Now in earlier
versions of MongoDB,
the way that you would
actually do an explain of this
is by calling
"example.find.explain."
That does something
a little different.
What that does is it
gets back a cursor,
because "example.find"
will bring back a cursor
with the "explain" set on it.
But the result's the same
when you see it in the shell.
So you won't see
any differences.
You'll see the same rejected
plan and same accepted plan.
And in some ways,
it might seem more
natural to call
"db.example.find.sort" and just
an "append" and "explain" on it.
So you might ask, well,
why do we change it
up to have this idea of
an explainable object.
And the reason we changed
it up in this version,
in version 3.0, is
because certain things
don 't return a cursor.
For instance, if I wanted
to run a count on this,
I can't then get an
"explain" output.
Watch.
Don't work.
On the other hand, if I use
my explainable object "exp"
and I do a count
on that, you can
see I can actually get
an "explain" output.
So one of the advantages
to this new syntax
of getting an explainable
object for the collection
and then calling
the query operator
is that it's opened up
using "explain" on a larger
set of things.
And it's also, of course.
given us this awesome helper
interface.
So now "explain.help" works
and tells you all the things
you can run "explain" on.
Now let's look at
another example.
Let's look at something where
it couldn't use an index
and see what happens.
So that's not hard to do.
Let's use our explainable
object again "exp."
And then look for a
document with "c" being 200.
Now, if you recall,
there's an index on "a, b"
and there's an
index on just "b."
But there's no index on "c."
So this query should in fact
have to do a collection scan.
Let's see what happens.
Well, it only
considered one option.
The winning plan was to
scan the whole collection
in the forward direction for
a document where "c" was 200.
No plans rejected because,
apparently, it knew pretty much
that it had no other options.
So again, there are two
ways to call "explain."
You can get an
explainable object
or you can actually
call explain the cursor.
So let's look at that.
So if I do "var cursor
equals db.example.find a 99",
then I can call "explain"
directly on this cursor.
And that's really
equivalent to calling
"db.example.find.explain."
And I'll get a similar
result telling me
that it used an index.
In this case, it used
the "a_1_b_1" index.
And then I can actually
call "next" on the cursor
if I want the result.
And that's just
a little subtlety
of the shell, which
is that when you
call "db.example.find" without
assigning it to a variable,
the shell actually iterates
the cursor for you.
Whereas, if you
assign it to a cursor,
then it doesn't iterate it
for you giving the opportunity
to then append and
explain, if you want.
Kind of a lot of strains the
little nuances of the shell.
But I guess the
real takeaway here
is that the preferred
way to call "explain"
in this version of MongoDB is to
call it on the collection first
and to get an explainable
object, and then to do a
"find."
Something like this.
OK, now it's time for a quiz.
Which of the following
are valid ways
to find out which index
uses a particular query?
Check all that apply.
And I'm not going
to go through these.
I'll read them to you,
but take a look at them
and try to see if you can
figure out which ones work.