All right.
The answer is a
lot of them work.
So db.example.find.explain
does work, and these work, too.
The example.explain.find,
this is very similar.
In this first case,
we're getting a cursor
and then we're
calling explain on it.
In this case, we're getting
the explainable object
and then we're calling
find an explainable object.
In this case, explainable
object, in this case,
it's an explainable object and
we assign it to a variable,
and then we use that
variable to call find.
And in this final
case, we got a cursor
and then we called
explain on the cursor.
The second case doesn't
work because what
we did is we called
db.example.remove,
which doesn't return a cursor.
See, that's the secret.
That's why we had to move
to this new interface.
And then we tried
to call explain
on it, which will not
work, and you can try it
and confirm that yourself.