The answer is that only the
last one is a covered query.
So let's go through it slowly.
So this query right
here only looks at name,
and it can use this index,
name, date of birth.
And then this final index
shows name, date of birth,
and suppresses _id.
This is completely eligible
to be a covered query.
This one above right here,
where it looks just at name
but returns hair
and name and _id,
the issue is here that
if it looks just at name,
it's going to use
this index right here.
It's not going to
use this index.
It can't use this index for name
very well because, of course,
it's not a left subset.
So it's not going to
choose this index at all.
It's going to
choose a name, date
of birth index for this
query, the third one, and then
it's going to have
to produce hair
and it can't do that
so it's going to go
to the documents for that.
You can test that out.
You can create some
collections to see.
Now, this one over here
looks just at name,
and here, once again, it's going
to choose name, date of birth.
But what's even worse is that
_id is going to be produced
by this query and that won't
work because _id is not
in the index.
And this one over here
is looking just at _id,
which is going to
use the _id index.
And so name and date of birth
do not appear in that index
at all, and so hence, it will
need to go to the documents.