OK, now I want to talk to you
about the concept of a covered
query.
Now, a covered
query is not a query
that is covered by a
house, but instead it's
a query where the query itself
can be satisfied entirely
with an index.
And hence, zero
documents need to be
inspected to satisfy the query.
Now, if you can satisfy a
query entirely from the index,
that's going to make
the query a lot faster.
Let's go through an example in
the shell to see how it works.
All right, I have a collection
that I call Numbers that
has a million documents in it.
And it was just put in here with
a nested loop of i, j, and k,
so pretty straightforward.
And if we look at Numbers and we
see what the indexes are on it,
we see that there are,
in fact, two indexes.
There's index on underscore ID
and there's an index on ijk.
Those are the only indexes.
So let's see how we
would create a query
and find out whether
it's covered.
So I'm going to create an
explainable object-- var
exp equals db.numbers.explain.
And I'm going to use
the execution stats
level of output.
Now we're going to use
that object to called find,
and we're going to look for
something where i is 45,
j is 23, and that's it.
And let's see what
that produces.
So this is our explain output.
Actually, before
we look at that,
let's just go back and see
what the actual result would
be of that.
Give it a little
bit more context.
You can see that if
we gave that query,
we get a bunch of documents i,
j, and k, and underscore ID.
And looking at
the explain output
and going up into the
execution stats part,
we see that there were 100
documents that were returned.
And that's right here.
And you can see that there
were 100 documents examined,
and you can see there
were 100 keys examined.
So if documents
were examined, that
doesn't sound like
a covered index.
And the question is since
there was an index in ijk,
and since we only
asked to see ijk,
why is it that this query had to
actually look at the documents?
Doesn't make a lot of sense.
And you can see that it
did use an index scan here
in that it use the ijk index.
And the reason is that we also
asked to see underscore ID.
And underscore ID is not
included in that index.
And so it had to
go to the documents
to actually return the result.
Let's change the
query little bit
and specifically project out
underscore ID zero, i1, j1.
Now we're saying we want
to see the i and j values,
and we don't want to see
the underscore ID value.
We can also see the k value.
It won't change the
result in this case,
because this is an index on ijk.
And if we did that query and we
looked at the executions stats
again in this explain output,
we see that once again we
got 100 documents out.
But this time, the number of
total keys examined is 100,
but the number of total
documents examined is zero.
And when the number of total
document examined is zero
and we use an index and
we returned results--
we have a number of
documents returned
that's greater than zero--
that's a covered query.
And this query was covered
by that index entirely.
And if we ran the query without
the explain, db.numbers.find,
we would see that we're turning
only the results for i, j,
and k, and no
underscore ID values.
And therefore, we can satisfy
this entirely with the index.
Now here's a slightly
surprising result,
which is that if we call
this query like this, where
we suppress the
underscore ID, right here,
and a silent on the other
options, we get pretty much
the exact same output.
This is exactly the same output.
But if you do an
explain of this query--
I'm going to find on
the explainable object
with the same query,
where i and j is specified
and the underscore
ID is suppressed--
we're going to find
that, in fact, if we go
to the top of the
execution stats,
100 documents were examined
and 100 keys were examined,
and 100 documents were returned.
So what's going on here?
That seems kind of weird.
And it's a little
subtle, but the issue
is that with this query, when we
suppress underscore ID but are
silent on what we want
to do with the other keys
in the document, MongoDB needs
to inspect every document,
because it doesn't
know if there's
another key in a document.
There could be an l or
a p key in a document.
It doesn't know for sure that
it could satisfy this query
with just the ijk index.
Only in the case
where you project
exactly what's in the index-- or
I should say a subset of what's
in the index-- and if it's
an index that doesn't include
underscore ID, then underscore
ID has to be suppressed,
it's only in the case where
the index could completely
satisfy the query with
certainty that it's covered
and the database can avoid
looking at the documents.
If there's any
possibility of having
to present the value for a
key that's not in the index,
then it can't just
stick with the index.
It has to go to the documents.
All right, now It
is time for a quiz.
We'd like to perform a
covered query on the example
collection.
And this example collection
is called example,
and it's right here.
It has these indexes.
Which of the following is
likely to be a covered query?
Check all that apply.