OK, you're going to be hearing
a new voice after this.
Shannon Bradshaw, our
Director of Education,
is going to be delivering
some of the lessons,
and I'll be returning
toward the end of this week,
and also back next week, to
teach the rest of the course.
So welcome, Shannon.
OK.
Now let's take a look at
how MongoDB chooses an index
to satisfy a query.
Let's imagine we
have five indexes.
When a query comes in, MongoDB
looks at the query's shape.
Shape has to do with what
fields are being searched on
and additional information,
such as is there a sort?
Based on that
information, the system
identifies a set of
candidate indexes
that it may be able to use
in satisfying the query.
So let's assume we
have a query come in,
and three of our five
indexes are identified
as candidates for this query.
So one, two, and three.
MongoDB will then create
three query plans, one each
for these indexes, and in
three parallel threads,
issue the query such that each
one will use a different index,
and see which one is able to
return results the fastest.
So visually, we
can think of this
as a race, something like this.
The idea here is
that the first query
plan to reach a goal
state is the winner.
But more importantly,
going forward it'll
be selected as the index
to use for queries that
have that same query shape.
So what's the goal state here?
Well, it can be one
of a couple of things.
So it could be that
one of the query plans
returned all the
results for the query.
Another way a query
plan can win is
by returning a certain
threshold number of results.
But there's a caveat
here, and that
is that it's able to return
the results in sort order.
Now, the real
value of doing this
is that for subsequent queries
that have the same query shape,
MongoDB knows which
index to select.
The way we achieve that is
through the use of a cache.
So the winning
query plan is stored
in the cache for future use
for queries of that shape.
Now of course, over time,
our collection changes,
the indexes change, so we
don't want this to necessarily
be the index we use forever.
So there's several ways in
which a query plan will end up
being evicted from the cache.
One of those is if there are
a threshold number of writes.
Right now that threshold
is 1,000 writes.
Another way, of course, is
if we rebuild the index,
or if any index is either added
or dropped from the collection.
And finally, if the [? mongod ?]
process is restarted,
we would also lose the
query plan, and other plans,
in the cache.
So this basic processes is
what MongoDB uses in order
to figure out which index to
use for the queries you submit.