Let's talk about
another type of index
that can be very useful
when dealing with text.
It's called a full
text search index.
So why would you use it and
what would you use it for?
Well, let's say you had a
very large piece of text
that was in a document,
something like the US
Constitution, which starts out,
"We, the people of the United
States, in order to form
a more perfect union."
Let's say you had that
document right here in a key
called My Text and you had
the entire preamble to the US
Constitution in
this key, My Text,
and you wanted to search it.
Well, if you searched
just on any given word,
then you wouldn't get
anything back because MongoDB,
when you search on
strings, the entire string
needs to be there.
So as an alternative, you
could put every single word
into an array and then use the
set notation operators to push
things into it and then
search for whether or not
the words are included,
but that's pretty tedious
and there are certain other
features that would be missing.
So instead, what we have is
something called a full text
search index, which is
abbreviated text, which
will index this entire document
and every word much in the way
an array is indexed to allow
you to do queries into the text,
basically applying
the OR operator
and looking for one
of several words.
So let's go look at
now a specific case
and see how it would work.
We've created a collection
called sentences,
and this collection
has got a bunch
of mostly just randomly
inserted words into a words key.
There is no text search
index on this right now.
This is a regular collection.
If I wanted to search for,
let's say, "dog shrub ruby,"
I could do it.
There we go.
So I searched for
"dog shrub ruby"
and I found this document with
the words "dog, shrub, ruby,"
but it's very particular.
If I leave off the period,
it doesn't find it.
If I just do "dog
ruby," doesn't find it,
and if I just do "dog,"
it doesn't find it.
That's not going to work
too well for me to search
on these different words.
So now let's add a text index,
db.sentences.ensureIndex,
and now I want to put an
index on words of type text.
There we go.
And now when I search it,
"dog shrub ruby," it's
going to work a lot
better, so let's do that.
Let's first look at the syntax
for searching a full text
index.
The way it works is
I have to say $text
and then give a
document with $search
and then what I'm looking for.
So we saw that, for instance,
"dog" did not work before.
Let's just look for "dog"
now and see if that works.
There we go.
So now I searched for
just the word "dog"
and I was able to get all
of these back that have "dog
moss ruby," "dog shrub ruby."
And then just to show
you again, when I just
search for "dog" using a
regular search of words,
I don't get anything, but if
I search using a text index,
I'm going to show you
the syntax right here.
I search using a text index
by specifying $text and then
$search and then what
I'm looking for, "dog,"
I do get documents back.
I get all these documents
back because they all
have "dog" in them.
And if I also say "moss," I
get all of these back as well,
and if I say "moss ruby," I'm
going to get all these back,
and it's quite flexible.
Putting in a period
makes no difference.
Capitalization
It's going to also ignore
certain stop words that are not
considered to be significant
like "a" and "the"
in the English language.
So that's really
very useful if I
want to search for a
bunch of different words
and essentially apply
a logical OR operator.
Now, there's one other
thing I wanted to show you,
which is how you
can get back these
in an order that indicates how
good a match MongoDB believes
there is.
So let's look for one of these.
I'm going to show you
the syntax for this.
So let's look for
"dog tree obsidian."
Dog tree obsidian.
Let me go back and change this.
We can see the document right up
there with "dog tree obsidian."
The best match for
"dog tree obsidian"
should be the dog tree
obsidian document,
but we're going to do
something special now.
We're going to
project a Score field,
and we're going to use
a special $meta operator
and then take the
text score, which
is something that's
internally computed as it
runs through this text search.
We're going to get
that text score out
and then we're going to
sort by that text score.
We're not going to
test you on this syntax
but I want you to know it
exists if you ever need it.
If you do that, you'll
see that now, it's
ranking the documents in
order of their text score
and that, if you're
searching for "dog tree
obsidian," the one with the
highest score, a score of two,
is the document with "dog
tree obsidian," all three
words in it, very
useful if you want
to find the best
match for, let's say,
a document that
contains all the words.
So now it's time for a quiz.
Let's say you create a
text index on the title
field of the movies collection.
Imagine having a
movies collection,
and then perform the following
text search-- db.movies.find
$text $search "Big Lebowski."
Which of these
documents might be
returned if all
of these documents
are in the collection?