Welcome back to M101.
I'm here with Ryan Bubinski,
the Technical Co-Founder of
Codecademy.
And he's going to talk
to us today about
their use of MongoDB.
So thanks for coming
here, Ryan.
Thank you, Andrew.
It's my pleasure.
All right.
So tell me first, describe
what Codecademy
does for the audience.
A lot of them are from
Eastern Europe, so
maybe some don't know.
Certainly.
So Codecademy is the easiest way
to learn to code online, a
series of interactive courses,
tutorials, that take a
complete beginner to someone
who's competent and literate
in technologies of programming
and coding.
All right.
And it's a little bit different
than the way we're
structuring this course, because
rather than video
segments followed by these
little quizzes, it's more of
an interactive system where
you'll read a little bit and
then you'll do a hand-on task
which lets you show mastery
immediately of what you're
trying to accomplish, right?
Yeah.
That's right.
So we favor a learn-by-doing
approach.
So we try to get our students
coding as early as possible,
and start to teach them as there
actually performing or
coding what's going on what and
they're doing, and showing
them how they can apply
programming to build projects,
to build websites and
applications, and to really do
whatever it is they want
to do with programming.
And some of the first tracks you
did was in JavaScript, is
that right?
Our first track was
in JavaScript.
So it's completely web-based.
It's within the browser.
And so JavaScript is pretty much
the language of the web,
and it's also the language
of browsers.
And we wanted to start with
something that was immediately
accessible to as many people as
possible, and would allow
them to immediately start
creating interesting web
applications.
And for us, that
was JavaScript.
And it's been pretty
popular, right?
You've had millions of people
who have done the stuff and
gone through and taken
some of these tracks?
Yeah.
I think our approach has
resonated with a very large
number of people all over the
world with a wide variety of
interests, and I think we've,
fortunately, introduced to a
large number of people, who
wouldn't otherwise be
interested in programming or
who otherwise wouldn't have
gotten involved with
programming, we've gotten them
interested in the craft, and
we're starting to make code
normal, which is what
we want to do.
It's very cool.
So you started with MongoDB.
So how'd you decide
you use MongoDB?
What were some of the thing that
were interesting about it
to you guys?
Sure.
So there's a long story.
I think we'll get into
some of the details.
But the short version of it is
when we were first setting
out, Zach and I, my co-founder,
we were
prototyping different versions
of the site.
We were working through
different ways of creating an
interactive online platform, and
we were quickly changing
our model definitions, quickly
changing our schema,
definitions and the relations,
and models.
And we wanted a data store that
was very flexible and
that wouldn't slow us down
as we were making these
definition changes.
And I actually wasn't
familiar with Mongo.
I was a relational database
guy for many years before.
And I saw Mongo as this
fantastic technology that
would allow us to not worry
about the schema up front--
or at least until we needed
to start thinking
seriously at scale.
And so for us, MongoDB was the
easiest way to rapidly
prototype different
models and their
relations one way or another.
And I felt like that very
significantly sped up
development for us.
So did you have any concerns
going into it?
If you come from the world of
relational, what would you be
most worried about?
Naturally doing joins across
different models and different
tables, or in the case of
MongoDB, collections.
I think in the world of
relational databases, your
intuition or your gut is
always telling you to
normalize, normalize, normalize,
and in a document
or key values store, you need to
denormalize sometimes, and
sometimes that doesn't
feel right.
But in many cases, you can find
a very happy balance or
best of both worlds that is so
much easier to deal with.
Yeah.
What is your implementation
language for Codecademy?
Sure.
So Codecademy is primarily
built on top of Ruby for
anything server side and
JavaScript for some of the
server-side logic
and all of the
client-side logic, of course.
And we have multiple layers
outside of MongoDB.
Our API layer is implemented
in Ruby.
Our application layer is
implemented in Ruby and
JavaScript.
And we have a series of
independent JavaScript
applications that power the web
client or the actual web
application that most people
know of as Codecademy.
I see.
And do you use our drivers
directly or something
intermediary, like some mapping
layer to talk to MongoDB?
So for our API that wraps our
data layer, we use a object
document mapper called Mongoid,
which uses their own
version of a MongoDB driver
that directly communicates
with our database.
And we've experimented with
using the driver directly.
In some cases, we do-- if we
want a very particular type of
insert or update and we want
to go directly to the data
store and move on.
But for most development using
an ODM is a nice way of
encapsulating that logic and of
focusing at a higher level
on how the model's structured,
how it relates to other
models, and that allows us
to kind of more easily
conceptualize how we're laying
out the data layer.
So except in the rare cases
where we need to optimize
performance or a particular
use case, we use an ODM.
Yeah.
So that's my question.
With these mapping layers,
sometimes it puts a developer
a little bit further away
from the schema.
And getting the performance on
any database backed system is
about making sure you
hit the indexes.
Yep.
So is it a problem--
and maybe if you have a small
team, it's a big issue-- but
to have everyone be cognizant
of how to write code that's
going to hit the indexes
if you're using this
mapping layer or--
what are the benefits, what are
the pros and cons of that?
Yeah.
I think when you're choosing
whether or not to use the
driver or an ODM, so you need
to be cognizant of how many
developers there are,
like you mentioned.
How familiar the developers
are with your data store.
Some of the pros of an ODM,
of course, are logical
encapsulation.
Specific to the Rails
framework-- which we don't use
for an API, but we use for
an application layer--
our API is essentially
a Rack application.
And so there's very little
convention on top of what
you're building.
Rack?
Rack is a HTTP API,
essentially.
It's a bare bones framework on
top of Ruby that gives you a
nice interface for handling HTTP
requests and responses.
So it's basically what
powers the web server
interface for Rails.
Rails sit's on top of
Rack as a framework.
So Rails is a framework
on a framework.
And Rails has a lot of stuff
that you don't necessarily
want in an API, but you do you
want in a web application.
And so in an API where you're
optimizing on response time
and availability, you want to
go as far down to the web
server level-- meaning, like
in our case, we use Nginx--
you want to go as far
down to the request
response cycle as possible.
Just like you're talking about
sometimes when you're
optimizing for your data layer,
you want to get as
close to the data store
as possible.
So to go back, in something like
a Rails framework or a
web development framework, you
do want to encapsulate a lot
of that logic.
And you're optimizing for a
higher level structure.
You want to make sure that your
documents have the fields
that they need, that the
relations are properly set up.
And sometimes if you're dealings
exclusively with a
driver, handling properties of
models, handlings relations
models can get cumbersome.
When you're rapidly developing
and things are quickly
evolving, when your structure
starts to converge and you
want to start optimizing and you
start to have to consider
query times, write times, and
you start to get significant
load that really tests your data
layer, that's when you
need to start, as a team, of
course, focusing on what
percent of the time are you
hitting your indexes?
Right.
If you're not hitting your
indexes, how large is the
collection?
Is there a serious performance
issue?
And then you just start
benchmarking.
So we have opted to make sure
that everyone on the team is
familiar, of course, with the
entire stack, that people are
familiar with the drivers
that we use.
Not everyone directly uses the
driver, especially if you're a
front-end engineer who's moving
into the back end.
You're probably going to be
interacting with our ODM or
our mapper, and less
so the driver.
However, we have set up
a series of tools--
both ones that we've
built and ones that
are available publicly--
that alert developers if they
have missed an index on a
large collection, if they've
written a query that isn't
going to be performant in
production, or just
if they wrote a--
I don't know if you've guys have
covered n+1 queries, or
queries that result in,
essentially, a very large
number of requests to
the database in a
single web page request.
Yeah.
And all these things are very
dangerous when pushed to
production, so we try
to catch those in
development, of course.
So we've covered looking
at the query
plans, and the profiler.
Do you guys use that?
Do you try to log
long queries?
Do you regularly monitor that?
We use the 10gen MMS service for
essentially if something
goes wrong.
Kind of doing a what-happened
analysis and just
looking at the logs.
We run the profiler a percentage
of the time or on
certain deployments.
Not all the time, because
of the performance
hit that you take.
Right.
But we try to watch just the
raw application logs during
development.
We enable, of course,
logging and
development for our driver.
Just count the raw number
of queries that
you're doing on a request.
There's a lot of holistic kind
of goals that you should
strive for when you're building
a web applications.
Just touch the database
as little as possible.
Right.
You don't want to be doing 200
queries to your database on a
single web request.
It doesn't matter even if
they're a single millisecond.
The latency of the request
is still going to
hit you really hard.
So, just making sure that simple
things like that, which
a mapper can, sometimes,
naively implement--
Yes.
--just enough to be dangerous or
you're not exactly sure how
it's executing the query plan,
you can get into some of those
really dangerous situations in
a production environment.
Do you use any caching layer
in front of Mongo?
Like memcached or anything
like that?
We've thought about it.
We haven't had to.
That's great.
I think one of the core tenets
of Mongo is that your active
data set sits in memory.
So we've kind of had, I guess,
a basic philosophy that if
it's not performant at the Mongo
layer, then we're not
doing it right.
That's gotten us very far.
We have not set up an
intermediary caching layer in
production.
And in terms of session
management for the users, are
the web servers themselves, the
application servers, are
they stateless?
From interaction to interaction,
as the user
interacts with the website, do
you pull the state from Mongo
to figure out where you left off
or is there some binding
of the user to the application
layer?
Certainly.
Tell me about that.
So we have a horizontally-
scaled web application,
meaning that we have numerous
web servers.
And when a person hits the
website, they can get any one
of the servers.
Exactly.
Which requires that at least
those servers themselves have
to be stateless, or not have
any internalized knowledge
about user.
Right.
Every user has a session, and
we use cookie-based session
storage for users.
So when a user hits the site,
they're given a unique ID.
That unique ID relates to
a document in our users
collection, and that also is
stored locally on the user's
browser in a cookie that
stores their user ID.
So that cookie is essentially
sent to whichever
web server they get.
The web server says, OK.
Based upon that user ID
from the cookie that
the user sent me--
and there's various encryption
and security measures to make
sure that someone isn't
spoofing a user ID.
The web server will
then go to--
we originally used Mongo
for our session store.
We used Mongo for our session
store because it was simple,
especially for Rails.
There were nice packages
that would allow for
Mongo-backed sessions.
Just because we wanted to
reduce the raw number of
database queries and the number
of times we were going
to the database for a request,
we switched to a Redis-backed
session store.
Which is in memory.
Yeah, it's a share in memory.
And not persistent.
So if you turn off the machines,
you'd learn session
state in that case, right?
The difference is that Mongo
would persist the session.
Redis is meant to be a shared
volatile data store.
They do you have weak or not
eventual persistence to disc--
not anywhere at the level
of guarantee that
MongoDB would provide.
Right.
So you use Redis for
the session state.
So what happens is that a user
hit the site, they're in the
middle of the track.
You obviously have to know,
when they're submitting an
answer, what they're submitting
it to and where
they are in the track.
They're submitting,
basically, the
information plus the cookie.
And then that cookie is used
to retrieve a session state
from Redis and then you
process the request?
Is that the way it works
in the server?
The session state's not kept in
the client, as well, it's
kept in Redis on your
servers, right?
Yes.
OK.
And then the rest the
information, once they
successfully complete a step in
the lesson, that goes into
Mongo, into the documents.
Sure.
So as you're pointing out, Redis
doesn't have the same
kind of persistence guarantee
that Mongo has.
And so we do use Redis as this
quick session storage layer.
That gives you the
user context, as
you're talking about.
And if the page requires loading
the user document, all
of the stateful representation
of the application
is stored in Mongo.
Gotcha.
So the session does not store,
for us, meaningful or, I'll
say, primary stateful
information.
It'll store metadata around
the state, it'll store
contextual information that
if it was lost, would not,
probably, even be noticed
by the user.
But it helps us know where
we need to go to load the
stateful representation, and
primarily that's in Mongo.
So the web application or the
web server will go first with
the cookie, will go to Redis,
load the session context, and
then that will dictate what the
query plan is to load the
state for whatever web page or
portion of the web application
needs to be served back
to the client.
And then the web server
will go to Mongo
whatever that state is.
Almost all of our state
is persisted in Mongo.
OK.
So I think what I want to do
next is have you take me
through some of the evolution of
your scaling in front of a
whiteboard and just explain
maybe a little bit of your
schema and what's been important
to index, and some
things around performance.
So we're going to switch
to a whiteboard.
All right.
Sounds good.
Let's go do that.
All right.
So take me through, at a high
level, what the system looks
like and where MongoDB
fits in.
Sure.
Certainly.
So there's three major
components to Codecademy as a
complete system.
There's the client, the
application layer, and the
data layer.
And I'll describe all three.
And obviously, Mongo sits
on the data layer.
Right.
So we have you, your computer,
is the client.
And then you have, I'll call
this Rails, and this is the
application layer.
This is the client layer,
so this is your browser.
And then you have
the data layer.
And I'll represent
this as API.
This is Rack, as I mentioned.
And this communicates
directly with--
I guess we'll draw it as the
traditional representation.
This is Mongo.
So there's three major
components.
There's there client layer, the
application layer, and the
data layer.
We want to encapsulate the data
layer to make sure that
there's a very well defined
interface for how we're
accessing Mongo.
Because as we talked about
before, improper accesses to
Mongo can lead to a lot of
problems in production.
Right.
And so by abstracting out
these three different
components, we're essentially
ensuring that we can focus on
each individually and optimize
each individually, because
they have very different
use cases.
Client, you obviously care
about things like
browser load times.
Right.
You care about--
it's a primarily JavaScript
application, of course, you
care about the complexity of
that and even the size of the
requests and the size of the
assets that you're serving--
images, your CSS, your
JavaScript, your HTML.
For the application layer, you
have a lot of coupling.
You have a lot of different
components to it.
That's where you're defining
your requests and how they map
to actions and controllers, and
then how those controllers
do various ways of aggregating
your data to format them into
a proper response.
So the API is what connects the
application to Mongo by
essentially encapsulating
those access patterns.
So if the application wants
to, say, return your user
profile, it's going to
query across multiple
collections in Mongo.
So it's going to issue multiple
calls to the API that
do joins across multiple
collections, or different
parts of the database.
And you want to be able to
optimize how you're accessing
Mongo for those different
types of queries.
So I think we'll dive in a bit
to the data layer and how
through a request cycle we
go from the client to
Mongo and then back.
OK.
Sounds good.
So a student is sitting at the
computer and they're in the
middle of one of these
tracks, and they have
to submit an answer.
So what happens after that,
when they're submitting an
answer and it needs
to get evaluated?
Sure.
So you're sitting at
your computer.
You are on an exercise and
you make a submission.
So as soon as you hit Run,
you have this request.
This request it's going to have
code and other associated
metadata, like your--
as we talked about, we
store our session
information in Redis--
so it'll have your cookie.
Your cookie will have a
lot of this metadata,
including your user ID.
We actually, at the moment of
the request, use an external
code evaluation service that we
created that's outside of
the system.
We call it codex.
What's important is that this
happens outside of this entire
flow, and that's for
security reasons.
Code, when it's submitted, will
actually go to codex and
will come back with an
evaluated response.
At the end of that evaluated
response, you get the output,
and then we propagate
it and store it.
OK.
I'll sandboxed to that--
Yep.
All code is sandboxed.
This happens outside of this.
OK.
So once you have your request,
then have your evaluator
response, goes to Rails.
In Rails, it's making a post
request to a submissions
controller.
And this is a route.
We'll call it submissions.
And this is where the
application is receiving, at
the HTTP layer, your request and
then it's processing it.
So it's taking your request,
it's pulling from the API the
appropriate metadata so
that it knows where
to write the context.
So this is going
to require a--
we'll split it up into reads and
then we'll split up into
writes that happen.
So this will read your user.
This will be an API call, so
these are both API calls, as
we've talked about across
this layer.
It needs to read your context
for the user and it
needs to pull the--
we'll call it the
context context.
So for a submission, it's
associated with an exercise.
An exercise belongs
to a course.
It has a content context,
is what I'm calling it.
So it's going to pull,
essentially, the associated
exercise data.
On top of that, these are the
only two things that we need
to actually pull for a write
to get the appropriate
associated data to write
your submission.
What are the major collections
inside MongoDB
that represent this?
So if we're going to jump--
the application layer has
no knowledge of this.
For the API layer, it
has knowledge of--
there's a user's collection,
there is a--
we'll call it a section
collection.
Section have embedded
exercises.
The sections of a track to learn
a skill, in this case.
Right.
So sections, you can just
think of them as
groupings of exercises.
Yeah.
OK.
There can be a variety of--
Chapters, if you will.
--of chapters or different
ways of showing those
groupings to users, but we
essentially just say it's a
grouping of exercises.
It's a single document
and it has
embedded exercise documents.
And then there's another
collection called submissions.
So we are reading from users
and sections and we are
writing to submissions.
Right and so the learning track
is represented by the
sections collection?
Yep.
And it doesn't change when a
user goes through the track.
This represents the course,
if you will, and then the
submissions collection
is taking the user--
you're keeping track of
user progress here.
And just everyone kind of knows
how this thing works--
but you're writing code and it's
getting evaluated, and
you're telling them whether
they got the
right answer or not.
So that happens over in this
corner right here.
This happens completely
outside of this site.
Right.
Just because you never can
quite trust code that's
written by the user.
Yeah, we definitely don't want
this service having any
knowledge of any other
part of the service.
Right.
And so by the time it all gets
to here, you actually already
know whether the student
got the right answer?
Mm hm.
We both the code that you're
submitting and the evaluated,
I guess, response or result of
your code, as well as any
errors that were thrown, any
other kind of the information
that resulted from running the
code or evaluating it in an
environment.
Can you talk a little
bit about--
the size the collection,
the submissions
collection is the big one.
The users is more modestly
sized, and the sections is
probably quite small, because
that's just the courses
themselves.
Yeah.
I'll talk a little bit
about what orders of
magnitude are here.
I think just to kind of finish
the API calls here.
Sure.
So when you have your request,
this goes to
the application layer.
It goes to this route
as a post request.
That then has to reads for the
user into that collection
across the API, and it has
reads to sections.
So I think now that we know
about the exact collections
that we're querying, I'll
call this a section.
This is the associated
section exercise.
And then the writes
are to submission.
Gotcha.
OK.
And this then goes to the API.
The API is what contains the
driver that is doing the reads
and writes directly from Mongo,
and that does, we'll
call it, just aggregation.
This isn't the aggregation
framework.
I'm just using this
generically.
From when it does its reads,
and then upon aggregation,
does its writes.
And then we send the response.
And the client knows that
there's been a successful
write and it won't reattempt
another request.
If, of course, there's for some
reason a failure, there's
just an exponential backoff of
retries to ensure that the
request went through.
So a lot of the interesting
details here are around how we
deal with these different
collections and the different
orders of magnitude
that we have.
We've stored user submissions
from the very beginning.
And over the year and few months
now that the site's
been live, we've collected
hundreds of millions of
submissions.
Wow.
And that, of course, has a lot
of challenges, especially both
with the volume but also the
fact that code that people are
submitting varies
widely in size.
And so a submission document, if
we were to include the code
that was being submitted, each
submission document could
range from a few tens of bytes
to hundreds of kilobytes or
even potentially a megabyte.
And I don't know how much in
detail you guys have gotten
about compaction in MongoDB,
but that can lead to a very
inefficient storage
within MongoDB.
Right.
So we can talk a bit more about
the evolution of the
submissions collection, which
has posed some interesting
challenges for us as
we've scaled--
both from where we started
and where we are today.
Yeah.
Let's talk about that.
So you were telling me earlier
you're in a replicated but
non-sharded environment,
but in the past,
you've actually sharded.
So maybe you can take the
students through the evolution
of that decision and how you
managed to go from sharded to
unsharded, which is obviously
easier to administer because
your [? added ?] performance
is great.
So if you could talk
about that.
Yeah.
So there's three different
eras or versions of the
submissions collection.
I think I'll erase this,
and then we can--
Sure, yeah.
--go into more detail
about that.
So as I mentioned, there are
three different versions or
generations of our submission
collection.
At first, it was just a raw
submission collection.
It had things like
exercise ID--
this is the content context.
User ID.
And this was a unique key
index compound on
exercise and user IDs.
So we can get more into how we
introduced indexes on this in
the second generation.
It was on exercises ID comma
user ID you said?
Or user ID comma exercise ID?
Which was the index?
User ID, exercise ID.
And then we had this the
array for answers.
Answers are what actually stored
the submitted content.
So this would be an array of
embedded answer documents, and
these would have things
like, we'll call
it the actual entry.
This would be the code
the user wrote.
And then there'd be additional
information, like a time stamp.
We actually use abbreviated
property names or key names
because they're included in the
document size, but I'll
write them out here fully.
And so you use abbreviated key
names because it reduces the
size of your overall data
footprint in Mongo.
Yeah, because your serializing
your document into a binary
representation.
The property names of your
adjacent document are included
in the document size.
Right.
And as a result, it's something
you can easily
optimize, and especially if you
split your applications up
into these different interfaces
between your data
layer and your application
layer.
It's easy to just do, in the
API code, just do a simple
mapping where you're converting
between the full
text or the full length version
of the property name
and the abbreviated version
of the property names.
Right.
So the developers still get
the benefit of intuitive
names, and you get the
efficiency of having shorter
names inside the MongoDB
collections.
Yeah.
And if you have a very large
volume of documents that are
relatively small, your property
names can be even a
fourth, or even half, I guess,
in some cases, the size of
your total document.
So even just doing a simple
abbreviation can cut down the
size o collection in half.
Yeah.
So just go to the general
structure here, this is how we
originally started out.
It's just a simple exercise ID,
user ID, and then an array
of answers.
The is sorted.
We had an arbitrary limit on
the length of this array.
Obviously it could grow
uncontrollably.
We just hard-coded a limit.
It was pretty easy through
atomic pushes and pops off of
it to maintain that size.
And that was it.
So what was really interesting
here is as this collection
grew, it, of course, very
quickly got into the millions.
We needed to be very careful and
explicit with the indexes
that we were using here.
And so one problem that we
originally had was that,
occasionally, if someone would
hit Submit twice in rapid
succession, we couldn't
do a proper atomic
lookup and then write.
We weren't doing an
upsert on it.
Or if we were doing an upsert,
it wouldn't 100% of the time
because we were using an ODM.
We couldn't guarantee
uniqueness.
There's things that we could do
that would get us very far,
but we still couldn't guarantee
uniqueness.
And we wanted to-- just keep
our data set clean--
we wanted to guarantee
uniqueness across user ID
first and then exercise
ID second.
And in Mongo, the proper way
of doing that is creating a
compound unique index.
So some indexes here that we
created, very simply, was user
ID, exercise ID.
Right.
User ID comma exercise ID.
Yeah.
Sorry.
I use the hashes for notation.
Or the pounds.
And this was just unique.
Right.
And that then guarantees that,
of course, you're not creating
duplicate documents across
these two fields.
Yeah.
That's the information you know
when the user submits an
exercise answer, also.
Right.
And this is how we map a user
for an exercise to their
submitted content.
And we want to make sure that
there's only one document in
the database that is associated
with those two
values, and that we're
guaranteeing that we're
storing all of your submissions
in the right order.
Right.
And these never change.
So once you append something to
this answer's array, it's
never going to get edited.
Is that correct?
Right.
It's written once, read many
times in that sense.
Right.
OK.
So then you're able to, when you
write this document, you
just push something to the end
of this array, basically?
Yeah.
We use an atomic push
operation on it.
You use an atomic push.
A find-modify, essential.
Yep.
OK.
To push something
onto the array.
Do you do any padding of these
to try to make sure that as
they grow that they don't need
to get moved in the collection
or do you just let Mongo
deal with that?
Originally, we just let Mongo
deal with it, because this was
our implementation when we had
exclusively JavaScript content.
We didn't have content that
would require multiple tabs or
multiple types of files.
We didn't have content that
involves writing an entire
application, it might just
simply be a simple function
call or a simple method.
And so the variation size of
these files was within one or
two orders of magnitude.
And so Mongo did a relatively
decent job of determining the
proper padding length.
As we started to add complex
types of content and to accept
more complex types
of submissions,
that of course changed.
So I think we can talk about the
second generation and how
we had to change this schema to
fit into that new use case.
OK.
So this is, we'll say, it's
first gen and this is about,
we'll say, order of magnitude
1 million submissions.
And so going on to the second
generation, this is when we
were getting to, well say, the
next order of magnitude, about
10 million, with a high
variability in document size.
So we carried a lot
of things over.
Some of the things that
we changed was--
we kept a lot of the same
schema, and What we really
changed was our implementation
of Mongo.
So we did a few things.
We beefed up our boxes.
So Mongo, for us, is
hosted on EC2.
Before, in first gen, we were
using a third-party cloud
hosted service.
We move over to EC2.
We are running currently
here on quad extra
large memory instances.
So we significantly increased
the amount of memory that was
available to us.
As this collection was growing
larger and larger, it needed
to be in memory, and as a
result, it was easy for us to
scale vertically just
by provisioning
more significant hardware.
Right.
Scale up versus scale down.
Yep.
Versus scale down.
You bought bigger hardware,
and solid state disc?
Or just regular?
I guess solid state just wasn't
available when you--
It wasn't available, and I think
there's particular use
cases where you get a
significant benefit from solid
state, and for ours, we were
sufficient to stick with EBS.
Right.
We scaled up.
We went 4x large memory
instances.
We did use provisioned IOPS.
Provisioned IOPS, which is a
feature of Elastic Block Store
at Amazon Web Services.
Yep.
And that guarantees a certain
bandwidth between the EBS
network storage and
your instance.
If you're on traditional EBS,
there's no guarantee of
bandwidth and it can fluctuate
wildly, which, of course, for
a memory store which should be
memory but isn't always, you
want a guaranteed backup there.
Right.
We also set up a replica set.
Which is a best practice.
You definitely want to
use a replica set.
Right.
So not exactly scaling
horizontally like you would
when you shard, but it did
create for us multiple
machines to read from.
Yeah, you decided to read from
your secondaries, which meant
that you're also dealing with
eventual consistency versus
strong consistency.
Right.
So we had a single primary,
of course, and we had two
secondaries.
And we did writes to the
primary, and we did reads from
the secondary.
And the reason why we did that
was just to guarantee that we
could horizontally scale the
read load, and one machine was
more than sufficient to handle
the write load that
we had at the time.
It's primarily a read-heavy
application.
And this allowed us to both
ensure that in event of a
failure that one of the
secondaries would be promoted,
or in some way the load
would be balanced
if a secondary failed.
But also, like I said, to
horizontally scale our read
such that if the read load
significantly increased, we
could continually add
more secondaries.
Yeah.
And there's some debate within
10gen about whether or not
this is the best way to scale
reads or whether you'd be
better off just adding shards.
Yeah.
Aside from the consistency
issues, which is that you have
to have your application be
tolerant of reading data
that's potentially different
than what you wrote.
In terms of slowing down the
secondaries and slowing down
replication, you have to make
sure, of course, that from the
capacity planning standpoint
that these are as large--
often, people will buy cheaper
boxes for their secondaries
sometimes, and then they'll have
problems with keeping up
with replication if they load
this guy down with reads.
So not everyone recommend that,
but certainly a lot of
users do that.
They scale reads using
replication versus sharding.
And we talked a little bit about
that in the application
engineering part.
Yeah.
Definitely.
There were some reads that
had to go to the primary.
If we needed to guarantee
consistency, we would, instead
of using the secondary session
configuration, we'd use a
primary session configuration,
where we'd both write and read
from the primary.
And that was sufficient, but,
of course, like you were
saying before, it requires that
developers understand the
implementation of the data layer
and understand when you
have a guarantee of consistency
and when you don't.
And, right.
It isn't always easy or ideal.
After this, we're very happy
with the implementation--
Right.
This is generation two.
Generation two.
We, as we continued to grow, had
to actually look into an
alternative way of scaling
horizontally.
So I think we can spend some
time talking about that.
Yeah.
Sure.
So we're going to go to
third generation.
There were a few things
that we did here.
This is order of hundreds of
millions of submissions.
So we're starting to get into
some significant storage
requirements here,
because these
aren't simply log entries.
These are large documents that
are potentially have an array
of answers that could be
a megabyte or more.
Right.
And as know, there's a hard cap
on the document limit, and
our content was getting more
complicated, more elaborate,
complex, and the types of
submissions or answers for
that content was similarly
getting more complex.
We started introducing web
courses, we started
introducing courses
where people were
building actual programs.
And so we started to see that
submissions were increasingly
resembling file projects.
Right.
And so we were starting to use
Mongo as a file store, which
is not its intended purpose.
Yeah.
There's some GridFS stuff
in there, but yes.
Personally, I've never
liked storing very
large things in databases.
I think they're better
off in file systems.
But.
So, right.
The first thing that we did here
for the third generation
was take our array of answers
and take the entry field from
each of those documents
and store that in S3.
So we did S3-backed
answer storage.
And so we were treating S3 just
as a key value store.
We used a hash of the contents
so that it was essentially
guaranteed--
Right.
As free as Amazon Simple Storage
Service, which I'm not
sure we've talked about a
tremendous amount, but it lets
you store files and guarantees,
pretty much, that
you'll get them back, and then
charges you by the byte in
terms of what you're storing
per month and also how much
bandwidth you use from Amazon.
And it's very, very reliable.
So you pretty much know you put
something in S3, you're
going to be able to
get it back out.
Right.
And the only major issue with S3
versus Mongo is, of course,
the latency of retrieval.
Yes.
Because you're going across the
network and you're using
another service, you have to
factor in the retrieval.
We actually load S3 documents
directly from the browser.
So we do not now include your
submitted entry history in the
response back.
As we talked about in the major
application, as you go
through the application layer
and the API layer.
We only send back the associated
metadata or store
the metadata in the submissions
collection.
The actual entry itself is
stored in S3, and that
retrieval happens
on the client.
And so that allows us to have
a very quick response cycle.
So we did S3-backed
answer storage.
And as a result, our submission
collection both
became significantly smaller,
but it also, each of the
documents in the submission
collection became more
consistent in size, so that
significantly increased our
compaction factor.
And so as a result, we got an
even larger essentially,
increase or benefit in the
decrease of the collection
size, which was quickly
ballooning.
So in generation two, did you
eventually go to a sharded
configuration?
This is generation
three, right?
Yeah.
This is generation three.
So in generation two, so the
documents are growing pretty
fast because you're storing
all the responses in this
answers array, and
the exercises are
getting more complex.
And so the amount of information
stored for each of
the answers is growing.
And after you moved to a
replicated environment where
you're setting your writes to
your primary and your reads to
your secondaries--
you told me before, we were
talking beforehand, that you
eventually got to the point
where even that wasn't enough
and you decided to
shard the system.
So can you talk a little bit
about the sharding you did and
the shard key you chose and
your thinking behind that?
Certainly.
So we had a submissions
collection which was very
rapidly growing.
And, of course, when you have
a collection that's growing
both in volume and size and
you're starting to overload
your machines, one of the, I
think, more common solutions
to the problem is sharding--
meaning that you're going to
split your collection across
multiple machines.
And you need to split that
collection by a shard key.
And I don't know how much detail
you guys have gone into
about covering how to choose
your shard key.
We did.
And we talked about that last
week from a developer's
standpoint.
We haven't really gone over
extensively how to set up
sharding configurations, which
is more of a DBA topic, but we
did talk about shard key
selection and criteria.
So what did what you guys
choose and what was your
thinking behind it?
So we chose--
and this, I guess, was
somewhat naively.
This was an experiment
in sharding.
We wanted to see if this was a
valid solution to the problem.
And when you pick a shard key,
you both want something that's
not monotonically increasing,
that has a random distribution
across whatever its range is,
and you also want, ideally,
locality querying.
If you're going to be querying
multiple documents, you want,
ideally, them to come from the
same box or at least to be
fresh in memory.
For us, that was really across
the user ID because we would
never, for a single exercise,
loads submissions across
multiple users.
It would always be for a single
user, and it might
potentially be across
multiple exercises.
And so for us, it was really
only two machines.
We noticed that there was an
even distribution of access.
Also a user who's currently very
active will be active in
the next few moments, and so
its fresh in memory and it
worked pretty well.
We weren't so happy with how
quickly the submission
collection was growing, just
in raw size, and not
necessarily in the number of
cardinality of the set.
And so, for us, we thought that
sharding did give us the
benefit of distributing this
collection across multiple
machines and the resources of
each, but we thought that
there might be a better solution
to the type of
problem that we were facing.
That problem is, essentially,
that we were treating MongoDB
as a file store for the
submitted answers.
So are you saying that you
experimented, set up some
experimental configurations that
were sharded but never
went live with the sharding
configuration for the users?
Or you did go live with the
sharded configuration?
We did go live.
This is before we hit the--
I think there's some
arbitrary shard
cap of like 120 gigabytes.
I'm not sure.
There's a collection
cap before you
can shard it naively.
And so before we hit that, we
wanted to experiment and see
is this a solution that we
wanted to commit to.
It's something that
we looked into.
Once we started experimenting
with it, I think we realized
that there was a better solution
for us, particularly.
OK.
So and when you went to a
sharded environment, you had
sharded replica sets?
Is that what you did?
Yeah.
We did a sharded replicants
sets.
It was just two shards.
You have your Mongo S, right?
I'll draw this over here.
You have your Mongo S. And we
had two shard configurations.
Each has a primary.
And then those were backed
by just two secondaries.
And this was, I think,
pretty standard.
We were just trying to get a
configuration that could scale
horizontally as we wanted to.
But obviously, you're
essentially doubling your
machine count.
We didn't feel like this was
necessarily the most efficient
solution to the problem, and
we were trying to identify
what really was our problem.
Our real problem was that the
size of the answer entries
varied wildly.
We also treated submissions as
primarily read-heavy and not
write-heavy, so we didn't need
high level performance on
submission reads.
Right.
Actually, you don't read
them that often, so.
Yeah.
As we talked about for the
flow of the request,
essentially it's
mostly writes.
Yeah.
You don't even need to read
the previous historical
response to take a new one.
Yeah.
Part of the solution here
before that we that we
denormalized a lot of the
progress information of a user
through content.
That's, of course,
very read-heavy.
As you're showing a user
his progress, you don't
necessarily need to retrieve the
submitted documents, but
you do need to retrieve whether
or not the user has
completed the content, to what
extent, information like that.
We denormalize into another
collection.
OK.
So experiments with sharding
found you didn't need it after
you moved to S3, and then moved
to what we'll call the
third generation, which uses
S3 for those documents, and
the documents are a
lot more compact.
And now you've moved back to a
situation where you're using
replica sets, and you basically
have a single
replica set, and it's performing
well enough to
serve the whole system.
Yeah.
A single replica set.
So we did move back from the
sharded configuration, as you
said, to a single primary
and two secondaries.
Both still quad, large memory
instances on EC2.
But we're able to keep our
active set in memory without
any serious issues.
We haven't needed to set
up a caching layer.
We've always tried to maintain
a policy of the simplest
solution is the best solution.
Yeah.
And for us, it's been incredibly
performant.
We will need to shard
at some point.
That moment isn't now.
And it's clear, I think, that
the submissions collection
will be one of the first
collections to be sharded.
But moving to S3 for us, at
the moment, was a pretty
significant win.
Yeah.
And in terms of your replicated
environment, have
you found that you have to be
cognizant of the fact that
you're in a replicated
environment or has it been
transparent to the developer?
So, as we mentioned before, you
do you have to be aware,
because we have writes to
primary and we have writes
from secondary.
Oh, there is that.
You have to be aware of that.
I wasn't sure if you were still
doing that now that you
realized you're more write-heavy
than read-heavy.
So you still continue to send
you reads through your
secondaries.
Well, the submission collection
is write-heavy.
The majority of the other
collections are read-heavy.
Ive got you.
OK.
All right.
So there's that level
of awareness.
You run with Safe Mode
equals true?
That's actually changed with the
most recent drivers, but
you obviously got started
much earlier than that.
Yeah.
If we're going to walk away
from the submission
collection--
I speak a little bit
more generally--
any kind of stateful information
that the user
would notice if it was to not
persist, or disappear, we
certainly use Safe Mode.
For a lot of the activity
logging or the more
event-based writes that the
application performs, we
disable Safe Mode or
we'll optimize for
just insertion speed.
I've got you.
OK.
So if it's more analytics or
something, then you'll--
Yeah.
We'll store additional
information on top of
submissions, like general
information about how the
user's interacting with the
site, where they're going, how
they're spending time on it.
We store a lot of that
also in Mongo.
But, for the most part, for
that, we're using drivers and
we're very specific about our
insertion strategy around that
type of information.
Right.
So let's talk a little bit about
scaling and the way you
do capacity planning and other
things of that nature.
So, first of all, you said you
were running on a 4x large.
Your replicas are the same?
Are they all the same machine?
Primaries and secondaries
run on the same
instance type on EC2.
Same instance type.
Yep.
OK.
And if you want to add
more capacity, how do
you go about that?
So they weren't always
quad extra larges.
We had to upgrade, and we wanted
to upgrade in such a
way that we didn't have
any downtime.
And to do that, Mongo allows you
to switch into a replica
set configuration, but you do
you have to, essentially, take
the site down and turn off your
database at least for a
brief moment.
So when we switched from a
single instance to a replica
set configuration, we did have
to bring the site down.
Between when you have a replica
configuration and we
wanted to upgrade our boxes,
what we would do is we would
add a larger provisioned
instance as a secondary, then
have that new instance be
brought up to date through
replication across
the replica set.
Once it was synced up, we would
then demote the primary,
and we would set the priority
flag in the new instance
secondary so that it would
assume responsibility for
being the primary.
So pretty seamless, actually.
Yeah.
And not a lot of downtime.
It could potentially be almost
no downtime right except for
the time when you're just
transitioning and when you
step down the primary to
bring the secondary up.
Yeah.
If you're patient, I think.
It's certainly faster to
sometimes take the site down,
and if you have EBS back-storage
to unmount it
from one instance, remount
it to another.
If you're pressed for time,
that's a quick option.
If you're not pressed for time
and you've properly planned
things out and you see the trend
or the writing on the
wall, then, yeah, you can,
potentially, of course, expand
your capacity without
any downtime.
Right.
So taking the server down,
attaching the EBS store to a
new box results in more
downtime but a shorter
duration of time from the time
you make the decision to do
this to the time you'll
be up with a new box.
Yeah.
Replication, especially for a
data set that's significantly
sized, can take a long time.
It could take hours.
Do you copy over the data
files first and then do
replication or do you
just let the whole
replication catch up?
We've done both.
We've tried our syncing
across the network
bandwidth or the writes.
If you have provisioned IOPS,
it's a lot better.
If you're replicating across
provision IOPS instances from
one to another, it's, of course,
much, much faster than
if it's a standard EBS or a
femoral back-storage instance
to a provisioned IOPS or any
other instance type.
But if they're both provisioned
IOPS, it can be
performant.
It's certainly easiest just to
connector a completely fresh
member to a replica set
and let it sync.
Sometimes you have to restart
it, but it almost
always syncs up.
And in terms of getting the
performance you need, you run
some of the front end on Heroku,
you were saying?
And then the back end
is actually on AWS.
So is that a challenge?
Does the developer have to be
aware of that longer latency
than sort of running
it locally.
Do the developers have to be
more aware of the cost of
talking to a database that's not
necessarily located in the
same LAN or something?
So if we go back to our client,
our application, and
our API layers, our application
layer and our API
layer, which essentially wraps
or handles all the reads and
writes to the database,
both of those two
are hosted on Heroku.
And Heroku is also AWS backed.
Right They use AWS.
Their dynamos are running
on top of AWS--
at least the last
that I heard.
And I'm fairly sure that
we use, in terms of our
availability zone--
AWS has different availability
zones
located across the world.
And, of course, whenever you're
across a network, you
care about the latency
between the nodes.
And if you're on the other
side of the world, you're
going to have more significant
latency than if the two boxes
are connected, assuming that you
have fantastic connections
between them.
And both us and Heroku
are hosting the same
availability zone.
And because of that, there is
less latency then if we were
in different availability
zones.
But we still are going
across the network.
And so whenever you have
an application that's
communicating with the database
and they're not on
the same box, so they have to
go across the network, you
have to deal with latency
of one sort or another.
And as a result, you have to
be very conscious of the
number of requests--
not only the types of queries,
but just the
raw number of queries--
that you're performing
on the database.
Because there's a communication
overhead just to
get to the database and get
the response back to the
application.
So for us, we try to make sure
that every single request
involves a certain number of
database requests or fewer.
For us, it's about 10.
Even that's a little
bit generous.
Yeah.
It's interesting, because I'm
kind of an old guy, but in the
'90s and in the early part of
the 2000s when you would
create a database-backed system
attached to relational,
the first rule of thumb was
you never attached the web
servers to the database because
it'd just be too slow.
And you cache it.
And I guess, for me, one of the
cool things about MongoDB
is that you now can attach the
web servers directly to the
database and not have a separate
caching layer and
still get adequate performance
for the users.
That's cool.
But I guess now that we're
virtualizing everything and
it's not always in the same,
it's getting a little tougher
because we're getting
more latency.
Yeah, we moved the cloud, so now
it's easier, of course, to
provision and horizontally
scale.
But we've introduced a lot of
latency between connections.
And as a result, you certainly
have to be very conscious of
just the volume of requests.
So you have to batch
your requests.
You have to be conscious of it.
Right.
And it's not even a throughput
issue, it's a latency issue.
It's not that you can't get
enough requests through the
server, it's that any one user
that's doing one thing on a
web page, you can't wait for a
lot of back and forths over a
network or it's going to
get too slow for them.
Yeah, that's a good point.
And that's why you want to be
making asynchronous requests
when possible or try to not have
them, at the very least,
be sequential.
Right.
All right.
Well, thanks for letting us in
on the internals of Codecademy
and telling us how
it all works.
This has been really great,
so thank you.
Thank you.
It was certainly
a fun exercise.
All right.
It was good.