Welcome to week four.
Congratulations on making
it to this point.
This week we're going to
talk about performance.
Now computer system performance
is driven by lots
of factors, including the
speed of the underlying
operations, like the disk
and memory and the CPU.
But the largest driver for
performance is going to be
your algorithmic performance.
And for a database server,
that's going to be how fast
can we execute queries.
And that's driven by whether or
not the database can use an
index to look data up.
So this week we're going to
talk a lot about indexes.
We're going to talk about what
they are, we're going to talk
about how to create them, and
we're going to talk about how
you figure out which parts
of your program are slow.
Finally, we're going to discuss
sharding a little bit,
which is a technique for
breaking up large collections
across multiple servers to
exploit greater parallelism.
Now performance is normally
the domain of database
administrators, but good
developers have an
understanding of performance.
They write with performance in
mind, and they can find their
own performance problems
within their programs.
So let's get started.