OK.
And the answer is that only
the third one is correct.
MMAP does not offer
document level locking,
it offers collection level
locking, so that's not true.
MMAP isn't the one
that creates the power
of two-sized documents
when they're inserted--
this was a little bit subtle--
but MongoDB makes the decision
that it wants to
allocate a document that
is power of two sized.
MMAP doesn't care.
MMAP is built on top of
the MMAP system call.
That is absolutely true.
And the final one is false
because MongoDB does not
manage the memory used by MMAP.
Instead, it's managed
by the operating system
itself and it
decides what to swap
in and out from this large file
that is mapped into memory.