All right, and the answer is
that you get document level
concurrency because it's
a lock-free implementation
for most paths
through the database,
and you get compression,
which is great.
You do not get power-of-two
document padding,
that is something that is
a feature of the [? NMap ?]
storage engine.
And you do not get in-place
place updates of documents.
If you try to update
a document, it
will wind up rewriting the
entire document to disk.
And it is not turbocharged.
Turbocharged is a
real thing with cars.
Turbocharged refers to the
idea of using the exhaust fumes
from a car, running
it through a turbine,
and adding extra power
to the drive train
by using some of the energy in
the exhaust fumes coming out
of the back of the car for
a fossil fuel based car.
So turbocharged is a
real thing, but not
in the WireTiger
storage engine, maybe
in some other
high-performance engines.