And the answer is that adding
the appropriate index on large
collections so that only a small
percentage of queries
need to scan the collection,
that's gonna have your
greatest impact.
Any more memory so the
working set fits into
memory, that'll help.
But, you typically won't be
able to get your entire
database into memory, although
you'll be able to get your
entire index into memory.
And that will be important
for performance
as we'll see later.
Adding a faster disk
drive, that helps.
But truth is that the
algorithmic improvements you
get from hitting an index are an
order of magnitude greater
than what you're gonna get by
having a faster disk drive
inside your computer.
The same thing is
true for a CPU.
Creating a faster CPU is
OK, but the algorithmic
improvements you get by hitting
an index inside the
database is far more
important.
And so thinking about indexing
when you're thinking about
performance in a database is
gonna be absolutely critical.