Let's talk about database
performance.
Database performance in MongoDB
is driven by pretty
much the same thing that every
database is driven by.
Which is, are you going to
use an index to resolve
your query or not?
So indexes turn out to be the
single most important factor
in database performance--
in MongoDB and in relational
databases.
So this will be a review for a
lot of you, but I want to take
you through the basics of
indexing and what it is and
why it's so effective.
So if you look at MongoDB or
any other database, it will
store its data in these large
files on disk, and this is
supposed to represent some
sort of collection.
There's no particular order for
the documents on the disk,
it could be anywhere.
And if you ask for a particular
document, you do a query.
What the database is going to
have to do by default is scan
through the entire collection
to find the data.
Now this is called a table scan
in a relational database,
and it's a collection scan in
MongoDB, and it is death to
your performance.
You do not want to have to scan
your entire collection
for your data if the data set
is large, because it'll be
extremely slow.
So instead we use indexing.
So how does indexing work?
Well it's pretty
straightforward.
If something is ordered, like
for instance this list is
ordered alphabetically--
apple, banana, kiwi, pear.
And even if it was very long,
it's very quick to find
something within the
list-- right?
Because you can use a binary
search to do it.
So finding something in
an ordered list--
in an assorted list--
is quick.
Finding something in an
unordered list is slow.
What we do is we keep
our keys ordered.
Now we don't actually keep them
linearly ordered like
this in MongoDB--
we use something called
a B-tree.
But conceptually, you can
imagine it looking like this.
And if I'm looking for, let's
say, "banana", I can quickly
search, find the item, and then
have a pointer to the
actual document inside
the collection.
This is the key.
So indexes in MongoDB are
an ordered list of keys.
So for instance, you could have
an index on name, and
then an index on hair color,
and there could be another
index on the date of
birth or something.
Now the order is important
because conceptually the way
the index is built is that name
will be at the top level.
So here are my names.
And this might be Amy,
and John, and Zoe--
well probably Zoe
is over here.
Now within this, the hair
color is sort of
conceptually over here.
So for all the Amy items we've
got brown hair, blonde hair--
I'm going to put BL
for blond hair--
black hair, and then repeat
it for every item.
So there will be some brown hair
here, black hair here.
And then finally within this--
I might pick a new color--
you might have a bunch of
items for date of birth.
So here's my hair color over
here, my name is at the top
level, and then finally I've got
this date of birth item at
the bottom.
So if you provide me
the person's--
just their name--
then I can go into the index and
I can find all the Johns.
And if you prefer to provide me
the hair color, I can break
it down and find all the
brown-haired people.
At the very bottom of this,
of course, is going to be
pointers into the actual data.
Now these things are going to
represent keys in the Mongo
document that we've
decided to index.
In order for a database to
utilize an index, you have to
give it a left-most
set of items.
So you can give it just the name
or you can give just a
hair color--
name and the hair color--
or you can give it the
name, the hair
color, and date of birth.
If you provide me just the date
of birth, I can't do much
conceptually with the index,
because date of birth is down
here at this level.
So I would need to do a binary
search through here, then do a
binary search through this one,
then do a binary search
through this one-- et cetera,
et cetera, et cetera.
Instead, I need to
start at the top.
And this is true whether or not
I'm doing a query or I'm
doing an update or I'm doing a
sort, because sorts also will
use an index to sort
their values.
So for instance, if I pull a
bunch of data out of the
collection and I want
to sort it by name--
well, the database can use this
index if we just define
name, hair color, date of
birth, to do the sort.
Now one other point I want to
make is that every single time
the database wants to insert
something into it--
or you want to insert
something into
the database, rather--
this index needs to be updated,
and that updating
takes time.
So although reads are faster
inside the database, writes
are a little bit slower if you
have an index, because the
index needs to be updated.
And so indexes are
not cost-less.
They take space on disks
and they also take
time to keep updated.
And that's something
to keep in mind.
So you don't want to have an
index on every single possible
way you're going to query the
collection, you instead want
to have an index on the ways
you're most likely to query
the collection.
Let's go through one
or two examples--
talk about the index.
Say I have an index on "a, b,
c", and I do a query on "b".
Can the index be used?
The answer is no.
If I do a query on "a", yes.
If I do query on "c", no.
If I do a query on "a,
b", yes-- it uses two
parts of the index.
"a, c"--
it uses just "a" part and it
ignores the "c" part for the
purposes of doing the
search on the index.
So I hope that kind of
gives you a feeling.
All right, so now it's time
for our first quiz.
Which optimization will
typically have the greatest
impact on the performance
of a database?
Adding more memory so that the
working set fits in memory,
adding a faster drive so that
the operation of the hit disk
will happen more quickly,
replacing your CPU with a
faster one-- say 2x as fast--
or adding an appropriate index
on a large collection so that
only a small percentage of the
queries need to scan the
collection?