OK, now we know how to create
indexes on a collection.
How would you discover
what indexes are already
on the collection?
Well, we can do that with
the get indexes command.
So I'm going to start
the Mongo shell again.
And once again, I'm going
to use the school database.
And then I'm going to call
db.students.getIndexes.
Students is the name
of the collection.
And as you remember,
in the last lesson
we just added an index
to it for student ID.
We're going to
call it getIndexes.
And if we do that we
get back this result,
which is a document.
Actually, it's an
array of two documents.
And the first one
tells you that there
is an index on underscore id.
Now, this index exists
on all collections.
And you can't delete it.
There's also an
index on student_id.
And that's the index
we just created.
And if we wanted to
get rid of that index,
we would call
db.students.dropIndex
and provide this
exact same signature
as when we created it.
So here we're
calling drop index.
And we're giving the same
signature, student_id:1,
that we gave when we
created the index.
And if we do that we
should be able to drop it.
And there you go.
[? Num ?] indexes was
two, and now it's one.
And if we get indexes again
we'll see that in fact,
there is only one
index-- perfect.
All right, one last
point I want to make
is that this call,
getIndexes, is a call
that you use in
MongoDB 3.0 and will
work on both WiredTiger
and [? Mapv1 ?].
And in earlier versions
of the database
you could look at a
special collection system
that indexes to see
what indexes existed.
That does not work
in WiredTiger.
And so the preferred
way to figure out
what indexes are
in a collection is
to do this, to call
db.students.getIndexes,
and again, is a
change in MongoDB 3.0.