Now I want to talk
to you about how
you can use dot notation to
reach deep into a document
and add an index
to something that's
in a subdocument of
the main document.
And also, doing this with things
that are arrays-- so combining
multikey with dot notation.
This is a pretty cool
feature of MongoDB.
It's a little tricky to
explain how it works,
and it may not work
exactly as you expect.
So let me show
you some examples.
All right.
I'm back in the Mongo
shell now, and I'm
going to look at this students
collection once again.
So db.students.find1.
This is the same
collection we looked
at in the previous lesson.
And it has these documents
that have structure
where there's a student ID, and
then there's a scores array.
And the scores array
has a bunch of documents
as elements in the array where
each document has a type, exam,
and a score.
And it's also a class ID.
So let's say we want the 2
index on this score itself.
We can do that.
The call would be as follows--
db.students.createindex
scores.score is 1.
That's how we would do it.
That's how we would
create an index that
would index this array and
this sub-part of this document.
And I did this off
camera, because it
took about 15 or 20 minutes
to create this index,
because there's 10
million documents,
there's four elements
in this array.
And it took a long time.
So you can see what indexes
are on the collection.
We'll do that right now.
And if you call
db.getindexes, you
can see there are now two
indexes on the collection.
One of them is on underscore
ID, and the other one
is on scores.score, which
is our multikey index.
So what can you do with that?
Well, first of all, you
can search for records
where any score was
above a certain value.
So let's look what
that query looks like.
This will find everything
where scores.score
is greater than 99.
And I'm actually more
interested in understanding
what the query optimizer does
with it than actually seeing
the results, so
I'm using explain
to return that information.
Let's do that.
And if we did that
query, you can
see that it's going
to do an index scan.
It says right here--
winning plan included
the scores.score index.
In the forward direction,
it looked for things
with scores.scores
between 99.0 and infinity,
and that's how it
retrieved this information.
And if you wanted to
see that information,
we could just remove the
Explain part of this,
and then we'll get
some documents back
where there is at least
one score above 99.
Let's pretty print it so we
can see that more clearly.
And you can see
that in this case,
it was the homework
that was above 99.
So what if we wanted to
find people that had an exam
score that was above 99?
How would we do that?
Now, I'm going to
show you the query,
and then I'll show
you a query that I
used before I looked into it
more carefully that turned out
to be wrong.
I think it's an
interesting example,
because it's easy to
get confused about this.
So the query that would
search for all the students
where an exam score was
above 99 looks like this.
And it uses this
LM match operator.
So we're going to go
through this very carefully.
It's actually being run
with Explain right now,
but let's look at it.
So we're trying to
inspect the scores
array inside the document.
And then we want to
find a document which
has an element of the array
that is of type exam and a score
greater than 99.8.
And to do that, we use this
operator called LM match.
Now, what LM match does--
and you can look this up
in the documentation--
is it matches
documents that contain an array
field with at least one element
that matches all the
specified query criteria.
So in other words, there might
be more than one element--
there might be more than
one exam in this array
that match this
criteria-- but we're
going to make sure that
we match at least one
with all this criteria.
So it's looking for
an element that's
of type, exam, and
score greater than 99.8.
And if we do that-- let's
first just get the results so
we can confirm that that
works-- so I'm going
to pretty print the result.
We see we get something that
has an exam score above 99.8.
Works perfectly well.
It's very nice.
I wonder how many
records there are, just
out of curiosity, that
would satisfy this criteria.
And the answer is that there
are 20,278 students that
satisfy this criteria of
having an exam score of greater
than 99.8 in this
somewhat random data
set of 10 million documents.
Well, what does the explain
output look like for this?
Because that's an
interesting question to me.
Let's run this with
Explain now to see
what the query
optimizer is going
to do to satisfy this query.
And to do that, I need to
remove this count at the end.
I just need to do
an Explain, tell it
that I want to see what it
would do with this Find command.
So I'm going to run that,
and it's pretty interesting.
We're going to go over
Explain in more detail.
But you can see, there's
a lot of information here.
But the winning
plan-- and it's easier
to read this from the
bottom to the top.
Because actually,
you can't quite tell,
but this is the first
thing it runs, I believe.
It says that first, it runs
a query on scores.score
being 99.8 to infinity.
OK, that makes perfect
sense, because that's
what the index is.
So it can't do any
better than to look
at the scores.score key.
And then after that,
it runs the output
of that-- this is
an index scan--
into the next stage, where it
finds all the documents that
satisfy that criteria,
which is probably 10x or 4
or 5x the number
of documents that
would have that
exam that score--
and then it runs the LM match.
And it says, I want
to find something
with a score that's greater than
99.8 and a type that's exam.
It calls this a fetch.
I don't believe there's
anything special it can do here.
I think it actually iterates
through every single document
and inspects them.
And we can confirm that by
running it with value true
and letting it execute
the query so we know
how many documents it examines.
And the answer is that it
examined-- so right here,
we can see the explain output.
It's a little hard to
read on the screen.
But again, we have the
winning plan information.
It's exactly the same as before.
But now we have some
additional information
called execution stats.
And we just go through here
and look at what's interesting.
And then we can see that it
returned 20,000 documents.
That makes sense.
But it examined
80,000 documents.
Wow.
And you know what
that number is?
It's probably the
number of documents
that have a score above 99.8.
So let's just confirm
that that's true.
Score greater than 99.8,
give me a count of those.
And there are 80,054
documents that
have a score greater than 99.8.
And it examined every single
one of them for this query.
Let's see where we can
find this information.
Here are the executions
stats for the query.
And you can see it
examined 80,054 documents
to return 20,278 documents.
That's because the way that
MongoDB went through this query
is it used the index it had,
which was on scores.score.
And then after
that, it essentially
did a scan of
everything that resulted
to do the LM match part of it.
Now, what mistake
did I make when
I was setting this lesson
up and thinking about it
that turned out to be wrong?
And the answer is, I
tried to use this query.
And I won't go through
it too carefully,
but I want to show it to
you, because it confused me.
Here's the query I
tried to use to get
the answer of every student
that had the exam above 99.8.
I tried to use the
and operator and said,
I want to find
things where scores
that I type is exam
and scores that score
is greater than 99.8.
And when I did that,
you know what I found?
I found documents
that look like this.
I found documents where there
is a score greater than 99.8%,
but it wasn't for the exam.
Really interesting, huh?
So actually, if you
use this and operator,
there's no guarantee
that when it
finds a document that satisfies
this criteria without the LM
match part that it
satisfies this criteria
in the same sub-part.
It might be different part.
And this really
comes out when you
look at the explain
output, actually.
The explain output
helps you understand
the way the database
interpreted this query.
And once you see
this explain output,
you're like, oh yeah, of course.
It makes perfect sense.
So the explain output said,
here's what we're going to do.
Here the winning plan.
It says in the first stage,
in the lowest level stage,
I want to find everything with
scores that score above 99.8.
And pass that up
to the next stage,
and the next stage
should look for things
with scores.type equal to exam.
Oh dear, that's not right.
Because basically, it's
returning all these documents,
returning a huge number of
documents from this stage.
Well, we know how many.
It's like 80,000 students
have 99.8 and above.
So first, it does this
query, finds all the students
with any score above 99.8.
Then it passes it
to this next stage
and says, now find me
all the documents where
scores.type is equal to exam.
And that's not going
to work, because that
is going to give you things
where the score was not
for the actual exam.
Now, compare that
output to what output
we got for the correct
query with the LM match.
When we used the correct query
for this, look at the output--
it's very different.
In that case, the first
stage of the query
did the exact same thing.
It looked for things with
scores that score above 99.8.
But in the second
stage, we didn't just
look for things with type exam.
We looked for an
element match where
both conditions were true.
Where the score
was again 99.8, we
reaffirmed that this was
true for the document
and that the type was exam.
All right.
That's a lot of information.
But I hope that helps better
explain-- no pun intended--
how that works.
OK, it's time for a quiz.
Suppose you have a
collection called
people in the database
Earth and documents
in the following form.
You can see the documents here.
What would be the command
in the Mongo shell
to create an index on
company descending?
Please type your
answer right down here.