OK, let's talk about
unique indexes.
So far, all the indexes
that we've created
have been non-unique.
But you can also
create unique indexes
that enforce the constraint
that the keys have to be
unique within the collection.
No two documents can have
the same key if it's indexed.
Let's going into the Mongo
shell and demonstrate
what we're talking about.
We're going to create a new
collection called stuff.
Just to make sure
that it's really gone,
I'm going to drop it.
Now I'm going to insert some
stuff into my stuff collection.
All right, I've inserted an
apple into the collection.
Now I'm going to insert a
pear into the collection.
And now I'm going to
insert another apple
into the collection.
And now I'm going to see
what's in the collection.
And we see two
apples and a pear.
Now if we wanted to
create an index on this,
we certainly could.
That would be no problem.
We could just do a createIndex
on Thing ascending,
and works just fine.
But if we want to create
a unique index, we cannot.
Let me show you what a
unique index would look like.
So let's drop the
index we just created.
And now let's create
a unique index.
We're going to call createIndex,
but this time, we're
going to give one additional
document in this command.
Rather than just say
createIndex Thing 1,
we're going to say
Unique is True.
And if we do that, what happens?
Well, we get an error.
And the reason we
get an error is
because it can't create
a unique index when
there's two things inside
this collection that
have the same value.
So let's drop the offending one.
So let's look at stuff
collection again.
And we see we have two apples.
So let's remove one
of those apples.
We're going to do it this way.
We're going to call remove.
We're going to find a document
that has Thing Apple in it.
And we're going to give
one option to remove.
We're going to say
that justOne is True.
We want to remove just one.
And if we do that, we
get Number Removed 1.
And now if we look in
the collection again,
we'll see we only
have one apple.
And now we should be able to
add the index that we want,
the unique index.
Thing 1, Unique True.
No problem.
We added the index.
And if we want to
insert something
that already is in
there, like a pear,
we get a duplicate key error.
In addition, if you look
at the indexes on stuff
by calling
db.stuff.getIndexes, you'll
notice that the database tells
you that the index on Thing
is unique.
Now oddly, it doesn't tell
you that the index on _id is
unique, although we've told
you that _id is unique and it
[? is a ?] unique.
So it's a vagary of the database
that it won't admit that _id is
unique.
So we can prove that
of course it is unique.
Because if we try to put
some documents into it,
let's say with _id Andrew,
and we try to put two of those
in there, we're going to
find it does not work.
db.stuff Inserted--
let's try another one.
Duplicate key error on _id,
which is exactly the same error
that we see on this other
duplicate key error,
the E11000 error in both cases.
So even though the database
doesn't tell you that the _id
index is unique, it is unique.
All right, so it's
time for a quiz.
Please provide the
mongo shell command
to create a unique index on
student_id, class_id ascending
for the collection Students.
Type it below.