All right.
Now, we know how
to create indexes,
and we know how to create unique
indexes and sparse indexes.
But the last concept I
want to discuss with you
is whether or not you create
this index in the foreground
or the background.
So let's go through the
different options-- foreground
and background.
Now, foreground index creation
is the default in MongoDB,
and the good thing about
foreground index creation
is that it is relatively--
and I say "relatively"
because it still can be slow.
It is relatively fast, and it
blocks all writers and readers
in the database that
has the collection.
So a foreground
index creation is
going to block the
writers and the readers
in the same database as
the collection exists,
even though we have
per collection database
locking in Nmap
V1 Storage Engine.
And in WiredTiger,
there is concurrency
at the document level.
Even though that's true,
if you do an index creation
in the foreground,
which is the default,
you're going to block readers
and writers to the database.
Other databases you
can still get to.
So you have to do this probably
not in a production system.
So you've got to be very careful
if you're going to do that.
And the other option is you can
do a background index creation.
Now, background index
creations are a bit slower
relative to the
foreground index creation,
but they don't block
readers and writers.
You can only have one background
index creation going on
at a time.
After that, the next
one will queue and wait.
I think that is on a
per database level.
And this is probably a better
way to create an index.
However, it's still
fairly high-load.
The other way to create
an index very efficiently
in a production
system is something
we haven't talked about yet,
but we'll get to a little bit
in this course
toward the end, which
is to create the index on a
different server than the one
that you're using to
serve most of the queries.
So if you have a
MongoDB replica set--
and this is a
concept we're going
to get to later on-- which
is a group of servers working
together in tandem, then what
you can do is you can take one
of them out of the
set temporarily,
only sending requests
to, let's say, this one,
and then run the index
creation in the foreground
here, which could
be much faster.
And then after the index
creation is finished,
then you could bring
him back in the set.
And you can rotate
around which server
takes most of the requests.
And in doing this,
you can create
an index in the
foreground on a server
without creating any performance
penalty from the application
standpoint that's talking
to this cluster of database
servers.
All right.
So again, foreground
indexing is the default.
Background indexing is
something you have to ask for.
Now, let's go through and
just try this and play with it
so we can see it in action.
Now, right here, I've got my
students collection again,
which I had 10 million records.
Remember, from the
previous lessons.
And it has two indexes
on it, and I've dropped
the index on scores.score.
And if you recall, it was a
very expensive index to create.
Each of these documents
has an array of scores,
and it just took like
20 minutes last time.
So I'm going to run
this in the foreground,
and it's not going to
complete anytime soon.
And then while I
do that, I'm going
to also take another Mongo shell
and use the school database
and then do db.students.findOne.
And you can see that I am,
in fact, completely blocked.
I'm getting nothing from
the database blocked.
That's too bad.
I'm not blocked from
other databases.
So there, I killed it.
Killed that request.
If I'm in the test database
and I do db.employees.find,
which I think is a collection
that should still be there,
then you can see, I can
access that just fine.
It's in a different database.
OK.
So let's go back and run
this in the background
now and then see if
that works better.
So I'm going to kill this index
creation in the foreground.
I hit Control C in the shell.
It offered to kill the op.
I said yes.
It seems to have killed the
shell as well, which is fine.
And then I'm going
to run Mongo, and I'm
going to use school again.
And now, I'm going to create
this index in the background.
So let's confirm that there
is no index, first of all.
All right.
So there's no index
on scores.score.
So that's good.
So let's create one.
db.students.createIndex,
and put it on scores.score.
Ascending.
And then give the option
for background, true.
So I'm going to say true
to that, and let's see.
I'm going to check it.
Looks OK.
Hit Return.
And now, it's going to go off
and do this in the background.
Pretty darn slow.
I'm still not going to
get an immediate response
from the shell.
It's not going to background
the actual operation
from the shell's standpoint.
But now, now that
I've done that,
I'm going to use
school again, and then
do db.students.findOne.
And you can see
that I successfully
queried this collection,
even while index creation is
going on in the background.
And so that's how
background indexes work.
All right.
Time for a quiz.
Which of the following are
true about creating an index
in the background in MongoDB?
Check all that apply.
And here are the choices.
A MongoDB instance can only
build one background index
at a time per database.
Although the database server
will continue to take requests,
a background index creation
still blocks the Mongo shell.
Creating an index
in the background
takes longer than
the foreground.
And in Mongo 2.2
and above, indexes
are created in the
background by default.
All right.
And please check your answer.