So far, we've been looking at
the Explain command running
in the query planner
mode right here.
The query planner
mode is very useful.
It's also the default
mode for Explain.
But there are two other
modes I want to go over.
One is the Execution Stats mode,
and the other is the All Plans
execution mode.
And they're increasing
the levels of verbosity,
because the Execution Stats
mode includes the Query Planner
mode and the All
Plans Execution mode
includes the Query Planner mode
and the Execution Stats mode.
Query Planner tells you
mostly what the database would
use in terms of
the indexes, but it
doesn't tell you what the
results of using that index
are.
For that, we're going to have
to use the Execution Stats mode.
Let's take a look once
again at the shell.
We're going to use
the same data that we
used in the last lesson.
And just to review that
data, it's a bunch of data.
There's a million
different documents
with values for a, b, and c.
And we can also look at the
indexes on the collection.
The collection is
called example.
You can see, there's an index
on underscore ID, of course,
and one on B, and
one on A comma B.
Now, let's run a query using
the new Execution Stats mode
that we just learned about.
So once again, we're going
to get an explainable object.
But this time, we're going
to give a different option.
This time, we're going to create
that object with execution
stats as an option.
And we're going to put the
result in this exp variable.
Now we're going to
call exp dot find,
and we're going to look at one
document in the collection.
And we're going
to, of course, run
the Explain Command
and Execution Stats
mode on this query versus
actually do the query.
Now let's look through this data
and see what there is to see.
So once again, we've got
the Query Planner mode,
and the Query
Planner mode tells us
that it is going to
use the a underscore
b underscore one index, and
that it will pass that along.
And at the parse query was this.
All good.
It tells us that there
was a rejected plan,
and the rejected plan was
to use the B index on this.
That's helpful.
But it doesn't tell us
what would have happened
if it used each of these.
So the execution stats over
here will tell us the execution
stats for the winning plan.
And there are certain
key items that I
want you to pay attention to.
There's a lot of data
here, and we're not
going to look at all of it.
But one thing I
want you to notice
is the number of documents
returned right here.
That's the number of documents
that the query actually
returned, or would return
if it were run to completion
and the data was brought
back to the client, which
is 100 documents.
We can see the
execution time millage,
which is the time
for the query, which
is unmeasurable in this case by
this the granularity of clock,
zero milliseconds,
a very fast query.
And we can see that there
was 100 keys examined and 100
docs examined.
So that tells us something.
It tells us that the
index worked pretty well.
We looked at all 100 keys, and
we got to the 100 documents.
And then you can see
here, as we go down,
we can see for each stage
the number of documents
returned from each stage.
And this is an inner stage
here where it actually
did index scan.
And an index scan, it
returned 100 documents.
You can see the key
pattern that was
used for the index,
which was, of course,
A B, and the selectivity.
And again, what t used to select
on, which was A min value 17,
max value 17, B min 55, max 55.
And you can see it also
provides an estimate of time
for this stage of the
query, which is zero.
And you really read this
from the bottom to the top
if you're trying to understand
the different stages
of a query.
And because this part
is an actual index scan,
it doesn't actually have
any docs examine part of it.
But if you look in
totality, you can
see that we examined 100
keys, we got 100 documents,
and that sounds awesome.
And it was pretty darn fast.
Now let's see what would happen
if we didn't actually have
this particular index to use.
We were selecting on A and B,
and we had a comma b index,
so that was a
pretty ideal index.
Let's drop this index
on A B ascending.
So we'll drop the index.
And there was three
indexes, now there's one.
Excellent.
So at this point, let's
run the query again.
We can go back in our
history by just going up
[INAUDIBLE] the [? shell ?].
And we already have
an explainable object.
We can use it again.
We're going to call
find A 17 B 55.
Same exact query.
And now let's see what happens.
So the results are slightly
different this time.
First of all, the winning plan--
once this awesome index is
missing-- the winning plan
is to use the B index.
It's not as good an index.
But it runs the B
index right here.
And it says that it's going to
use it with a balance 55, 55.
Makes sense.
And then it's going
to pass that up
to the fetch stage
of the query, which
is after the index is run, it
fetches the file documents.
It's going to look for the
document that have A 17.
All right.
That's good enough.
Sounds good.
And now we're going to go
down to the execution stats
and see what happened.
And now things are
a lot different.
So the first thing you notice
is that there's actually
an execution time here
of 5 milliseconds, which
is much, much longer than zero,
infinitely longer than zero.
Although of course, the first
one wasn't actually zero.
It was probably
just not quite one.
This query is a lot slower,
and that's not surprising.
Because if you
look down, you can
see that we examine 10,000
keys, and 10,000 documents.
And that's because the first
stage of this index scan on B
returned 10,000 documents
then had to be examined
during the fetch stage.
Let's see if this tells
us that information
as we go through it.
So let's see.
How do we understand this?
The innermost document was
the first stage run, the input
stage.
And that run a query
using the index B.
And you can see that it
returned 10,000 documents
as part of that.
Or I should say, it returned
pointers to 10,000 documents.
Because of course,
the index scan
didn't really return
the documents.
And then up here,
those 10,000 documents
had to be whittled down.
They were all examined with
a filter of A equals 17,
and there whittled
down to a final number
of documents of 100.
And whenever you see
the number of documents
examined much larger than the
number of documents returned,
you know that you did
a lot of extra work,
that you took a lot of extra
data out of the database,
and at some point, it
had to be inspected
and then rejected before it was
returned to your actual client
program.
So that's what
happens when you give
the option for execution stats.
Now, we said there's
a third option.
And that third option
is all plans execution.
So let's run it that way.
First, let's recreate our index.
So db.example.createindex,
A ascending, B ascending.
About a million
documents-- a few seconds.
There we go.
Our index is back
in the collection.
Now let's get a new
explainable object.
My new explainable
object will have
the option all plans execution.
Now, what does all
plans execution do?
All plans execution does
what the query optimizer
does periodically.
What the query optimizer
does periodically
is it runs all the possible
indexes that could be used,
and it runs them in parallel,
and then makes a decision
about which one is fastest.
And it periodically does this.
And then it remembers
which one is
fastest for a certain
shape of query,
and it always uses that index.
But when you run the explain
command in all plans execution,
you are running the query
optimizer that periodically
runs to determine
what index would
be used for any
particular shape of query.
So it gives you even
more information
about the different
possibilities.
Because you remember, in
the last one, what we saw
was the execution stats
for the winning plan.
But we didn't see any execution
stats for other plans.
So let's see what happens now.
We're going to do the same
exact query we did before.
And now, now what do we get?
We get a lot more
information, certainly.
We had the executions
that we had before,
and they look pretty
much the same.
We did an index
scan, and we decided
to use the winning
index of A comma B.
But what about the all
plans execution area,
which is right here?
What does that tell us?
Well, let's see.
The first one is actually
the most interesting.
Because the first one is
considering using the B index.
A little hard to read on screen.
By the way, this
all plans execution
is an array of different plans.
The first one was
actually rejected.
It returned zero documents.
And the reason it
was rejected is
that the database ran the query
using the B index right here,
B_1.
And when it did that,
they examined 101 keys.
Now, we know from previously
when we removed the A comma B
index that to complete this
query with just the N index,
you'd look at 10,000
different documents.
But in this case,
you looked at 101.
Why is that?
Well, the reason
is that 101 was as
many as the database
needed to see
to know that it was a loser.
Because-- and you'll
see here it says
that it returned
zero documents-- so
it says, didn't return any
documents in this plan,
because this plan
was eliminated.
It said, this is
not the best plan.
I know that because I got
to 101 documents examined,
and I have a plan
here-- which is
the second plan in the
all plans execution--
which is going to
return 100 documents
and only look at 100 documents.
I look at 100 documents,
I look at 100 keys.
And that's using the A comma B.
So now you can really see the
logic that the database applied
to make the decision,
which is as soon as it saw
that using the index just on
B was going to look at more
documents than using
the A comma B index,
it immediately
abandoned that path,
and it didn't follow it
through to completion.
So although this all plans
execution mode will give you
some execution information about
alternative paths to satisfying
its query, it won't
tell you everything
that would have happened,
because it treats it just
like the query optimizer.
When it knows that
it's bad, it stops.
And if you remember, when we
removed the actual A, B index
and ran this query,
it told us it
looked at a lot more
documents than that
when it used just the B index.
Now, one thing to keep
in mind with the database
is it's good to have an
index for every query.
That is, every query
should hit an index.
But it's also important
that every index that
is on your collection,
that there be at least one
query hitting it.
Which is to say that when you
have an index on a collection
and it's never chosen,
it's never selected,
it's just a waste.
And you're wasting time
inserting into that index
and keep that index up to
date when, in fact, you
don't need to be.
So you want to have a good
balance between the indexes
on your collection
and the queries
so that all the indexes get
used and all the queries have
at least one index that
can satisfy them and work
efficiently.
It's time for a quiz.
Let's look at this
option for verbosity.
Given the following
output from Explain,
what is the best description of
what happened during the query?
And this looks a lot like
what we did in the class.
We are creating an
explainable object
and looking at this query.
So examine these
results carefully,
and then figure
out what happened,
and then pick the right answer.