So now I want to talk a
little bit about index sizes.
As with other
databases, with MongoDB,
it's very important that we're
able to fit what's called
the working set into memory.
So the working set is
the portion of our data
that clients are
frequently accessing.
As you might imagine,
the key component of this
is our indexes.
For performance
reasons, it's essential
that we can fit the entire
working set into memory
because going to disk for data
is a time consuming operation
and performance will
degrade significantly
if, for frequently
accessed data,
we have to go to disk regularly.
Now, this is especially
true with indexes
because if, in order
to search an index,
we first have to pull it
from disk into memory,
we lose a lot of the
performance benefits of having
the index in the
first place, so it's
especially important that
our indexes fit into memory.
So let's look at how we can
measure the size of our indexes
as a means of, say, estimating
the amount of memory we'll
need for a MongoDB deployment.
So let's take a look at
our students collection.
We have individual students,
classes, and the scores
in this collection.
There are 10 million
records here.
So first, let's take a look
at what indexes we have.
We can see that in addition
to the primary index,
we have a secondary
compound index
on student ID and class ID.
If we want to see the
size of our indexes,
we can use the stats method.
So we call the stats method
on the collection of interest,
and here we can see
the total index size,
and this is also
broken down for us
into the individual sizes
for the two collections
that we have.
There's a shortcut
method for this
as well, which gives
us just the total.
So from this, it
looks like each index
we have is adding 300 megabytes
to our total index size,
and of course, this
has an impact, then,
on how much memory our
working set requires.
Now, with the release
of MongoDB 3.0,
we've introduced the Wired
Tiger storage engine.
One of the key
features of Wired Tiger
is that it supports a few
different types of compression,
one of which, called
prefix compression,
allows us to have
smaller indexes.
So that last
example we looked at
was against a MongoDB running
the MMAP V1 storage engine.
Now let's take a look
at index sizes for a 3.0
server with the Wired
Tiger storage engine,
and in particular, we've got it
index prefix compression turned
on.
So let's launch a shell
and connect to that mongod.
That one's running
on the default port.
So I have exactly
the same data set
loaded here, again, 10
million records, and I've
got the same indexes as I
had in our last example.
So now let's take a look
at the index sizes here.
And we can see that our
total index size here
is just under 200 megabytes.
So rather than 300
megabytes each,
our indexes are something on
the order of 100 megabytes each.
Now, I should also say
that this compression comes
at the cost of
CPU, and it really
depends on your data
set as to whether or not
you can take
advantage of something
like prefix compression, but
it's something to be aware of
and something I wanted
to show you here.
I'll also just briefly point
out that with the Wired Tiger
storage engine, the stats output
looks a little bit different.
In particular, we've got
this Wired Tiger document
that reports on a bunch of stats
for that particular storage
engine.
So again, pay attention to
the size of your indexes.
Make sure they can fit in
memory so that you can realize
the full performance benefits.