OK.
Let's talk about
another type of index
that can be very useful
when dealing with text.
And it's called a
full-text search index
Full-text search
was first introduced
on an experimental
basis in MongoDB 2.4.
And now it's available and
for general availability
in MongoDB 2.6.
So why would you use it, and
what would you use it for?
Well, let's say you had a
very large piece of text
that was in a document,
something like the US
Constitution, which starts out
"We the people of the United
States, in order to form
a more perfect union."
Let's say you had that
document right here in a key
called "mytext."
And you had the entire
preamble to the US Constitution
in this key, mytext.
And you wanted to search it.
Well, if you search
just on any given word,
then you wouldn't
get anything back,
because MongoDB, when
you search on strings,
the entire string
needs to be there.
So as an alternative, you
could put every single word
into an array, and then use
the Set Notation operators
to push things into it, and
then search for whether or not
the words are included.
But that's pretty tedious.
And there are certain other
features that would be missing.
So instead, what we
have is something
called a full-text
search index, which
is abbreviated "text," which
will index this entire document
and every word, much
in the way an array
is indexed, to allow you to
do queries into the text,
basically applying
the OR operator,
and looking for one
of several words.
So let's go look at
now a specific case
and see how it would work.
All right.
We've created a collection
called Sentences.
And this collection has got a
bunch of mostly just randomly
inserted words into a Words key.
Now, if I wanted to
search-- and there
is no tech search index
on this right now.
This is a regular collection.
If I wanted to search for,
let's say, dog, shrub, Ruby,
I could do it.
I could do-- all right.
There we go.
So I searched for
dog, shrub, Ruby.
And I found this document
with words dog, shrub, Ruby.
But it's very particular.
If I leave off the
period, doesn't find it.
If I just do dog,
Ruby, doesn't find it.
And if I just do dog,
it doesn't find it.
That's not going to
work too well for me
to search on these
different words.
So now, let's add a text index--
so db.sentences.ensureindex.
And now I want to put an
index on words of type Text.
There we go.
And now when I search
it-- dog, shrub,
Ruby-- it's going to
work a lot better.
So let's do that.
So let's first
look at the syntax
for searching a full-text index.
The way it works is,
I have to say $text,
and then give a document--
we had $search-- and then
what I'm looking for.
So we saw that, for instance,
dog did not work before.
Let's just look for dog
now, and see if that works.
There we go.
OK.
So now I searched for
just the word "dog,"
and I was able to get all of
these back that have dog, moss,
Ruby, dog, shrub, Ruby.
And then just to show
you again, when I just
search for dog using a
regular search of words,
I don't get anything.
But if I search using
a text index-- I'm
going to show you
the syntax right
here-- I search
using a text index
by specifying $text
and then $search,
and then what I'm looking for--
dog-- I do get documents back.
I get all these documents
back, because they all
have a dog in them.
And if I also say moss, I get
all of these back as well.
And if I say moss, Ruby, I'm
going to get all of these back.
And it's quite flexible.
Putting in a period
makes no difference.
Capitalization
So it's going to also ignore
certain stop words that are not
considered to be significant,
like "a" and "the"
in the English language.
So that's really
very useful if I
want to search for a
bunch of different words,
and essentially apply
a logical OR operator.
Now there's one other
thing I wanted to show you,
which is how you can get
back these in an order that
indicates how good a match
MongoDB believes there is.
So let's look for one of these.
So I'm going to show
you the syntax for this.
All right.
So let's look for
dog, tree, obsidian.
OK.
Dog, tree, obsidian.
Let me go back and change this.
And we can see the
document right up there
with dog, tree, obsidian.
I mean the best match
for dog, tree, obsidian
should be dog, tree,
obsidian document.
But we're going to do
something special now.
We're going to
project a Score field.
And we're going to use a
special $meta operator,
and then take the tech score,
which is something that's
internally computed as it
runs through this tech search.
And we're going to get
that text score out.
And then, we're going to
sort by that tech score.
And we're not going to
test you on the syntax,
but I want you know it
exists if you ever need it.
And if you do that,
you'll see that now it's
ranking the documents in
order of their tech score.
And that if you're
searching for dog,
tree, obsidian, the one with
the highest score, a score of 2,
is a document with dog, tree,
obsidian-- all three words
in it.
Very useful if you want to
find the best match for, let's
say, a document that
contains all the words.
All right.
So now it's time for a quiz.
Let's say you
create a text index
on the title field of
the movies' collection.
You imagine having a
movies' collection.
And then perform the following
text search-- db.movies.find,
$text, $search, "Big Lebowski."
Which of these
documents might be
returned if all these documents
are in the collection?