OK.
So at this point,
we know quite a bit
about what types of
indexes MongoDB supports,
how to create indexes, and
the importance of indexes
for the efficiency
of our application.
What I'd like to do now is
walk through an example that
gives you an idea of the type
of thinking you need to do when
you're designing your indexes.
The goal is that our
read and write operations
are as efficient as possible.
But as with so many things, this
requires some upfront thinking
and some experimentation.
To be sure you get the right
indexes in place, what you'd
really want to do is test your
indexes under some real world
workloads and make
adjustments from there.
But that's outside the
scope of this course.
What we're going
to look at here is
some of the initial
thinking you can
do to get ready for some
of that real world testing.
So what we're going for here is
the selectivity of our index,
and to what degree for
a given query pattern
the index is going to minimize
the number of records scanned.
And we have to consider this
in a scope of all operations
to satisfy a query, and
sometimes make some trade offs.
So we'll have to consider, for
example, how sorts are handled.
OK.
So let's go through our example.
And again, this
is really the tip
of the iceberg in terms of
designing a set of indexes.
But it gives you an
idea for the type
of thinking you're going
to have to do in order
to get those indexes right.
So to think about
building indexes that
can handle our query
patterns efficiently,
let's return to our
student data set.
Now, in this version
of the data set,
I've added a field
for a final grade.
And we're dealing with
about one million students.
So here's the query
that I want to look at.
And the reason for this is
because it illustrates several
of the issues that we
have to think about
in designing our indexes.
So note that what
we're doing here
is a query for all students with
an ID greater than 500,000--
OK, so that's going
to be about half
the students-- and
records for the class 54.
There's about 500 classes
represented in here.
And then finally, we're going
to sort in ascending order
on student ID, the same
field we're querying on here.
Now, throughout
this example, I'm
going to be running
explain on the cursor
that the query returns
to us and specifying
that I want to see execution
stats so that we get
nice detailed output about
exactly what MongoDB did
in order to satisfy the query.
So let's run this.
OK.
So I want to draw your attention
to a couple different things.
So first, let's take a look
at this-- total keys examined.
This is how many
keys within the index
MongoDB walked through in order
to generate the results set.
The results set, on the other
hand, is only 10,000 documents.
So we had to look at
a lot more index keys
then we really needed to in
order to find the documents.
What this means
is that the index
that was used in order
to satisfy this query
wasn't very selective.
And you remember
that selectivity
is one of our key goals when
we're designing an index.
So let's see if we can
figure out what happened.
OK.
Now, when you move
above executionStats
in the explain output, the
thing you're going to see
is the output from
the query planner.
So starting from the top
and working your way down,
you've got a winning plan.
And then you also get a chance
to see the rejected plans.
So this is in JSON form a
specific outcome for this ID
here, racing a couple
of different query plans
against one another.
OK.
So what happened here
is that the winning plan
used a compound index based
on student ID and class ID.
And the losing plan--
there's only one other--
would have used an
index based on class ID,
but then it would have had
to do an in memory sort.
That's what this component
of this particular query plan
means.
Any time you see a sort
stage in a query plan,
it means that
MongoDB was or would
have been unable to sort
the results set according
to the sort specified by the
query in the database itself.
Rather, it would have had
to do an in memory sort.
So what happened here is
that the index that won
is one that was able to
return sorted output.
So it only had to get to
that certain threshold
number of returned results,
which is, I believe,
101 returned documents.
First is, if you
remember, 10,000 documents
would have to have been
returned by any query plan that
was unable to do a sort
within the database.
Because we actually were able to
identify 10,000 documents that
matched the query
parameters stipulated here.
Again, the issue is
one of selectivity.
And the problem
here is that we're
specifying a range query that
just isn't very selective.
And so we end up
touching every single key
in this index that has a student
ID value greater than 500,000.
So that's about half
of the records here.
Now, I'm sure you can see
where I'm headed here.
It's this query,
the point query,
that's going to be considerably
more selective for us.
OK.
So as I said, there's
only about 500 classes
represented in this data set.
And now, granted,
there's lots of students
taking those classes.
But this is going to
constrain our results set.
And this is really what leads
to those 10,000 records being
returned as opposed to the
850,000 that were identified.
So what would better,
given the indexes we have,
is if, in fact, we use
this particular index.
Because this is going to be
substantially more selective.
So let's do that.
Now, MongoDB does provide a
way of forcing the database
to use a particular index.
I can't stress strongly
enough that you
should use this with caution.
It's not something
you should necessarily
make part of your deployment.
But it is a way
of overriding what
would be the outcome
of the query planner.
So that is called Hint.
OK.
And with Hint, we can
specify a particular index
that we'd like to use, either
by specifying its shape
or its actual name.
In this case, I'm just
going to specify its shape.
And what I'm going to do
here is I'm going to say,
OK, I want to use
the class ID index.
OK.
So let's see what
happened with this query.
OK.
We're now down from having
scanned 850,000 index keys
to just about 20,000
in order to get
to our results set of 10,000.
OK.
And the execution time is
only 79 milliseconds as
opposed to the 2,600
milliseconds we
saw before using other index.
OK.
Now, the fact is, what
we'd really like to see
is that nReturned
is, in fact, very
close to total keys examined.
So one way of addressing this
is to design a better index.