So here is that index.
Offscreen, I've gone ahead and
created a compound index based
on class ID and student ID.
So with class ID as
the prefix, we'll
be using the most selective
part of our query-- the point
or a quality query.
Now, generally
speaking-- and this
won't hold for all data sets.
But generally
speaking, when you're
building compound
indexes, as you're
thinking about field order
in the compound index,
you want to work with
fields on which you're
going to be doing your
quality queries first.
Putting them before range
queries, as we did here.
OK.
Now, I'm going to mix
things up a little bit,
and you can see here
that I've actually
changed the sort we want to
do to use that final grade
field that I introduced when
we first started looking
at this particular example.
So let's run this query
now and see what explain
tells us about performance.
OK.
That was fast.
So we scroll up
to executionStats,
and look at this.
Number returned is exactly
equal to the totalKeysExamined
and the totalDocsExamined.
Our executionTime
is 138 milliseconds.
So let's look at the
query plan here then.
And here, I want to call
your attention to the fact
that we have a sort stage.
Now, what that means is that
we're doing an in-memory sort,
and I bet you can
figure out why.
Because we can
see from the index
scan stage that we're
using that new index
that we created-- the compound
index on class ID and student
ID.
No mention of final grade here.
So in order to sort,
we're going to have
to do the sort in-memory.
Generally speaking, it's
best to avoid in-memory sorts
when we can.
But in order to do
that, we're going
to have to make a trade-off.
And that is-- and
this is typically
the trade-off you
have-- we're going
to have to examine a few
more keys than the number
of documents we return
in order to be able to do
that sort in the database.
So let me show you what I mean.
So we created this index here.
Well, let's think
about how this works.
We're creating a bunch of
pairs of values, in effect,
of class ID and student ID, but
what we'd like to be able to do
is walk the index in sort order.
OK.
So in order to do
that, well, we've
got our most selective
part of our query here,
which is fine because
we want to identify
every single record that
uses the class ID specified
in the query.
But then in order to be able
to sort within the index,
we'd have to be able to walk
the index keys in order, which
means that we're
going to have to have
that field on
which we're sorting
as part of a compound index.
And it's going to have to go
immediately after class ID.
So we want to create
another compound index.
And in fact, this is
the one that we really
want if a common query
pattern is this one that we're
looking at because this will
very selectively identify
the records that
we want to look at.
And then by walking
the next component
of the keys all the
way through the index,
we'll be able to pull out all
of the records in the specified
sort order.
And what we can
do along the way,
as we're walking
through those keys,
is simply eliminate any that
don't match the student ID
range that we're looking for.
OK So we're going to have
to touch a few more index
keys than will end up
being in our results set.
But by doing the
sort in the database,
we're going to save
ourselves executionTime.
So let's create this index.
It'll take a little while.
OK.
And our index finished
up, so let's take a look.
Now, there is one thing I
want to tweak about this,
and that is that
I want to change
the way we're
sorting so that we're
sorting in descending order.
And this index we created
will work just fine for that
because MongoDB can walk
the index in reverse order
just as easily.
So let's run our query.
OK.
Now, let's take a look
at what happened here.
OK.
Now, this is going
to vary depending
on what else is going
on in the system,
but you can see that
our executionTime is
down quite a bit.
And this is because doing
the sort in the database,
by simply walking the
index keys in order,
it's going to save
us executionTime.
And if we look at
the query plan,
we can see that the
winning plan does not
any longer have a sort stage.
And in fact, what
we ended up using
was the index that
we just created.
OK.
So why is this a better
index for this query?
Well, for this data set, we know
that class is very selective.
By specifying an
individual class ID,
we're eliminating easily more
than 90% of the data set.
And in fact, it's quite
a bit more than 90%.
And by specifying
this, we can simply
walk the index keys
in order in order
to get our sorted results set.
And along the way,
based on the student ID
component of this
compound index,
we can simply make
this comparison
to get rid of any records
that don't match this range
constraint.
And if we take a look at the
explain output one more time,
we'll see that that trade-off
is, in fact, there--
that good executionTime, but
we are walking a few more index
keys than we have documents
in our results set.
But in many cases,
this is a trade-off
that's well worth making.
OK.
So this gives you
some idea of how
to think a little bit
about structuring indexes.
And we looked at
compound indexes
because this is where people
have the most difficulty
setting up their indexes.
And thinking about
selectivity and thinking
about how to get our sorts
accomplished in the database
gives us indexes that
pretty efficiently
handle our operations.