We've talked about how you
create indexes and we've
talked about how you use the
explain command to figure out
what indexes are getting used
and how they're getting used
in your queries, but ultimately,
about the
performance of your programs
you're going to need to do
some profiling to figure
out what is
slow inside your programs.
Now, there's actually, there is
a profiler built into Mongo
D and I'm going to teach you
how to turn that on, but
before you even do that there's
a default facility
that could help you and that
is that Mongo automatically
logs slow queries of above 100
milliseconds right to the log
that Mongo D writes when
you start it up.
So this is a default
logging facility
that can be very useful.
So let me show you
how that works.
So I'm going to start Mongo
D here with the default.
Here, I'll shut it down.
I have a DB path and
nothing else set.
If I do that, all right, do
nothing else and then I go
over here to my Mongo shell.
I'm going to have to reconnect,
so the first time I
hit this, it's not
going to do it.
And now, I'm going to do
a find on the student's
collection, and student's
collection is a 10 million
document collection that
we've seen many times.
And I took all the indexes off
it so it's going to be slow
since it has to scan the whole
collection, if I look for
student ID 10,000.
So I'm going to do that.
It's going to take a while.
It has to spin up a disc even
to do it because I haven't
done it in a while.
It finds the object in
question, finds the
document, all good.
And if we go here, into the log,
you can see, right here
it says that there was this
really slow query.
It actually gives me the query,
I looked for student ID
10,000 and it was in school dot
students and it took about
four seconds.
Very useful and certainly, you
should be checking your logs
to make sure you don't have a
lot of slow queries and this
is something that's built in
and you don't need to do
anything to get this.
It's automatic.