All right, the last topic of
this unit is sharding.
And sharding is a technique
for splitting up a large
collection amongst
multiple servers.
So so far we've been talking
about having a single Mongo
server, which I'll represent
as this disk.
But there comes a time when you
can't get the performance
you want from a single server.
And so what you can do
is you can shard.
And when you shard, you deploy
multiple mongod servers, and
in the front, you have a mongos
which is a router.
And your application talks to
mongos, which then talks to
the various servers,
the mongods.
Now one wrinkle, which I won't
go into here, is that rather
than being a single server, this
is sometimes and often
and recommend to be
a set of servers.
So imagine three of these guys
behind here in what's called a
replica set.
And a replica set keeps the data
in sync across several
different instances so that if
one of them goes down, you
won't lose your data.
But logically, you can look at
this replica set as one shard.
And when you're doing this--
and for the most part, it's
transparent to the
application--
however, the way Mongo
shards is that you
choose a shard key.
So for instance, in that student
collection, you might
decide that student_id
is your shard key.
Or it could be a compound key.
And the mongos server, it's
a range-based system.
So based on the student-id that
you query, it'll send the
request to the right
Mongo instance.
So what do you really have to
need to know as a developer?
Well the, first thing you need
to know is that an insert must
include the shard key,
the entire shard key.
So if it's a multi-parted shard
key, you must include
the entire shard key in order
for the insert to complete.
So you have to be aware of what
the shard key is on the
collection itself.
And the second thing you need to
know is that for an update
or a remove or a find, if mongos
isn't given a shard
key, then what it's going to
have to do is broadcast the
request to all the different
shards that cover the
collection.
So you have some collection,
like the students collection,
and it's broken up into big
parts that map each to
different shards--
shard0, shard1.
And then there's some chunking
within here to allow Mongo to
keep it balanced, but that
doesn't really matter from
your standpoint.
The point is that if it doesn't
know the shard key, on
the query, it has
to broadcast it.
Now, it may be the case that
you're doing a query that you
don't know the shard key,
in which case it
does have to be broadcast.
And that's fine.
But if you know the shard key,
you should specify it because
you will get better performance
because you'll
only be utilizing one
of the servers.
And you won't be keep the other
servers busy with this
query as well.
A couple of other subtleties--
with updates, if you don't
specify the entire shard key,
you have to make it a
multi-update so that it knows
that it needs to broadcast it.
And we're going to go over a lot
of this in the application
engineering part
of the course.
But I just wanted to explain the
role that sharding has on
performance and also the
subtlety of having to think
about the shard key a bit.
And choosing a shard key is a
topic in and of itself, which
we are not going to go over.
Now within each of these
servers, all these instances,
the same techniques apply as
we have been talking about
this entire unit.
So you could certainly
use Explain.
You can look at the
system profile.
You can connect directly to the
Mongo instances that are
running on here if you'd like
for debugging purposes.
So a lot of the same
things apply.
But at the highest level, your
application will be talking to
a mongos router.
And that mongos will be talking
to the mongods,
usually on different physical
servers because that's
probably the reason why you
sharded in the first place was
to get higher performance.
And just in case you were
wondering, mongos is often
co-located on the same machine
as the application, and you
can have multiple of these
mongos services.
And you may have noticed the
mongos binary in the Mongo
distribution, and that's
what it is.
It lets you shard a collection
and split it across multiple
servers and access it
pretty easily--
somewhat transparently, except
you have to have some
understanding of
the shard key.
All right, so that completes
our unit on performance.
I hope you've enjoyed it, and
I'll see you next week.