Now I'd like to tell you
about the Mongostat command.
The Mongostat command is a
performance tuning command,
and it is somewhat similar
to the iostat command
from the Unix world, if
you're familiar with that.
What it will do is it will
sample the database in one
second increments and give you a
bunch of information about what
is going on during
that one second.
For instance, it will give you
the number of inserts, queries,
updates, and deletes.
It'll also give you
different information
depending on whether you're
running Wired Tiger or MMAP V1
as a storage engine.
So let's take a
look at Mongostat
in a running database.
Now, I've got both
storage engines
currently running on
this computer, both Wired
Tiger and MMAP V1.
And I'm currently creating
the student collection,
which is a million students, 10
classes for each student, so 10
million documents,
and that's going on
in parallel for both the Wired
Tiger and the MMAP V1 storage
engine.
Two different mongods, and one
of them is running at 27017
and the other one
is running at 27018.
So if I wanted to
see how it's going,
I could run Mongo, use
the school database,
and count the number of students
that are currently here,
and you can see there's
about 850,000 in this one.
And if I wanted to see what's
going on in the Wired Tiger
one, which is running at
27018, I could do that as well,
and you can see there are
793,000 students in that one.
And every time I
run it, that number
will be a little bit higher
because it's actually running
a script in the background.
Now, if I wanted to look at
this and see what's happening,
I can run Mongostat
and I'll run it
without a port number, which
will run it against 27017.
And if I do that, you
can see a bunch of data.
Unfortunately, it's
wrapping on the screen
so it's a little
hard to read, but you
can see the number of inserts,
queries, updates, and deletes,
and you can see that, for
the 27017 server, which
is the default port server,
I'm running about 4,000 inserts
every second.
There's a bunch of
other information
here that we'll go
over in a moment.
Now, if I want to then look
at the other storage engine,
I could do that, and you can
see that that's also running
about 4,000 inserts per second.
Now, let's stress it just
a little bit further.
So it's running this
large insert script
that's going to insert all
these different student records,
but now let's also run this.
So I've written a small script
called stress_students.py,
and it doesn't do much.
What it does is it
goes through and looks
in the range of
400,000 to 500,000
and it tries to look up
the student by student ID,
and there is an index on
student ID for this collection
on both storage engines.
And every 1,000 or so, it just
says, I did 1,000 searches.
So let's run that,
and while we're
running that, let's go back.
And now, once again,
let's run Mongostat.
And now we see the results
are slightly different.
We can see that not only
are we doing some inserts,
and actually, the
insert rate has now
gone down to about
3,000 per second,
but we're also doing
a bunch of queries.
We're doing about 3,000 to
4,000 queries per second.
So you can see how
this data changes,
depending on the
workload in the database.
So let's go over a few more
of these different columns
and talk about what they do.
I'm not going to go
through all of them.
Insert, query,
update, and delete
are just these different query
operations and deletions.
Those are pretty obvious.
Getmore is how many
getmore commands
we're running every second.
Getmore is the way you
get more from a cursor
if you're doing a query
that has a large result.
This is the number of commands
that are running per second,
things like create
index and get indexes.
These are commands.
I'm not going to
talk about flushes.
It has to do with
the number of times
that it flushes out
the disk per second,
but I'm not going to
talk too much about it.
Mapped is the amount
of mapped memory
that exists in the
MMAP V1 storage engine.
You can see we're
mapping a lot of memory,
but you can see that we only
have about 4.2 gigabytes
resident.
This is the number
of page faults
that we're causing
every second, and that's
an important number in MMAP
V1 because page faults mean
that you're getting
more I/O, and more I/O
means a slower database.
Now finally, this right here--
and these are all wrapped,
it's hard to read these-- but
these are the queue lengths
for a number of
sockets, I believe,
that are requested or waiting
for read and for write,
and this is the number of active
readers and active writers,
and then this is
the amount that was
sent into the database
and out of the database
during this time frame.
Now, let's run Mongostat for
the Wired Tiger storage engine
and look at the differences.
Now again, Wired Tiger
is running at 27018 port,
so let me connect to it there.
Now, you can see for the
Wired Tiger storage engine,
I'm not seeing any
queries because I'm not
running that stress test against
the Wired Tiger storage engine.
If I wanted to change that and
run it against the Wired Tiger
storage engine, I could do that.
Let's change that stress
test.py to connect to 27018,
and now let's run that.
So now we're going
to run that, and then
while we're running
that, we're going
to run our Mongostat
against 27018.
Let's do that.
Great.
So I'll let that
run a little bit.
Then I'll stop it.
The first thing you notice is
that the Wired Tiger storage
engine is actually
managing a few more reads.
We're getting reads in
the 5,000 range per second
while we're still doing about
4,000 inserts per second,
so we're seeing better
performance out of the Wired
Tiger storage engine.
This is not the best
performance test.
I've got two different
mongod servers running
on the same box, but it is an
interesting stat nonetheless.
Now, you'll notice here that we
still have this getmore column
and we have this command
column, but then we
have a bunch of
different columns.
First of all, the MMAP column
is gone because we're not
mapping memory anymore.
Instead, we have the
%dirty and the %used,
and this refers to the
percentage of the Wired Tiger
cache that is dirty, meaning
that it's written and will need
to be written back to disk if
we want to reuse the space,
and the %used is a percentage
of total cache size that
we're using, and you can see
that that's 10% and that very
little of this cache is dirty.
And then we can see that
we have about 1.6 gigabyte
resident in the storage engine.
And then the queue lengths
are again very close to zero,
and the active clients
are-- it says one.
Maybe two is Mongostat
attaching to it.
I'm not sure.
Or potentially, maybe that's
our stress test, actually.
It could be our stress
test connecting to it.
Now, let's see.
In terms of the
resident size, I'm
just going to go back
and see what this was.
The resident size before
in MMAP was 4.2 gigs
and the resident size
here was 1.6 gigs,
so it looks like the resident
size is a lot smaller
on Wired Tiger.
That gives you a taste
of what these stats are.
Now, obviously, you're most
interested in the stats that
indicate both the users
of the database and also
how much I/O you're doing.
For the MMAP V1 storage engine,
the number of page faults
is a pretty good indicator of
the amount of I/O you're doing.
Of course, you could also
find that out from I/O stat.
And for the Wired
Tiger storage engine,
I don't see anything that's a
clear indicator of the amount
of I/O you're
doing, although you
can tell by the
percentage of your cache
that you're using how
close you are to seeing
some pressure on that cache.
Obviously, if you're not
using the whole cache,
you're probably not
seeing very much pressure
at all on its size.
Now, if you want to find
out more about Mongostat,
of course, the
best way to do that
is by looking in the manual.
Right here, I'm just
googling "mongostat MongoDB,"
and if I look here,
the first link
tells me all about Mongostat.
I know it's a little
bit small here.
These are the command
line options to run it.
I'm not going to get into that.
And then finally at
the bottom, we've
got the fields, which
pretty much follow along
with what I just talked
about, telling you
the number of inserts,
queries, updates
per second that are
happening, and then explaining
some of the more esoteric ones
and which ones also exist only
for Wired Tiger, or what
they mean in Wired Tiger
versus in MMAP.
So for instance, flushes
has a different meaning
in Wired Tiger versus MMAP.
Dirty, as I said, is a
Wired Tiger only term.
It's about percentage of
the cache that's dirty.
Mapped is an MMAP
V1 storage term.
Size is actually-- I
didn't see a size output,
I saw a vsize output, which
why I haven't talked about it.
Documentation seems to be
slightly off with respect
to this column, and
I filed a ticket,
so you might see this
as changed or more clear
when you watch this video.
Resident is the amount
of resident memory used
in both cases, and faults, of
course, is an MMAP V1 concept.
So those are the major parts
of the Mongostat command,
and you should use
the Mongostat command
if you're curious what
the database is doing,
so that's Mongostat.
Now it's time for a
quiz on Mongostat.
Which of the following
statements about Mongostat
output are true?
Check all that apply.
The MMAP column field appears
for all storage engines,
the getmore column concerns
the number of requests
per time interval to get
additional data from a cursor,
only the Wired
Tiger storage engine
reports the resident memory
size of the database,
the faults column appears
only in the MMAP V1 output,
and by default, Mongostat
provides information
in 100 millisecond increments.