All right.
And the answer is that this
find is using BtreeCursor
created at index.
We know that that's an index on
just the created at field.
It reversed it.
We know that Mongo can only use
one index for any given
query, and since created at is
in the sort field and it's not
in the criteria field, we know
that it's probably being used
for the sort.
And we also know that it's not
using anything for the
criteria part because it can't
use more than one index, and
we know that the follower
count is not in
the created at index.
So from that, we can determine
that we probably did scan the
entire collection even though
we did use an index.
We used the index
for the sort.
And we also note that it's not a
covered index, but of course
you did a table scan, so that
probably make sense.
And it took 205 milliseconds.
So let's see what we can
learn from this.
Returned 10 documents, OK.
So, the answers are, this query
performs a table scan.
A table scan is the same
as a collection scan.
The answer is, yes it does.
The query uses an index to
determine the order in which
to return the resulting
documents.
Yes, that is true.
The query uses an index
to determine which
documents to match.
That is not true.
You cannot use that index.
The index here, BtreeCursor
created at could not be used
to satisfy this criteria, and
so therefore, it is not.
The query returns 46,000
documents.
That's not true.
The query returns
10 documents .
The query visits 46,462
documents, that is true.
Yeah, 46,462, right there.
And, this query is a covered
index query, and that is not
true, which is plainly obvious
from the fact that it says
index only false.
OK, so that's the answer
to this question.