OK, and the answer is that the
first one can't use an index
because it asks for brand GE,
and as you can see, the only
index that has brand in it is
a compound index and it's in
the second column, so
it can't use it.
And then the next one is brand
GE as well, so that won't use
the index, but it sorts by
price, and there is a
index on the price.
So that second query can
utilize an index.
The next one looks for prices
that are greater than 30 and
less than 50, and it
sorts by brand.
So this can use an index because
the price query can
use an index, and this sort
won't use an index.
And the last one is to look up
a brand GE, which we know
cannot use the index, and then
sort by category and brand in
that order.
Category and brand.
And you can see here that there
is a category and brand
index, but the issue is that
it's in the wrong order.
So its category ascending, brand
ascending, and we try to
do a category ascending, brand
descending index, which it
will not do.
So for that reason, that
answer is not chosen.