Now we've gone over how to
create index, and we have some
basic understanding of when
an index will be used.
But there is a command inside
the database, Explain, that
will tell you exactly what
indexes were used for your
queries and how they
were used.
And in this lesson,
we're going to go
over the Explain command.
I've created a collection called
foo inside the test
database that has 10,000
documents.
And the documents are
pretty simple.
They have a structure.
They have an a, b, and c key.
And you can see here a
is 0, b is 0, c is 0.
And then I just increment 1,
1, 1, 2, 2, 2, et cetera.
I put an index on this
collection, and the index is a
compound index on a, b, and c.
And let me scroll through
and show you
that ensureIndex command.
So this was the index that I
put on the collection where
there's a, b, and
c in the index.
And now I'm going to do a query
where I would expect
that the database could not use
an index, so for instance,
the query where b was
10 or something.
So let's just do that.
There's one.
We'll do on where c is 1.
That is a query where we would
expect that the database could
not use the index.
And we get the result.
There's one document that
matches that criteria.
Now we're going to call the same
exact query, but we're
going to append an Explain on
the end, and we're going to
look at the result.
So I added Explain to the end.
And now, instead of getting back
to document itself, we
get back an explanation of
what the database did to
perform the query.
Now the first thing to note here
is that it says cursor
BasicCursor.
Now BasicCursor means that there
was no index used to
execute this query.
That doesn't surprise us,
because we know that we gave
just c, and we know that the
index is a, b, and c.
So we know that the index
couldn't be used, so it
doesn't surprise us to
find out that it
couldn't use the index.
Now I'm going to go over a lot
of these fields soon, but I
just want to bring your
attention right now to this
millis field, which is the
number of milliseconds that
was required to execute
the query.
And as you know, there are
1,000 milliseconds in a
second, so this was 3/1,000
of a second to
execute this query.
All right?
That's pretty slow
for a database.
If you want to do thousands and
thousands of operations a
second, that's going
to be pretty slow.
Now let's do another query.
But this time let's have it be a
being 1, or let's say a 500.
I won't go back and get the
document because we know
there's one in there.
I'll just look at the
Explain output.
Explain output is much
longer this time.
The first thing to note is
that it no longer says
BasicCursor up here.
It says that there is a
BtreeCurson, a 1, b 1, c 1
used to perform this query.
Now that is the name of the
index, the compound
index, on a, b, c.
So the first thing you note here
is that the database is
using the index, which
is excellent.
That's exactly what we wanted.
Second thing to note is that
is isMultiKey is false.
This is whether or not the index
is a multikey index.
None of the values inside a, b,
and c are arrays, so it is
not a multikey index.
n 1 is the number of documents
that is returned.
This is a simple theory
where a was 500.
There are 10,000 documents in
this collection, and there's
only one of them where
a is 500, so it
returned the one document.
nscannedObjects is the number of
documents that were scanned
to answer the query,
which was the one.
The index drilled down,
found the one
document, and it was returned.
nscanned is the number of index
entries or documents, I
believe, that were looked
at, which, again, is 1.
And then I won't go over some
of these, but I want to just
point out a few of them.
And one is that there's
this indexBounds
element right here.
That's one element I want to
point out, which shows the
bounds that were used to
look up the index.
And it's not surprising that
we looked up 500, 500, the
lower and upper bound of 500 for
a to perform that index,
and then the rest of them are
set to min and max element.
Not too surprising.
This last field that I want to
show you right now is this
indexOnly field.
And this indexOnly field tells
us whether or not the database
query could be satisfied
with just the index.
This is a concept we haven't
talked about yet.
It's called a covered index.
If everything you're asking for
can be satisfied with just
the index, then the indexOnly
field will be true, and then
the document itself didn't
have to be retrieved.
Let's see if we can modify this
query to make that true.
So I'm going to go back
to this query where
I look for a 500.
And this time what I'm
going to do is ask
for just a is 500.
And I'm going to ask for just
the a field and the b field,
and I'm going to suppress
the _id field
and not ask for that.
Let's look at that query.
Let's run it.
We see there's one item.
This is a query that should
be completely
satisfied by the index.
Let's call Explain and
see what we get.
And here you can see that now
indexOnly Only is true,
because we didn't need to go
to the actual collection to
answer this query.
All the information that we
needed is in the query.
All right.
Let's look at a slightly
different variant.
Let's look at a query where
MongoDB cannot use the index
for finding the documents but
it can use the index for
sorting the documents.
So in this query we have and
clause, and we're looking for
c values that are greater
than 250 and less
than or equal to 500.
And we're going to sort by a.
Now we know the index is on a,
b, c, so it shouldn't be able
to use the index to find the
documents, but it should be
able to use the index
to sort them.
So let's see what happens
when you run that
query and hit Explain.
All right.
So what we find out is that 250
documents were returned,
which is what we'd expect.
And it says that it uses
BtreeCursor index, but it
didn't use it for the
actual find part for
selecting the criteria.
Instead it used it
for sorting.
And the way you can tell is that
the number of scanned--
this is index or documents--
was 9541.
The number of scanned
documents was 250.
So in this case, what
MongoDB did--
and I'm not positive about this,
but I'm pretty sure--
that it scanned the
index itself.
It only had a look at 9,541
index entries before it felt
that it had gotten exhaustively
all the documents
that were between
c 250 and c 500.
And so then it actually went
into those 250 documents, and
this right here is the number
of documents it touched, and
then gave us the results.
Let's change this around a
little bit to make it more
clear exactly what's
happening here.
I'm going to drop this index on
a, b, c, and I'm going to
add a new index on just a, b.
Now we are absolutely positive
that it can't use the index
values for the find, even
if it scans them all.
Now we're going to
do the same find.
Remember, we're looking for c
greater than 250 or less than
500, and we have an index
on only a, b.
But we're asking to sort on a,
so it should be able to use
the index for the sort part.
Let's see what happens.
In this case, the result
is more clear.
You can see that, again, it
returned 250 documents.
But you can see the number of
scanned index or documents is
10,000, and the number of
scanned documents is 10,000.
So in this case, it couldn't
use the index all, couldn't
even scan the index to figure
out what the answer was.
So it went right to the
collection, it's scanned them
all, and then it was able to use
the BtreeCursor index to
return the results
in sorted order.
And just to show you that this
is the index on a and b, I'm
just going to show you the
getIndexes command, which will
show you the indexes that
are on the collection.
You can see this collection
has the index a, b is now
called a_1_b_1 for ascending
and ascending.
All right.
It is now time for a quiz.
Given the following output from
Explain, what is the best
description of what happened
during the query.
And the choices are the query
used an index called
BasicCursor and returned in
5,151 microseconds; the query
scanned 10 million documents,
returning 10,000 in 5.2
seconds; the query scanned
10,000 documents and returned
in 5 milliseconds; and the
query was able to use a
covered index to answer the
query entirely within the
index without looking
at the documents.