We started out this unit by
talking about the importance
of being algorithmically
efficient by using indexes to
resolve our queries.
Now the next level of
optimization is that we want
those indexes to be in memory.
Because if our index is not in
memory-- if our index is on
disk, and if we're using almost
all of it, then we're
going to find that the
performance is severely impacted.
Even though algorithmically it's
much faster than, let's
say, traversing the entire
collection to get the answer,
it still isn't going to be super
fast if we have to go to
disk to access our index.
So there's a question-- and
we're going to talk more about
this in the rest of the unit--
about working set and how do
we keep the most important parts
of the data in memory.
But even more important in
keeping the data in memory is
going to be keeping the
index in memory.
So the first question
you might have is,
how big is an index?
Let's go back and look at this
student's collection that I
created earlier.
And if you recall, it has 10
million student records in it.
So if we look at that
collection, we
can get it's stats.
And it just says
db.students.stats.
And you can see that the average
object in this is 232
bytes and that overall this
thing is using almost 3
gigabytes on disk.
And we may not have a computer
with 3 gigabytes of memory,
but we might have a computer
that's big
enough to hold our index.
So the next question is, well
how big is the index?
And the answer is, that
if we run the command
totalIndexSize,
db.students.totalIndexSize, we
will find out the size of
the indexes on disk.
And the answer is
that our index--
and we only have one index in
this collection if I recall--
well I'm not sure about that.
I'll check in a second.
Our indexes are 543 megabytes.
And now let's look at how many
indexes are on this thing.
Yeah there's only one index that
we added, which is this
index of student_ID.
So overall, 543 megabytes of
space spent on indexes.
And if we're curious about how
much of that is spent on the
_ID one, I guess what we can do
is just drop the index that
we created and run it together
and find out-- this is
interesting.
I don't know the answer.
So I'm just going to remove
the index on student_ID.
We drop the index, and now
you can see it's gone.
And let's get our index size.
And it dropped by not quite
about half, to 292 megabytes.
So you can see that it looks
like for every index that we
add to this collection, we'll
have to have over 200
megabytes of available memory
if we want to keep all the
indexes in memory--
or at least the ones
we're going to use.
This is important to keep in
mind when you're designing
your system.
Think about, well hmm, how large
is my collection going
to be and how large are my
indexes going to be?
It's kind of a system
administrator topic or
database administrator topic.
But it's good as a developer
to just keep it in mind and
realize that indexes are
not entirely free.
And that you're going to want
to keep them in memory and
they can get kind of large.
They are the single most
important determining factor
in terms of whether or not you
get good performance from a
query, or whether or not
those are in memory.
All right, it's time for quiz.
Is it more important that
your index or your
data fit into memory?
Check one.