When designing your indexes,
you want them to be as
selective as possible.
And this is a concept that is
really no different than the
world of relational.
But when you're choosing a
compound index, if you don't
choose something that's
selective, then there isn't a
lot of value to specifying
that field.
So here's an example.
Let's say you were doing some
logging and there were only
three different types
of log operations.
There was a save, and there
was an open, and a run--
I'm just imagining logging
operations you might see--
and a put, and a get.
And we had hundreds of millions
of these logging
operations.
And each of them has a date and
time, or say a timestamp.
So would you rather have an
index that was the timestamp
comma the opcode, where these
are the opcodes, or would it
make sense to do the opcode
comma the timestamp?
Now, the answer is that it would
make a lot more sense to
do the timestamp first.
And the reason is that if you
typically know the range of
time that you're looking for an
operation, and you specify
an opcode, well there's only
five of these opcodes.
And so by specifying
one you're only
eliminating 4/5 of the data.
There's a tremendous amount
of data that you
still need to go through.
And if you just had an index
on opcode for instance, it
wouldn't be a lot different
than doing a
full collection scan.
Whereas, if there was an index
on timestamp comma opcode, and
you did know the times when
you wanted to query the
opcode, the time interval, then
it would be pretty fast.
Because it would be a very
small percentage
of the total log.
And after that, once you narrow
it down by 99%, then
searching for the opcode would
be efficient and there
wouldn't be that
many operations
in that time interval.
This idea of trying to choose
an index with selectivity is
universally true in databases,
it's true in relational
databases, and it's
true in MongoDB.
So just keep that in mind when
you're creating your indexes,
that you'd like to have them be
very selective if you can.
, Otherwise, there's just not a
lot of value to having them.
If you just want to search on
just the opcode, well then
fine, but it's going to be
almost all the data every
single time you look at it.
All right, so time for quiz.
Given the following attributes
of automobiles--
color, weight, manufacture, and
odometer mileage, which
index is likely to be the most
selective, provided you can
provide all four attributes
on a search?
So which of these is going to
be the most selective to
narrowing down the number
of automobiles?