Now let's talk about
the profiler.
The profiler is a more
sophisticated facility.
It will write entries,
documents, to system.profile
for any query that takes longer
than some specified
period of time.
There are three levels
for the profiler.
There's level zero, level
one, and level two.
Levels zero is the default
level, and it means it is off.
Level one means, I want to
log my slow queries.
And level two means, I want
to log all my queries.
So why would you want to
log all your queries?
And the reason is because not
so much for performance
debugging, but because when
you're writing a program, it's
convenient to see all the
database traffic so that you
can figure out whether
the program is
doing what you expect.
So this is really more of a
general debugging feature than
a performance debugging
feature.
And you might want to use that
when you're debugging your own
programs, to turn the profiler
on a level two and see
everything that's happening
in the system.
But right now, we're going to
focus on this level one which
is logging the slow queries.
Let's go and start Mongo up
logging slow queries.
So we're going to run mongod
minus dbpath and, same as
before, the one I used.
And then minus profile one, log
my slow queries, anything
above two milliseconds.
So I'm going to do that.
And now, it's logging
my slow queries.
And now, I'm going to
do a slow query.
So I'm going to do that
same query again.
All right, it took a while.
It took about four seconds.
And now, I'm going to look in
db.system.profile and see what
there is to see.
And this is the query
we just did.
We can see that there's a
query to the students
collection, that
we were looking
for student_id: 10,000.
It happened here,
this time stamp.
And it scanned 10 million
documents.
That sounds slow.
It returned one document, and
took 4.2 seconds, 4,231
milliseconds.
So this is going to
be really useful.
And you can see it
actually returned
more than one document.
It returned some of the
work I did before.
This is a cap collection, which
means that there's a
fixed size collection and it
will recycle space in the
collection after
it uses it up.
So we can use this
information.
We can query on it.
So we see, for instance this
millis over 4,000.
So let me show you some of kind
of queries you can do.
So in here, I'm doing a find
in the profile collection
looking for anything with
test.foo in it in the name
space, which is the foo
collection which is another
collections I've been writing
queries to as well.
And then, sort it by the time
stamp, prettyprint it.
And you see there's nothing in
there right now from test.foo.
But if I switch that up to be
school.students collection,
I'll get the query
we just did.
We can also look for things
that are slower
than a certain duration.
Let me show you how
that works.
Here we go.
This is a query, again, of the
system.profile where we're
looking for things that have
milliseconds greater than one.
And we're going to sort by
the time stamp again and
prettyprint it.
Very convenient.
So that's how you would
use the profile
information you get.
You can turn on this profiler
from the Mongo shell.
Let me show you how
to do that.
So you can get the
profile status.
Here, let me show you that.
getProfilingLevel--
we're set to level
one right now.
Let's get the status.
And you can see it's set to one,
which is slow queries,
anything above two
milliseconds.
We can set the status
if we want.
This is how you turn
the profiler on
from the Mongo Shell.
Let's set it to level one, but
I want to only look at things
that are longer than
four milliseconds.
If I do that, oh
I meant set the
profiling level, not status.
If you set the profiling
level--
right here--
set profiling level to 1 comma
4, that means slow queries
above four milliseconds.
And now it tells me what it used
to be, just so I can do
some debugging information.
But if I do a get of the status,
I can see that it's
now set to level one and
anything above four.
If I want to turn it off
entirely, I just set it to
zero, and that should fix it up
for me. setProfilingLevel--
and if I get the profiling
status now, I
should see it's zero.
And if I get the profiling
level, which is another
command, it'll also
tell me it's zero.
So those are the commands you
might want to know which is to
get the profiling level,
that'll tell
you what it's doing.
If you want to set
the profiling
level, you can set it.
It takes two parameters.
I only gave one here because
I was turning it off.
But it takes two parameters
which is the level and then
the number of milliseconds that
I want to log beyond, any
query that exceeds that
will get logged.
OK, it is time for a quiz.
Write the query to look in the
system.profile profile
collection for all the queries
that took longer than one
second ordered by timestamp
descending.