Now before we go into too much
detail about how you can do
things in the database using
the Mongo shell, we have to
talk a little bit about how
MongoDB actually represents
data, and how you can understand
how the Mongo shell
interprets that data
when it gets it
back from the database.
As you already know,
MongoDB is a
document-oriented database.
What this actually means is
that MongoDB's fundamental
record type is a kind of nested
dictionary of key value
associations.
As a matter of programming
language convenience, we map
the documents that come out of
MongoDB to objects in the
programming language that can
represent these kinds of key
value associations.
In JavaScript, the type of
object that represents these
kinds of key value associations
is called a
JavaScript object.
So, for example, if I define the
variable "obj," O-B-J, to
be equal to a "1," b "hello," c
"apples, tomatoes," then the
value of the variable "obj"
is suitable for use
as a MongoDB document.
What I mean by that is that we
can take this JavaScript
object and put it into the
database for safekeeping.
As it happens, though JavaScript
uses a syntax
that's very similar to
the JSON Syntax--
in fact, JSON Syntax was
inspired by the syntax of
JavaScript--
MongoDB internally, doesn't use
this stringy syntax for
storing or retrieving data.
Instead, MongoDB uses a binary
representation for the data
inside of documents.
The specification for the binary
representation that
MongoDB uses is given
at BSONspec.org.
We call our binary format BSON,
which stands for Binary
JSON, and in effect, this is a
serialization format that's
designed to represent a superset
of what can be
transcribed in JSON Syntax.
The exact specification
is given here.
The basic data types that BSON
supports are, of course, a
superset of those that
JSON supports--
double precision floating point
numbers, string values,
where string means a sequence of
validly encoded UTF-8 code
units, embedded documents,
that is to say, nested
objects, embedded arrays, that
is to say, nested objects
whose keys are the integers
0, 1, 2, 3, et cetera, the
Boolean Values false and true,
and the null value.
These are the basic data
types of JSON.
But BSON goes a little bit
further by adding a binary
data type, a data type called
Object ID, which is used for
unique identification of things,
a date-time type,
which represents time since
January 1, 1970, a 32-bit
integer type and a 64-bit
integer type, and a few other
types, which are mostly only
used for internal purposes,
such as regular expressions in
the query protocol and time
stamps for replication
purposes.
These data types, which go
beyond the JSON specification,
correspond to types available
in various programming
languages or else have some sort
of special handling in
those programming languages.
Let me show you what
I mean by that.
In the shell, we use the
JavaScript language.
The JavaScript language has
support for numbers, which are
interpreted as double floats,
strings, which are interpreted
as UTF-8 strings, arrays,
objects, true, false,
null, and so on.
To represent an exact integer
value in the Mongo shell, we
provide a constructor.
"Number/Int" gives you a 32-bit
value and prints out
using the constructor syntax so
that you can cut and paste
easily without losing any
numeric precision.
"Number/Long" gets you 64-bit
integer values.
And we support at least some
arithmetic on these things, as
well, though we might not
exactly round trip without
some loss of precision.
For instance, adding two
Number/Longs appears to give
us a regular old JavaScript
number, which will be a double
precision floating point
value when it gets
back into the database.
So be careful when you use
programs in a language like
JavaScript or Perl which might
not have the expressiveness or
the type expressiveness to
faithfully represent all of
the types that MongoDB
can store.
Similarly, JavaScript's
date-time types are
represented with a JavaScript
date object, which, for
reasons having to do with
esoteric details of
JavaScript, we print
out with the
constructor we call ISO date.
This constructor always gets you
a new date object with a
particular timestamp inside
it, which is somewhat
different from what the apparent
date constructor does
in the JavaScript language.
So to construct an object in
JavaScript that contains
numbers that are fixed precision
integers or that
contain dates such as the one
that's currently on the
screen, you can use these
constructor syntax's.
In this way, the JavaScript
shell can, more or less,
faithfully handle all of the
data that comes out of the
database, and allow you to
input, more or less, all of
the data types that you're
likely to want
to store the database.
I say more or less only in
that it appears that the
arithmetic operations that are
available might not preserve
numeric type information.
In any case, the main idea is
that MongoDB actually traffics
internally in a binary
representation
which we call BSON.
The BSON representation supports
the basic data types
that MongoDB contains.
The BSON specification
incorporates all of the types
that JSON can contain, plus a
few more, and the Mongo shell,
as well as all of the drivers
that can talk to MongoDB,
support the various data types
that BSON supports in some way
or another.
OK.
Let's have a quiz.
Which of the following types
are available in BSON?
Strings, floating point numbers,
complex numbers,
arrays, objects, time stamps.