So now that we know what a
document is in MongoDB, let's
find out how to actually put
them into the database.
As we discussed, MongoDB
documents are represented in
JavaScript by JavaScript
objects.
So we can create a variable
in JavaScript--
let's call it doc--
whose value is some JavaScript
object, such as, say, name
Smith, age 30 profession
hacker.
All this does is establish a
binding between a variable in
JavaScript and a value.
To actually communicate with the
database, we're going to
have to use handle
on the database.
As it happens, the shell has a
variable called db whose value
is a handle on the
current database.
If you evaluate the variable db,
you get back the name of
the database.
Documents in the database live
inside of collections, which
are simply sets of documents
within a
particular named database.
From a programming language
perspective, in the JavaScript
shell, we present collections as
properties of the database.
So if I type in
db.people.insert, then the
shell will interpret people as
the name of the collection
inside the current database,
that is, the test database.
Insert is a method
on collections.
And it takes as an argument a
JavaScript object, such as my
variable doc.
The Insert method puts a
document into the database.
But as you see, the shell
doesn't print anything out
about success or failure.
The shell is normally very
terse by default.
There are ways of customizing
this, but we're going to stick
to the basics during
this course.
To actually see that I
accomplished something with
this insert method, I'm going to
skip ahead for a second and
show you how to query something
back in a simple fashion.
To query a collection, you
input the collection, for
example, db.people.
And then you execute find method
on that collection.
If you call find with no
arguments, you'll get back all
the documents in that
collection.
And there's my document back.
That is, I get back a document
where name is Smith, age is
30, and profession is
the string hacker.
But you see that there's a new
field called underscore id,
whose value seems to be
something called an object id,
consisting of some sequence
of somethings.
As it happens, when you insert
a document into MongoDB, the
server requires that all
documents have a unique
identifying field.
In fact, we use the underscore
id for this field.
The underscore id field
within a document is
a primary key field.
That is to say, it's required
to be present, the value of
the field is required to be
unique for that document
within the collection, and we
also go a little bit further
than some other databases do in
that we require the primary
key to be immutable.
We don't let you change the
value of the underscore id
field within the document
in the system.
You could simulate changing
the underscore id field by
removing the document and
putting another document in
with a different value for the
underscore id field, but the
same values for the other fields
say though that would
not be an atomic operation
within the database.
So the underscore id field
is the primary key.
All normal collections in
MongoDB have an underscore id
primary key requirement.
We'll talk about abnormal
collections eventually during
this course.
Now what about this object id
business, on the right hand
side of the colon?
Well, in MongoDB, we require the
underscore id to be unique
within the collection.
In order to facilitate this,
we give you a type called
object id, the construction of
which takes into account the
current time, an identifier
for the machine that's
constructing the object id, the
process id of the process
on the computer that's
constructing the object id,
and the counter global
the process of
constructing the object id.
By smooshing these pieces of
information together, we get a
value that has very high
probability of being unique,
that is to say, won't be
generated again so long as
time continues moving forward.
In this way, an object id in
MongoDB is intended to be a
global unique identifier.
In consequence, we can use an
object id as an underscore id
fairly simply without any
probability that there will be
any collisions in the underscore
id space within a
particular collection.
And so in fact if your
application does not
explicitly fill in a field
called underscore id when it's
inserting a document into the
database, an object id will be
constructed for you that will
be used as the underscore id
of your documents.
So let me show you that again.
If I put a document into the
database, such as by typing
db.people.insert and then
construct a document, and then
retrieve all the documents from
the collection by calling
find with no arguments, I'll
see that a document was
created with the field name
Jones, the field age 35, and
the field profession baker,
and an underscore id
value was filled in.
You could use any type of value
that you want for the
underscore id.
You could use numbers.
You could use strings.
But if you don't fill one in
yourself, you get an object
id, which is extremely
likely to be unique.
OK, let's have a quiz.
Insert documents into a
collection called fruit, with
the attributes name having a
value apple, color having the
value red, and shape having
a value round.
Assume that you're already in
the database that you want to
create the fruit collection in.