OK, let's go a little bit
further into the query
facilities.
We've already seen how to query
for specific values of
given fields, such as student
19 and type essay, but you
need to do a little bit more in
order to construct the most
practical applications.
What we've done so far we
typically call query by
example queries, where you give
an example of the fields
that you want to see
in the documents
that you want to retrieve.
For instance, student
19 and type essay.
But many kinds of queries need
to go a little bit further
than constant values.
For example, if I wanted to
get all queries where the
score was greater than, say, 95,
I can do so in MongoDB by
means of query operators.
To perform a query, again, we
start with the same kind of
syntax that we've used before.
The database handle dot
the collection name
dot the find method.
And the first argument
to find, again,
is the where clause.
In this case, if I want to give
an inequality comparison
for a particular field, such
as score, I can do so by
specifying the field name, and
its corresponding value in
this first argument to find will
be a sub document having
as its corresponding
field an operator.
In this case dollar, gt, and
some argument to the operator.
Closing off the document and
going back to re-read this,
what this says is that
the score should be
greater than 95.
This is our first departure from
query by a constant value
on a field such as score.
In this case, we're doing an
inequality comparison for the
field score.
And we get back a number of
documents, and it looks on the
right hand side as if
these values are all
greater than 95.
I see a 96, a 98, a 97, another
97, 99, and so forth.
Again, the query looks like
what's at the bottom of my
terminal window.
The field name, such as score,
and then a corresponding
value, which is an embedded
document having an operator,
in this case dollar
gt, and 95.
I can go further and add another
field to the query,
for example, score 95 and type
essay, in which case I will
only get results where the type
is essay and the score is
greater than 95.
Again, to show that at
the bottom of my
terminal, there it is.
Now, you can put multiple
constraints on the same field.
For example, if I want scores
that are greater than 95 and
less than or equal to 98.
I specify it as it is at
the bottom my screen.
That is, score has as its
corresponding value inside of
this query document, a nested
document with the fields
dollar gt and dollar lte
with the respective
values 95 and 98.
And the meaning of this peculiar
looking construct is
that the score should be
strictly greater than 95, and
less than or equal to 98.
And additionally, the type
should be essay.
And it looks good.
The results on the screen, at
least, suggest that I'm seeing
results from 96 up to 98.
This is our first example of a
query operator in the MongoDB
query language.
Well, I suppose the first
two examples, dollar
gt and dollar lte.
Unsurprisingly, we have dollar
gte operator, which means
greater than or equal, and a
dollar lt operator, which
means strictly less than.
And again, just as a reminder,
the two fields score and type
occurring at the top level of
this query document have the
meaning that both the score must
match on its criteria,
and the type must match
on its criteria.
So this is equivalent to the
logical end of score being in
the range up from 95 up to
but not including 98.
And the type must be
equal to essay.
And it looks good.
There are a number of more query
operators in the MongoDB
query language, some of which
we'll be visiting as we go.
OK, let's have a quiz.
Which of these finds documents
with a score
between 50 and 60 inclusive?