Let's learn how to put multiple
queries together with
a logical connective.
We've already seen how you can
perform queries based on
numeric equality and numeric
inequality, string equality,
string inequality, regular
expressions over strings, and
comparisons of whether a field
has a particular type, and
whether a field exists.
Sometimes you want a union
of these sorts
of complicated queries.
That is, any document that
matches some criteria, or some
other criteria.
And indeed, MongoDB offers you
an operator to do this.
For example, in the people
collection, if you wanted to
find all of those people whose
names ended with an e, or who
had an age, you can do so using
the dollar or operator.
What that looks like is
something like this.
The dollar or operator, unlike
the rest of the query
operators that we've seen so
far, is a prefix operator.
It comes before the sub-queries
that it's going to
connect together.
It takes as a kind of operand,
an array whose elements are
themselves queries that you
could give separately, and it
computes the set of all those
documents that match any of
the queries in the array.
So for example, what's on the
screen shows that the name
should match the regular
expression ends with e, and
the age should exist.
So either of those criteria
must hold in order for a
document to be returned.
And so we see the result has the
documents where the ages
is 30 or 35, that's
Smith and Jones.
And it has those documents whose
names end with e, such
as Alice, Charlie, and Dave.
As you can see, our query
documents get somewhat
complicated here.
There's a bit of closed
bracketing messiness on the
right hand side of the screen.
Some people find this stuff a
little bit difficult to adjust
to, but it only takes, in my
experience, a few hours, or
perhaps a couple of days to
become familiar with what you
need to key in here.
Remember that the goal is to
close off JSON objects in a
syntactically correct manner.
The shell, in fact, can
help you with this.
You may or may not have noticed,
but as the cursor
moves around, when the cursor
is over a grouping symbol,
such as a parenthesis, or a
brace or a bracket, the
corresponding grouping symbol
is highlighted in a
kind of dark blue.
At the moment, my cursor is over
the left parenthesis at
the right hand side of this
JavaScript line, and the
corresponding open parenthesis
on the left
hand side is in blue.
As I continue to move backwards,
further and further
grouping symbols inside the
JavaScript expression are
being highlighted in blue.
This can be somewhat useful to
help you check some whether
you've gotten the
matching right.
As a side detail, if you get
the matching wrong, for
example, if I take out, say
the square bracket that's
supposed to close off the array
that goes along with the
or, JavaScript will print
out dot, dot, dot.
This dot, dot, dot means that
its input was incomplete.
As it happens, there's no way
that I can correctly complete
this expression, because I've
left out a grouping symbol
that was very deep inside
the document that I
was trying to construct.
In order to exit from
JavaScript's attempts to parse
this fragment, I can hit enter
twice, in which case the
prompt will return.
At that point, I could try to
re-key the query, or whatever
it was that I was not able
to complete correctly.
So again, to recap, the dollar
or operator takes an array,
and the array contains
documents.
Each document is treated
as a separate query.
And the dollar or operator
matches is any document that
matches any of those queries
inside the array.
And so it in effect computes
the union of these queries.
If you've got all that,
let's have a quiz.
How would you write a query to
find all documents in the
scores collection, where the
score field is less than 50,
or greater than 90?