OK.
Now that we've learned about
arrays, let's look at some
other ways that queries
can get inside of
documents in MongoDB.
So far, all of our example
documents have had strings and
numbers, or arrays, for the
values of embedded fields.
However, documents can nest.
Let's create an example document
and look at that.
Here, I've just inserted a
document with the name field
"richard," that's me, and an
email field whose value is a
nested document, having two
fields within it, work and
personal, for a couple
of email addresses.
And there's the example document
printed out a little
bit more cleanly.
Now, when you have a nested
document, there are a couple
of things you might want to try
to do to find the document
based on the embedded content.
One possibility would be to
query for the exact match on
the email field.
If I key in db.users.find and
give it as an argument, a
document with the top-level
field email whose value is an
embedded document with fields
work, richard@10gen.com, and
personal, kreuter@example.com,
I will indeed find the
document that I inserted.
Note that it's important that
the order of the fields in the
embedded document
be preserved.
If I reverse them, the database
will not find the
document that I'm asking for.
In effect, the stuff that's on
the right-hand side of the
colon, if it does not contain
a $1 operator, a query
operator in the find language,
compares exactly byte by byte
the contents of the
two documents.
If the field orders differ, then
the representations of
these documents in BSON will
be different, and so the
database will not consider the
embedded values to be equal.
Therefore, it's important to
be consistent when you're
storing data.
However, the queries that I
have above, which we call
query by example, are
somewhat limited.
Perhaps I only know the work
address of the user and not
the personal address.
How could I query for that?
Note that the following
will not work.
What I have now at the bottom
of my terminal window is a
query that will match only a
document whose email field is
exactly the document work
colon richard@10gen.com,
nothing more, nothing less.
And indeed, the database returns
no results when I
perform that query.
However, MongoDB has a special
syntax that allows you to
reach inside the email field for
a specific embedded field,
regardless of what other fields
might exist around the
embedded field that
I'm looking for.
And we call this dot notation.
Let me show you what
that looks like.
If you submit a query and
specify for a field name, a
dotted field, such as
email.work, then the query
execution will take a look
at documents in the users
collection looking for the email
field and then recurse
into that email field looking
at the contents of the
embedded document for any
field called work.
If that embedded field called
work matches the specified
string, then the document
matches.
And it doesn't matter whether
the email field at the top
level has any other embedded
fields, such as
the personal field.
And indeed, there's
my document.
So the purpose of dot notation
is to allow you to reach
inside of nested documents,
looking for a specific
embedded piece of information
without any knowledge of any
surrounding context.
It's a little bit like a fixed
depth path expression into a
BSON document.
OK, let's have a quiz.
Suppose you had a simple
e-commerce product catalog
with a collection called catalog
whose documents look
sort of like this.
They have a product field, and
a price field, and a reviews
field, whose corresponding
value is an array with
embedded documents as the
elements of the array, and the
embedded documents inside the
array each have a user, a
comment, and a rating.
How would you write a query that
finds all products in the
catalog collection that cost
more than $10,000 and have a
rating of five or better?
So the price should be greater
than $10,000, and there should
be at least one rating
of five or greater.