Moving along to some more
update operators.
Occasionally, you want to
be able to remove a
field from a document.
For example, in my People
collection, if I want to
remove Jones's profession,
I can.
One way to do it, of course,
would be to do a wholesale
replacement specifying all
of the fields except for
profession, but this is somewhat
cumbersome to do if I
happen not to know what
fields exist in
that document in advance.
And so we have another operator
analogous to dollar
set, and that operator is
called dollar unset.
This will remove the field and
its value from the document
that matches the specified
criteria, and so the
profession is gone.
This is occasionally useful, for
example, to perform schema
change manipulations when the
application requirements
change, or occasionally to
model certain kinds of
transformations of your data.
For instance, rather than
storing a null value if a
piece of information is not
present, you can add and
remove fields to a document
as the information becomes
present and relevant, or becomes
irrelevant and no
longer necessary.
This is one aspect of MongoDB's
schema-less nature.
All right, let's have a quiz.
Write an update query that will
unset the Interests key
in the following document in the
collection called Users.
So the document has username
Jimmy, favorite color blue,
interests the array, debating
and politics.