The resulting document should
look something like this.
The underscore ID is
Mike, of course.
And the interests should be
botany, then skydiving, then
skydiving again, then skiing.
The first push changes
the array to
chess, botany, skydiving.
Then the pop removes the
leftmost element of the array
because the argument to
the pop is negative.
This leaves us with just
botany and skydiving.
Then we had to set would add
skydiving to the array if
skydiving were not
already there.
But skydiving is already present
because of the results
of the first update.
And so that add to
set does nothing.
Finally, the push all appends to
the array on the right-hand
side skydiving and skiing,
leaving us two duplicates of
skydiving and this the
resulting answer.
It's unusual to mix add to set
and push operations in the
same document.
Typically, if you're using add
to set you want to treat the
array as a set which should not
contain duplicates of the
same value.
The push operator simply treats
the array as regular
old sequence of values.