All right.
This is Andrew Erlichson again.
You've just gone through the
CRUD operations-- Creating,
Reading, Updating and Deleting
data-- using the Mongo shell.
And now I'm going to take you
through those same operations,
but this time using PyMongo.
And after that, I'll get you
ready for this week's homework
by teaching you a little bit
more about the blog project
that we're going to be
building in this course.
But first, let's review.
You have MongoD-- and
MongoD, of course,
is the server that runs
the database itself--
and you were working
in the Mongo shell
in the last few lessons.
The Mongo shell talks using
BSON to MongoD to access data,
to insert data, to
update data, et cetera.
Now you're going to learn
about doing it from PyMongo.
You're going to write your
application code in Python,
and this Python is going
to talk to the database
through PyMongo, which is
a Python library, to allow
you to access the database.
And PyMongo talks to the
database server using
BSON using the wire protocol.
So let's get started.
Now if you've been following
these lesson sequentially,
you probably already have this
grade data in your database.
But I don't have
it on my computer,
so I'm going to put
it back on there.
And to do that, I
have this program
create student
collection data.js.
This is JavaScript
that I'm going
to import into the Mongo shell.
I'm going to redirect
it into the Mongo shell.
And this is a very
simple program,
it just uses school database.
It drops the scores collection.
And then for the type of
exam, homework and quiz,
and for 100 students,
it puts in one document
per student for each type.
So for a student, there'll
be an exam, a homework,
and a quiz with a score
that's been randomized--
it's wrapping here, but this
is just a random number.
And it inserts it
into the database.
So let's run that.
I'm going to run that by
calling Mongo and redirecting
the input from create
student collection.js.
This is on a Unix box, so
if you're familiar with Unix
you know how that works.
So if I do that, it
runs successfully.
All right.
And if I run Mongo and
use the school database
and then look in the
scores collection,
I see a bunch of data,
and each of the documents
has a student ID, a type
of either homework or exam
or quiz, and a score.
I'll print one out so
it will print it pretty.
And you can see
what they look like.
They look like this.
All right.
So now we want to retrieve
some of this data from Python.
So we've got a
program to do that,
and I'm going to walk you
through it line-by-line.
This program is
called using_find.py,
and I'll give you these programs
so that you can download them
each week from the lesson
if you'd like to run them
yourself.
Now this program starts
right at the top.
This is a Python program, and
this is running inside Emacs,
but you can use whatever editor
you want to edit your stuff.
So I import PyMongo,
and then I import sys.
I need both of these libraries.
This is for the
exception handling,
and PyMongo is so that I
can attach the database.
Then I get a connection to the
database by calling MongoClient
and assign it to the
connection variable.
My connection string
is mongodb://localhost,
because the database is
running on my local host.
In another terminal window,
I've started MongoD running.
And now I need to connect
to the scores collection.
So to do that, first I get
a connection to the school
database-- so db equals
connection.school--
and then I get a connection
to the scores database,
and scores equals db.scores.
Now we're going to look
at both find and find one.
First let's look at find
one, take you through there.
So looking at the find
one function, which
I've written here,
you can see what
it does is it prints that
it's reporting for duty.
Then it sets up a query
as a Python dictionary.
It says it's looking
for the document which
has a student ID of 10.
Now a thing to note here
is that Python dictionaries
require you to quote the key.
This is not true
in JavaScript, we
wouldn't have had to quote this.
But we do have to quote it here.
After that, we put the
find_one in a try except block.
And since it's a find_one, it's
not going to return a cursor,
it's going to return
a single document.
So I call find_one on the scores
collection-- scores.findone--
find_one-- with the query.
Now in the shell, it was
find_one with a capital
O. It was camel cased.
Here, it's find_one.
Now each of the
drivers names things
in a way that are idiomatic
for the language itself.
And in Python, it's
much more typical to use
underscores for function names.
So that's why it's named
this way inside Python.
You're going to notice
these types of differences
throughout the drivers.
In addition, the drivers now
implement a new specification
called the CRUD spec,
which slightly changes
the way you access
data inside MongoDB
relative to what you'll
see in the shell.
And this Python driver is
one of the first drivers
to conform to the CRUD spec.
This is the beta
version of the driver
that, if you started it on
the first day of class--
if you started a week
later or if you're
a few weeks into the
class, it's the release
version of a driver.
So this is the
latest and greatest
interface to the
database, so you're
seeing the most modern way of
accessing data within MongoDB.
So anyway, getting
back to the program,
we assign the result to
find one to a document,
and then we print it out.
Pretty simple.
And in order to make sure
that we call find_one,
I need to call-- this is
my main loop, essentially,
outside of any function
inside Python--
I call the find_one function,
which will invoke find_one.
All right.
So let's now go into
the regular Unix shell
and invoke Python
interpreter on this program.
So we did that.
What happened is
it printed exactly
as we expected-- find_one
reporting for duty--
and then it printed
the document.
Now you'll remember
that inside Python,
all we did is say print doc,
and then by some miracle
we got something that
is essentially readable.
One of the nice
things about Python
is it does a pretty good
job printing complex objects
to the screen.
So you can see here that
it prints one document.
We asked for the one where
the student ID was 10,
and we got that.
Student ID 10, it
has an underscore ID
which is an object ID, and
then the type of this record
was exam.
That was arbitrary,
since we didn't actually
specify that inside the
query which record we were
going to get for the student.
So we could have gotten a quiz,
we could have gotten an exam,
but we actually got an exam.
And then the score itself.
That's it.
That's all you need
to do to pull data out
of MongoDB using Python.
It's very easy.
Now you'll notice that
the student ID is actually
a floating point number.
That student ID is stored in
the database as a floating point
number because, when we created
this data using the JavaScript
shell, we didn't do
anything special,
and the only number type
built into JavaScript
is a floating point type.
MongoDB does support
integers directly,
and we could have inserted
an integer in there,
but that's not what we did in
that small JavaScript program
where I loaded the data.
Now let's see how we would
call find, not find one,
if we wanted to get a
whole bunch of documents.
To do that, we're going to look
at this program right here.
This is the find.
I also have a function
that calls find right here.
It's in the same file, so it has
access to the same variables.
And find is going to do
something slightly different.
It's going to do a query
where type is exam,
and it's going to call
find on that query-- again,
the query is in the form
of a Python dictionary--
and you're going to get
a cursor back this time,
not a document, because you
have multiple things returned.
And if it raises an exception,
that will happen over here.
Now providing you
don't get an exception,
we want to print
out these documents.
And so I'm just going to
iterate through the documents
in the cursor.
I'm going to say for doc in
cursor, in Python, print doc.
And this stuff
about sanity is just
limiting the number of things it
prints to 10 and then breaking.
So I'm just limiting how
much I print of the screen.
And to make sure that I
run find versus find one,
I have to change my
program to call find.
So I will do that.
And now I'm going to go to
the terminal and run it.
And when I do that, I get a
whole bunch of data this time,
all of it with
type equal to exam.
So this is pretty
much what we'd expect.
All right.
It is now time for a quiz.
This is a program very
similar to the one
that you saw in this lesson.
In this program, you can
see that we once again
connect to the school's database
and the scores collection.
And we try to pull data
out of the database,
except we've removed one
line, which is this xxxxx.
And what we'd like you to do
is write the one line of Python
that would find data,
a single document,
and put it into the
variable document
so that it can be printed out.
So write that line here,
and that's the answer.