All right, and the answer
is the third one is correct.
The third one, you
call students.find.
Then, you specify 'student_id':1
and you suppress the _id.
So you give it a 0
value in the document.
So why are the
other one's wrong?
Well, the first one
is wrong because it
doesn't have this projection
as a second parameter.
It actually has it as
the first parameter
so it's going to be
interpreted as a query.
This one is wrong
for similar reasons.
It's the first parameter,
not the second parameter.
It's also forgets
to suppress _id'0.
The third one was right.
The fourth one is wrong only
because these literals are not
quoted as they need
to be inside Python.
OK.