OK, and the answer is that the
second one is correct.
The one that specifies this
type quiz and score dollar
greater than 20 and dollar
less than 90.
You notice that they're
quoted there.
The first one is not correct,
because it doesn't specify
that the type is quiz.
The third one is actually kind
of backwards, but if you're
just getting started
with Mongo, it's an
easy mistake to make.
Instead of having the key first
then a document this
specifies the criteria for the
number, it actually starts
with dollar greater than
or dollar less than.
But this is not correct.
And the last one would be
correct if not for the fact
that the quotes were left off
those two literals, which
won't work inside Python and
PyMongo, but would inside the
Mongo shell.