Now that we know how
to use find and
find one inside Pymongo.
Let's talk about how
we do projections.
Projections would let us select
out particular fields
to pull during the query and
not pull the rest of them.
So let's go back to that query
we had before where we asked
for everything with 'type'
'exam' out of the scores
collection that we were using.
And this time let's also create
a secondary dictionary,
which I call selector, where
we would like to retrieve a
student ID and not show the.
underscore id field.
So we're suppressing and
retrieving specifically
student underscore id.
And again, you'll notice these
quotes around these literals.
And then right here we're
calling in Pymongo scores,
which is the handle to the
scores collection, dot find,
and then the query, and then
what I call the selector.
And then we iterate through
and print out the results.
So what happens when
we do that?
Let's see.
Let's go through and run it.
And as you can see, it
retrieves the student
underscore id only, and
suppresses the underscore id
field, which is exactly
what we want.
All right, time for a quiz.
Which of the following
statements--
these are Python statements--
could work using Pymongo
depending on variable names,
because the variable names
have to be legal.
But let's presume they are.
I have to select out just the
student ID from the scores
collection using a find command,
so very similar to
what we just went over.
Which of these is correct?