And the answer is that it would
return the document with
id equals 2.
So how would you reason
that out?
Remember, the sort
happens first.
So the first thing it's going
to do is sort them in value
descending, which means that
it's going to sort them with
this document first, then this,
then this, then this.
And then after it does
that it's going to
skip three of them.
So remember, it was this one,
then this one, then this one.
So if it skips three of them,
it's going to skip these.
It's going to skip 10, 20, and
7, after it sorts, leaving the
one with value 5, which
is id equals 2.
And then it's just going to show
1, which is all that's
left anyway.
And so as a result, the answer
is that it's going to return
the document with id equals 2.
Because the sort always
happens before the
limit and the skip.