There's one or two more points
I want to make about sorting
within Pymongo.
The first is that the reason why
the syntax varies between
the Mongo shell and Python, the
reason why you need to use
these tuples in this array is
that dictionaries inside
Python are not ordered.
And since the order matters
when sorting, if we simply
give a dictionary of these
items, then when they were
sent over all the way to MongoD
the order wouldn't
necessarily be retained.
Remember that JSON does retain
the order of the key value
pairs, but Python in its
dictionaries does not.
The second thing is that if
you have a single sort
element, this line right here
that's commented out, that
we're only sorting on one key.
You can see there, we simply
give the key and then comma
and Pymongo dot ascending or
Pymongo do descending, all
caps on the ascending or
descending, that's how we
would sort if we had a single
key we wanted to sort on.
But if we want to sort on two
keys, syntax changes a bit.
In that case, we're giving an
array with these tuples that
are then items in the array.
So you can see that it's a
different syntax for using a
single key than it is for
using multiple keys.
And of course if you do want to
use one key, you could also
use this syntax.
You could use an array with
a single tuple and
you would be fine.
Anyway, I just wanted to make
those two points about the way
sorting is implemented inside
Pymongo and how it's different
from the mongo shell and also
why different, and then that
they implement the two different
syntaxes for having
a single key versus
multiple keys.