Now that we know how to insert
one document using PyMongo,
let's show how to
insert many documents.
So you insert many
documents at once
by using the insert_many
command from PyMongo,
and it takes two arguments.
The first argument is a list
of documents to be inserted.
And the second argument
is an ordered flag,
and the ordered flag tells
database whether or not
you require the documents
to be inserted in order.
So let's see how this
affects what happens.
Especially when an
error occurs when
you're inserting documents.
So here's a program-- very
similar to the program
we looked at before.
We're just going to
insert two documents-- one
for Andrew, one for Richard.
My underscore ID is
specified, Richard's is not.
Which means that the database
driver PyMongo will create
unique underscore ID on insert.
We create a Python list
with Andrew, Richard,
and then we call insert_many.
And then we specify
the list and we specify
that the ordering is true.
Now, this program has a little
bit of scaffolding around it--
not very much.
Which is that it
prints the people
in the collection and
the people collection,
then it does the
insert_many-- calling
my insert_many function.
And then it retrieves the people
out of the collection again.
Print_people just gets the
connection to the database
and does a find, and
shows every document
in the people collection.
All right, let's run this thing.
I've cleared the
people collection
in the school database
so there's nothing in it.
And now we're going to
invoke the Python interpreter
on the using
insert_many program.
And if I do that
before the insert_many,
there's nothing in the
collection as we expect.
And after, these two documents--
one for me and one for Richard.
And I projected
out only the name
so I didn't show the
other information
from these documents.
Now what if I run it again?
Well if I run it again,
this time I get an error.
And I expect that I would get an
error because we know that you
can't insert me twice because
we specified the underscore ID
and there's a conflict.
But because we said
ordered equals true,
and because my document was
inserted first in the list
if you recall, you'll notice
that the document after that
didn't get inserted and
that we still have only two
documents in the collection.
I can run over and over
again and I'm never
going to have more than two
documents in the collection
when I'm done.
And again that's
because in the program,
documents are inserted
"andrew,richard"--
that's the ordering.
Since the ordering
has to be maintained,
and since my insert's
going to cause an error,
the second insert or a
third insert of Richard
isn't going to occur.
Now what if we changed
this ordering to be false
and then we try to run it?
Then what happens?
So now we're no longer
requiring ordering.
We do that and we run it.
Now, we're still getting an
error on the insert of Andrew,
but because the database is
not guaranteeing ordering,
the insert Richard
happens anyway.
So if we run it over
and over, now there's
still only one Andrew, but lots
of Richard's in the collection.
And the order parameter
determines whether or not
the database will
continue to pass an error,
and in particular
without guarantees
to insert a document
in order, which would
stop the inserts on an error.
All right, and it
also turns out--
in case you're wondering-- that
the ordering parameter defaults
to true.
And if you leave it
out, the database
will automatically
insert things in order
for the insert_many command.
Now it's time for a quiz.
Here's a program that
is similar to the one
that we just showed you.
And in this program, we
have an insert_many function
and we have a bunch of documents
that we're going to insert.
And it's going to try to
insert these documents using
insert_many(docs).
Now based on what you've
learned in this lesson,
what are we going to
see in this collection
after this insert_many runs?
And here are the four choices.
Check which one is correct.