Now that we know how
to insert some data,
we need to figure out how
we can update it inside
of the database.
There are two different
function calls inside PyMongo
that you're going
to use to do this.
One is update_one, and
the other is update_many.
There's another call
I'm going to talk
about in another
lesson, called replace.
But for now, let's
talk about updating,
which updates a document
in place in the database.
There are two
different parameters
that you're going to
need to remember to use.
One is the filter,
which filters out which
documents you want to update.
The other is an
update statement.
And the update statement has
to have some sort of operator,
a dollar operator, such as $set,
that tells the database how you
want to manipulate the
document, and what field you
want to change.
As a reminder,
both of these calls
map to the same underlying call
inside of the database, which
is the update command.
And if you remember,
inside the Mongo shell,
there isn't an update_one
and an update_many,
there's just an update command.
And I'm going to show you how
we can understand this better
by showing you some of
the PyMongo source code,
at the end of this lesson.
All right.
So now that we have update_one
and update_many, let's
look at those in
a small program.
We're going to return now
to the score collection
that we used in some of
the earlier lessons, which
is in the school database.
And if you remember,
there's a bunch
of documents in
this collection that
look like this, with a
student ID, a type-- like exam
or homework-- and a score.
And I just showed one
of these documents,
but there's a bunch of these
documents in the collection.
So now we're going to
add a reviewer to that.
Let's look at this
program, which
is going to update a single
document inside the scores
collection.
Now there's a function here, add
review date using update_one,
which is going to
take a student ID,
and then it's going to retrieve
the document for that student
ID of type homework only
from the scores collection
right here.
And then after it
does that, it's
going to retrieve
the underscore ID.
And it's going to do this to
make sure that this update hits
exactly one document.
We know that underscore ID is
unique within the collection,
so we know that if we update
one with an underscore ID set,
that we're always going
to get one document.
And we're going to set it equal
to the record ID that came out
of the record we just found.
And then after that,
we're going to update it
in the following way.
We're going to set--
$set-- the review date
to the current date time.
Now you'll notice here
that this is a document,
and that dollar set
is the operator.
And then the value for this
$set is the review date,
and what you want it to be.
So essentially the final
state of that key value pair.
And then it turns
out that update_one
returns a number of matched,
so we can print it out,
result.matchcount.
And you can see that if you look
in the PyMongo documentation.
Then, we're just going to
find the document that we just
updated, and we're going
to print it out again,
just so that we know that
we updated it properly.
So let's run that
and see what happens.
Let's make sure we're calling
the right function here.
Add review date
using update one.
There's actually two
functions in this file,
but we're only going to look
at one of them right now.
And now we're going to run
[? it to ?] a terminal python
using_update.
All right.
So what happens?
Well, it gets the
document here--
this is the document
that it pulls out--
and you can see that
it has a student ID 1,
which is what we specified, and
there's no review date on it.
And then after
the update one, it
has a review date right here.
So that worked properly,
no problem there.
Now let's update a
bunch of documents.
To do that, we're going to
change this program slightly.
Instead of calling this
function right here,
which is the add review
date using update_one,
we're going to use this one
right here, which adds review
date for all of the documents.
And it does this
using update_many.
The filter is
empty, so it's going
to hit every single document.
It's going to print out
the number it matched,
and it's not going to print
out the final documents
in this case, because
there's a lot of them.
So let's change the function.
OK.
Now let's go and watch it work.
There we go.
It updated using update_one
and set, and in this case
it matched 300 documents.
And if we go inside
the Mongo shell
and we find some documents,
we should see that they all
have review dates, and they do.
So it updated all the documents.
As I said to you before,
update_one and update both use
the same underlying
command at the database.
How would you know that?
Well, you couldn't look inside
the PyMongo documentation
to find that out, because
that wouldn't tell you.
But if you were curious
about how it worked,
you could go into the actual
source code for PyMongo.
I'm going to show you how to
navigate that real quickly.
Right here, I've gone to GitHub
at www.github.com/mongodb.
And I'm just going
to type Python
into the query to find
the Python driver project.
There it is.
I'm going to enter it.
So I want to find the 3.0
branch, because, in this case,
we're not on master yet.
We're using this beta version.
And if I go in here
and I look at PyMongo
and I look at everything
in the collection class--
and we know all
of these functions
were all in the
collection class,
so I'm just going
to look in there--
and now I'm just going
to search for update_one.
All right.
There's update_one right here.
Update_one is a function that
takes-- this self pointer is
just the way object-oriented
programming works in Python,
you can ignore that--
the filter, which
was the query, and
the update operator,
and an upsert parameter,
which we haven't talked about.
And we can see that update_one
is going to make a call to this
_update function right here,
with filter update, upsert,
and then false.
And if we look at
update_many, right here,
we can see that it also
makes a call to _update.
The only difference is there's
one more parameter tacked on,
which is true, and
that defaults to false.
That parameter, which is
similar to the one you saw
on the shell, controls whether
the _update function will
update many documents
or just one document.
And you can see this
is kind of complicated.
I mean, compared to having
a nice simple function,
update_one or
update_many, you'd have
to understand the way
this parameter works
to know whether or not
your update's going
to update one or many.
And again, this is the
way the shell works
and the way the
drivers used to work.
But now, we've deprecated
those functions,
and we recommend you use
update_one and update_many.
All right.
Let's have a quiz.
In the following
code fragment, what
is the Python expression
in place of xxxx
to set a new key examiner to be
Jones using the set operator?
This is again the
same scores collection
that we've been using before.
So you can see there's
an xxx missing here.
We're calling
update_one, and you
have to figure out what
goes in right there.
And you should type
it there below.