OK, here are the answers.
The first two are false.
It's not true that
replace_one and update_one all
move the same amount of data
across the wire to the server.
[? But is ?] in
fact, update_one is
going to send just a small
$set operator or unset operator
or an increment operator.
And it's not going to
send the entire document.
Replace_one is going to
send the entire document,
so this one's not true.
For atomically updating
or incrementing something
in the document,
replace_one is not
a great choice, because of
the window of vulnerability
that exists when you
pull a document out
and you manipulate it and
before you push it back.
You'd probably want to use
an update in that case.
The next two are true.
Replace_one, update_one,
and update_many all
use the server's update
command behind the scenes.
And I showed you that inside
the PyMongo implementation.
And the final one turns out
to be true, but it's tricky.
And actually, it points out the
way the original update command
was implemented, which is
that if there's a $operator,
the underlying update
command of the server
knows that it's an update
versus a replacement.
And it turns out that if you
use update_one or update_many,
you have to specify a $operator.
You must specify
it because that's
the way those commands work.
If you use replace_one, you're
giving it an entire document,
and you can't have any sort of
$set operator in the document
you're going to
use to replace it.
Because that wouldn't
make any sense.
It's supposed to be a
literal document that's
going to get replaced
inside the database.
All right, that's about it.