Now I want to talk to
you about replace one.
Replace one is a
lot like update one.
The difference is it does
a wholesale replacement
of a document.
Let's say you have a
document on the server,
and it has these three key
value pairs-- ID 1, a 2, b 3--
and you want to update
the entire document.
What you can do is
you can bring it
into a variable--
let's say in Python,
you could bring it
to the variable doc--
and then you can
make changes to it.
You could say doc a equals 5.
And that would change the
key value pair for the a key
to be five.
And then you could save it
back to the server using
replace one.
Now unlike the update
command, you're
not changing a small
part of the document
when you actually send
the command to the server.
You're sending an entirely
new document to the server.
Because if you load
this document variable,
let's say by doing a
find one from the server,
if you load this
up using find one
and then you work locally
in your Python program,
when you do replace
one, you're going
to send the entire
document back.
And that differs
from, let's say,
using an update with
a dollar set operator,
where you're only sending a
command through the server
to change one small part.
Now let's go through a program
and look at an example.
Here's a program that's going
to work on the same grade data
that we've been looking
at in previous lessons.
Now the first thing we want
to do in this program--
we want to add a review
date to a particular record,
but before we do that, we
want to remove all the review
dates from all the records.
So we're going to do that
using this function I wrote
called remove all review dates.
And what that does
is it actually
removes the review date
for every record using
an update many.
Now this is a lesson
on replace one,
but it's still interesting
to see a way that we
can do that using update
many before we go in
and use replace one.
So if we wanted to
remove the review date
key from every
single record, then
we can do it by saying review
date, if it exists true,
then unset it review date one.
So this is, right here,
this is our filter.
We're saying look for things
where review date exists
as a key in the document and,
if it exists, unset review date.
And that just means review
date is one that's unset.
It tells you how many
documents it matched.
Result.match_count.
Now if we do that, then
all the review dates
would be missing
when we're done.
Or I should say,
they'll be removed.
Now once we've removed
all the review dates,
let's say we wanted to add one
review date using replace one.
How would we do that?
Well, here's a
function that does it.
I call this function add
review date using replace one.
It takes a student ID, it
looks at the school database
and the scores
collection, once again.
And then, it calls find
one to find the document.
Now it does this
because-- this is
a typical way you
might use replace one
inside your program, which
is that you call find one,
you find the record
for the student ID
that was sent into this
function of type homework,
and you put that
into a variable.
You put it into
the variable score.
Then we print it out, just
so that we know what's there.
And now, we set a new key.
We set review date equal
to datetime.utcnow.
Now at this point,
we have a document
in the Python interpreter
that looks exactly
like the one on the
server except it
has a review date set.
Now we want to update that
document using replace one.
Completely change it.
So how do we do it?
Well, we're going
to call replace one.
We need to describe what
record we want to replace,
what document we
want to replace.
And I'm pulling the underscore
ID out of the document
I took from the server.
That way I'm guaranteed
to match properly,
because the underscore
IDs are immutable.
So matter what criteria you used
when you pulled it out, then
underscore ID couldn't change.
And then you passed
the document,
which has now been changed and
amended to have this review
date, into replace one.
And that will replace
a single document--
right here-- with the
document that we've modified
and mangled up here.
Now just to see
what happened, we're
going to another
find one, and we're
going to print
out what we get it
right here so that we can
see what the document looks
like after we're done.
Let's see it run.
And this program is called
using_replace_one.py.
So Python, using_replace_one.py.
All right, we've run it.
First it removes all
the review date data.
It remove review date
from all the records.
It says it found 300
documents and it removed it
from every one.
And then it pulls out that the
student with student ID one--
and you can see that it
has no review date on it--
and then after it
does replace one,
you can see it
has a review date.
And that's it.
The way it works.
Now there's one
additional point I
want to make about
replace one, which
is that when you use it in
the way we just described,
it isn't atomic.
We pulled a document
out, we made a change,
and then we replaced
the entire document.
So there could have been
an intervening change,
because there's no
transactions in MongoDB.
So if you know that you
wanted to, for instance,
increment something,
it might be better
to use an update
statement where you
can use a dollar set operator
and know that there's
been no intervening change.
Because there's actually
a window of vulnerability
in this code, and the
window of vulnerability
is that between the time
you found this record
and pulled out and the time
you called replace one,
any intervening changes to
the database of this document
are going to be lost, because
you're going to squash them
when you do the replace one.
Now the last point I want
to make is that replace one
uses the update server command
just like update one and update
many.
I'm going to show you the code.
This is from GitHub,
from the PyMongo driver.
This is the 3.0 beta.
It should be released
by the time a lot of you
see the course, and it
won't be in beta anymore.
So here's our replace one code.
The replace one code, if
you look at it, at the end,
what does it do?
It calls underscore update,
which is a private operator,
to update the document.
And this is exactly the
same underscore update
that is called when
you call update one.
You can see underscore
update also called
when you update one,
and also is called
when you call update many.
So both the replace
one and the update
many call, but they all
use the update command
for the server.
And the way that works is
very similar to the way
you saw in the shell, although
the shell command doesn't
necessarily have to be exactly
the same, because the shell
command is separately
implemented.
And then also calls the
update command on the server.
All right, now it's
time for a quiz.
And this sort of brings
together some knowledge
you've gotten from
the last few lessons.
Which of the following
statements about updating data
for PyMongo are true.
Check all that apply.
And you can see here
are the statements.
The first one, I'll
read them to you,
is whether you use update
one or replace one,
the same amount of data is sent
across the wire to the server.
If you want to atomically
increment the counter,
replace one is preferred because
the entire counter is replaced.
Replace one, update
one, and update many all
call the server's update
command behind the scenes.
If you use update
one or update many,
you must specify a dollar
operator of some sort.
If you use replace
one, you may not
specify a dollar operator,
where operator is something
like dollar set or unset.
All right.
Check all that apply
and all that are true.