OK, here's the answer.
The first and the
third are correct,
and we'll go through each one.
In the first one, we're doing
an update one with "_id" "bat",
and we're setting "friend",
"ball", and "cousin" "glove."
This is very similar to the
one we showed in the lesson.
And in fact, it will insert
if there's no document
in the collection, something
with "_id" "bat", "friend",
"ball", "cousin", "glove."
Works fine.
The second one won't work
because there's a "$"
operator on the right-hand side
in the document to be replaced,
which is not legal.
When you're using "replace_one,"
this cannot have a "$"
operator.
The third one is correct.
And the third one's
a little subtle.
And we didn't actually show
this exact case in the lesson.
We're looking for
something with "_id" "bat."
And then we're doing "$set_id"
"bat", "friend", "ball",
"cousin", "glove"
with "upsert=True."
And we will get a document
with these items in it.
Now, it might be surprising that
you can use the set operator
on the "_id" field
because, in fact, the "_id"
field is immutable.
But if the "_id" that you're
setting is exactly the same
as the one you're filtering
on, the database knows that
it's not really changing it,
and it won't be a violation
of the immutability
of the "_id."
And as a result, you
can do this update,
you could do this insert, and
you'll wind up with something
with "_id" "bat", "friend",
"ball", and "cousin", "glove."
If you try that in PyMongo,
you can confirm that.
The last one we also
showed in the lesson, which
is that this insert won't
fail, it'll be successful.
But what you'll wind
up with is something
that has "friend",
"ball", and "cousin",
"glove" set, because
it was a "replace_one."
And "_id" "bat" won't be set.
Instead, you'll have
something with a "_id"
operator that was
assigned by the driver.
OK, and that's the answer.