OK.
Let's talk about doing
upserts within PyMongo.
We already covered
upserts in this unit
when we talked about
the Mongo shell.
And if you don't
remember how they work,
you should definitely go back
now and look at that lesson.
Upsert is a variant of update.
Upsert says, if I can't
find a document to update,
I want to insert one.
And you specify upsert as the
final parameter in an update
or replace.
You say upsert equals true,
or upsert equals false.
And the default is false.
Now upsert affects update
slightly differently
than the way it
affects a replace one.
The basic flow
chart is the same.
When you do an update, you
see if there's a match.
If there's no match, you see
if the upsert parameter is set.
And if the parameter
is at the true,
then you perform an insert.
If the parameter is set
to false, you just stop.
Now of course, when
you do an update,
if there is a match,
regardless of upsert,
you just perform the update.
And in the case of update
one or update many,
there has to be some
sort of dollar operator
here-- like dollar set or
dollar increment-- that's
going to be used to
perform the update.
The replace one is
slightly different.
Replace one also takes
an upsert parameter.
But with replace one, you're
specifying the entire document
that you want put in place.
So again, you look for a match.
If there's no
match, then you see
if upsert is set in the call.
And if it is set, you
then perform an upsert
with the document that was
specified to the replace one.
And if upsert wasn't
set, you stop.
Similarly, if there's a match
when you do a replace one, then
regardless of upsert, you just
completely replace the document
with a new document.
OK.
So let's look at how
this works in practice.
I've written a
short program here
that's going to do some upserts.
It's going to put some things
into a collection called,
appropriately, things.
And the first thing
it's going to do
is just drop the collection
so that the collection
is completely empty.
Then we're going to do
three different commands--
two updates and a replace one--
all of them with upsert=True.
And you can see here that
it's the last parameter path
to update_one, upsert=True--
or in this case,
the third parameter,
and the third parameter.
Now in the first case,
we're going to update_one.
We're going to look for a thing
that has a value of apple.
Thing, apple.
And there won't be one, because
this collection is empty.
And then, since upsert is True,
we're going to $set color red.
Now in the next case,
we're going to update_many,
and we're going to
look for thing banana.
And here we're going
to $set color yellow,
and of course it's
an upsert True,
so if this is not going
to find a document,
it's going to insert one.
Now update_one and
update_many are
going to work pretty much
identically in the upsert case,
because in the upsert
case, update_many is going
to insert exactly one document.
Now replace_one works
a little differently,
and we're going to
see how this goes.
So in this case, we
look for something
with a value of pear
for the key thing.
And we then specify a document
replace-- color, green.
And again, upsert True.
After that, we're going to
find each of these documents.
We're going to find the one with
thing apple, the one with thing
banana and thing pear, and we're
just going to print them out.
And that's all
this program does.
It looks for
exceptions, and here's
where it calls the function
we just wrote using upsert.
So let's see how this works.
I invoked the Python
interpreter on using upsert,
and what do we get?
Well, the first two are
pretty much what we expect.
In the first two,
we pull out an apple
with color red, thing
apple-- and an underscore ID
that was put in by the driver.
The banana, which was the
result of the update many call,
looks similar.
It's a thing banana and color
yellow, with an underscore ID.
But the pear-- the
pear is not found.
Well, that's kind of weird.
What happened here?
Well, let's go back
to the program.
It looks like, for
update_one and update_many,
we have a $set operator
here, and we're specifying
that we want color red set.
But for the upsert, we're also
getting thing apple, as well.
It's creating a document with
thing apple and color red.
Same thing with update_many.
But with replace_one,
since we specified
that this is the exact
document we want inserted,
it doesn't insert a document
with thing pear and color
green.
Instead, it inserts a document
with just color green,
and thing pear is missing.
So let's look at that.
Let's look in the
Things collection
and see what we find.
And in fact, we can see
that there's an apple,
there's a banana-- as
we expected-- the pear,
the color green part is there,
but the pear part is missing.
And the pear part is missing
because we didn't specify it
on this side.
Now if we had put thing colon
pear here on the right side,
we would have gotten the
document we expected.
All right.
Now it's time for a quiz.
OK, here's the quiz on upsert.
Let's say we want to upsert
the following document
into the collection Stuff.
This is using PyMongo.
We want the document to look
like this when we're done.
ID bat, friend
ball, cousin glove.
Which of the following
Python statements
work when using PyMongo?
Check all that apply.
And you better look at
these pretty carefully.