All right.
We've learned most of the things
you need to know to
program against MongoDB, at
least from a crud standpoint.
Creating data, reading the data,
updating the data, and
deleting the data.
But there's a couple of things
we haven't covered.
For instance, if you wanted to
produce a sequence number
using Mongo, how would
you do it?
So a sequence number is a small
set of integers, like 1,
2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
And you want to make sure that
two users, let's say, never
get the same sequence number,
and that they're going to be
sequential.
Now, in a relational database,
you would do this using
transactions.
And you'd probably begin a
transaction at an adequate
isolation level, as you could
read the data and then update
the counter, and then eventually
release it.
But we don't have transactions
in Mongo, but we do have
atomic operations on the
documents themselves.
And that's going to let us
do what we want to do.
So the command we're going to
look at is Find and Modify,
which is going to find a
document that satisfies
certain criteria, possibly
inserting it if it's not there
using an upsert.
And modifying it, and
returning the
old or the new value.
So let's look at how we would
create some sequence numbers
using MongoDB.
Here's a small program that I
wrote called Find and Modify,
and it's going to get
a sequence number.
Now, it does this by connecting
to the database,
test database, counters,
collection.
And then it gets a sequence
number as follows.
It calls find_and_modify
query is--
and notice this a named
parameter-- so
query equals type name.
So you can call this function
with, let's say, the string
could be a user ID, or sequence
number, or library
card number, or whatever you
were looking to get that was
sequential.
And then it would substitute
it right here.
And then update this document,
incrementing the value by one.
Now, calling the counter a
value is my own decision.
It's not anything special
about this command.
And then I've also called it
with upsert equals true, and
new equals true.
So upsert means that if there
isn't a document with type
name, then please put one
in the collection.
And new means return the
new value, not the
old value to me.
So then I'm going to get this
counter right here, counter
value is counter value.
Remember when we returned a
dictionary from this command.
And then I'm going to look
up the value, and I'm
going to return it.
That's it.
So right here in the main body
of the program, I'm just going
to do that three times.
So let's try it out.
All right.
Using Find and Modify.
Call that and it produces
1, 2, 3.
Call it again, it produces
4, 5, 6.
Call it again, 7, 8, 9,
and again, 10, 11, 12.
Perfect.
So let's go in and see
this collection.
Use test.
db.counters.find.
And there it is.
Pretty print it.
You can see there's type uid,
with a value of 12.
And the reason it's type uid
is that when I called
get_next_sequence_number here,
I named the sequence
uid, for user ID.
And that is how you'd get
a unique sequence
number using MongoDB.