Now we know how to create,
read, update, and delete data
in a database, both from
the shell and from PyMongo.
So what's really left?
Well, one thing you might
want to do sometimes
is atomically change a
document and see its value,
either before or
after the change.
So if you think about having
a document in the database,
you can certainly find
it using find one,
and then you can update
it using update one.
But if you do that, there
could be an intervening change,
and there's no guarantee that
the document that you retrieve
from the database is
the exact same one
that you're storing back.
Now there's a general
idea of find and modify
that solves this problem.
We're going to go over three
different variants of this.
They are find one and
delete, find one and replace,
and find one and update.
And in all cases, these are
going to find a single document
and then either they're
going to delete it,
they're going to replace
it with another document,
or they're going to update it.
In the case of updating, you
can specify whether or not
you want to see the document
state from before the update
or after the update.
And this becomes
very interesting,
especially if you're trying
to create a unique counter.
And that's the example I
want to show you today,
which is how to create a unique
counter in the database that's
guaranteed to go up by one
every single time you call
it using find one and update.
Before I go into that,
I want to also let
you know that if you look
into the actual implementation
of these commands
inside PyMongo,
you'll see that they all map to
find and modify at the server.
Now, the new [INAUDIBLE]
specification
states that the commands you
use are find one and delete
and replace and update, but if
you go into the PyMongo code,
you'll see that,
underneath, they're
all calling find and modify
command at the server.
Furthermore, in the Mongo shell,
there's also a find and modify
function, and that find
and modify function
also calls the find and
modify command in the server.
So this is another area
where the shell has
diverged a bit from
the current state
of the art inside the drivers.
All right, let's look at our
program to increment a counter.
Here's our program called
get sequence number.
Now this program
imports PyMongo,
and then it has
one function called
get sequence number, where
the sequence number is a name.
It could be any string.
And then what it
does is it connects
to the test database and
the counters collection,
and then it's going to
call find one and update.
The document it's going to
look for has type, name.
So you can imagine having a
bunch of different counters
in this collection,
each one represented
by a single document.
And then it's going
to do an update.
It's going to apply
dollar ink to something
we call value, which
is the arbitrary key.
We decided to keep our
counter value in value.
And we're going to increment
it by one, using the dollar ink
operator.
We're going to say upsert=True.
And the reason we're going to
upsert=True is that we want
this to work even if there
is no counter document
in the collection yet
for this counter type.
Now if we're saying upsert=True,
well then find an update
can't return the document
from before the update,
because that document wouldn't
exist for the first time.
So instead of
getting the document
from before the update, we
have a special parameter
that we've set here inside this
find one and update where we've
said the document we want
returned by find_one_and_update
is the return
document dot after--
pymongo.ReturnDocument.AFTER.
And if you look in
the documentation,
you can see this
is a constant that
is defined in PyMongo that
specifies to the driver
that you want to get the
document after the updating,
after the incrementing.
So let's see what
happens if we do this.
We're going to print get
sequence number for uID.
So we're imagining that
we're creating a unique user
identifier.
And by the way, you can see
that, what this function does--
I didn't show you
this part-- is that it
gets the counter value from
a document that comes back.
So we get back this
document counter,
and we get back this
value right here.
Then we pull a value out of
the document and we return it.
So that's what
we're going to print
in this get sequence number.
So let's run that a few
times and see what happens.
First, I want to show
you that, in fact, there
is nothing in this
collection when you start.
So db.counters.find.
Nothing in the collection.
Now let's run using
find and modify.
We're going to run that.
Let's see what we get.
All right, it ran it three
times and it got three
different sequence numbers.
Now I'm going to do it again,
and I got three more sequence
numbers.
Do it again, and I have
three more sequence numbers.
We've now counted
all the way to nine.
So what's inside the collection?
Let's look.
Db.counters.find, we can see
there is just a single document
of type uID, value nine.
And now that you
see this, maybe it
makes more sense what
this program is doing,
which is that it's looking
for a document of type--
we passed in the word
uID, so type uID.
And we've said that
the update itself
is dollar ink, value
increment by one.
Now if we change
this to minus 1,
we'd be decrementing
the value each time.
And if we changed it to minus 2,
we'd be decrementing it by two.
I can show you that.
Let's change this to minus 1.
Now we're going to count down.
And now we're counting
down, and it should count
to negative numbers, as well.
So this is how you create unique
counters using find and modify.
So find and modify is
pretty useful, especially
because MongoDB
lacks transactions.
And although each
action to a document
is atomic, if you want
to get back the value
and make a change all
in one go without there
being any intervening
change, then
you can do it using
find and modify.
OK, so that's it.
That's find and modify.