Now we're going to return to
building our blog, the project
that we're going to be
doing in this class.
For this week's homework
assignment you're going to be
completing the user
registration
parts of the blog.
And I want to take you through
how those should work when
it's complete.
And we're going to give
you all the user
interface for this.
So it's just going to be a
matter of putting in a few
Mongo commands into the code
to get it all working.
So we're going to go through
author registration.
An author, in order to write on
our blog, is going to have
to register.
And we're going to go through
user login and author login to
validate that they're allowed to
login with their password,
and logout.
And I'm going to show you how
those functions work.
And then after that I'll give
you a tour of the code.
So I'm going to run the code by
typing python blog dot py
and running the server.
And now I'm going to go
to the web browser.
And I'm going to just go to
local hosts and hit return,
see what I see.
And it says, this is the
placeholder for the blog.
There aren't very many URLs that
are going to be defined.
But one of them is going
to be signup.
And if you want to sign up for
the blog, you go to this URL
and you'll type the name.
I'm going to put in "erlichson."
And then I'll
just give a password of "fubar,"
something very
simple, and then leave
out my email.
And then I'm going to submit.
You'll notice the URL
is currently signup.
And then I get redirected
to a welcome page.
And it says, "Welcome
erlichson." And then it says I
can go to my blog home or
I can logout or I can
create a new post.
Create a new post won't work,
because we haven't
implemented that yet.
Logout will work fine.
In fact, why don't we log out?
And now it brings us
back to this page.
And if I click on Login, it
brings me back to this page.
And I'm just going to type my
username and password again.
And that sends me back
to this page.
So that's the way it works.
That's all it's supposed
to do at this point.
So what did it do behind the
scenes, and how does it work?
We're going to get to that in
some of these next sections.
So we'll start there.
And then we'll do another
section to show you some of
the underpinnings.