OK, so I've created a
user in the blog.
That user is me, erlichson.
And now I want to go through
some of the session management
that goes on behind the scenes
to present this welcome page
with the name erlichson on it.
So it all happens
through cookies.
And if you go into MongoDB after
you create a user when
you've completed the first
part of the homework this
week, you should see
the following.
I'm going to use blog, and
then I'm going to show
collections.
And you're going to see
three collections--
sessions, system.indexes,
and users.
Let's focus on the sessions
and users collections.
So, db.users.find--
you can see here that there's a
user in this collection with
the ID erlichson, and that's
me, with a hash
version of my password.
And we're going to give you the
logic to do the hashing.
And there's also something in
the sessions collection.
And that is an association
between my web
session and my username.
So there's this long random,
and that's going to be put
into the browser cookie.
And then it's associated
with my username.
Now if we go here into the web
browser, I've installed a
cookie utility.
And if you click on it, you
can see the cookie that my
browser is presenting
in this session.
And you can see that it starts
with ab and ends with f.
And if you go here, you can see
ab ends with f, that's the
exact same string that's
in the sessions table.
So how does this session
management work?
Let's go over it.
When the welcome page is
presented, it's done through a
get request.
And what happens is the browser
sends a request via
HTTP with the cookie present to
your application, which is
written in Python.
And this is the blog
application, and, of course,
it uses Bottle to take
the HTTP requests.
And then the application
makes a request
using PyMongo to MongoDB.
And it presents this session
identifier, this session ID,
and then it gets back
a username.
And then when the application
responds, it responds with the
username embedded in
the HTML page.
And then it says "welcome
erlichson." And it does this
through this process.
Now let's look at one other
flow, which is the flow for
logging in.
So let's go through that.
When you log in, there's
a login page.
And that login page
has a username and
password field on it.
And it's presented via
a get request.
You're going to put username
and password in, and it's
going to be sent via a post
request to your blog.
And what the blog is going to
do is check it against the
credentials inside the users
collection inside MongoDB.
And if it looks like a valid
login, it's going to create an
entry in the sessions
collection.
And that's sessions collection,
it's going to have
this long session ID which is
going to become the cookie.
So it's going to respond back
with the session information
if it's a valid login.
And then what's sent back your
browser is actually a redirect
to the welcome page with
the cookie set.
And so your browser is going
to round trip that, and say
all right, and then redirects
this to the welcome page so
then it's going to get
on the welcome page.
And so this is a round trip
because the browser gets a
redirect and then does a get
on the welcome page.
And what does that get?
It's now going to present the
cookie that it saw during the
redirect, and that's going
to produce this "welcome
erlichson."
All right, so that's the flow
of how session management
works inside the blog.
And now I'm going to show you
some of the internals of the
blog so you're ready for
this week's homework.