In this problem, we asked you
to add the code to the blog
that would allow people to sign
up for the blog and log
in to the blog.
You needed to work
in two places.
The first one was in this add
user code in userDAO.py.
You needed to add this statement
right here and
insert the user record right
here, self.users.insert(user).
And the second place you needed
to work over here in
validate_login.
You needed to find the user
and the user collection.
And the way you do that is
self.users.find_one.
And then you specify underscore
ID and the user
name that was given
by the user.
That pulls out the document.
Then you compare
the passwords.
And that's where you
needed to work.
So this is the finished
solution.
Let's see if it works.
So we'll go here.
And we're going to run it.
Oh.
It looks like Python's
already running.
So let's just kill all Python
and see if that does it.
Yup.
And then right here,
we're going to run
the validation script.
And you can see that
it did work.
And it got a validation code,
which is blanked out here.
But you'll get the real
one when you run it.
And let's see if
the blog works.
Here we go.
Let's log out.
Let's create a new user.
Test101, password test,
verify test.
All right.
Now let's log out and log
in as this test101 user.
And we're able to log in.
So it seems to work properly.
And the final part of that, of
course, would be to go into
the users collection,
so db.users.find.
And oh, there's a whole bunch of
test entries that were put
here by the program.
Let's do a find where
the underscore ID is
this test101 user.
Pretty, print that out.
There we go.
You can see test101
is the user.
And here's the hashed
password.
So that all seems to work.