OK.
We've talked about how we get
durability on a single node by
waiting for the write, let's
say, to go to the log.
But how do we get availability,
and how do we
get fault tolerance?
And by that, I mean if that
node goes down, we want to
still be able to
use the system.
At if the primary node goes down
and we lose it entirely
for some reason, let's say
there's a fire, how do we make
sure we don't lose our data
between the backups?
And so what we do to solve
both those problems is we
introduce replication.
And I'll show you
how that works.
So we have the concept
of a replica set.
And the replica set is
a set of Mongo nodes.
And I'm going to show
you three nodes.
And these are all Mongos,
mongod's that act together and
all mirror each other in
terms of the data.
There is one primary, and
then the other nodes are
secondaries.
But that's dynamic.
And data that's written to the
primary will asynchronously
replicate to the secondaries.
Your application and its drivers
stay connected to the
primary, and will write
to the primary.
You can only write
If the primary goes down, then
the remaining nodes, in this
case these two notes will
perform an election to elect a
new primary.
To elect a new primary, you have
to have a strict majority
of the original number
of nodes.
So since the original number of
nodes here was three, you'd
need two nodes to elect a
new primary, and that's
the number we have.
So if that went down, then this
can become the primary.
And at that point, what would
happens is your app would
reconnect to the primary for
rights, through the drivers.
All transparently.
So this group of nodes is
called a replica set.
And that's going to form the
basic mechanism by which we
get fault tolerance and
availability in Mongo.
Now, there's some other details
of this in terms of
whether reads can happen to the
secondaries or not, and
we'll go through that.
But this kind of gives
you the basic outline
of the way it works.
Now when this node, this node
came back up, it could come
back up as a secondary, and in
which case it would rejoin the
group, and be able to act as a
secondary while this one acted
as the primary.
So this is the basics
of replication.
Now, the minimum number of
nodes, as I said is three.
And the reason is that if you
had fewer than three nodes,
then what would remain would not
be a majority of that set,
of the original set.
And so there would be no way
to elect a new primary.
So you'd go without a primary,
which means you could no
longer take rights.
OK, let's go over a quick quiz
on some of these concepts.
What is the minimum original
number of nodes needed to
assure the election of a new
primary if a node goes down?