In the replication within
MongoDB, there's only a single
primary at any given time.
And in the default
configuration, your writes and
your reads go to that primary.
Now, your writes have to go to
the primary, but your reads
don't have to go
to the primary.
The reads could go to the
secondaries if you'd like.
But if you allow the writes to
go on to the primary, then
what happens is you get strong
consistency of reads with
respect to writes.
And what this means, among other
things is that you won't
read stale data.
That if you write something,
that you'll be able to read
it, and other application
servers that read it will also
be able to read what you wrote
after you wrote it.
Provided that you waited for the
write to complete through
journaling.
Now, you can, if you prefer,
allow your reads to go to your
secondaries.
But if you do that, then you may
read stale data from the
secondaries, relative to what
you wrote, or somebody else
wrote in the primaries.
And the lag between any two
nodes is not guaranteed,
because the replication
is asynchronous.
So you want to keep
that in mind.
And we'll go through the
different read preferences
that you can set in terms of the
drivers to decide whether
or not you're willing to
accept reads from the
secondaries.
And the reasons why you might
want to read from the
secondaries, I mean, the
traditional reason people do
it is because they want to scale
their reads through the
replica set.
So they feel that if they can
sen their reads to all the
nodes, that they'll get
some read scaling.
We'll go over that a little bit
later in terms of whether
that's really true or not, and
whether it's a good idea.
But I guess for the purposes
of this, I just want to
explain to you that the memory
model here is strongly
consistent.
On the other hand, though, when
failover occurs, briefly
during that time when there's no
primary, you can't complete
a write, because there
is no primary.
And then when another primary
is elected, let's say this
primary goes down, which
is going to be
pretty rare, obviously.
Then during that period, you
won't be able to actually
perform any rights.
And this is in contrast to
some other systems that
compete with MongoDB that have
a weaker form of consistency.
Some of them have what's called
eventual consistency.
And eventual consistency means
that eventually, you'll be
able to read what you wrote, but
there's no guarantee that
you'll be able to read it in
any particular time frame.
And I mean, the problem with
eventual consistency is it's
pretty hard to reason about,
because when you write
something into the database, I
mean, most web servers these
days, most application servers
are stateless.
So it's a little disconcerting
to, let's say, write the
session information and write
other information into the
database, and then read
it back out and
get a different value.
And then have to reconcile
what that means.
So MongoDB does not offer
eventual consistency in its
default configuration
where you read and
write to the primaries.
If you want to form an eventual
consistency, you can
read from the secondaries, which
will give you eventual
consistency.
OK, so let's do a quiz.
All right, so during the time
when failover is occurring in
a replica set, can writes
successfully complete?
The answer is yes or no.