Now let's turn our attention
to the way that drivers
connect to these replica sets.
I have a program here--
pymongo_to_replset.py, and I'm
using the new MongoClient
client class.
And what I'm doing here is
connecting to a host in a
replica set, and naming it
to replicaSet, and then
specifying that w equals
1, j equals True.
Now this host is what's
called a seedlist.
And you'll notice that I only
listed one of them, and it
should be enough to connect
to the entire replica set.
If you want to be sure that
you're going to connect, you
can list all of them
as a list.
But here, I'll just show you
when I'm listing one.
So I'm using c.m101--
I'm sorry, the m101 database,
and the people
collection in it.
And I'm trying to put these
three items in it.
So let's see if that works.
OK, and it works just fine.
And you can see you can also
list all the hosts right here.
So I'll do that just to
show you how it works.
So now I've listed all
three hosts in the
replica set as a list.
And normally, these would
probably be three hosts
running on the standard port,
but we're just running on
localhost here.
And here I'm using localhost.
It seems to work fine connecting
using the driver,
using the localhost
name, which is the
local IP of the machine.
This is all in the
same machine.
All right, so we're going
to do this again.
Now we're connected with a
seedlist of all three, and
we're going to run it again.
And, it works fine again.
And by the way, if you want to
see what's in this collection,
you can see that the three
items I put in times two,
because I did it twice.
So that is the way a seedlist
works, and the way the driver
works inside Python.
And the other ones are
pretty similar.
Java is pretty similar.
They're all pretty much the same
thing, in terms of the
use of a seedlist to specify
the hosts that are in the
replica set, and handling
the automatic failover
as they need to.
OK, let's do a quiz.
So the quiz is--
if you leave replica set node
out of the seedlist within the
driver, what will happen?
The missing node will not be
used for the application.
The missing node will be
discovered as long as you list
it at least one valid node.
The missing node will be used
for reads, but not for writes.
Or, the missing node
will be used for
writes, but not for reads.
So check the right answer.