All right.
Now I'm going to show you
how to install MongoDB.
This video is going
to show you how
to install MongoDB on a Mac.
In the next video, we'll show
you how to install it on a PC.
If you're a Mac user,
watch this video.
If you're a PC user,
watch the next one.
So the first step is to
find the download page.
I'm going to do
that using Google.
I'm going to type
in, download MongoDB.
And when I do that, I get an ad.
And then after that, I get the
first organic link right here,
download MongoDB.
And I'm going to click on that.
OK.
So we come to this
page, and we can
see that the first
thing that we're offered
is MMS, which stands for the
MongoDB Management Service.
Now that's a cloud
service, and it's not
the way we're going
to run MongoDB today.
We're actually going to install
and run it on our computer.
Now if we look down, it offers
us the most recent release.
This course is going to cover
MongoDB 3.0, which is the most
recent release of MongoDB.
It was released only weeks ago
at the time of this recording.
And you should download whatever
is the most recent production
version when you hit this page.
It may not be 3.0.0 by the
time you get there, but 3.0.
something is what you want.
And since we're on a Mac,
it's already defaulted us
to the Mac download.
And I'm going to click
this Download link to get
this tarball onto my computer.
Now let's go to a terminal shell
and figure out where it is.
So I know it puts these
things in /downloads,
so I'm in the
downloads directory.
For those who aren't
sure how to get there,
I'll show you how to do that.
All right.
So there it is in the
downloads directory.
I'm going to un-tar it by
using the tar command, xvf
mongodb-osx et cetera.
That's going to
expand the tarball.
I'm going to enter the
directory, look around.
I see a readme file, the
license, and a bin directory.
I'm going to go in
the bin directory.
Let's see what there is in here.
Well, in here, we have a
bunch of different programs,
but the ones of greatest
interest to us right the second
are mango, which
is the Mongo shell
program lets us connect to
the database, and mongod,
which is the actual server.
And it's the server that
we want to get running.
Now the server is going to
put its data in /data/db
by default, so we need
to create that directory.
Now to do that, I'm going
to need to become root,
so let me do that.
So now I'm root.
And now I'm going to make
dir/data/db like that.
So now that there's
a data/db directory--
and we're just running
in development.
And I'm going to
keep this simple,
so I'm going to actually
chmod those directories
777 so that I can exit root and
write to them from my account.
And let's just confirm
that /data/db is 777.
And we can see that it is 777.
It's world writeable.
So I'm going to
exit the root shell.
All right.
So now we're going to
get mongod running.
I'm going to start
it running as myself.
Who am I?
I'm aje.
I'm going to run it right here
in this directory by typing
./mongod.
This will guarantee that
I take the executable
from the current
directory and not
from somewhere else
in my path because I
want to make sure I get
the one I just downloaded.
And I do that, and a whole
bunch of stuff prints out.
And see here, it's
listening on port.
By default, it listens
on the port 27017.
And you can see here it says
it's listening on port 27017.
Let's get a new terminal window.
And let's see what
my directory is.
It's downloads/mongodb bin.
Good.
And now let's run
the Mongo shell.
All right.
So I connected to
the Mongo shell,
and now I'm going
to insert something
into a names collection.
I'm going to insert a
document with my name
in it, so db.names.insert.
I'm going to test database.
There is one key name with
a value Andrew Erlichson.
Hit Return.
It inserted the document.
And at this point,
if I do a find,
I can see there's the document.
All right.
So I'm pretty much
done, but just
to make this work a
little bit better,
what I'm going to
do is I'm going
to kill the server by
hitting Control-C. I'm
going to become root again.
Now I'm root.
And now I'm in
the bin directory.
I'm just going to copy all these
programs to usr/local/bin just
like that.
And then, I'm going to
exit this root shell.
And then, I'm going
to type which mongo.
And I get the one
at usr/local/bin,
so that means that
usr/local/bin was already
in my path, which is great.
And so at this point,
mongod is running.
And I go back to
my home directory
if I ever want to do that.
And if I type mongod, it will
start the server running again.
And now, if I go to another
shell, I can connect to it.
So that's all there is to it.
And now, I have MongoDB running
on my computer in the simplest
possible configuration.
This is a standalone,
not a replica set,
and not necessarily running
with the same parameters
and the same configuration
you'd want in production,
but a fine configuration for
our purposes for development.
OK.