OK, now that we've got
MongoDB installed on Windows,
the next step is to get
Python installed on Windows.
You might already have
Python installed on Windows,
and if you do you
can skip this step.
But a lot of folks don't so I'm
going to show you how to do it.
I'm in Google and I'm
going to type "download
Python for Windows."
And when I do that I
get to the first URL
is Python releases for
Windows, Python.org.
And then it looks like the first
download link is what I need,
but I'm just going to
scroll down for a second.
And its Python 2.7.9,
we're not going
to use Python 3 series
for this course.
So if we go down
here, what do we have?
We've got some downloads.
Let's see, Gzipped source,
I don't want to compile it,
Mac OS, I don't want to
do that, Windows debug
information files.
Windows x86-64 MSI installer,
this looks good to me.
For AMD, for EMT, x86, not
for Itanium processors.
Well, I don't think I
have an Itanium processor,
so I'll try that.
And now I'm going to run that.
Install for all users.
It's going to install it at
C colon slash Python27 slash.
OK, that sounds good.
All right, and I
say Yes to that.
All right, seems to
be doing its work.
Oh, it's installing set
up tools including pip,
I read that on the
screen, it's going
to be very convenient for us.
So even if you have an
older version of Python
you might want to
install this one.
You must restart your system
for your configuration changes
to take effect, click Yes
to restart now or No if you
plan to manually restart later.
Wow, full restart.
OK, well I'm going to
restart the computer
and then I'll pick this
up after it restarts.
OK, we're back post
reboot now and we're
going to finish up the
process of installing Python
on this Windows
PC by making sure
that the path is set correctly.
So to do that we
go over to System
and we click on
Advanced System Settings
and then we click on
Environment Variables.
And then for
environment variables
we scroll down here, find
the path, there it is.
And now we're going
to edit the path,
and now I'm going to position
the mouse at the very end
and I'm going to put
the separator in,
which is a semicolon.
So I put in C colon
slash Python27 slash.
And that should do it.
So let's say OK to that and
OK to that and OK to that.
And now if we bring up a
shell and if we type Python
we get the Python
2.7.9 interpreter
and now we're going to
just print "Hello World",
and we see Hello World.
And Python is
installed on this PC.
OK, so Python is now
installed on Windows,
but the last piece we
need to also make sure
that we get right is that
we have the Python setup
tools in our path,
because we're going
to want to use pip, which is
an installer, P-I-P. If we
try to do that right now
we can't because it's not
in our path.
Now, I searched using
Windows Explorer
and found that it was actually
in Python 2.7 Scripts.
So let's go ahead and change
our path to include that.
So once again we're going to
go to System, Advanced System
Properties,
Environment Variables,
we're going to scroll
down to this path variable
and we're going to
edit it one more time.
And this time we're going to add
another semicolon at the end.
And then C colon slash
Python27 slash scripts.
And I believe that it
was actually capitalized,
although I think it's case
preserving and case insensitive
so I don't think it matters.
So let's do that, say OK, and
now let's get another shell.
When I right click
I get a shell.
And then let's see if pip
is actually installed.
Excellent.
Now if I type "pip" I can
actually install things.
That's going to be very
useful for installing
PyMongo and installing Bottle.
So that's the end of the
installing Python lesson.