Let's start out by reviewing
what we try to strive for in
the relational world in
the third normal form.
Because I think it'll motivate
a lot of the trade offs that
we talk about in the
mongoDB world.
This a bit of a review for
people who come from the
relational world.
Let's look at a potential schema
for a posts table for
the blog project that
we've been talking.
And this isn't the whole thing,
this is just the posts
itself plus the authors.
So let's say that you had a
posts table and you decided to
have a post ID, and a title, and
the body, so these are the
different titles of these posts,
like Elvis lives, and
the body says, yes he does.
And the author of the
post here, Andrew.
And then the author email andrew
at 10gen.com The second
post in the table says,
mongo rocks.
And it was written by Richard.
And has his email, richard
at 10gen.com.
And the third one has the
title, hello world.
And it was written by Andrew.
And it has the email andrew
at 10gen.com.
So this is a denormalized
table structure in the
relational world.
It's not the third
normal form.
It's broken.
And it's broken very clearly
because you can see right here
that if I want to update my
email, let's say the email for
Andrew, I would have to update
it here and also here.
And there's a possibility of
leaving it inconsistent.
I could update it in this row,
but not update it in this row,
and therefore, leave
it inconsistent.
And you can pretty much
see that this violates
normalization because it
violates a common way of
describing normalized tables
in the third normal form,
which is that every non-key
attribute in the table must
provide a fact about the
key, the whole key, and
nothing but the key.
And that's of a play on words
for what you say in a US
courtroom, telling the truth,
the whole truth, and nothing
but the truth.
And, in particular, the key
in this is the post.
This is going to be the primary
key for this table.
And there is the attribute, this
non-key attribute, author
email, which does
not follow that.
Because it does, in fact, tell
something about the author.
And so it violates that
third normal form.
And, if you remember, from the
world of relational having a
database table in the third
normal form there's several
good things about that.
And I'll show you
what they are.
All right, so what are the goals
of normalization in the
relational world?
Well, there's three goals.
One is that it frees the
database of these modification
anomalies, like, for instance,
the one I just showed you,
where I could update my email
address in one row, but not
update it in another, and
therefore, leave it
inconsistent within
the database.
And the next is it's supposed to
minimize the redesign when
extending the database.
Now this, I think, it's a
little bit controversial
whether that does that or not.
But that's the idea
of normalization.
And the final reason that you
normalize these tables, in a
relational world, is this one,
is to avoid any bias toward a
particular access pattern.
Now, when we look at building
systems within mongoDB, and we
look at the schema that we
design in mongoDB, this is the
one that we're not going
to worry about.
And the reason is that when
you're not biased toward any
particular access pattern,
you're equally
bad at all of them.
And one of the ideas behind
mongoDB is to tune up your
database to the applications
that you're trying to write
and the problem that you're
trying to solve.
And so, we're not going to worry
about avoiding the bias
toward any particular
access pattern.
Now, we are going to
worry about this.
We don't want to have to
redesign the whole system
every time we change
something.
And mongoDB is very flexible
that way because we can add
keys and attributes to documents
without changing
every existing document.
And then, the last one is
freeing the database of these
modification anomalies.
and, although you might think
that embedding the data would
cause these, it doesn't
have to.
And, in fact, we're mostly going
to avoid embedding data
in documents in mongoDB
In ways that
create these anomalies.
So we're going to be careful
not to create them
for the most part.
Occasionally, for performance
reasons, we're going to decide
that we do want to duplicate the
data within the document.
But that's not going
to be the default.
The default is that we're going
to avoid it, so that we
don't have these types of
anomalies where data can be
inconsistently changed.
And in some applications, you
might want to allow it and it
doesn't matter.
Or you might want to keep it
up-to-date in the application,
but mostly we're going
to avoid it.