And the answer is that, of
these four, the only one
that's really not well-supported
is, providing a
table of contents by tag.
To do that, we would probably
have to use the aggregation
framework to do some sort
of a group buy.
It wouldn't be that
easy to do it.
But the other ones are pretty
well-supported.
So we could certainly collect
the most recent blog entries.
We would just do a find in the
collection and order them by
the date and then
just do a limit.
Collecting all of the
information for a single post.
You saw that--
very well use of the
entire document.
The entire blog post is
contained in a single
document, so it's easy
to display that.
Collecting all the comments
by a single author.
This was a little tricky and
we haven't quite told you
enough about this.
But the answer is-- and let me
show you this document again.
It does support that very well,
provided you add an index.
You could actually add an index
on comments.author and
it will reach inside the array
and index that information.
We haven't talked too
much about that.
But if you did that, then you
could do a find and find all
the comments by a
single author.
This is the find, is the
author of the comment.
But, as I said, that last one
is not well-supported, which
is providing a table of contents
by tag, where you can
see all the blog posts
that are filed
under a different tag.
There's no easy way to do that
in this design because you'd
have to basically--
First of all, you have to look
for the entire collection,
pull out every one of these
tags, and you'd have to
organize it by tag.
You can do it with the
aggregation framework
but no other way.