Let's say we wanted to try
a different design
for our blog schema.
For example, rather than have
everything in the post
collection embedded with an
array for the tags and an
array for the comments, we
could have a separate
collection for posts,
comments, and tags.
And if we did that--
add an s here--
if we did that, what
would it look like?
Well, we have our post
collection again.
And a post would be--
the underscore id would probably
be the post ID.
And there'd be the title of the
post and the body and the
author and the date.
But then, for the comments, we'd
have multiple documents
in the comments collection.
And they'd probably be tied
together in a similar way that
we would in the relational
world, which is that we would
have right here, this post ID
would be the same as this ID
right here.
And then we'd have the author
for the comment here and the
author email there.
We'd now need an order
attribute, because, remember,
these comments are ordered
on the blog post.
And whereas we got that for
free when we embed them,
because there was an array and
arrays are ordered, now we
have to have the order, because
if there were five
comments, one of them would have
an ordinal value of 0,
one would have an ordinal value
of 1, 2, 3, et cetera.
And then, finally, for the
tags, we'd have to have
multiple tag entries.
So to add three tags to follow
this post and the three tags,
we'd have to have three
different documents in this
tags collection.
Now, the problem is that we
don't have any sort of joins
inside MongoDB.
So if you want to display one
post, you're going to have to
manually collect this in code.
You're going to have to go
through and read the post ID
and then use it to read the
comments collection.
And then you're going to have
to use it to read the tags
collection.
It's pretty tedious in code.
And there's no locality of data,
because these are in
separate files on disk.
This is in one file, probably.
This is in another file.
So a disk is going to seek
in the post collection.
You're going to find the post.
You're going to read the whole
thing into memory.
Same thing for the comments
collection.
It's a separate disk seek to
find the comments, and then
read that into memory.
And the same thing
with these tags.
So it doesn't work particularly
well.
And one good rule of thumb with
MongoDB's schema design,
is if you see yourself doing it
in exactly the same way you
would do it in a relational
design, you're probably not
taking the best approach.
So always try to embed data
where you can, prejoin it
where you can.
Now, there are some limitations
to that that we're
going to get to.
In particular, these documents
can only be 16
megabytes in size.
So in certain situations, it
won't work to embed the data.
And you'll have to keep it
in separate collections.
But there are some ways around
that that I'll talk about in
some future segments.
But anyway, this an alternative
design for the blog.
And I think it's one that
doesn't work particularly
well, although it might seem the
most natural coming from
the relational world.