One thing I think about a lot
with mongoDB, because I come
from the world of relational
before I started working at
10Gen and thinking a lot about
the advantages of mongoDB, is
that there are a lot of great
things about relational.
And one of the great things
about relational is that it's
really good at keeping
your data
consistent within the database.
And one of the ways it does
that is with foreign key
constraints.
So what is a foreign
key constraint?
Well, a foreign key constraint
is that let's say these are
actually more like tables, but
these are collections in the
case that we showed, what
guarantee is it that when you
insert a document into the
comments collection, that this
post ID will actually appear
in this post collection.
That's a foreign
key constraint.
And the answer in mongoDB
is there's no guarantee.
It's really up to you as the
programmer to make sure that
your data is consistent
in that manner.
And that when you store
something in a collection, if
you mean for this to be an index
into the post collection
that you guarantee that.
Because the database won't
guarantee that for you.
And maybe in a future version of
mongoDB, we will guarantee
it, but we don't offer a
way to do that today.
Same thing with this.
And so, how do you live in a
world without these foreign
key constraints without
constraints and keep your data
intact and consistent?
And the answer is that embedding
actually helps.
And that's why this alternative
design that I
showed isn't a particularly
good one.
So let's look at the particular
case we just talked
about, which is that we had this
comments collection and
it had a post ID that we could
not guarantee was in the post
collection.
Notice, when we embedded the
data, we've solved this
problem entirely.
Because now, since the data
appears directly inside the
document, like the comment
appeared directly inside the
document, there's no way for me
to insert something where
the comment's post ID isn't
in the post collection.
That information is already
tied together when you
pre-join this data.
Same thing with the tags.
There's no way that we can
accidentally store a tag into
the tag collection where the
post ID isn't in the post
collection because I've already
pre-joined the data
and it's in here.
And so, what I just wanted to
point out is that you should
pre-join the data.
You should embed the data in
ways that make sense for your
application for lots of
different reasons.
And one of them is, it makes
it a lot easier to keep the
data intact and consistent.
All right, so time
for a quick quiz.
And the quiz is, what
does living without
constraints refer to?
And the answers are, living
every day like it's your last,
saying whatever you want when
you want to, keeping your data
consistent even though mongoDB
lacks foreign key constraints,
or wearing no belt.