We talked a little bit early on
in the first week about the
lack of transactions support
within MongoDB.
And from the relational world
a lot of you know that
transactions offer atomicity,
consistency, isolation, and
durability.
But, although we don't have
transactions within MongoDB,
we do have atomic operations.
So what does that mean?
Well, atomic operations mean
that when you work on a single
document that that work will
be completed before anyone
else sees the document.
They'll either see all
the changes that you
make or none of them.
And using atomic operations, you
can often accomplish the
same thing you would have
accomplished using
transactions in a relational
database.
And the reason is, that in a
relational database, you need
to make changes across multiple
tables, usually
tables that need to be joined,
and so you want to
do that all at once.
And to do it, since there are
multiple tables, you'll have
to begin a transaction and do
all those updates and then end
the transaction.
But with MongoDB, since you're
going to embed the data, since
you're going to pre-join
it in documents--
and they're these rich
documents that have
hierarchy--
you often cam accomplish
the same thing.
For instance, in the blog
example, if you wanted to make
sure that you updated a blog
post atomically, you can do
that because you can update the
entire blog post at once.
Whereas, if it was a bunch of
relational tables, you'd
probably have to open a
transaction so that you can
update the post collection and
the comments collection.
So what are your approaches that
you can take in MongoDB
to overcome a lack
of transactions?
And the answer is there are
really three different
approaches.
And I want to go over
them real quickly.
The first is that you can
restructure your code so that
you're working within a single
document and taking advantage
of the atomic operations that we
offer within that document.
And if you do that, then
usually you're all set.
And you won't miss the
transactions at all.
The second thing you can do,
if you'd like, is you can
essentially implement some sort
of locking in software.
You can do this by creating
a critical section.
You can essentially build a
test, test, and set using find
and modify.
You can build semaphores
if you want to.
And, in a way, this is the way
the larger world works anyway.
If you think about it, if one
bank needs to transfer money
to another bank, they're
not living in the
same relational system.
And they each have their own
relational databases often.
And they have to be able to
coordinate that operation,
even though you can't begin
transaction and end
transaction across those
database systems, only within
one system within one bank.
So there's certainly
ways in software to
get around the problem.
And the final approach, which
often works in modern web
applications and other
applications that take in a
tremendous amount of data, is to
just tolerate a little bit
of inconsistency.
An example would be if you're
talking about a friend feed in
Facebook, it doesn't matter if
everybody sees your wall
update simultaneously.
It's OK if one person's
a few beats
behind for a few seconds.
And then they catch up.
It often isn't critical in a
lot of system designs that
everything be kept perfectly
consistent and that everyone
have a perfectly consistent
and the
same view of the database.
So you could simply tolerate a
little bit of inconsistency
that's somewhat temporary.
So those are three approaches.
You can restructure to make sure
that everything happens
within a single document so that
you get the advantages of
atomic operations.
You can implement
whatever you're
looking for in software.
Or you can tolerate a little bit
of a consistency that you
might get without
transactions.
All right, so, let's
do a quiz.
So here's the quiz.
Which of the following
operations operate atomically
within a single document
in MongoDB?
Check all that apply.
And the choices are, the update
command, the find and
modify command, the add to set
command within an update, or
the push, again within
an update.
And if you remember add to set,
add something to an array
list, if it's not there,
push, push, is at
the end of the list.