We started out this unit talking
about the third normal
form and denormalization.
And if you recall, one of the
reasons why you normalize data
in the relational world is
because you want to avoid
modification anomalies
that come with the
duplication of data.
And when you look at MongoDB
and how it's structured,
allowing these rich documents,
it's easy to assume that what
we're doing is we're
denormalizing data.
And to a certain extent,
that's true.
But as long as we don't
duplicate data, we don't open
ourselves up to modification
anomalies.
So looking back at what we went
over in this unit, we
talked about one-to-one
relationships.
And in that case, it's perfectly
safe to embed the
data if you'd like.
And you don't open yourself
up to these modification
anomalies, because you're not
duplicating the data.
You're basically just taking
something that would normally
be in a separate table,
and you're folding it
into another table.
And that doesn't necessarily
duplicate any data.
Now, when you have a one-to-many
relationship, then
embedding can also work well
without duplication of data,
as long as you embed from
the many to the one.
Now, if you want to go from
the one to the many, then
linking would avoid the
duplication of data.
Now, again, if you need to embed
something, even if it
causes duplication of data, for
performance reasons, to
match the access patterns of
your application, then that
could make sense, especially if
the data is rarely changing
or being updated.
But you can avoid it often
enough, even in this
relationship, if you go from
the many to the one.
So in the many-to-many relation,
which we looked at
with students and teachers and
authors and books, there, if
you want to avoid the
modification anomalies that
come with denormalization, all
you need to do is link through
these arrays of object
IDs in the documents.
And if you need to, for
performance reasons or for
other reasons, matching some
type of query you have to do
for your application, then
you can embed data.
But do realize that you might
be duplicating some data.
And it's up to you as the
application programmer to keep
it all up to date.