All right.
For the first problem this week,
you're going to analyze
a data set, similar to last
week, and remove the lowest
homework score for
each student.
Now, last week we had a
collection where there was a
document for each assessment.
So there were four documents
per student.
This week, there's going
to be only a single
document per student.
And it's a student's
collection.
And you're going to need to
find the lowest homework
score, and remove it, and keep
the whole data set intact.
Now, it's a little more
complicated because of the way
the scheme is arranged
this week.
And that is the idea.
Now, just like last week, you
don't need to write this
program in Python.
You can write it in
anything you want.
Here's the problem
description.
You're going to start out by
downloading the students.js
collection.
You're going to import it into
a database called school.
And then after that, you're
going to write your program.
Now, to help you verify that
you've got the right answer,
we have some queries and the
answers to those queries after
you do the work.
So there should be 200 students
in the database after
you do the work.
You shouldn't be removing
any students.
And we also give you what the
record will look like, the
document will look like, for
student _ID 100, which is
Demarcus Audette's record.
And you can see, at this point,
Demarcus has only three
grades left because the lowest
homework has been removed.
And then after you finish all
the work, to verify that you
got the right answer, we're
going to have you run this
query which uses the aggregation
framework, does
require MongoDB 2.2.
And it's going to print
out a document.
And the _ID field is going to be
the _ID of the student with
the highest average.
And that's the answer
to the problem, just
that numeric number.