Welcome to week five of M101.
Congratulations, we are almost
done with the course.
This week, we're going
to go over
the aggregation framework.
The aggregation framework has
its roots in the world of
SQL's group by clause.
If you've ever done a select
something something, group by
something something in SQL, the
aggregation framework in
MongoDB can answer a lot
of the same questions.
We're going to use it to
calculate sums, and counts,
and averages, and other
functions over entire
collections grouped
by certain values.
By the end of the week, you're
going to be able to write
simple aggregation queries that
answer a lot of the same
questions you were writing code
to solve at the beginning
of the class.
Let's get started.