Aggregation uses a pipeline
in MongoDB.
And, if you're familiar with the
Unix world, you probably
know what pipes look like.
For instance, if I wanted to
look in a directory and find
the size of every sub-directory
in it. du minus
s star piped to sort minus n,
that would numerically sort
the size of the sub-directories
and print them
on my screen.
So that's the Unix world of
pipes, and we have a similar
idea of a Pipeline here.
At the very top, is
your collection.
And, for instance, that products
collection is sent
through document by document.
The documents are piped through
this processing pipeline.
And they go through a
series of stages.
And then we eventually
get a result set.
Now, the one stage I showed you,
is the group stage, which
is going to do the
aggregations.
But there are lots
of other stages.
There's a potential sorting
stage and a matching stage we
filter for documents.
I'm going to go through each
one real briefly to explain
how it works.
But these stages can
appear multiple
times inside the pipeline.
If you recall, when I showed you
that aggregation command,
there was an array inside
the function call.
And the reason there was an
array, is that each of the
items in that array is a stage
of the pipeline that is going
to transform that collection.
So let's go through what the
different possible stages are
of an aggregation pipeline
at the high level.
And then, we're going to dig in
to each one, individually,
and then I'll show
you what it does.
All right.
So the first one is
dollar project.
And it is doesn't have to be the
first one, but often it is
the first one.
And a dollar project is going
to select out which keys
you're interested in.
It could also reshape
the document.
And I'll show you how that
works, if you want to change
its form a little bit--
taking something out of a
hierarchical document and
putting it at the high
level, you can do
it with dollar project.
Now dollar project--
for every document that dollar
project sees, it
sends out one document.
So it's one to one.
If it sees 10 documents, it
produces 10 documents.
The next one is a
dollar match.
And they don't have to be in
this order in the pipeline.
And the match is going
to filter.
So, for instance, in the case I
showed you in products, if I
was only interested in products
by Apple, I could
filter early on in
the pipeline.
And make sure that I'm only
looking at the documents that
have the manufacturer
being Apple.
That's what match
is going to do.
I can group, of course,
which you saw.
And this is going to be your
aggregation functions.
Now, filter--
for every document that
filter sees, it
may only see a subset.
So, for instance, it might see
100 documents, and then it
might actually produce
25 documents.
With aggregation, the same thing
is true because it's
aggregating.
So it's grouping by
a certain key.
So it may not produce as many
documents as it sees.
So I'll call this n to one,
since it reduces the number of
documents down a bit
or can reduce
the number of documents.
And then, there's
a sort stage.
And the sorting stage does
exactly what you could
imagine-- it sorts.
And that's one to one.
Every document it sees, it
produces another document.
And then there's a skip stage.
And the skip stage
can skip forward.
It only makes sense
after you sort.
And it just skips.
I don't know how to explain
that, other than skipping.
And, again, this is
not one to one.
This is n to one because, of
course, if you skip forward
10, then you aren't going to
produce all the documents.
You are going to produce a
subset of the documents.
There's a limit stage.
And that limit stage is going
to limit the number of
documents produced.
Again, it's used usually
with skip.
You might skip forward 10, and
then limit myself to showing
three documents.
And that's also going to be
usually limit the number of
documents that comes through
the pipeline, in some way.
That's one, two, three,
four, five, six.
There's one more operator, and
that is unwind, which we're
going to get into much more
completely later.
What unwind does--
in MongoDB, we've got these
documents that can have
sub-arrays inside them--
pre-joined data.
And what unwind does, is
it un-joins the data.
So you can imagine, that if
you had, let's say, a blog
post with tags, and tags were
sports and outdoors and
summer, what unwind will
do is, it'll--
when it encounters
a document--
and you're going to unwind
in a particular key, like
[INAUDIBLE]
tags--
it's going to produce a document
for every single one
of these sub-elements with
everything else repeated.
So, basically, it normalizes the
data, again, so that you
can more easily aggregate
it, is what it does.
So this is going to create an
explosion of documents.
So I might have one document
with three keys.
And it might produce three
documents going through the
unwind stage.
So I'm going to say, 1 to n.
We'll go through what
every single one of
these stages does.
I want to point out that
you can have a stage
exist more than once.
So you could decide to match
on some documents.
You can then group them.
Then you could match again.
You could then sort them.
You could skip them.
You could even unwind them over
and over again, if you
wanted to do that.
And I'll show you some cases
where that might be
interesting.
But, for now, I just want you
to understand that the
aggregation system uses
a pipeline concept.
And that that pipeline has
various operators that can run
other documents.
And that you can conceptually
think of the documents as
coming in the left side, getting
transformed through
these stages, and then getting
a result set from that.
And, so far, we looked only
at the grouping operator.
But we're going to go
through them all.
OK.
It is time for a quiz.
And I think this quiz is going
to be pretty straightforward.
Which of the following
are stages in
the aggregation pipeline?
Check all that apply.
Match, transpose, group,
skip, limit, sort,
project, and unwind.
Just check all that apply.