Now we know how to group
by a single key.
But what if we want to group
by multiple keys?
For example, what if we wanted
to find the number of products
that each manufacturer
had in each category?
This would be equivalent in
the SQL world of doing a
select manufacturer, comma
category, comma count star,
from products, grouped by
manufacturer, comma category.
And if you recall, the data
set looked like this.
So we want to find the number
of products that each
manufacturer has in
each category.
We do this using the aggregation
framework by
having a compound underscore
ID key.
So rather than just say we want
to organize our grouped
documents by manufacturer, I
might say I want to organize
them by manufacturer
and category.
And again I get to name
these anyway I want.
That's the manufacturer, colon,
dollar manufacturer,
and category, dollar category.
And I'm having a document be my
underscore ID key so that
as the aggregation framework
runs through those documents,
it'll be looking for documents
that have the same manufacture
category and running the
aggregation on them.
Here is that query a
little bit cleaner,
written out in text.
You can see that I'm
grouping here.
And rather than just grouping
by dollar manufacturer, I'm
grouping by manufacturer,
dollar manufacture, and
category, dollar category.
Now these names right here,
manufacture and category, are
my own invention.
I'm essentially able to create
a new key, or underscore ID,
for each document and name it
any way I want, with these
being the values.
And then I am aggregating and
getting the sum of all of
those different groupings.
So if I run that,
what do I get?
Let's see.
So here, here's the
results set.
You can see the results set
has an underscore ID of
manufacture, Amazon,
category, tablets.
And number of products two--
Google tablets, one,
Apple laptops, one.
Now it was arbitrary how
we named these things.
So if I go in here and I change
this to be maker, then
that works too.
Now it's maker, Apple,
category, laptops.
It doesn't really matter
what it is.
It's also useful, if I want, I
can use this ability to create
a key that is itself
a JSON document.
I can use it to better label
even a single grouping key.
So for instance, we had before
our simple example where I was
organizing the number of
products by manufacturer.
I was getting a report
on that.
And rather than just have it
be underscore ID, [? be ?]
dollar, manufacturer, what if I
actually created a document
key which is manufacturer,
colon, dollar, manufacturer.
And the benefit of that is
that now the result is a
little bit easier to read.
So rather than have it just
be underscore ID, Apple--
maybe that was obvious
before--
now it's underscore ID,
manufacturer, Apple, num
products 4.
Same result, but a little
bit easier to read.
Now you can create a compound
key in the grouping phase that
has as many keys as you want.
So it doesn't need
to be just two.
It could be three or four.
Whatever you want to group
around, you can put right in
here as the underscore ID of the
documents that are going
to get created during
the grouping phase.
OK.
Let's have a quiz.
Given the following
collection--
which is right here,
db stuff--
and has a, b, and c keys for
each of the documents, and the
following aggregation query--
right here, we have created a
compound grouping key which is
a JSON document, Mo,
Larry, and Curly--
how many documents will
be in the result set?
Check one.