All right, let's talk about the
dollar sort pipeline stage
when you're aggregating.
Now, dollar sort does pretty
much what you'd expect.
It sorts the documents, but a
few things to keep in mind
when you sort.
The first is that it can
be a real memory hog.
The aggregation framework
doesn't go to disk for sorting
as far as I know.
And so it's going to
sort in memory.
If the sort is before a grouping
and after a match, I
think it can use an index.
But if it's after the grouping
phase, I don't believe it can
use an index.
And the second thing to remember
about dollar sort is
it can go before or after
the group phase.
You can sort multiple
times if you'd like.
And it's going to be
really useful.
Now, I'm going to show you
a sort at the end of the
pipeline, which is good for
formatting a report.
But sorting before you do a
grouping is even more useful
in terms of aggregating
different pieces of data from
the collection.
So let's look at sorting at
the end of the pipeline.
We're going to go back to
our zip code data set.
And each document looks like
this, if you recall.
And then we're going to just add
a sort at the end of this
query that we did before.
Makes it a little bit
more useful though.
We're going to match on all
of the zip codes in the
state of New York.
We're going to group by the
city and sum up the
population.
And then we're going to project,
just to make it a
little bit neater.
We're going to rename the
underscore ID field to be
city, essentially through
these two operations,
suppressing the underscore ID
and then creating a new key
called city.
And then we're going to include
the population.
And then we're going to sort
by population descending.
And of course this can
be a compound key.
It doesn't need to be just
a single key here.
But, in this case, I just want
to sort by the population
descending.
Let's see what that
looks like.
All right, so it looks
like this.
I'll just make sure I'm running
the right one here.
There we go.
It looks like this.
And you can see that now we've
got the result in descending
population order.
So we could see the biggest
cities in New York.
And the biggest city in New York
is considered Brooklyn,
which is one of the five
boroughs in New York City.
And again, as I told you before,
it looks like in this
data set each borough
its own city.
And actually, beyond that, so
this is Manhattan right here.
This is the Bronx.
This is the city of Rochester.
And then this is Staten
Island, which is
where I grew up.
And then you can see that Queens
has been broken up into
multiple pieces.
Buffalo is a separate city, but
the borough of Queens is
not even a city.
It's put in as Flushing,
and Jamaica,
and a few other places.
I guess the post office of the
United States has its own
notion of what a city is,
interestingly enough.
So that's news to me.
I consider New York to be one
city since it has one mayor.
All right, so let's now
do a quiz on sorting.
So again, considering the zip
code collection, which has the
documents that look like that.
Write an aggregation query to
sort by state comma city,
ascending, both of
them ascending.
And assume the collection
is called zips.
And put your answer
right there.