In MongoDB 2.6,
we have a new pipeline operator,
a new stage available
and it's the $out stage.
Prior to 2.6,
you could not redirect
the output of aggregation
to a new collection.
You have to write
a custom program to do that.
But in 2.6 you can specify
a collection
that should receive the results
of your aggregation
and that makes it very convenient
if you want to use those results
after you perform
the aggregation.
And this is new in 2.6.
So let's go over how it works.
Okay, I've set up a small collection
of documents that represent
the outcome of games played
by a few players.
And the structure of the document,
let's say the first name is "Jerzy"
and the last name is "Fischer,"
he got two points in that game
and here were his moves.
You can see that there's a few
different documents in here.
The players were Shannon Bradshaw,
our Director of Education,
Jerzy Fischer does all of our video production,
and of course this is me.
So not very many documents.
And if we wanted to aggregate these
we could do it like this.
Alright, here's a simple
aggregation query
that we're going to perform
on this collection.
It's just going to aggregate
and group by first name
and last name
and sum up the points I received.
If we did that, it's called simple_agg.
Let's run it.
You can see that it produces
three documents,
one for Jerzy, one for Shannon
and one for me,
with the total number of points
that we received.
It just aggregates the collection.
That's pretty straightforward.
Now, let's say we wanted to actually send
that result to another collection.
Well we can do that now,
using the $out stage.
So let's look at that.
Okay, here's the same aggregation query
but this time
we're going to redirect the output.
It's a simple grouping,
the _id for the grouping
was first name and last name
and we summed the points.
That's what you just saw.
Now we're going to have a new stage
called $out
and the value is the name
of the collection
we want to send the results to.
'summary_results'
Alright, so let's see that work.
Now, there is no collection
called 'summary_results' right now,
I dropped it before the video
so let's run this little script,
see what we get.
And it doesn't produce
a lot of output to the screen
because, of course, it created
a new collection
called summary _results
and if we look in the collection
called summary_results
you can see that here is the collection
that we created.
Now the $out operator
is destructive.
If the collection already existed,
it would destroy it.
And so be very careful
if you're going to use it
to make sure that you're okay
with dropping the previous collection.
Let me show you
how that would work,
so I'll show you how it's destructive.
So let's delete the collection.
Let's put something in the collection.
Now there is something
in the summary _results collection.
I'll just show you that.
And now let's run that script again.
And now let's connect to MongoDB
and see what's in the summary_results collection.
And we can see that that little document
I created with "foo" : "andrew"
is gone and now we have these three documents.
Now another thing to be wary of
when you do this
is that you need to make sure
that the _id's
that you're sending
are unique
and there are certain cases
where they might not be.
So let me give you an example.
So, let's do a simple unwind
of this collection.
So we're just going to unwind
the moves array
that's in each document.
And if you remember,
here are the documents
in the collection
and each of these documents
has a moves array,
and if I unwind
the moves array,
this is what I will see.
So, I unwind the moves array.
We get an explosion of documents.
Each document is in here multiple times
because the moves array has been unwound,
and you'll notice that the _id
for this when you unwind
the documents can be duplicated.
So for instance, this _id
is the same as this _id.
So if we redirected that
to a new collection,
we're going to get an error if we try.
So let's see what happens if we do that.
Here, I'll show you what the script
looked like,
it's called the broken _out command.
And here we unwind the moves array
but we also send the results
to summary_results.
We haven't done any grouping here,
just an unwind,
so because we have
some duplicated _ids,
we're going to see an error
when we try to do this redirection
to this new collection.
So let's see that happen.
So I'm going to run this thing
called "broken_out"
and we can see that if you do that
you get a duplicate key error.
So here we are.
We get a duplicate key error.
We see the insert failed.
And the way this works,
if any of the inserts fail,
then you won't destroy
the previous collection
and you won't see your result.
Because what actually happens
under the covers
is that when you are doing an aggregation
with $out,
it sends the results
to a temporary collection
and at the very end
it does some renaming
to reassignment, to update it
so that the collection
reflects where you redirected
the output.
So, for instance, this failed
and if I go into MongoDB
and I look at summary_results, you can see
that I have the previous results
because it wasn't destructive
to this collection.
Alright, so that's how the $out
operator works.