The aggregation framework
is super cool.
But it is subject to certain
limitations.
And I want to discuss those
with you right now so that
you're aware of them.
The first one is that the
results set is limited to 16
megabytes of memory because, as
you know, it's returned in
a single document.
And a single document in MongoDB
is limited to 16
megabytes of memory.
So that's pretty large.
But for a very large collection,
that could be a
limitation if it's going to
run across the entire
collection.
Another limitation is that you
can't use more than 10% of the
memory on a machine.
Now that's a lot of memory.
But these aggregations can be
quite complicated, especially
if they're going across
the entire collection.
Now you can reduce the size of
your aggregations by doing
early matches to do filtering,
if you don't need to do
calculations across
all the documents.
Similarly, you could use Project
to filter out some of
the fields so that
you're using--
processing less data.
But these are two things
to keep in mind.
And the last one is how
it works in a sharded
environment.
So let's go through a
sharded environment.
So in a sharded environment, if
you remember, you typically
have your collection.
We're not going to go over this
extensively in this class.
Collections split amongst
multiple Mongo instances.
And these are often
replica sets.
So there might be three servers
here and three servers
here and three servers here that
are all handling the same
part of the collection.
And then rather than sending
your query directly to a
MongoD process.
And these all have MongoDs
running on them.
You send it to a
MongoS process.
It's a router.
So your application is here.
And it talks to MongoS, which
then talks to MongoD.
And each of these is a shard.
So aggregation does work in
a sharded environment.
But after the first group, or
the first sort phase, the
aggregation has to be brought
back to the MongoS.
So the first group in Sort can
be split up to run here on a
particular--
well if you're going to run an
aggregation across the entire
collection, the MongoS will send
group and sort to all the
shards, and it will do them.
But after the first group and
sort, they need to be gathered
here in the MongoS, brought
together for final result
before they're sent to the next
stage of the pipeline.
Because the next stage of the
pipeline needs to see the
finished result.
So as a result, if you have a
very long pipeline, you can
easily wind up where
your calculation is
running on your MongoS.
Now in terms of application
engineering, usually the
MongoS process is running on
the same computer as your
applications.
So as your app is running, and
then you put a little MongoS
on the same box.
And that box might be
sized differently,
relative to the database.
Might be smaller.
And this aggregation
might be gigantic.
So keep in mind that when
you're in a sharded
environment and you're doing
allegations, that your
calculations probably happening
in your MongoS router.
And that might have an effect
on other application
performance if MongoS is
co-located with the
application.
Kind of beyond the scope
of this course.
But I just want to mention it
because I know that some of
you probably do work in sharded
environments on large
production systems.
And we're going to talk a little
bit more about the
implications of sharding and
replication and other aspects
of system architecture as
a developer next week.
Now there are other alternatives
to the
aggregation framework if you
don't want to use it, or can't
use it because of some
of the limitations.
You can use MapReduce.
There's a version of that
built into Mongo.
And we haven't talked about
it in this course.
But you could use it.
You could also use Hadoop.
And the Hadoop framework
is basically an
implementation of MapReduce.
And if you want to do that,
there's a Hadoop connector
that can connect between
Hadoop and MongoDB.
So those are some other options
if you can't use the
aggregation framework for
a particular query.
All right.
So that's it.