Okay, so, I want to talk to you about
Python and the special way
it interacts with Aggregation.
Or you should say that it is slightly
different in 2.6 than it was previously.
In the shell but not in Python.
And I'll explain what I'm talking about.
So, prior to mongoDB 2.6,
mongoDB returned all the
aggregation results in one big document.
And this has a lot of limitations.
For, instance if all the aggregation
results are gonna be returned
in one document, then, of course,
your aggregation results
are limited to the size of the document
which is 16 megabytes.
And now, new in 2.6, very exciting,
is that aggregation can,
and does, inside the shell
return a cursor.
So, that's a big difference.
And what we've seen inside the shell,
of course, is that aggregation does
return a cursor and gives you
all the documents one after another
using an iterator.
But prior to 2.6,
this was not the way it worked.
Prior to 2.6, you got one big document.
So, the question is,
what happens in Python?
Well, it turns out that, in Python
we still return by default
one big document in 2.6.
So, Python lives over here.
But it optionally can do
what the shell does.
So.. Let's draw this out a little bit more
'cause I think it's kinda tricky.
So, we had 2.4 and had 2.6.
And then, we had
what happens in the shell.
what happens in Python.
So, in 2.4, the shell and Python
returned one big document.
And in 2.6 the shell now returns a cursor.
And Python still returns one big document.
But optionally Python returns a cursor.
Let's see this in action.
It's pretty interesting!
Okay, we're gonna once again aggregate
on our zip code collection.
This is a small Python script.
Let's go through it line by line.
We're gonna import Pymongo.
Get a connection using MongoClient.
We're gonna connect to our
aggregation data base.
And then, we're gonna aggregate.
We're gonna group by our state,
and we're gonna sum our population up.
Very straight forward aggregation,
the same we've been doing
over and over again.
And then, we're gonna print the result.
Let's see what we get.
Okay. So, now we will see what we get
when we run this
populationbystate.py file
that I just showed you.
Wow! That's a big mess,
but let's go through it carefully
and see what it is.
Alright, and remember, all I did
in this particular program
is print the result I got
from the aggregation.
So, if go through here, I see that
the result is in itself a document.
It returns the fact that
aggregation was true.
And, at the result is this array of
documents each one is one of the results
of the aggregation query.
That, for instance, we have, let's say,
Pennsylvania has a population of,
maybe,11 million.
I can't quite see what that is.
This is North Dakota, has a population
of 638,000. That's a very small state.
And, over here on top, was West Virginia,
with a population of 1.7 million.
Is that right?
Wow, small state, 1.8 million!
If you wanna round it.
So, this aggregation result
will be limited to 16 megabytes.
This is the older style
of returning results.
And, we didn't wanna break Python programs
in 2.6, so, we kept the old behavior
by default.
However, you can get the new behavior
where you get a cursor,
and you're not limited to 16megabytes.
And I'll show you how.
So, right here,
we have the same aggregation query,
and this case, we're gonna tack on
a new value called
'cursor equals empty document'.
And this keyword argument to aggregation
is going to change the behavior
of the aggregation framework.
So, now that we're going
to get back a cursor,
I can no longer just print the result.
Instead I have to iterate
through the result.
So, let's do that,
for doc in result: print doc.
And, that should take care of it
and print every document in the result.
It's because I gave the
cursor equals empty document option.
So, let's run through there.
See what I get.
And, there you go!
You get that nice clean result
we got before which is similar
to what you get in the shell.
Where you see that each document in
the aggregation result comes through
as a separate document in the cursor
that you get back
and you can iterate through them.
And, if you wanted to set other options..
For instance, if you wanted to set
the option for using disk,
you could do that.
You could say allow disk use equals true.
And you can see it's the different style
of giving options
than you gave in the shell.
So, keep that in mind. This is Python.
And, if I do that, and go through it,
this shouldn't change the result at all.
It gives you the same result.
Maybe a tad slower.
So, how disk use will let you get around
that hundred megabyte limit
for any pipeline stage.
Okay, so anyway,
that's how you ask for the behavior
that is default in 2.6 in the shell
which is to get a cursor back
versus getting one big document back.
And, generally speaking its
a lot more convenient
to get one big document back.
But because we didn't want to
break Python programs that worked in 2.4,
we made it backwards compatible
by having the default in Python
be the older behavior.
In the shell, we were not
backward compatible.
The default behavior is now to return
a cursor that gives you
a list of documents.
Okay, its time for quiz.
Let's see how carefully
you were listening.
Let's talk about mongoDB 2.4 and 2.6,
and the behavior of aggregation
and particularly the aggregate method
and whether it returns a cursor
or document in the shell or Pymongo.
Which of the following statements
about aggregation results are true?
Check all that apply.
And I won't read them to you,
but you should read them and figure out
which ones are true.