Now that you've gone through the
aggregation framework, you
should have a better
understanding--
especially is you come
from the SQL world--
how the pieces of the
aggregation framework map to
what exists in MongoDB.
So, I think this is fairly
obvious once you've done it,
but I just want to take
you through it.
The where clause that you might
see in SQL is equivalent
to the match clause in a match
phase of an aggregation.
When you group by something in
SQL, that's equivalent to
using the group phase of the
pipeline in MongoDB.
Now, if you don't know SQL,
you're probably not familiar
with a lot of these.
But the having clause lets
you specify which of the
aggregated results
you want to see.
It's an additional level of
filtering you get than in SQL.
And that's really
straightforward in Mongo
because since we can put
multiple operators in the
pipeline, we can have multiple
match stages.
So you just put another match
stage and it works perfectly
well that way.
Selecting out what you want is
equivalent to projection.
Ordering is equivalent
to sorting.
Limiting is equivalent
to limiting.
Sum is equivalent to summing.
In counting, you use
a sum operator.
You use a 1 if you want to
count, and if you want to sum,
and then you use a sum operator
with the key of what
you want to sum on.
And the join is really no direct
analog in MongoDB, but
it's sort of similar to the way
you use unwind, because
unwind unwinds then rejoins in
a way that makes it more
amenable to aggregation.
So if you have SQL in your head
and you're thinking about
how it all fits together, then
this little chart, which is
available in our
documentation--
and you can just Google for SQL
to aggregation framework
MongoDB and you'll
get this page--
shows you how that maps.