OK, this problem was called
Removing Rural Residents.
And in it we said, well, the
data set has some cities that
start with a digit.
And if a city starts with a
digit, then let's assume that
it's really not a city, that's
it's just a zip code that's
not in a city.
And can we figure out the sum
total of people who live in a
city that starts with a digit as
a name, ostensively, so we
can remove that number from the
overall population number?
So we called it Removing Rural
Residents, although what
you're actually going to do in
this problem is calculate the
total population of people who
live in a rural area that's a
city that starts with a digit.
Now, to do this, we suggested
that you might use the
substring operator to pull the
first character out of the
city so that you
can compare it.
Now, you could also do this
with a regular expression.
And I specifically suggested
a substring operator, not
because of efficiency or
anything else, but just
because we hadn't gone over the
substring operator, and I
thought it was an interesting
operator, and I wanted to
expose you to it.
So that's why it's
in this problem.
Let's look at the answer.
So the answer is-- as I said,
we first do a projection to
the zip code database.
And we create the first
character of the city.
We extract out just the first
And we also carry through the
population and the city name
and the zip code, which we now
call zip, which was originally
the underscore ID.
And then we include the state.
I guess is also could
have just said one.
Didn't need to say $city here,
so that was sort of odd.
You could do it two different
ways, but I did it this way.
Now, we're going to go through
and we're going to match only
the cities that start
with a digit.
So we're going to call match the
first character being in
this array of digits.
At this point, we've got a set
of documents that only
represent these people who live
in the rural areas where
the city starts with a digit.
And we just want to get a sum of
that population, so we just
run a grouping on id null,
figure out the population, sum
of the populations that
we see in every
document as it comes through.
And that's pretty much
the entire answer.
I don't think there's
anything more to it.
Nope, that's it.
Here we're going to run it and
find out the population of the
rural areas is 298,015.
And let's see if that was the
answer that was accepted.
And the answer is yes,
that was the
answer that was accepted.
So that's how you
do this problem.